Dr. Austin Leaks, welcome to Miami and
welcome to Biohawk Kids.
>> Yeah, thanks for having me.
>> I'm really excited to sit down with you
since we chatted in London.
>> Yep.
>> You brought up something when we had
dinner together about how people are
constantly chasing symptoms.
>> Well, yeah, it's easy to do when you
have a lot of symptoms going on and a
lot of unknown reasons as to why they're
happening. I think you can start chasing
your tail pretty quickly and uh it takes
a lot of work to figure out what's going
on. It's kind of like being an
investigative analyst like you have to
really dive deep and oftentimes we don't
have the time or the resources to do
that.
>> And when it means like in my opinion
sometimes people do you think they just
kind of come up with symptoms as well
because something else is going on
they're projecting other areas of their
life. Is it almost like avoiding things
that are unhealed?
>> Yeah, that's a really good question. I
think um you know much like when you get
sick I think you start having you know
you feel malaise you feel fatigued you
have runny nose like you just overall
don't feel very well and it's it starts
creating this dysfunction within your
system to where um it's easy to become
like a hypochondriact about what's going
on because when you're aware of what's
what your body is trying to tell you
start trying to figure it out on your
own and so every little thing becomes a
potential problem when the reality is
sometimes it's just part of living in
this world and other times there it
really is an actual issue.
>> For anybody listening, why do you think
conventional medicine fails so many
people every single year?
>> Well, it's kind of like what I was
saying before, like it takes a lot of
effort and time to figure these things
out. And also, we have a system that
profits off the sick. Um, whenever
you're rewarding people for not helping
people to get better to their full
capability, um, you're going to create a
system that is very toxic. And um I
think we're seeing the full effect of
that now with our you know the fact that
we spend the most amount of money in the
world on healthcare and we have one of
the sickest
>> developed nations in the world like
there's there's your evidence.
>> I you know I always look at other
countries that are you know kind of
spend on healthcare and stuff and I was
like why are they doing better than us?
Like is it do you think it's just down
to the fact that pharmaceutical industry
is so intertwined in our government and
it's become so corrupt or do you think
it's across the board from agriculture
to how we're training people in medical
schools and turning out doctors these
days? Like where do you see the largest
piece of the problem? I think the
largest piece is going to stem from our
beliefs as a culture that we can put all
our trust or all our eggs in the basket
of conventional medicine thinking that
they can solve all our problems because
that's been the indoctrination since the
you know early 1900s is that you know
your doctor knows everything health
related and they don't. They're trained
in specific areas of health for sure and
are really good at it but they are not
the end- all beall when it comes to
health. And so our culture, especially
our grandparents and our parents, they
think there, you know, there's a pill
for every ill and that's all you really
have to do. You don't have to do any
actual work. But then that stems into,
yeah, agriculture stems into our
workforce. It stems into what happens in
the home and uh it creates a very
vicious cycle.
>> When we, you know, we were there for the
inauguration together and, you know, we
were so excited to bring in Bobby
Kennedy and I think they HHS has done
some amazing work. However, do you think
they're as far along currently to date
as we had maybe hoped or expected?
>> I think probably not as far as we would
hoped. I I think it's realistically
though it's is probably as far as we
could have gotten to this point. There's
a lot of undoing that we have to to do
to kind of get at real progress. And
also understand that there's a lot of
there's a lot of temptations or active
threats going against uh Bobby Kennedy
and the whole organization because
there's a lot of money to be made. And I
think the advancements with technology
and AI is really uh something that we
probably don't fully understand the full
consequences of that yet. But it's
coming under the guise of like well this
is better for the health of the people
when the reality is it probably may lead
to more control.
>> I saw this little clip I think it was a
couple of weeks ago and it was President
Trump Bobby Kennedy who was obviously in
it Dr. draws and it was perhaps the CEO
of Fizer but definitely somebody from
from Fizer
>> and they were talking about like their
funding and what they're going to do
with it and I just stood back and I just
shook my head. I was like this is not
about giving you guys more funding. This
is about
>> looking deeper into what a lot of the
products that they have created. Not a
single product that has come out of
Fizer has led to a cure ever,
>> right?
>> And so for me that was that was a little
like disappointing almost because I was
like listen like we all know what's
going on here. But that's where I say
that the pharmaceutical companies have
such a power over our government because
of the amount of funding that they have
brought in that I don't think any
government these guys have definitely
done a much better job are completely
free of that. Well, again, I think if if
what they were doing was leading to
healthier nations and and populations,
then it's great, you know, but if it's
just about, hey, instead of uh getting
at the root cause of things, now we're
just going to create a new product with
a different angle that's going to help
you, you know, treat the symptom and not
actually fix a problem. It's like, well,
we're just like, it's a revolving door
of what we've already been exposed to.
So, I'm hoping that we actually have a
true desire to heal people. But when you
look at people like the World Economic
Forum where they have a stated
depopulation agenda, I don't believe
that that's really what we're trying to
do.
>> Yeah. When you if you were like actively
part of HHS and you could work on
certain policies and stuff, what are
>> Boy,
>> what are three policies or things that
you would like to get funding for? And
what policies would you have liked to
put into place? Yeah, it' be uh policies
for having like microagg,
you know, exposed to the the things that
it is and have to have the preservatives
and all that stuff in it. Um, the other
one would be supporting the nuclear
family so that we can have women if they
want to work like that's fantastic, but
allowing for more flexibility so they
can be at home with their new babies or
supporting their families and having um
roles for husbands to take on that where
they can make more money to buy good
healthy food. Like these are all very
like, you know, maybe not so practical,
but they also all are very practical at
the same time. It's like we want to have
a nuclear family. We want to have good
healthy food and we don't want to treat
our our homes like hotels. I think if we
can avoid that, we would start seeing a
lot more health in our nation.
>> You know, it's funny you talk about how
women should have more choice. I think
feminism was terrible. The first wave of
feminism where we were able to vote and
have our own bank account. Amazing
obviously. Okay.
>> But the second wave of feminism that
came in I think is completely been toxic
to the family system because it has
taken away traditional gender roles
which made us women stay in our feminine
and men in their masculine. And when I
look at America, because I'm I'm
obviously Pakistani, I spend a lot of
time in the Middle East as well. When I
look at America and what's happened to
the men in this country when it comes to
being providers and protectors, which at
the end of the day is the two main
purposes of being a man,
>> right?
>> If you're not alignment over there, then
what are you doing,
>> right? But so many stories I hear them
all day that people man in this country
are so disconnected from understanding
that that is your role and function to
provide safety and security to your
partner and to provide financially to
your partner.
>> Right. Well, I think again culturally
speaking, we've we've created this fear
at least what I've experienced as a as a
white male. It's like I feel bad for
being a white male who wants to protect
my wife. Like
>> why? because that's what we've been told
for since I was a kid that like this is
a toxic masculinity thing. The reality
is uh and what I've realized now that I
have four kids and been married for 12
years um being a a male is is hard and
if anything it's uh it's a lot of
responsibility, right? It's it's it's
not that I get to abuse my leadership.
It's if anything, if I'm going to be a
good leader, it means that I have to die
to myself. I have to sacrifice. I have
to give up what I what I want to do for
my for the for the benefit of my kids
and my wife. And so I think um there's a
picture of like true masculinity from
like a biblical perspective that doesn't
align with what our culture says
masculinity is. So that's part of the
problem.
>> You know, I wouldn't even look at it
like that and I'll I'll pose this to you
and you tell me what you think. I think
it's not even giving up what we want,
but it's repositioning the narrative
because a woman also adds so much
structure and and and a woman's energy
is naturally a manifestation, right? So,
she creates that structure at home and
brings in that creativity for and tells
a man, I'm going to give you peace in
the house so that you can go out into
the world and create and you can go out
into the world and bring home abundance
for us because I'm providing you that
safety as well. It's almost like an
energetic exchange
>> in some ways and and women are I I think
choosing the right partner is very very
important.
>> Um but I think that again needs to be
shifted as a narrative is like instead
of making men feel like they're
sacrificing
it's that together planning so the man
still feels supported as well but
understands the woman's also taking on a
lot of responsibility especially in this
country where child care is next to
impossible for a lot of people. Right.
>> Very expensive. No, I think that's such
a like I think about my wife and I like
most of my business success is I mean
almost all of it has been because of her
like she is she like she stays home with
our kids by design like she wants to
like that was what we discussed before
we even had kids when she worked um at
different points when our early in our
marriage before we had kids and she
actually provided most of the financial
income when I was in school because she
had to and but when we were first
married um I told her I was like look we
want to have kids like you want to stay
at home even though you could go out and
do anything that you wanted to and So we
took a financial hit up front, you know,
to to for me to have one income.
>> But by us doing that, she pro yeah, she
provided that peace and stability within
our home to where we would have amazing
meals. Like we would have a peaceful
environment. Like our house would be
very maintained. We'd have a lot of
guests come over. We would like host a
lot of people. And you know, since we've
had kids, it's just kind of continued.
So I I 100% agree with you. Like that is
an energetic exchange that if it wasn't
for her or wasn't for me working
together, it wouldn't have happened.
>> Yeah. And I don't think you can almost
put a price tag on that sort of a
beautiful harmony between the two,
right? And I think when we look across
the world in any cultures, I think both
people understanding their roles and
understanding what they're bringing to
the table improves their health,
improves the community that they're part
of. And I think that's where we've gone
wrong in this country is we've become so
disconnected from understanding our own
personal identities. And that's where I
think a lot of women are also women are
30% more susceptible to autoimmune
disease. But I think also women are
living out of design. Women are
chronically stressed. We're pushing
ourselves to do things that we're not
necessarily designed to do. And we're
constantly like we we we our cortisol
levels are unwired. Well, that's I mean
I always I've always said, you know,
when you look at things like PCOS and
indenturosis and and really what you're
seeing is the reversal of the benefits
of female hormones. You're switching
from like, you know, femininity to
masculinity by design because like you
you have to that's a cortisol response.
And so I think whenever I'm working with
a female client, it's always I'm always
trying to portray that to them and help
them to analyze areas of their life
where where that's not happening where
it's like where are you adding extra
cortisol or extra stress unnecessarily
sometimes and sometimes because you have
to like you know there's just certain
things you have to do but more times
than not when you have this culture
that's saying like do more do more and
you start getting less and less like you
have to understand the connection
hormonally as to why that's happening.
And that's that's the whole point. If
you are taking protein powder, you
definitely need to hear this. The Clean
Label Project tested 160 different
proteins from different vendors and
brands across the US. And you're going
to be shocked at the discovery that they
made. Nearly half of the top selling
proteins in the US tested high for lead.
And if you're somebody who consumes
protein powders daily, this is something
you have to be concerned about. And to
make matters worse, most brands do not
value transparency and will not reveal
their test data online. And I want my
community like myself to always make an
informed choice of what they want to be
exposed to and how they consume their
daily protein. And that is why I love
Pure. I also sat down with the founder
and had a full honest transparent
conversation with him about how they
source, how they educate their consumer,
and also what their products offer on
the market, which sets them apart. Their
Pure PW1 protein tastes absolutely
exceptional and you know you're not
getting the gunk of heavy metals in it
to start your morning with. And that is
why I absolutely love Pur's PW1 whey
protein and that is how I choose to
start my day every morning. Every single
batch is third party tested by the Clean
Label Project and no product is ever
sold unless it passes these tests. NPU
is one of the only brands in the US that
has the clean label product
certification on their products. And
that is only possible because they make
all their third party testing completely
transparently available to the consumer
through a QR code where you can track
the exact journey of the batch of
product that you're purchasing. So you
guys can see for yourself exactly how
clean the PW1 that you're consuming in
the morning is. Every single serving
gives you 21 g of minimally processed,
high quality bioavailable protein. It
comes from pasture-raised
cows, no GMOs, no hormones, no
herbicides, no pesticides, and
definitely no heavy metals. So, this
means I can start my day with confidence
knowing I'm having something super clean
to support my skeletal muscle mass. My
personal favorite flavor is a Berber and
vanilla. no artificial flavors and no
funky aftertaste. So, make sure your
daily protein powder is not hiding any
nasty chemicals and they're not being
open and transparent with you. So, if
you want something clean, delicious, and
bioavailable with transparency, go now
to get this amazing discount. Poor.com
pury.com/biohackit.
Switch over to Pur's PW1 protein and you
can thank me later. when you are working
with your female clients, right? What
are the three things you tell them to
optimize their hormones before they turn
to something like um hormone replacement
therapy, which we're going to get into?
>> Yeah. Uh it's always going to be
circadian rhythm first of all.
>> And so what is that? Let's explain to
the audience.
>> Yeah. So circadian rhythm is is
basically whenever light is interacting
with your pineal gland coming through
your eyes, it's going to help to
regulate hormones within your body. So
appetite like grein, leptin, uh
cortisol, melatonin, all those hormones
are being regulated because of your
circadian rhythm. And so when you're
awake in the morning time, you're
starting that circadian clock. And so
when you eat food in the morning, that
kind of breaks your fast, right? That's
why we have breakfast.
>> A lot of women that I work with, they
are told to fast, right? And so they're
skipping breakfast, but they're yet
having caffeine or caffeine with sugar
or milk or whatever in it, breaking
their fast, and that's their breakfast.
And so they're starting their day off
with this disregulated circadian rhythm
already. And so now all of a sudden
insulin, which is going to be regulating
your sugar coming into your body, which
is essentially energy, it's going to be
saying like, "Hey, let's store this as
fat because we're going to need it as
for later for a rainy day
>> instead of utilizing it for energy
uptake throughout the duration of your
day." So now you're going to start
having fatigue. You're having more fat
storage
>> just because you had a bad start to your
day. Okay. And so if you do that
frequently and then you have other
stressors of like you're eating toxic
food like a lot of processed food or
ultrarocessed food that's adding even
more of a burden to your system or maybe
you're exposed to m exposed to mold or
maybe you have parasites or heavy metals
or just radiation from your phone.
>> Now all of a sudden your cells are very
toxic laden and they're having to work
on all these extra stressors which is
essentially what's happening to your
body. So oxidative stress is essentially
what's happening and a lot of women are
just not really able to fully see the
the dots that they're connecting as far
as like why they feel the way they feel
and why their cells are not functioning
well and then subsequently why they have
you know like thyroid issues or sex
hormone issues or infertility issues
because all that stuff is connected back
to each other.
>> So it's so funny you were saying that
most women wake up in the morning and
tend to so I was having black coffee in
the morning and then I'd go work out and
then I'd come back and have a protein
breakfast right and then a dear friend
of mine Dr. John Kim was like, "I don't
think you can do that because your
hormones are so wired right now. Your
cortisol is really high." So, he taught
me this recipe. It's called a Russian
custard. Have you heard of it? Yeah.
>> So, basically, two egg yolks raw with a
little bit of sea salt and honey. And
he's like, "The first thing you do is
besides have water with electrolytes and
minerals. Right after that, you're going
to take this shot of this Russian
custard and then you can have your
coffee." Right. But that is what you
have to do because your body has to
absorb the nutrients before the cup of
coffee hits your stomach.
>> Yeah. Because caffeine spikes cortisol
and cortisol is going to spike your need
for blood sugar for sugar. And so you're
going to have more sugar cravings.
You're going to be more hungry. You're
going to be more likely to have snacks
in between meals. And all this is just
causing this disregulated circadian
rhythm. So that when you do go
throughout your day now, you're going to
have a big crash in the afternoon or
>> that was happening to me.
>> Yeah. Or then when you uh do eat a meal,
you're going to want to overeat. And
then when you do go to bed, you're going
to have disregulated sleep and then
you're going to start this whole vicious
cycle. So circular rhythm would be the
first thing that I would say would be
the what you need to fix as a as a
female.
>> Uh second thing would be um I think just
ensuring you understand what your toxic
burden is, right? And so I kind of
mentioned this a little bit already, but
a lot of women don't know.
They don't know what they don't know,
right? Just like most of us, if you
don't test, you don't if you don't know
kind of what's going on, you're not
going to have any idea where to start.
So, if you've been exposed to mold or
you have a history of mono and EBV or
you've had issues with parasites or
heavy metals, like all these things I
said, if you have that kind of brewing
in the background and you're taking, you
know, your your supplements, you're
eating the right food and you're you're
trying to do all these things, exercise,
>> but you have these underlying um
stressors to your cells, you're you're
going to be kind of chasing your tail
for a while. Like, and that's what I was
mentioning with your symptoms before. if
you don't know what you're really trying
to fix and you're just trying to fix a
symptom, there's a lot of reasons you
could have certain symptoms. And so,
it's not always just like, oh, I have a
runny nose, it's this, or I have joint
pain, it's this. It's like, well, it
could be many things. And so, you have
to kind of get at the root of that. And
that's where I would say to be the
second thing. Um, comments on that or
>> No, I think um a lot of times we are,
like you said, we're so focused on the
on the symptom that we forget that we
have to zoom back and look at the larger
picture. How are we sleeping? How are we
eating? what are external stressors in
our life? How are we getting enough
sleep? Right?
>> So, when my hormones were completely out
of whack this summer, I realized I
wasn't getting enough REM or deep sleep
at all. And when I started fixing my
sleep hygiene, having a proper like
nighttime routine, making sure I'm in
bed by 10:00, trying to put away my
phone, um turning off my phone so I'm
not getting any of the EMF of radiation
coming through. And I just checked my
sleep score. And my sleep score after
four months, for the first time ever,
five months was like at a 98.
>> Wow. And I had two and a half hours of
REM sleep, an hour and a half of deep
sleep. And I was like, "Wow,
>> big difference.
>> It makes such a big difference." But
that was getting my body the right
nutrients, circadian rhythm cycling, and
then from there, making sure that I'm
working on my sleep hygiene.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it's it's the boring
stuff, right? Like it's the things that
really
>> But that's the beautiful part. It's the
free stuff that people don't realize.
Start with the things that are free
before you go buy another supplement,
before you get on this. And even before,
you tell me if this is right or wrong.
Before you consider getting on hormone
replacement therapy, I think you need to
fix certain like functions in your life
and make sure you're creating certain
healthier habits and then adding in the
hormones.
>> Yeah, that's always been my stance
because if you just add hormones to a
broken system, you're just going to feed
you're going to feed this the the the
wrong pathway that is causing the
problem. So, a lot of women will get
like testosterone or they'll get, you
know, estrogen or progesterone,
whatever. But if they're already having
a dysfunctional hormonal pathway,
they're just going to re-emphasize the
problem and so it's going to exacerbate
it.
>> Um, and this is the same with
parmenopause, too. Like a lot of women
that are going through parmenopause,
entering menopause think that, well,
this is like a dysfunctional thing, but
the reality is parmenopause is is is
happening for about 10 years up until
menopause occurs, right? And so a lot
of, you know, conventional doctors be
like, "Well, once you don't have a cycle
for 12 months, now you're you're
menopausal, you're postmenopausal." It's
like, it's like if you if you like were
pregnant and and the doctor's like,
"Well, you're not pregnant until the the
baby's here." Correct.
>> It's like, "No, like you've been
pregnant this whole time leading up to
it." Absolutely. And so I think a lot of
people um will throw hormones at a
problem when they don't realize that
there are symptoms like you know PMS or
mood swings or you know weight gain or
fatigue or brain fog happening for 10
years leading up to menopause that needs
to be addressed. And if you address
those things, then menopause is actually
>> uh you go from fertility to stability,
right? Like it's if you have good
hormonal balance leading up to it, it
can be a great experience for a female
to become, you know, transition into a
different phase of life where you can be
a stable force rather than like a
fertile force.
>> And I think um but it all gets back to
like the foundational problems that were
persisting before that.
>> So your wife has had four beautiful,
gorgeous, healthy babies. Is it true
that when a woman gives birth, her body
almost experiences right after that like
a menopause like for a little bit?
>> Yeah, I mean that's why you don't you
don't have a cycle, right? There's that
there's a lack of a cycle.
>> And how long do you not have a cycle
for? I mean,
>> it depends on the woman. So, a lot of it
depends on breastfeeding. So, like if
they're breastfeeding at night um for
like my wife, she she's still
breastfeeding and she just had her cycle
and she's like 12 months post delivery
and so but she was feeding our baby like
all throughout the night until a couple
couple months ago. her circadian rhythm
is not
>> Yeah. So she's but she's still her
body's still requiring that. So I like
our neighbor for example she you know or
I can't remember maybe one of my wife's
friends she she starts having her cycle
like eight weeks after she
>> and she was breastfeeding or no
>> she her breastfeeding is different from
and I don't even know who this person is
but this is just my wife has told me. So
either way um it just it varies quite a
bit depending on where you're at. You
know, I feel like the female body and I
had another guest on in London when we
were together uh on the podcast and this
man told me he's like, "We always place
this idea of like strength and courage
and all on the men, but the women are
really truly res resilient more than men
could ever be or dream of being because
imagine a woman who gives birth and she
does not sleep properly sometimes for
years. cuz I have friends who are like
don't really have a nanny, are doing
everything themselves, the baby's always
with them, and some of their kids are
like 2 and 1/2 years old, and they have
not slept properly for 2 and 1/2 years,
>> and they're still functioning at work.
They're a great hands-on mom. They're a
great wife. And I'm like, man, if you
did that to a man, he would fall apart.
Like, a man going through two years of
sleep regression.
>> Yeah.
>> They wouldn't be functioning.
>> Well, it's it's hard to it's just it's
such a hard and it gets back to what you
were saying before. It's like there's
different
>> there's we have different skill sets and
different abilities.
>> I think men because of our cycles are 24
hours on the clock. Like we're very
stable in that sense. And so
>> we can handle a lot of load and and do
we actually do better with it. I always
say men are like trailers. Like we pull
straighter with a heavier load. And like
I think that is true. Um and that means
that we need a lot of responsibility. We
need to kind of know what direction
we're going and we need to be kind of
like very aware of that. I think females
um
again there there's a consequence to
those things like I I don't want women
to think that I can do that because I'm
I'm tougher and then it like leads to
these issues because that's why most
women use most the financial health
dollars in the in the world in the
United States because they do have 80%
of the autoimmune issues. They do have
more issues with heart attacks. They're
more likely to die after a heart attack.
They're like they're using more of these
dollars because our society has not
treasured them enough to protect them
enough and understand that hey you're
not getting enough sleep. Maybe we
shouldn't be putting more burden on you
expecting you to work out or doing these
extra things with your career. Like
maybe we should take a bit of a sbatical
from that so we can protect you.
Absolutely. And so I think it's
important to kind of understand like you
know where we are with that stuff
because it's
>> there's a bit of a cultural issue on
that like we were saying before.
>> And when it comes to women in their 20s,
30s and 40s, obviously every decade is
so different for a woman than a man. How
can these women listening to the to the
podcast start optimizing their hormones
from 20-year-olds to 30 year olds to 40
and into their 50s?
>> I mean, you again, I would I would do
the circadian rhythm thing really well.
I would figure out what kind of
potential toxic burdens you're you've
been exposed to or dealing with. I would
make sure you understand what a good
supplement regimen looks like for you.
>> Okay. And it's individualized, correct?
>> Yeah. I'll talk about the common ones
that I feel like are most most
appropriate for most women and just
people in general, but I I think for
most women, they need a good methylated
B complex. I think that's such a
critical
>> why is that?
>> Um, so about 60% of women have MTHFR and
so that's that issue with you don't you
don't basically detoxify, you don't
methylate very well and that's genetic
variant. So there's nothing you can
really do about that. I have that. My
wife has that. Most people probably
haven't unfortunately. Um, and so if you
have that, you need you need these
methylated B vitamins that can be easily
absorbed so that you can then make
energy, detoxify, and methylation
happens about 300 billion times a day.
So, it's like a very important process
that needs to occur.
>> If it's such an important process, how
does 60% of the population have this
disruption?
>> Um, I think I've researched this a
little bit, but I think that has some of
it has to do with folic acid that we're
putting into our our foods and
fortifying cereals and things like that.
>> So, it's become worse over the years.
>> It's hard to say that with confidence.
According to my research and what I've
read, um, we don't know that for sure,
but there definitely seems to be some
worsening of that or at least more
awareness to it. But either way, um it's
a big problem. And so you can you can
very easily mitigate that by taking a
methylated B complex. And some people
don't do well with that depending if
they have like comp tea or something
like that. But most of the time it's a
good option. And so you can get
methylolate into your system. The
problem is a lot of women that are
pregnant will give um will take folic
acid because that's what they're told um
in their in their prenatalss. And folic
acid if you have MTHFR is like a toxin.
It's very very toxic for your system. So
you'll
>> And they're not even checking these
women.
>> No, they don't check them. So they're
told to take folic acid to to prevent
like cerebral palsy and all these
different kind of things and um or no
spinoipida I think is maybe what it is
but we're taking it and then afterwards
they're having a lot of postpartum
depression and according again to my
research it's because of the folic acid
detoxification that they're having to
get out of their system and so they'll
have this postpartum depression. So
taking a methylated B complex is
critical in my opinion. Um omega-3 fatty
acids are very very low. So um we should
have like a 1:1 ratio of omega 6s to
omega-3s. We're like a 20 to1 ratio is
kind of where most people are in the
population
>> and that's super helpful for your cell
membrane being flexible so you can get
things in and out of your cell. Um so
that omega-3 would be a really important
one. Um obviously magnesium I'm a huge
fan of magnesium glycinate. It's a good
jack of all trades. It can be taken on
an empty stomach. It's it does very well
for people taking it 200 400 milligrams
before bed is usually a good option. Um
and then vitamin D can be a really good
one as well. Yeah. With K2
>> because so many people are vitamin D
deficient. It's very very very common.
>> It's very common because if you're So
when you're deficient, it often means
that you're inflamed. So, uh, your
body's actually utilizing that vitamin D
to help you. So, you can't see it on a
lab test because it's not floating
around your in your blood. But, if you
if you were to look at most people and
if they didn't have high inflammation,
they probably have sufficient levels of
vitamin D. The other issue is when you
take too much and it's not converting
well because you're not taking K2 or you
don't have enough magnesium, you start
to deplete those resources. And so you
can actually create more problems if
you're taking especially if you're
taking like D2 which is synthetic and
your doctor's giving you 50,000 IUs once
a week and it doesn't get paired with
magnesium or vitamin K2. Now all of a
sudden you start calcifying your
arteries or your joints and things like
that and it can cause a lot more
problems. So you got to be careful with
that and you got to make sure you kind
of know like what your issue is and then
pair it with the right supplements. So
that would be the the other one to
consider. Um yeah,
>> and for women who are trying to
conceive, let's say, so this is, you
know, we we told everybody 20s, 30s,
40s, these are vitamins that they need
to get on. We talked about three
different things, ways to optimize
themselves from circadium rhythm, making
sure they're obviously, you know,
careful with any sort of depletion. When
it comes to um additional things that
they should be doing, is there anything
else that women should be start checking
or be like, okay, in this decade of my
life, this is what I need to be paying
attention to? Yeah, I think in your 20s,
um, I I would I would the mindset I
would have is don't abuse your body.
Like just start to appreciate it and
treasure it and take care of it. Um,
staying up late, drinking a bunch of
alcohol, you know, not taking vitamins
at that point, skipping breakfast,
fasting, doing all these high intense
exercises, especially not respecting
where you are in your cycle. Yeah.
>> Um, just getting a decent understanding
of how your body should function at a at
a at a foundational level would be the
20s. The 30s would be kind of
understanding that
um the reason that diseases kind of
persist or develop is that you spend
more time in a state of deficiency. And
so when you start seeing like oh I'm 35
or I'm 36 now I'm starting to have these
issues that just came out of nowhere.
>> In my opinion it's like well you've
you've been deficient from these things
for 15 20 years and now you're starting
to see the the fruit of your labor.
>> Um so kind of getting an understanding
of of that and then starting to counter
it by actually taking those things
having good sleep hygiene. Um, and in
understanding again that less is
probably going to be more at that point
in time. Um, and I think for a lot of
us, we don't have much peace. Like we
don't have much Sabbath. We don't have
much rest. And, uh, if we have these bad
habits from our 20s, our 30s just kind
of exemplify that. They kind of just
exacerbate it a little bit. So, I think
getting some rhythms in your life to
where you have some stability of in
peace and calm um, would be really
important in your 30s. And then your 40s
again it's be extension of all these
things that I just mentioned but I think
in your 40s it would be understanding
like why your body is transitioning and
and why that's important. And so again
for a female it's understanding that
parmenopause is is actually a good
thing. You know it's it's by design.
It's it's not a problem but then
understanding that you can use things
like you know biioidentical hormone
replacement therapy to kind of
specifically target your deficiencies
but it's not it's not a it's not a a
replacement necessarily. It's like it's
like a supplement. It's like you want to
you want to use it supplementally to
kind of
>> fill the gap a little bit. Correct.
>> But I think if you just do that and not
do anything else like we said before,
it's not going to do as much as it could
for you at least long term.
>> And if we want to educate the audience
also on bioidentical hormones, right?
Obviously the difference between
synthetic versus non-synthetic and then
also where they should be starting with
that. Obviously going to see a
specialist for that.
>> For sure. Yeah, you definitely want to
get with uh I mean the way that I work
with my clients is that you know I don't
prescribe medications and so we we like
to work with them before or after
they've done bioidentical hormone
replacement therapy but if
>> you partner with a hormone specialist
like somebody who can give them the
hormones if they need you
>> not no like we we found that there's
just so many people out there that do
that like we're usually working with
them before they do it or after they're
like hey I've already tried this and it
didn't work now what should I do and so
we're trying to get
to like optimize so that they can then
adjust their dosage accordingly. But um
sorry what was your first the question?
>> The first question was teaching women
about like hormones like bio identical
hormones and stuff. So in and then so
I'd reverse kind of the question being
like how do you prepare these people for
that? Is it the things we already spoke
about the three kind of um points or is
there additional stuff that you guys add
in?
>> Yeah, we I always start with the
foundational things first. just said and
then depending on the the person, the
woman, we'll then look at them
individually and say like, "Okay, this
is what your apparent issues are." And
then we'll walk them through a detox of
of parasites, heavy metals, radiation,
mold, just to make sure that we kind of
know that those things have been
addressed. And then from there, it just
depends on like if we need to do a Dutch
test or whatever to kind of identify
specific deficiencies. But more times
than not, once you correct the cellular
level, their hormones start to be
corrected at the same time. So you don't
really have to I I think the emphasis is
rarely on getting more biioidentical
hormones. It's more about reducing the
the dosage that they were already on or
not having it at all.
>> And then what is your take I wrote this
down about DHEA? Do you like it? Do you
not like it? Do you ever recommend it to
your patients?
>> Yeah, it's a mixed bag. I think mixed
>> it seems to be very low dose. I think a
lot of women that are getting it,
they're taking like 25 milligrams and
again it's feeding this cascade of of
hormonal events that is feeding it
improperly. And so so like for example
if it's kind of hard to pick I have like
this picture in my head. So if you have
like cholesterol which is a building
block your hormones and you have
pregnalone and you kind of go
progesterone cortisol over here you have
like DHEA and and and and from there it
kind of goes into like testosterone and
estrogens and all that sort of stuff. If
you're feeding somebody, if you're
giving somebody DHEA and it's not
converting well, it'll likely convert to
like androgens and become unfavorable in
terms of testosterone. So, if you just
give somebody DHEA and you don't correct
anything else, at least from what I've
seen, it doesn't usually bode well for
them.
>> How can you tell if DHEA is not
converting properly for somebody?
>> I mean, you'll probably just have a
worsening of your symptoms. like you
probably have worsening of like thinning
of hair on your head, maybe facial hair
on your face, maybe more issues with
estrogen becoming um
>> yeah, like you're not detoxing from
estrogen, so you're becoming more
estrogen dominant. You can have so if
you're taking if you have a cycle, it
could worsen your cycle a little bit.
>> Um and again, this is like more of a
longer term perspective. I think
shortterm it could probably be like, oh,
I feel better for the first couple
months. Yeah. And then after a while,
you're like now all of a sudden things
are going wrong. So it just it has to be
nuanced with with the client. For sure.
when it comes to the role of emotions
with women's health. Um I think I
thought it was yesterday I saw something
on Instagram by Dr. Mary
>> Claire
>> and she talked about how now we know the
ovaries themselves are an entire
ecosystem
>> and I found that post really really
fascinating because we just thought okay
the ovaries you know are this organ that
kind of she's like no the ovaries are so
hyperlin to your nervous system that
they take all the bof feedback. So if
you're in a state of fight or flight or
if you're in a state of rest and digest,
the ovaries fill it. And what happens
when you're aging, the ovaries become
more and more and more and more
sensitive to that. And so it's this
massive ecosystem that is playing and
and is regulated by your nervous system,
right?
>> Which I don't think any of us have
really stopped and thought about that
when it comes to women's women's health.
>> Yeah. I think and again it that should
be well known in in in like the health
care space but it's not we don't really
emphasize that enough because you know
your hypothalamus your pituitary gland
your adrenal glands your thyroid and
your gonads they all work on this axis
and so it's like when your thyroid is
influenced by stress then your adrenal
glands are influenced and then your
gonads which is your ovaries and right
>> testes depending on your sex like that's
that's all working within this this
ecosystem or this axis that is
influencing each other and so you When
women are going through permenopause and
they're transitioning to post-menopause,
they no longer make progesterone in
their ovaries. They only make it in
their adrenal glands now. So, like you
make this huge switch from your from
your ovaries to adrenal glands. That's
why stress becomes a much bigger factor
when it comes to balanced health. And
that's why women start to experience a
lot of hot flashes because if you get a
lot of stress one day or your your blood
sugar spikes or you had poor sleep,
>> fatigue.
>> Yeah. you're going to spike that and
you're going to have a sudden uh
epinephrine rush or adrenaline rush and
that's where you have a hot flash. And
so a lot of women are getting that in
the middle of the night throughout
throughout the day and it correlates so
much back to your nervous system 100%.
>> And then so when you're when you're
working with these women in in your
practice and stuff, how do you support
them with the with the emotional side of
stuff if it's so important to their
overall health and to their hormones and
everything? I think a lot of it gets
back to just having the conversations
upfront about the importance of it and
and understanding that like hey this is
something that you are able to have an
impact on right like you have control
over this as much as you know you can
and if if they have a partner or spouse
it's like saying hey
>> we need to get them involved to
understand what their role in this is as
well and also if you have kids like they
need to know that mom's in a state of
healing or you know that that whoever
this person is that they're in a state
of healing and just like if you break
your wrist you're not going to just put
a cast on and take the cast off you on
the weekends to go play basketball, like
you're going to like be on a healing
journey. And this healing journey is
going to require that you have some
stability at home, that you have good
sleep patterns, that you have good
adherence to your diet, that you take
your supplements, and like the family
needs to know like what you're doing and
why. And then they can help to support
you because if they don't if we don't
bring that up though in the beginning,
then they're just they're not going to
be thinking about it enough to actually
do something with it
>> and feel supported enough at home.
>> Yeah. And feel supported. And so I think
there's that component to it, but also
they need to have a belief that what
they do makes a difference. And so like
if they're going into a meal and they um
understand that like if I'm eating this
food in a rush state or my nervous
system is all wound up, I'm not going to
be able to digest this food very well.
So maybe I should be praying before a
meal to kind of like do some deep
breaths and kind of make sure I'm
correcting my nervous system so I can
Yeah, I can regulate a little bit. or
like what you can do before bed if
you're all wound up and you're having
racing thoughts like you know you can
take magnesium 38ate you can do box
breathing you can do these different
things to kind of control this and just
giving them the tools and the belief
that if they do it it'll actually work I
think helps quite a bit
>> and I also went to jump since we're
speaking about women's health and
hormones for young women who are on
birth control
>> what is your advice for that
>> don't do it yeah just don't do it I mean
I think controlling a cycle with birth
control or helping to control symptoms
uh it's it's just a whole it's the
epitome of what our conventional medical
system is and it's just honestly kind of
disgraceful um especially for young
women that are missing out on the peak
phase of their of their cycle like that
the best time that they could experience
is like being eliminated and the reality
is you know a lot of these these issues
are metabolic issues like they're
they're issues that need to be
controlled through what they consume how
they regulate their circadian rhythm
>> and not
>> insulin resistance
>> yeah insulin resistance and not just
taking a pill that would you know
deplete B12 B6 folate zinc and and
create a whole host of other issues with
autoimmunity, estrogen dominance, PCOS,
like the list goes on and on.
>> So, this what happened to me when I was
younger. I got diagnosed with um I was
getting a lot of ovarian cyst. I didn't
have PCOS, so I would just get really
large cyst
>> and they put me on birth control when I
was really young. So, then I went
through years on birth control.
Obviously became really deficient in all
my minerals and stuff. Those leeched out
of me. And then as I got older, as I
entered my 30s, you know, I'm 42 now, I
started having like things I would get
migraines. I wasn't feeling well. I feel
really drained. I was starting to look
really gaunt. And it wasn't until I
found a functional meiosin doctor who
said, "You have estrogen dominance. You
have candida. You need to completely get
off birth control. You shouldn't even be
touching it. You're completely
depleted." And until I started working
on that foundational health, I didn't
feel well my entire life. So 30 years of
my life was spent kind of not feeling
well. It wasn't until like kind of my
mid30s when I started taking this
different route and started
supplementing and taking care of myself
that the building blocks started back
up. Wow.
>> And so, like you said, in your 20s and
30s, if you're spending your time being
so depleted, then in your 40s,
everything just hits you like, you know,
I'm just getting older.
>> Yeah. And it just kind of hits you
because your body's been running on
fumes for so long, it cannot sustain
itself anymore. And so that's when I was
like, "Oh, I'm vitamin D deficient or
this that, and the other, and I need to
supplement." It's because I spent so
many years on this birth control. It
took away basic minerals that my body
needed. And they were trying to treat my
ovarian cysts with birth control, which
by the way didn't always work anyways.
And all it did was disrupt my cycle when
nobody bothered treating my estrogen
dominance, which was causing
>> the rancis to begin with.
>> Yeah. And that's that's a story for most
women, you know, and I think u
it's it's very it's very unfortunate and
I I again I don't know what else to do
except for what we're doing right now
and to talk about it and to kind of
bring more awareness to it because
conventional doctors just don't have the
bandwidth or the resources to really
properly fix it and and following the
algorithm that they've been trained in.
That's that's the next best step is
birth control and then it's a partial
hysterctomy and then you know and here's
some some more pills after that. And so
it just
>> it's a cycle.
>> It's a huge cycle and u
>> and it feeds the medical system.
>> Yeah. It's uh it's it's hard because
doctors do doctor doctors aren't like
they want to help people most of the
times. It's just they've been trained to
think that
>> if I don't know it then nobody else
knows this. Correct. And so that creates
this this hierarchal issue to where the
information that's being passed down to
them is what they're studying and being
trained in and becoming an expert in
>> when we're ignoring this whole other
section of of health that needs to be
implemented and tied back in. So, I
don't know. It might take a few
generations to see this truly change.
But I'm hoping
>> and research I think I think women's
health for the longest time we were
told, "Oh, women are just small men and
we're not at all small men. We're
completely different." And I think that
that kind of like putting women to the
side and being like, "We're not going to
study your health. We're definitely not
going to study your hormones. We're
definitely not going to look at your
ovaries and we don't care about what's
going on over there has been such a
disservice." And I feel that quote
unquote like feminists, if you're
pushing for anything, you should be
pushing for more research on women's
health so women can go back into being
true to their form and design.
>> Yeah. Most Yeah. As you said before,
most studies are not looking at women.
They're looking at men and they're not
looking at pregnant women and they're
not looking at different stages of where
women are cycle and not controlling for
those variables.
>> And so, yeah, you have a very uh
>> lopsided, you know, perspective on this
stuff and it's just uh Yeah, they're not
they're not little men by any means.
>> No.
>> Yeah. I wanted to quickly talk about us
and your personal journey from
traditional kind of medicine into you
know kind of this whole like space.
Yeah. Um you know your brother had
gotten sick and so how did that impact
you? I know your brother was diagnosed
with leukemia.
>> Yeah he had leukemia when he was 14. I
was 12. Um that was that really
motivated me to want to get in the
health space. I didn't really know what
I wanted to do with it. It was um yeah,
it was kind of shocking as a 12-year-old
to kind of be in the hospital and see
him lose his hair and like get
injections all the time and just
>> um you know, he he survived and he got
through it and he's doing well now, but
he had you know, two like knee surgeries
and he's had some issues after that
because like the the chemo and radiation
just destroyed his bones and
>> you know he's he's had three kids and
you know he's he's actually survived
really well. Um but it still it had a
huge ripple effect on my my parents, my
mom, my dad um just all the issues they
had to go through and then they started
getting their own health problems and
you know there was there was definitely
some issues in terms of our um lifestyle
factors and high stress and just trying
to survive. And so I really got this
exposure to all these things and what
what the consequences of it are and it
made me just motivated to help to want
to help people not have to go through
that. And so that's kind of why I am who
I am now.
>> Think about what you do and practice
what you do.
>> Yeah. And I had my own issues. I had
chronic pain, chronic fatigue for like
10 years when I was like 18 to no 16 to
like
>> your peak of your health as a man. You
had
>> like I had uh I was taking ibuprofen all
the time cuz I got a back injury from
football and then I had like uh more
back pain that the chiropractor couldn't
fix and I was just like well what's
going on here? And turns out I had um a
stomach ulcer that was happening from
the ibuprofen and H. pylori and all
these different issues and then yeah
just like tons of antibiotics and just
all the typical stuff and yeah so gut
was destroyed and then thankfully I met
my wife and she showed me what cooking
real food looked like and you know how
to provide and you know and she like
that whole energy exchange at your time
I was like exactly what happened like
she exchanged that with me and just
showed me like what that was like on a
practical basis and
>> it was uh it was a whole combination of
things like I met this other provider
who cured himself from cancer he had
like this big tumor he fixed naturally
and he showed me these bunch of people
that were um very insightful to my my
yeah my practice and my mind because I
mean this is important like I'm not a
physician so like I don't prescribe
medications like I've never done that
and so it's really
>> it's really always forced me to want to
fix things from a
>> holistic perspective and honestly I
always I didn't want to go down the
conventional medical route like my my
business partner and colleague he's an
MD and you know like he um he's kind of
regretful that he actually did that
because he spent years trying to untrain
himself from the things that he learned
>> the programming that you get at medical
school,
>> a lot of indoctrination can happen. So,
I think the good news is that you can
work with somebody that's that's been
trained a certain way and they can still
come out of it and still see things from
a very complete perspective. But, uh,
yeah, like there's a lot of
indoctrination that happens to all of
us.
>> And when it comes to even social media,
I know you've talked about being in
social media jail because you've tried
to educate and talk about things that
you've learned or experiences you've
had. How did you kind of overcome that
with the algorithm? Because the
algorithm is very unforgiving to that.
>> Yeah, it's I don't know honestly. I
think I just stayed persistent with it
and uh didn't give up and I just through
a lot of prayer I you know
>> back in the day I I prayed that you know
God would open the floodgates and bring
people to me that wanted help and uh
that night I had a viral post go crazy
and um it was like kind of the beginning
of it all but I've had ups and downs got
banned on TikTok still haven't got that
back and
>> I've had to be careful with a lot of
things and I I kind of share
>> as much of the truth as I feel like I
can
>> without getting
>> without getting too far and then like
people that are in my community or my
clients I kind
go as as much as say as much as I need
to. But yeah, I've just had to be kind
of tactful with it.
>> Yeah. Wait, Tik Tok is very unforgiving,
even more than I would say Instagram
because it can be something that is, you
know, it's a piece of advice you want to
give online, but it says no, like this
is not with the terms of our community
and stuff and they can completely like
shut down your account or flag you and
then the flag stays forever or they like
lock out your account because it's not
according to community guidelines. Yeah.
but it's in somebody's practice, you
know, advice that they want to share.
>> The worst part is I've had people come
after my license. Um I've had like some
just to be honest, like they've been
very liberal people that have kind of
filed complaints against me and they're
not even clients. Like they're just
people.
>> Well, I I that's why I don't understand
how somebody can go out of their way to
be so cruel.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And so it's created a hassle
for me and um I but to me it's just part
of the part of the job. It's it's worth
it to me because I know that people I've
been able to help a lot of people from
it. So, it's it's part of the job, but
um yeah, it's just been kind of amazing
the amount of resistance and I don't
want to call it persecution, but um in a
way it's kind of persecution that you
face if you're trying to share truth.
And
>> I don't get everything right. I'll be
the first one to tell you like I've
gotten a lot of things wrong. But I
still feel like the movement that I've
been a part of like the Maha movement
and I I mean I'm not like an you know
official member of the Maha.
>> We are very supportive of it. That what
that's what we all believe in, right?
That's why we're here.
>> Yeah. We want to make America healthy
again. Like that's a good movement. And
so I think um we've all we've all had
persecution in different ways. And to me
it doesn't make sense why we should do
that if we're just trying to help
people, you know? So
>> I think it's the heavy indoctrination.
It's the deep-seated programming. It's
also fear that people need to
>> like look at their own decisions for
their family and their health and be
like maybe what was their role to play.
And I think people are too scared to go
inwards and they're like, "Oh my god,
like what these people are talking
about, maybe I had a hand in that and
maybe set that person in my family might
have got cancer or set maybe my child
has certain conditions and maybe I
overlook certain things." So they're
angry. They're angry at themselves and
they project it onto other people which
is I think it's a lack of
self-awareness, right?
>> Well, it takes humil humility to do
that. Like uh a lot of us are very proud
and um when you're proud like you don't
want to make changes. You don't want to
admit that you're wrong. And again, like
just like I've had to do. I've had to
admit when I'm wrong. And I think that's
again as as a Christian, I feel like if
I can't be humble and I and I can't like
grow and learn, then like what's why why
be a Christian? You know, why why have
that? Because that's really
>> the backbone of of for me that's my
backbone. But for people who don't have
faith, like they're going to make their
god their their political party or their
conventional medicine. Like they'll
they'll make that their religion. And so
like it's going to be very hard to like
go against your religion when you're
being told that it's it's wrong. And so
for me I don't make health is not my
religion. Like it's not my idol. Um so I
I just want to be humble with it and
it's easier to accept you know your
mistakes at that point.
>> I wanted to leave your like a piece of
advice from you to our community um for
them listening to this podcast like what
is one massive we've had such incredible
takeaways but what is one piece of
advice you'd like to leave them with?
I mean for me uh the most important
thing is just again my faith like that
that to me at the end of the day if I
have perfect health or terrible health
like I if I still have Christ and I
still have my faith and like I I have a
joy that's um
>> right
>> that comes from a place that's
sustainable beyond anything else. And so
if you don't if you don't have that then
that's that would be my recommendation
is to find that because that will give
you a superpower of healing and and
self-control and discipline that nothing
else can give you. Um no like self-help
Tony Robbins like that all those things
are great but for me it comes from a
place of where's my foundation what is
my belief and how does that change how I
operate in the world.
>> So I think you know my name in Arabic
means faith. So Iman actually literally
means faith. So I went to this um
seminar this guy was giving and he
explained what faith truly is and he
said real faith having faith in creator
in life it's something beyond yourself
is the following. He said imagine you
have a bill to pay but you have x amount
in your bank account and you have a bill
coming in that you have to pay.
>> That is not having faith.
>> Imagine that you have a bill to pay and
you know you have money coming in. It's
not quite in your account yet but it's
coming in. So you know okay that's not
faith either. Blind faith in creator is
knowing that you have a bill to pay and
you might have nothing in your bank
account but you know that creator is
going to take care of it. Yeah,
>> that is the unwavering faith that you
need to have operating through life that
you know something higher than yourself,
bigger than yourself is going to take
care of it. That is true faith when you
have no way of understanding where it's
going to come from.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's going to get resolved.
>> Yeah. That's the piece that surpasses
understanding. And I think our culture
has very little peace. If anything, we
have no peace.
>> We also don't have much faith.
>> Yeah, we have no faith. We have chaos.
And I think there there are a lot of
good people out there though that do
have faith, that do operate in that
mindset. And we they don't they don't
get enough attention. We only focus on
the negative things. But I think um
yeah, that's that's perfectly said.
Yeah, I think whether you're like us and
you're from one of the Abrahamic
religions or like really just believe in
source and God and creator, I think it's
really important to believe in something
beyond yourself in a how I think
spirituality is the core foundation of
living well.
>> Yeah,
>> that for me is extremely important.
>> Yeah, I think that's that's what
holistic holistic health is supposed to
be, right? And we've we've subtracted a
huge element of of health when we when
we do that from people because uh you
can't study that very well. You can't
study the conscious mind. And and we we
like to act like we know what's going
on. Yeah. We like to act like we know
what's going on. But most
>> times
>> we we have very little knowledge of of
the of the world in front of us, let
alone the world that happened before us.
And I think uh we just have a lot of
ignorance and a lot of pride again
>> and a lot of arrogance.
>> Yeah. A lot of arrogance for sure.
>> Thank you, Dr. Austin Lakes for flying
down and being on the show. And I know
my audience is going to absolutely love
this episode. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you for tuning in to Biohackit. If
you've enjoyed today's episode, please
don't forget to subscribe, rate, and
leave a short review. It really helps us
reach more listeners just like you.
Follow us on Instagram @ biohack-it for
exclusive content and the latest
updates. Remember your health is in your
hand and curiosity heals.