I'm all about finding nutrient-dense
options that are good for you, organic,
whole foods because especially I'm a
founder who's always on the go and I'm
always looking for ways to eat something
that fills me up, is good for my body,
and also it's properly sourced. And so,
Daily Harvest was a brand that I
discovered and I wanted to reach out to
them and get their CEO on the podcast
because these guys are authentic,
genuine, and their product is incredible
and it's very nutritious. So, Ricky,
thank you for coming on to the show
today.
>> Of course. Thanks for having me.
>> How did you guys decide with all of the
stuff in the space, you have Sakiraa,
you have this, you have that. How did
you guys decide to come up with Daily
Harvest? And how did you guys decide to
set yourselves apart?
>> Yeah. So, at Daily Harvest, we like to
say we're real food made easy. Our our
founders's vision was I very certainly
we could change the way food was grown
and the way people eat if we make it
easy for them. Um, at the end of the
day, organic fruits and vegetables are
the foundation of a healthy diet. And
yet we all know that but there's this
friction built in. Um it doesn't taste
exactly as we want or we think about it
in some you know non-convenient
capacity. And so the early first
instinct was make a product that is
delicious. Make a product that is
convenient and our first founding
product. Our ready to blend smoothies
are still our number one product which
people love.
>> And on average how many grams of protein
does your smoothie have?
>> So we actually have a range of different
offerings. We are big believers in uh
for different parts of the day and
different nutritional needs. You're
going to have different needs. So, we
have a range of uh offerings, a range of
protein content, but we just launched
our what we like to call our our power
five. Uh it's uh smoothies with 20 grams
of plant-based protein. And we also
offer um our own organic single
ingredient pea protein. So, you can add
additional protein if you're looking for
it. Would you guys because animalbased
products are you know blowing up animal
based protein? It's obviously
bioavailable in a different way to
plant-based.
Do you see yourself as a market is
moving more towards that to integrate
more of that in?
>> So I think what's really interesting
about Daily Harvest is for our entire
time we've been based on organic fruits
and vegetables. We are
>> vegan products and yet we don't consider
ourselves a vegan brand. And so while we
explore different ways to make people uh
uh happy and healthy, we are certainly
open to the idea in the future um about
incorporating other nutritional
components including potentially dairy,
potentially meat in the future. As you
may know, we just were acquired by the
incredible business Jabbani who is built
on uh dairy as a great protein source.
So certainly something we'll look at in
the future. How did you guys
differentiate yourself in a market that
is so saturated with so many different
brands coming out? Because you guys have
done an amazing job with your marketing,
brand messaging, stayed really authentic
and genuine. So, how did you guys do
that?
>> I mean, you just said it right.
Authenticity is what matters maybe more
than anything these days for a brand to
be built successfully. We've always kept
it very simple. We've tried to make it
very clear what we are, what we stand
for, and how we make it easier for you
to get that foundational um you know,
nutrition each day. Um, we are daily
harvest. We encourage you to make one
simple choice each day and it starts
with breakfast or you know if you want
it to be dinner that works too but for
us breakfast is the foundation of a
healthy day.
>> Running a company in the health and
wellness space you know that has to do
with foods a lot of it comes down to
farming and stuff. What are some of the
biggest challenges being the CEO of this
company you faced?
>> You know we've never been shy to embrace
complexity. The American food system
unfortunately has prioritized, you know,
simplicity and scale and efficiency. Um,
if you really want to deliver a healthy
food system, one that uplift uplifts
nutritional value for the individual,
you know, livelihoods for farmers, you
have to lean into the complexity. And so
that complexity comes from biodiverse
ingredients that we source right from
all over the country. And some of those
ingredients coming from other parts of
the world. Building a supply chain that
can manage that complexity has probably
been the biggest challenge. Um, but we
built that into our DNA from the
beginning. We weren't going to shy away
from that.
>> Looking back at your journey with Daily
Harvest and being the CEO, has it been a
specific moment in time that was
probably one of your most difficult
decisions to make?
>> You know, I would say two two things
come to mind. The first was, you know,
the pandemic was a a massive accelerant
for the business, right? people were at
home. People were nervous and scared.
How am I going to get my food? We had
already had a, you know, a major
customer following and reaching out to
them and telling them, look, you're
scared right now, but we're here. We're
available and we're going to continue to
supply your food even at times we you
didn't we didn't know what was coming.
Um, but staying true to that and staying
connected to the consumer was the most
critical thing for us. The next was, you
know, we were a business built on the
direct to consumer model. Knowing that
it was time to also pivot into the
retail landscape to find more consumers
and meet them where they were was a big
change. You have an entire business
model, an entire organization designed
for one channel. How do you successfully
make that leap was a a a critical moment
for us and one we're still figuring out.
But I think those are two moments that
jump out to me. And looking at how
marketing has shifted and changed over
the years since when you guys started,
you went through the pandemic. You've
come out on the other side, what are
some of the biggest learnings when it
comes to being a health and wellness
brand. When it comes to how you're
approaching your marketing,
>> there's always going to be a new trend.
We see that time and time again in the
wellness category. Each and every year
there's a new one. Um, we try to be the
consistency in people's lives. Bring
them back to that foundation. And I
think you also have to, you know, pivot
and understand what people are looking
for. That that evolves over time. We're
living through a moment where more and
more awareness and focus on the food
system, the challenges that exist. Uh
people are looking for trusted voices.
And so we've started to inject more of
those trusted voices inhouse. You know,
our chef, our nutritionist, right? How
do we give them more of a direct voice
and a connection to the customer so the
customer doesn't see just marketing,
right? They see information that they
can trust and information that helps
guide decision making for them.
>> Do you guys do things which are seasonal
or you like just basically get stuff
throughout the year?
>> So the beauty of frozen, we like to say
we're frozen for a reason is because you
can uh pick ingredients at the peak of
their harvest so they're taste great and
they're the most nutritious and then
lock in all that nutrition u through the
freezing process, right? And so while we
will introduce seasonal flavors from
time to time, uh for example, our
pumpkin spice latte, which is
>> truly built on pumpkin, most of them
aren't. Um uh is a seasonal offering
that people love. That being said, our
organic fruits and vegetables uh come to
you on a daily basis, on a weekly basis,
all year round because of that freezing
process.
>> And where are you guys sourcing from?
Are you working in partnership with
specific farms? What does that look
like? Yeah. So, we source uh you know
across the country and we also source
certain things internationally as you
might know. We don't grow a lot of co
coconuts here in the US. Um but we love
to work as close and direct to the
source as possible. We have a number of
incredible partnerships uh with farmers
directly. Um there's a really um
incredible project I'm very proud of
called the Almond Project. We've worked
with our almond growers and a few other
brands to actually do a five-year study
on the impacts of regenerative and
organic agriculture for those farmers.
So, those are examples of where we'll go
above and beyond not just buying the
ingredient or procuring the ingredient,
but actually partnering with a farmer.
>> And when it comes to your personal daily
practices, how do you sustain energy
being, you know, a CEO running this like
scaling company? It helps to work at a
company that is based on organic fruits
and vegetables because I truly believe
that nutrition is the unlock.
>> Are you vegan?
>> I am not vegan. Okay.
>> Um but I eat a cherry almond smoothie
every morning. Um I add that scoop of uh
our organic pea protein powder and that
really gets me going. And I think for me
I've always been connected to food. My
background is actually in chemistry but
I was also a personal chef. And so I
have this sort of dual reality of
understanding the sciences and the sort
of the art at the same time.
>> Do you still work on any of the recipes
at the give feedback on some of the
>> Our head chef would love to tell me that
I don't I'm sure. No, I'm kidding. Um
but I I do love to be in the kitchen
with the team. I love to get in there.
We love to talk and taste. I mean, and I
think that's what's been true and unique
about Daily Harvest from the beginning,
>> you know, to work at a company that
everyone cares so deeply about the food.
You know, from eight years ago, I
remember sitting around uh the office
and actually making time to sit together
to eat. Eating at Daily Harvest wasn't
sort of a lunch break. It was an
opportunity to idate. It was an
opportunity to solve problems. And I
think that's what food has always done,
right? Food is a problem solving
dynamic. Exactly.
>> How big is the team? So, we're just over
50 people today.
>> Wow. And everybody's based in New York.
>> We're spread out. We've got a large New
York base, but we're also some remote
team members as well.
>> And how is that done for you guys? I I I
assume obviously marketing can be
remote. It doesn't really matter, but
everything when it comes to production
and all of that is based in New York.
>> Uh we work with great partners across
the country, right? We're direct to
consumer business first. Retail
recently, but so you have to get the
food to people. Um we are a frozen
direct to consumer business, which adds
its own complexity. So, we do have, you
know, operations spread out across the
country so people can get what they
need.
>> If you are taking protein powder, you
definitely need to hear this. The Clean
Label Project tested 160 different
proteins from different vendors and
brands across the US. And you're going
to be shocked at the discovery that they
made. Nearly half of the top selling
proteins in the US tested high for lead.
And if you're somebody who consumes
protein powders daily, this is something
you have to be concerned about. And to
make matters worse, most brands do not
value transparency and will not reveal
their test data online. And I want my
community like myself to always make an
informed choice of what they want to be
exposed to and how they consume their
daily protein. And that is why I love
Pure. I also sat down with the founder
and had a full honest transparent
conversation with him about how they
source, how they educate their consumer
and also what their products offer on
the market, which sets them apart. Their
Pure PW1 protein tastes absolutely
exceptional and you know you're not
getting the gunk of heavy metals in it
to start your morning with. And that is
why I absolutely love Pur's PW1 whey
protein and that is how I choose to
start my day every morning. Every single
batch is third-party tested by the Clean
Label Project. And no product is ever
sold unless it passes these tests. And
Purey is one of the only brands in the
US that has the Clean Label product
certification on their products. And
that is only possible because they make
all their third party testing completely
transparently available to the consumer
through a QR code where you can track
the exact journey of the batch of
product that you're purchasing. So you
guys can see for yourself exactly how
clean the PW1 that you're consuming in
the morning is. Every single serving
gives you 21 g of minimally processed
high quality bioavailable protein. It
comes from pasture-raised
cows. No GMOs, no hormones, no
herbicides, no pesticides, and
definitely no heavy metals. So, this
means I can start my day with
confidence, knowing I'm having something
super clean to support my skeletal
muscle mass. My personal favorite flavor
is a Berber and vanilla. No artificial
flavors and no funky aftertaste. To make
sure your daily protein powder is not
hiding any nasty chemicals, and they're
not being open and transparent with you.
So, if you want something clean,
delicious, and bioavailable with
transparency, go now to get this amazing
discount. p u r i.com
pury.com/biohackit.
Switch over to pur's pw1 protein and you
can thank me later. What are some of the
biggest hacks for productivity that
you've learned along the way?
>> So because of my scientific background,
I'm a big believer if you don't measure
it, you're not going to know how to fix
it. I do a lot of own sort of personal
monitoring of my activity. Rather than
set sort of an aggressive goal for
productivity, I really take stock in
what I've been doing each week, each
month, even something like exercise. We
all know exercise is really critical as
a foundation, but rather than maybe have
an aggressive goal that I can't reach, I
actually just measure how many days did
I get active this week? How many days
did I get active this month? And that
helps set a foundation and a baseline.
And most importantly, I always tell
people, you have to trust how you feel,
right? There's a lot of hacks out there,
a lot of measurables, a lot of
wearables, which I totally support. But
if you don't just take stock and pause
and say, "How did I feel today after
doing X, Y, and Z?" You're never going
to really be able to fully embrace the
full capacity of yourself
>> when it comes to your whole like farm to
freeze organics, right? How does that
set you apart from some of your
competitors?
>> So, look, organic fruits and vegetables
is not easy, right? In fact, there's a
growing demand still for organics in
this country. And yet, we're seeing more
and more farmland move away from organic
agriculture. It's complex. There is a
cost to it. And so, we've really
attempted to stay true to that belief
that what is hard is hard for a reason.
And we've got to make it easier for
people to make those decisions. So, I
think a lot of brands when they go to
look for more consumers, they start to
trade away their values. Um, you know,
the food system, as I said earlier,
largely built on one that is looking to
get sort of the the most efficient
calories to consumers. We've always
taken the the harder path, which I think
will, you know, keep us strong in the
long run.
>> And has anything like, you know, when
there is a problem with food shortage
or, you know, a certain item goes out of
price, how do you guys factor that into
your pricing? Are you raising prices on
certain products? Are you just swapping
out the recipes? Like, how do you adjust
for that? From as a business
perspective,
>> we've got a fair amount of variety in
our food offerings. And so we try really
not hard not to sort of pass any of
those challenges on to consumers, right?
Different ingredients are going to have
different markets each year, different
pricing each year, but we try to build a
business that that is somewhat blind to
the consumer, right? In the same way
Rachel started the business to keep it
easy for people, we try to keep it easy
still. Um, we don't want you thinking
about those things. We want you to be
able to successfully make that good
choice for you each and every day.
>> And when Rachel started the company, did
she think the direction it's heading in
now, this would this is where it would
be, or has the market dictated a lot of
different things along the way?
>> One thing that Rachel instilled in me in
early days when I joined, as I said, my
my job was to help operationalize her
vision. Um,
>> so much of what she believed in was
listen to your consumers. Um, the direct
to consumer model is really unique in
that you have this very direct line to
consumers. So if you allow them, they're
going to give you information that helps
you guide decision-m. So we've really
adopted a strategy listening to listen
to the consumers, make great products,
help them solve different challenges
throughout the day, and yeah, be willing
to pivot. Not everything's going to
work, right?
>> And I think that's the the hardest thing
for businesses is, you know, do you
become so riskaverse because you're
afraid something will fail or do you
build a culture that allows you to try
things and if it doesn't work, you move
on. which was thinking back like being
the CEO of this company, what was one of
the biggest risks that you took that you
didn't know where it would go but it
worked out?
>> Fascinating question. Yeah, I think you
know when we think about some of the
latest offerings we've introduced um and
we think about sort of being able to
connect to an entirely new audience,
we've started doing a range of more
curated uh orders. Um, we've been a
company built on a subscription model
almost from the beginning.
>> Allowing people to move away from
subscription is a business risk, right?
>> Yeah, of course. Huge.
>> Um, but that's what consumers are
looking for. And so, we've started to uh
create and offer um ways to purchase
Daily Harvest without it. Obviously,
retail is a huge way to do that without
a subscription, but there's a lot more
to come on this. So, I'm excited for
consumers in the next couple of months
to see what we've got cooking. And when
you say retail, do you see more people
still wanting to walk into our brick and
mortar and pick up their Daily Harvest?
>> This data changes regularly, but about
15% of consumers want to buy food
online. That means there's 85% of the
consumers who still want to go to the
grocery store. And so we've got to meet
consumers where they are. We've got to
be able to have the right offerings at
the right price for different target
audiences. But, you know, retail is a
big big opportunity for us still.
>> And when it comes to retail, who do you
guys see yourself partnering with?
Because every business has its own
model, right? Yeah.
>> So, do you see yourself being with the
Whole Foods or the Airwarms? Like, where
do you see yourself?
>> So, before joining Daily Harvest, I was
with a company called Vit Coco,
>> the leader in coconut waterconut.
>> Um, I love what they've been successful
at, which is you actually can win in all
retailers. It might look like slightly
different offerings across the way, but
that's a brand that works in Whole Foods
and works in Walmart. Yeah,
>> you know, my aspirations for Daily
Harvest is that we're making healthy,
accessible food based on organic fruits
and vegetables everywhere.
>> Right. Also, I think it's so interesting
you have a background as a chef. So,
what foods do you recommend which are
incredible for focus and mental clarity?
>> So, I know it's a it's a moment right
now and it's the moment that's long been
we've all been waiting for is this focus
on fiber. Um, right. The fiber maxing
conversation is finally hit. But I it's
so funny, right? Because protein is what
we always hear about, right, all the
time.
>> But actually feeling full and having
satiety is what ultimately gives you
energy, allows you to focus, you know,
really allows you to level up your
performance. And I think what people are
starting to really grasp on is things
like sugars, things like proteins,
things like carbohydrates are better
absorbed and better actually uh enablers
if you have the fiber with it,
>> right? And when it comes to things such
as food and energy, what do you think
most people completely get wrong?
>> So, I think people are looking for one,
a quick fix, and I I think
>> in everything in life.
>> Yeah, that's true. But I also think that
you it's easy to sort of lose sight of
the longer run. And I brought this back
up when I was talking about my own sort
of management of my exercise routine,
right? I try really hard not to get too
locked into one day or one week, but try
to build up those sort of habits over
time. We like to say like start with
breakfast, right? Don't skip breakfast,
please. Breakfast is so important. But
if you get that one choice right, and
that's why we're so focused at Daily
Harvest on whether it's our smoothies or
our oat bowls, allowing you to make one
easy decision out of the gate that
really sets the stage for your nutrition
throughout the day.
>> When you think of breakfast, what do you
advise people to like how do they pair
your your product? So, if it's if they
want more than just the smoothie, what
else do you suggest they pair it with?
>> Yeah. So, you know, a smoothie with some
protein powder. That's going to get you
pretty much everything you need in the
morning. But if you want a little bit
more than that, like have a couple eggs,
for example, right? Right. Maybe
something else. Maybe obviously a great
piece of sourdough toast. You got to
trust yourself. Um, and that's why I
love to tell people, you know, we want
nutrition to be this sort of zero or one
binary game, but nutrition is so much a
personal reality of how you feel, how
you react to things. Um, and so I I try
not to be too prescriptive because at
the end of the day, what people what
works for them may be different than
what someone works for someone else.
>> And for a business that does rely on a
supply chain that's sometimes out of
your control, farmers, what's available,
you know, what can actually be sourced?
How do you recover from like high stress
environments or like high stress
situations or setbacks that may take
place you personally? Yeah, on a
personal level, this is something I've
really I think had had a tremendous
amount of experience with, right,
leading a company is certainly
stressful. I really try to step away and
do something completely different than
the day-to-day. And honestly, it sounds
a little bit like old school, but going
out and doing something for your
community is an incredible way to get
away from what you were just dealing
with stress-wise. I think we all know
that feeling when you give back or when
you help someone, and that could be
literally anything. It could be tutoring
someone in your neighborhood. It could
be going to a food bank and support. It
could be showing up to support the high
school football team. Like whatever it
is, I think when you're in community and
when you're giving back, it's a great
way to create some perspective for
yourself because if you're just
grinding, if you're just in it, you're
sort of stewing over the the stress or
the issue or the the setback. To your
point, I don't think you ever really
find the space and time to think through
how you got there and where you're going
to be in the future.
How for somebody listening can they you
know and they want to start their own
business and they want to build it. How
do they build culture while at the same
time as scaling in the earlier days
because in the early days about growth
growth growth growth growth how do you
instill culture with that and what does
that culture maybe look like?
>> I think one of the the maybe strongest
leadership lessons I've personally
learned and I really try to instill for
the team and push my leaders that you
know work within the company to exude as
well is is be yourself. like you you
have a world, a life, a reality outside
of the company you're building,
>> right?
>> I think some leaders think that in order
to get everything out of their team to
build and to grow, you need to be solely
focused on the task at hand, the
organization, right?
>> But you as a human is uh the best way to
get people motivated to work for you. If
you display elements of what you care
about outside of the job, people are
going to get to know you more. They're
going to think of you more as that
human, not just the leader of the
organization, and they're going to think
about ways that they can drive even more
value for the organization and maybe
open up more about themselves that allow
you to then lead that individual even
better.
>> How have you been doing that personally
for your team?
>> So, um, uh, in the last 10 years or so,
I've become a average drummer, uh, in a
really fun band in New York City. I play
for a band called Our Lady of Sorrows
and I have made a point to be uh very
open about that internally even to the
>> How often do you do you play with the
with the band?
>> So I have an electric drum kit in the
office. I you know we play fairly
frequently in in New York City. Um and
that makes a huge difference for me.
It's a great personal outlet like a
creative outlet. But also again, just
sort of being very vocal about that and
some of the other components of my life
have allowed the team to get to know me
in a way that maybe they wouldn't
otherwise.
>> Do you think you're type A?
>> Oh man, I'm I'm certainly type A in a
lot of ways. Um, but I I try to round
that out uh
>> in in the creative ways with stuff.
>> Yes.
>> How do you distill between pushing your
team to do more and allowing time not
only for yourself but also for the team
for recovery? I struggle with that at
times. Yeah, it's really hard. I think I
I often talk about the values I I try to
instill and sort of foster the most in
the team is a sense of curiosity first
and foremost. Um that idea when I'm
taking a look around and I'm going
people are maybe showing up with less
questions, maybe there's a little bit
too much focus on, you know, the
day-to-day. We're losing that curiosity.
That's a signal to me that, okay, we got
to pause and take a step back. How do we
again maybe instill a sense of reset for
the organization? It's amazing
what that will do for you. If your
people are not showing up in a curious
and sort of creative fashion, it means
something's wrong,
>> right? And when you say curiosity, is
that in their role? Is that on the
growth of the company? Is that to do
with market trends and what's going on
in the space? I think it it comes down
to, you know, within their role, within
the individual's responsibilities, how
are they showing up with their tasks,
with their effort, with their strategy,
you know, are they asking questions that
>> tell you that they're really thinking
about what their responsibilities are in
a way that is like this is not just
about getting it right today. This is
really about, you know, sustaining for
the future and coming up with new ideas.
Um, and so it's going to manifest in
different ways, but you know, curiosity
and conviction are the two things. If
you show up to me and you present great
idea and you show, hey, I've thought
about two or three different approaches
here, but I've got this one that I'm
recommending, that tells me you're
really engaged. If you look back at so
far all the marketing campaigns and all
that you've done, what was one of the
most successful marketing initiatives
you guys launched for Daily Harvest that
really
maybe you weren't expecting the return
on investment, but it was like
completely blown you away?
>> So, I think we have there's two things I
would say. One, and we've always felt
this way. If you can just try Daily
Harvest, you're going to be hooked. I
think um for a frozen direct to consumer
business, finding ways to sample our
food has been challenging. Yeah, of
course.
>> And so what we've been really successful
out of late is finding a couple of key
partners that share similar values and
want to have Daily Harvest available and
accessible for their community. That may
not be in a traditional sort of retail
setting. It may be much more in a you
know um there's this community that
gathers each and every week or each and
every month. How do we have our food
there? How do we integrate ourselves
into that organization? Again, it's a
different version of sampling, but I
think it makes a huge difference. The
other is I just think people want to be
told very clearly the value and the
impact the food can have um we've
>> on their lives.
>> Yeah. We we've had a lot of really
success recently with the concept of a a
reset or a detox, right? People want
that opportunity to eat healthy every
day, but we all know how hard that is,
right? You've been traveling or been
very busy at home. you know, how do I
take a couple days to reset myself? And
you know, for us, not to to knock any of
the other offerings that are out there,
a lot of those thing, you know, those
offerings that exist in the detox sense
are are sort of like very restrictive,
right? Basically, don't eat for 48 hours
and you you'll be reset, right?
>> For us, it's no actually
>> eat and be rooted in healthy foundation,
you know, food based on organic fruits
and vegetables. I keep saying it, but
it's who we are. Um, and that is a sort
of incredible reset for the system. I
feel it if I go travel for work or
>> and then you come back and kind of do
>> I am craving it at that point. I crave a
couple days.
>> When it comes to community events, can
you give us examples of ones that have
been successful and how have you done
that because it is frozen, right? So, is
it dethawing and having stuff available
as tasters or, you know?
>> Yeah. So, I think we've there's a few
different spaces. I you know we've had a
lot of success building longer term
relationships with you know uh wellness
and sort of um exercise partners right
people that hold you know exercise
classes or have their own communities
maybe it's a run club or maybe it's an
exercise studio how do we do events with
them in a way that brings the food on
site our team will come and blend
smoothies for you right um and actually
show up and be a part of the community
versus it just sort of feeling like this
giveaway right you know standing outside
the subway and handing
>> totally you know, a granola bar. Sure,
that that's what sampling used to be.
But for us, it's about really showing up
inside communities. Another interesting
one is, you know, my wife uh actually
rides in um uh the equestrian world and
the show jumping world. And that's a
community that is constantly rushing
around, busy, busy, busy, and almost
nutrition is sort of a second. Exactly.
And so we've had a really strong
partnership with some of the events
where we actually show up and again make
our food available for people and the
the stop and pause moment that you watch
people have to say, "Oh my god, this is
exactly what I need
>> right now to get me going." Yeah.
>> To get me going or to recover and and
also again being there as a source of of
information more than just food I would
say are the strongest examples.
>> Do you guys look at like nutritional
studies that are coming out constantly
because you said you have a nutritionist
on on this on the team as well. Are you
guys looking at research and trying to
pair different recipes according to
research that's coming out or if
something is supposed to be really good
for you, do you incorporate it in?
>> Yeah, I mean a great example of that is
we all know the sort of you know uh sort
of expansion of GLP1s as you know a
medicine that many are taking now.
Whatever the latest that is, it's always
astonishing to me. um we actually have
been able to curate a companion set for
GLP-1 consumers that it's more important
than ever to get the levels of protein,
the level of nutrient density. You
mentioned that up front and so our
nutritionists work to actually create a
curation sort of companion set for
consumers. Um so we're always looking at
what's happening both from a trend and a
science perspective. Um, it is, again, I
keep saying it, but because we're based
off of this sort of like first
principles, triedand-true belief that,
you know, organic fruits and vegetables
are the healthy starting point, there's
not a tremendous amount of new science
on that because it is it is the core.
>> What are what does the GLP1 set include?
>> So, u, we've had a few different
offerings, but we try to uh make our
sort of a subset of our food available
throughout the day so you can make sure
you're getting the level of nutrients
you need. So that could be a number of
our meals that you'll have either for
lunch or dinner. Some of our smoothies
are really perfect companions because
you are getting the calories, the
protein, and the fiber that you need.
Um, and so we're just always looking at
our portfolio and making sure that the
the proportions of, you know, delivery
from a nutrient perspective are there
>> is always there. How do you make
difficult decisions under pressure?
>> So there's actually a framework that I
adopted a few years ago that I
absolutely love. It's called the Canvan
framework and there's sort of breaks
apart decision-m through two lenses. Are
you living in a predictable world or an
unpredictable world? And how repeatable
is the challenge you're dealing with?
The reason I've loved this is because I
watched a few years ago the the pandemic
was a great example where you know what
I felt was like a very high performing
operations team. We started to make
decisions in a way that felt sort of
inconsistent, right? And this framework
helped me realize like it was because we
went from this highly predictable
>> moment to a highly unpredictable moment.
And there's really great ways to help
people move from back from the
unpredictable to predictable. How do you
make small experiments that help guide
your confidence in your conviction in
the next step? How do you think about
things through the lens of is this a
two-way door or a one-way door? It's my
other favorite phrase, right? If you go
through
>> what does that mean? The two-way door
versus oneway door.
>> Two-way door. you can go forward and
then you can go back, right? That's a
decision that you can reverse or
sometimes you'll hear people say a
reversible decision or an irreversible
decision. There are some that you're
making that leap and that's it. And so
in when you're living in that more
unpredictable time,
>> I I would say you lean more into
experimentation. When you're living in
more of that predictable, you really
lean into best practices and getting it
done. I feel like we I think there
always has to be when you're a founder
or a CEO of a company, there has to be
just the right amount of pressure that
is applied to the team at all times.
>> Yes.
>> For them to see what their growth
potential could be. Otherwise, people
get like almost like complacent, you
know, in a way.
>> I'm a I'm a because of my chemistry
background. Yeah.
>> I talk about experimentation all the
time.
>> All the time.
>> But I think what's interesting, a lot of
people talk about experiments and fail
fast. I hate that phrase, fail fast. Who
wants to fail? To me, it's about how
quickly can you learn? How quickly can
you gain the insight you're looking for
>> and land on your feet?
>> Exactly. And I think the one other thing
I think companies get wrong,
particularly when they're early on and
challenged and capital constrained, you
know, they you do a lot of experiments,
but then you look back and you go, did
we even really set the experiment up for
success? And then what did you make the
draw the wrong conclusion? And so what
we try to do at the company now is is
really focus on defining the experiment,
ensuring we all agree that we are
setting it up to succeed knowing that in
two weeks it might get a little
uncomfortable if we're not seeing
exactly want to see
>> but this is an experiment that's going
to take eight weeks. We better give it
its full eight weeks of potential.
>> Can you give us an example of an
experiment like that that you ran as a
team?
>> So of late, you know, this sort of uh uh
subscription versus not subscription is
a great example, right? allowing
consumers the flexibility that they
clearly have been asking for, right, is
a nerve-wracking, challenging shift to
the team.
>> Your revenue completely shifts.
>> Exactly. How you predict, how you
forecast, right? How do I know how much
food to make, how much food to buy? Um,
but we know it's the right thing. And so
we're setting up the experiments in a
way that allow us to learn to manage the
risk appropriately, and then to iterate.
And when you are taking people off these
subscription models from a financial
perspective because you touched on it
briefly, how are you guys covering
yourself? Because there can be some
months that are great and some months
that are not so great.
>> I think that's what I meant by setting
up experiments. You know, one that you
can manage the risk, right? Okay. You
know, there are some things that, you
know, businesses will have to just make
big leaps of faith on. There are other
things, you know, like this, for
example, or new products we may want to
offer or new marketing channels we want
to enter where there's ways to carve out
the appropriate amount of risk to learn
until you're, you know, you're really
there. You know, the classic online
version of this is AB testing, right? To
really try to validate, but you can't AB
test everything.
>> What is your one big marketing no where
you think brands waste their money?
>> H, great question. I I feel like it's
not necessarily one thing. It's more,
you know, getting caught up in just
doing something for the sake of doing
something. I think kind of first
principles rule for me is, you know, is
is something we're doing in service of
the greater mission. Are we actually
getting to new consumers? Are we
strengthening the relationship with the
existing? Um, a good example of this for
us, and this is not true for for every
business, but I'll just give a real life
Daily Harvest example is it's so easy to
think about sort of like college
campuses as an opportunity.
>> Yeah. And yet,
>> of course,
>> we're a frozen brand,
>> freezer space is limited, right? So,
there are certain times where you just
go, okay, there are audiences, there are
interested parties, but is that really
going to be a truly
>> perfect fit for us? I mean, trust me, if
you're out there at college, we've got
a, you know, uh, educate education
discount for you. I'm not I'm not
telling you not to eat Daily Harvest,
but I recognize that's probably not the
best place for us to focus our energy,
>> right? Which place have you seen the
most growth? Is it like young
millennials? Is it older millennials? Is
it Gen Z's? Like, where have you seen
the most market adoptability?
>> Busy moms, right? Busy families, busy
parents, right? people that are that
understand look taking care of their
children in particular is the the first
number one priority but you can't really
do that if you don't take care of
yourself right
>> and I think we see so much adoption and
so much uh enthusiasm from parent
audiences who are just looking for that
easy choice make one a day right start
your day with something healthy like
Daily Harvest and it sets the entire
tone for everything else
>> being a CEO in the health and wellness
space where do you think longevity is
headed So longevity right now is all the
craze, right? People are thinking about
longevity. For me, I you know, I I think
about this through the lens both on a
personal level, right? How do you
leverage the expanded opport you know,
information that's out there both
around, you know, things that work for
everyone and then more importantly
things that work for you, right?
>> I feel very strongly, like I said, every
day is a a data collection opportunity
for yourself. Again, the wearables are
certainly ways to accelerate that, but
how do you just stay really true and in
tune to yourself and how you're feeling
physically and mentally? I think
ultimately what we will see over time is
the more sort of grounded and and happy
we're allowed to be is probably the
greatest sign for longevity
opportunities. But look, life is hard.
You know, it's very complicated for
people uh in a world that we live in
like today to to to make it easy. So, we
just try to inject a little bit of that
easiness and joy into every every day.
>> I think if you're fueling yourself
correctly and you're getting adequate
amounts of sleep, but even if you're not
getting the sleep, but you're fueling
yourself correctly, when those daily
stressors show up in your life and you
want to squirm under it, when you're
fueled correctly, your brain works
better, your hormones are firing better,
you have a little bit more peace in your
life. So, how you react to that stress
is easier.
>> Look, and stress, I think, is, you know,
the the stress and inflammation, right?
I think are the the two greatest
>> uh you know impact issues of our time
and they're directly connected and I
think on a personal level I can say
there are times where you go through a
long you know r you know window of
stress and you don't even realize how
resilient your body and your mind are
you're just absorbing it over and over
and over basically
>> and when you finally get a chance to
release it
>> you physically feel how much you've been
carrying and so I think what I've
learned in my life is Don't overestimate
the power of talking to people in and
out of the company about what you're
dealing with. Correct. I think there's a
sense as a leader like you're not
supposed to be stressed. You're not
supposed to be challenged, right?
Particularly CEOs, it's like this
notorious like admitting your stress
would be some sort of sign of weakness,
right?
>> I have found the greatest strength in
talking with friends, family, strangers,
right, in community just about what's
going on. It's amazing what you realize.
>> So, you're extroverted. I'm definitely
an extrovert, which is a benefit,
>> which is amazing. You know, that's also
for me being a founder and I'm obviously
building two businesses. Me just
connecting to somebody and I can
energetically feed off them and be like,
"Oh, my problem is solved. I feel so
much better about this. I vented. I got
what I needed."
>> Often times, just saying it out loud or
writing it down. You know, there are
times I've been an introvert in my life.
I would say I have found that writing is
a really powerful way to get to the same
challenge, the same outcome, I should
say. You know, hey, what am I thinking
about? How am I navigating that?
digesting it in in the written form um
is a really powerful way to get it out
there.
>> What do you hate about being a CEO
>> cuz listen, I'm telling you, there are
things we all hate.
>> Yes. No, it's true. You go first. Fluff
this up. You go first.
>> I really don't like managing people.
>> Okay. Very true.
>> I'm very honest about that. I'm uh I'm
very creative. I'm very solution driven,
>> especially Jenz's. And I'm very honest
about that. I hate managing Gen Z's
because I'm an older millennial. I'm 42
years old. So, the way we were raised to
work and our work ethic is very
different. We will grind through
anything. We're like a bull in a ch. We
will go through and we're like, "Okay,
we're going to go down this path." I
feel like younger gen Z's especially,
they just get overwhelmed really quick.
They're overly sensitive generation.
>> I got I got something for you and I'm
going to tell you this at the risk of my
future book being co-opted by someone.
But I I've come up with a theory, okay?
Okay? And as very similar ages, I I
think you'll probably hopefully you'll
agree. you'll tell me this is a good
theory.
>> I think the the the sort of moment in
time that I evaluate is
>> did you ever use Map Quest?
>> Yes.
>> And if you think about that, did you or
did you not use Map Quest is the perfect
divide from a leadership standpoint
because and then people always get mad
at me when I say that and they say, "Oh,
you're being, you know, aegis or
something." And I go, "No, no, no,
>> no, no.
>> It allows me to understand how I'm going
to lead you if you haven't used Map
Quest." Correct. Because, you know, now
I happened to be this week. I used to
use Map Quest and I had to think,
>> you know, with with Google Maps, I just
followed, you know, the directions and
often make a mistake and then be like,
"Oh, the the Google maps messed it up."
No, I I didn't. I did that. So, I I use
that as a reference point to say I've
I've really honed in on different
generations, different individuals need
different things from a leader. Correct.
How I coach them, how I manage them is
going to be different. Maybe the Map
Quest line isn't perfect, but it's been
really useful for me. good direction. I
I would agree with that because I think
like you just said with the Map Quest
example, some of we are just built a
little bit tougher. We're like, "Okay,
we will blame ourselves and we'll say,
listen, you messed up. Let's go back to
the drawing board."
>> I feel that the non-map quest generation
sometimes is overly sensitive, like this
is work. It's okay.
>> You're adopting my non-map quest
generation.
>> Yeah. I'm like, it's just work. Don't
take things so personally. And I do
think there's a there's sort of a
different expectation of what work is
and how what it what it represents
certainly generationally. I think that's
been true in other generational changes
too. And I mean I remember you know
growing up earlier in my career and the
generation behind me or you know before
me I should say was shocked that you
might leave a company every couple of
years right so you think about the
generation
>> how much we shifted right totally. I
think it's also about very intuitive
leadership and men and women obviously
lead very differently but still it's
about knowing what's your mission what
is your purpose and some people will
stick around for that for three four
five 10 years and some people won't last
more than a few months but you are not
meant to shift your mission and your
purpose to adopt every single employee
who comes to the door I'm sorry
>> and more importantly I think on that
note I would say as the leader it's
really incredibly valuable to explain
that and share what you need to be
successful. One of the things, you know,
we I often get into conversations
around, you know,
>> the remote versus not, you know, reality
that, you know, since co um I know
plenty of companies that are only
remote, right? Remote first and that
works for them.
>> Yeah.
>> What I've stopped uh uh trying to
articulate is what works for Daily
Harvest. Right now, I'm the leader of
Daily Harvest and what works for me is a
particular what might work for
>> and actually but sharing that out loud
is is such a powerful tool as a leader.
I again I I go back to this sort of
authenticity and transparency for
leaders
>> um used to mean something else, right?
Like the idea of the CEO sitting in the
the boardroom like very difficult. Yeah.
I want you to know who I am. I want you
to know how I work. I want you to know
you know how I am successful because if
I if you know that then it's that much
easier for you to decide one do you want
to be here and then two if you do how
we're going to work together.
>> How we going to work together? So I both
the companies that I run um am the
founder and CEO of are both all female.
Yeah.
>> And one of the things I started doing is
when I'm hiring women is like I was like
I hate I like transparency. I
like authenticity. You cannot be scared
to come up to me. I'm a strong
personality. But I need you to voice
your opinion. And if you need to push me
back, you need to push me back because I
will respect you more for that.
>> If you're somebody who's a little too
shy and too nervous to say your point of
view, then this is not the place for
you. and being upfront about it.
>> I'm very upfront about it. I was like,
that is the energy and that energy does
not work for everybody.
>> Yeah.
>> And you're either sold into the dream
>> and you're here to build it with us and
you're here to voice yourself
>> or you're not.
>> Curiosity and conviction. I go back to
it. Yeah.
>> And again, I I've
>> for the last number of years, I I have
found myself coming back to those two
words. Yeah.
>> Because it allows people to really
understand what it is you're looking
for. And I think that people, you know,
have this false sense that you work for
a founder or a CEO. It's like you're
just working hard on on their behalf.
>> Yeah. No, you're not. You're also
growing yourself.
>> And there was a there's a reason behind
it.
>> Yeah. And I think every single job, if I
look back at my career, every single job
has taught me such an important skill
set. Every boss that I've had has taught
me something so imperative that worked
out later in life, you know? And so when
you're working somewhere and I always
encourage the girls, the women who are
working for us, be like there's a lot
for you to learn here. This is about
your career. It's about your growth as
well. Don't just think you're working
here for me. You're doing this for
yourself.
>> So um one of the things I'm maybe most
proud of in my eight years at Daily
Harvest is we have a very strong alumni
network.
>> Amazing.
>> Both formally and informally in that,
you know, I stay very connected to a lot
of our former team members whether they
work for me directly or not. And what I
have found is the the sort of strength
of your alumni and how prideful you are
of them. Absolutely. Is a great sign of
whether or not you're going to get more
people to come and work for you in the
future. Right. Some of our biggest fans
are are XT members.
>> Yeah. Employees.
>> And I always say, you know, not every
company is going to be able to scale
forever in a way that your next job is
definitely going to happen inside the
company. Yeah,
>> I've always looked at my ability to get
people the next role externally as a
huge measure of my success.
>> I look at some of our, you know, people
who worked for us previously that have
gone on to do amazing things or I've
introduced, I was like, this might not
be a fit or you might have hit your cap
here, but let me introduce to you
another company that you do amazing.
>> And it's fun, there's often times when
I've done that and people are sort of
shocked at first, right? Because it's
like, wait, are you trying to get rid of
me? It's like, no, no, absolutely not.
>> For your own, I'm trying to get you the
next opportunity and then we'll figure
this out together, right? But the
reality is I think I it always comes
back to are you just being that open
with individuals?
>> Right. Of course.
>> You know when you when you demand you
know transparency and you demand
engagement you better show up with that
yourself.
>> Absolutely. How do you manage burnout?
>> Have you ever had burnout? Like
>> I've definitely had burnout. Okay. I
think we all have
>> as founders. Yeah.
>> Yes. Um
>> as CEOs all of it. Yeah. As leadership.
Um, I I look,
>> travel and and true vacation are truly
the only thing that I I've ever been
able to say actually does the solution,
right?
>> Um, so that's not always available.
>> Are you able to tune out on holiday
completely or no?
>> So, for whatever reason, if I can get to
Europe, that's the answer.
>> All warning to yourself.
>> That's the answer. Um, well, I think
it's also just being I say Europe, but
really I mean international travel as a
whole
>> is is a way to sort of you you almost
have to be uh tuned out because you're
in a different culture in a different
society entirely. Um,
>> you never fully tune out. You know that,
right? You can't. Um, but part of that
is how you trust your team. And if your
team sees you, you know, let go during
that time period, they wanna they want
to show up and work hard for you, too.
So I try to remember that one small
thing that I've really tried um uh to
sort of come back to is is food. Um so
again, not everyone loves to cook. Um so
you don't have to cook, but I I come
back to if I'm really feeling it, I'm
going to prioritize, you know, getting a
couple friends together for dinner,
ideally at someone's home. You know,
going out to dinner, particularly I live
in New York City. You could never You
could go every night to a different
restaurant.
>> You still have options. Correct.
>> Stopping being in your apartment or
someone else's your home and actually
sharing food, connecting over stories,
laughing, crying, whatever it may be.
>> Those are the Yeah, it's it's healing in
a way that sort of rebounds you quicker
than you realize from from feeling
stressed and burnt out. Um, but man, if
we come up with the uh the solution to
burnout, we've got the next opportunity.
>> That's it. That's a new longevity hack
that everybody will want to buy into. I
just wanted to leave I I've just loved
getting to know you as a CEO because you
know we bring on so many founders and
CEOs but sometimes really diving into
what is your strategy, how have you
scaled, how have you built your team is
always interesting to peel back the
layer because then you really understand
the company because you understand the
people behind it.
>> If there was one piece of advice you'd
leave our guests with if they want to
build something in the health and
wellness page, they want to get started,
what would that be? So I think there's a
lot of space for brands to collaborate
and so one advice I would give is you
know people talk about white space
opportunities from innovation
>> you know first two or novel this I think
if you really break down what works for
health and wellness it comes always
comes back to the basics right are you
getting the nutrition you need are you
getting sleep right it's the basics that
matter and so if you conviction that
you've got an idea, a product, a service
that's going to be additive
>> for any size audience.
>> Go after it.
>> Yeah.
>> And don't be afraid to partner with
people even if they seem like
competitors.
>> Absolutely.
>> My background is operations and so I'm
I'm it's a little bit more true in the
ops world where you go every week you're
having conversations where like why are
we all solving the same problem, right?
>> What does it look like to support each
other
>> and share that information? Yeah,
>> I also think it's so terrible when
people want to gatekeep and they don't
want to empower somebody else to learn
or do better. And I think sharing your
challenges or hiccups or things that
you've struggled with and if you can
help another founder, help another
business, that is how and just good
energetic exchange. That's how you give
back.
>> You give back and honestly it's mentor
other people what that what doors unlock
when you do that.
>> Absolutely. Thank you so much for coming
on to buy. Thank you for flying down and
sharing your really interesting
background, but also a lot of your great
leadership advice.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you for tuning in to Biohackit. If
you've enjoyed today's episode, please
don't forget to subscribe, rate, and
leave a short review. It really helps us
reach more listeners just like you.
Follow us on Instagram @ biohack-it for
exclusive content and the latest
updates. Remember your health is in your
hand and curiosity heals.