Howie Mandel has been making us laugh as
a comedian and entertainer for the past
40 years and he has never ever been in
more demand. He's starring in two,
that's right, two big series right now,
America's Got Talent and Deal or No
Deal. But behind the laughs, how he has
dealt with some serious health issues,
including a heart procedure that saved
his life. And he's here today to talk
about it all. How Mandel come on out
here. Wow.
[Applause]
There you
go. Thank you. Thank you. Wow.
Wow. That's a That's a trip. I know.
That's a trip. They couldn't make a
closer door.
This This was a set of a soap opera way
back when, right? And so it is actually
the longest squawk in network
television. We are told it is. I would
have got sponsors and raised some money
had I known I was going to be walking
this. It's sort of like a stress test. I
can see if you're up with the interview.
How am I doing? Am I okay down there? So
good. Once you you walk around, you
first of all, these shows are so much
fun. And I think, you know, Deal No Deal
is about enjoying life, but I think our
country can use that kind of I I say
first of all, Deal or No Deal is back
after 10 years on
CNBC and it is bigger and better.
Wednesdays 8:00 on CNBC are new
episodes. Don't miss it. But I think
that it is the ultimate escape. You
know, we don't talk about anything in
the news and you're watching real
people. It's mindless. It really, you
can be an idiot and be on our game.
There's no trivia. There's no physical
acumen. There's no skill. You just have
to say, "I want that one." And that's
all you have to say and answer one
question, deal or no deal. And it's
really it's really wonderful and
relatable to watch a real person and
maybe put yourself in that position.
People tell me they spend the whole
evening at the edge of their seat
screaming at the TV. It's very visceral
television and whether you're screaming
because you're happy or whether you're
screaming because you think they are an
idiot and you're saying no, but there's
in in the hour or the couple of hours
that you watch, there is crying, there
is fainting, there is laughter, every
emotion. It's the biggest emotional
roller coaster in television. It's Deal
or No Deal. Now, new back on CNBC.
Punching clawing and gnarling. But it's
hard to do a show when you're losing
some of your key characters. So, one of
your briefcase models defected. Megan
Markle went off and got married to
Prince Harry. You call that a defection?
Well, I'm just going to The fact that
she left this country and became royalty
someplace else. No, she left your show
and became royalty somewhere else.
That's what my show does. My
show Why do you laugh? You laugh because
you're not on my show. If you're on my
show, you don't know what You'll either
walk out of there with a million
dollars. You could walk out a princess,
you can walk out a television star.
Chrissy Tegan is also from our show. And
uh we have had so many people. Hillary
Clinton number 17 from the first scene.
Yes. You don't you don't remember? Of
course. What do you remember about
working with Megan? And just out of
curiosity, were you invited to the
wedding? I was not invited to the
wedding, but don't get mad. I went and
uh I was not allowed in the building and
I uh what do I remember? I'm going to be
totally honest with you. Nothing. I
don't remember Megan. I don't. when she
uh got the you see this picture that
you're looking at right now. I saw that
picture when she became the Dutch or
when she got engaged. Yes. And I saw
that picture and they went she was a
deal or no deal ma and I go really
really what number? And then that
picture put up that picture again cuz I
was trying to remember what number was
she? There's no number even on her case.
So how do you know she was actually a
model? I think she's just a young lady
with a lot of baggage and you know that
Too good. No, she's a wonderful,
beautiful young lady and I'm so happy
for her and all I want for each and
every person. They don't even have to be
on my show to be successful and healthy.
So, most folks respect you because
you're an incredibly talented comedian
and entertainer, but I respect you. I
respect you. I like It's not just about
looks. I know what you're going to say.
No. Shine you up. Exactly. The uh You're
honest. You tell the truth. And you
spoke about uh OCD at a time when people
just weren't talking about it. Yeah,
they were they weren't open. You know,
I'd like to say that I was uh open about
it, but I come from I'm I think I'm
older than you. I come from an age where
uh you know the stigma of having any
mental health issue. There's a stigma.
Yeah. And I didn't talk about it and I
was diagnosed with OCD and I've talked
about this before and I I did a book and
I I talked about it in my book. You
know, uh one of just one of the tiny
little things with my OCD is is touching
certain things. And I remember I was on
the Howard Stern show this about 20 25
years ago and uh contamination in that
studio. Yeah, there was, you know, and
that studio in particular, I feel like
this is hermetically sealed and
everybody here has been washed. But the
thing is that I was going to leave and I
was wearing short sleeve t-shirt and so
I couldn't pull down my sleeves and I
said, you know, I don't want to touch
the door. Can somebody open the door?
And they thought it was kind of funny.
They go, no, you touch the door. And I
go, no, I don't want to touch the door.
And they said, you touch the door. And I
went to grab a tissue and they pulled
the tissue away and they were having fun
with me. But the truth is, because
people think cuz I'm a comedian, they
thought I was joking. And I started
having an anxiety attack, which feels
like a heart attack. And I said, and
then in the in in my panic, I said,
Howard, seriously, I go to a doctor and
I'm uh I have OCD and I see a
psychiatrist and I feel like I'm going
to die right now. You got to please, you
got to let me out. And he opened the
door. They saw the the reality. And when
the door opened, I got to the other
side. I could still hear the broadcast
from inside the studio. And I had no
idea. I thought I was on a break. Oh my
goodness. So that's what I thought. I
thought, "Oh my god, I just said that
publicly on national radio." So, number
one, I thought, "My poor family has I,
you know, I outed myself as, you know, a
mentally unstable person that how are my
kids going to be able to go to school? I
mean, they're going to it's going to be
horrible. Number one. Number two, my
career is over because who's going to
hire any show cost millions of dollars?
Who's going to hire somebody who has
mental health issues?" And remember,
this is 25 years ago and it was the
darkest day of my life. And I thought,
"This is it. What do I do?" And I just
going to I got to end it. I got to run
into traffic. I'm in Manhattan. So I I
go downstairs. It's the busiest place in
the world. And I remember walking
through the uh glass doors onto a
teeming street of pedestrians and
traffic thinking, "This is it. I don't
know what to do. I've never felt lower
in my life." And just as I was doing it
in my periphery, somebody came up to me
and he said, "Are you Howy Mandel?" And
I said, "Yeah." And I I made no eye
contact. And and he said, "You know, I
just heard you in Howard Stern." I felt
my my heart drop into my stomach and I
thought, "This is it." And before I
could make a move, he said two words
which meant something very different
until now. But he went, "Me too." And I
went, "What?" And he goes, "Me too?" I
go I go, "What does that mean?" He goes,
"Me too. I I suffer from obsessive
compulsive dis disorder." And I went,
"Really?" He goes, "And it felt good to
hear somebody talk about it." And I
said, "Well, thank you." And that was
the first. Now, at this time, there was
no there maybe wasn't internet, but
nobody was emailing. Nobody was
tweeting. No, there was no social media.
When I got home, I started getting
letters from people to say, "Oh, that
was so great. We heard you." And then I
thought and it opened me up. And then I
thought like, "What am I hiding? And
what is the stigma?" And the truth is
that with all the proper help that I get
and all the love that I have, I am being
supported. I am functioning. I have a
beautiful family and it's ridiculous.
And I've made it my soap box. Yes. Good
for you. You know, I've I've
I've Thank you. I've made it my soapbox
to kind of remove the stigma from
anything, whether it be mental health,
and mental health is really people
should be taking care of it like they
take care of their dental health. You'll
take a, you know, a kid to a dentist
when nothing hurts and they get an X-ray
and they go, "Look, mom, no cavities."
But there's nobody talking to, it's not
part of our curriculum. There's nobody
talking to young people. all this stuff
that is happening in society today. I'm
sure there were red flags when there
were three and four and five, but
there's nothing in place to really take
care of that's the biggest issue is
mental health. And I believe and as an
MD and you can if you think I'm wrong,
you could tell me, but I think if we can
get our mental health strong, we can
help our physical health. I think two
people, if you cut into two different
people with their heart, I think if
somebody just doesn't have the right
frame of mind or coping skills, I think
their healing process is a lot tougher.
So, um, you know, I'm a proponent. We
all need to just take care of our mental
health, talk about it, and remove the
stigma. Good for you. Thank you. It is
good for me. And you deserve the soap
boxes. Let me ask you just um, and I I I
didn't realize how profoundly it
affected you until you told that story.
But the idea that you would come out and
again look at a street and maybe throw
yourself into it because you thought you
destroyed your career. I destroyed my
family first. Your family first, even
more importantly. When was the worst for
you? You know, it's always a struggle
and I always need help and I always and
I tell people who struggle with it.
People say I have a little bit of OCD
because they're a little bit of a
germaphobe that. But when you really
have it, it stops you down. And there
are times when I could totally get
stopped down. I I'm not a doctor and I
don't uh really understand what's going
on. But I can't get past a a reoccurring
thought. I can't get past checking the
door. I'm my thoughts are and they make
no sense. I think I'm somewhat logical,
but and so I even understand more that
my thoughts aren't logical and I can't
get out. You know, everybody knows the
Howard Hughes story where he ended his
life in in a room alone naked, you know,
urinating into a bottle and not I
promise you that many times and probably
in the future I'm close to that, you
know, and and and the dichotomy between
feeling like that and knowing what my
career is doesn't make any sense. you
know, there's nobody that's, you know, I
didn't choose this career, but I'm I'm
thrilled by it and I'm, you know, I'm
out there, but this is not a comfortable
world for me, but it's worth it. So, how
do you interact with your family with I
mean, your wife, obviously, we have
beautiful picture of her, by the way,
and those, you know, my wife's right
here. There she is. No, my wife's in the
room. Oh, she's here. Where is she?
That's my wife right there. Oh, please.
Oh my goodness. She is right there. She
literally is right here. Yeah. I'm so
happy you're here. Yes. How do She's the
saint. She I've been married for 40
years. She is the
Well, here. Bring her out. Would you
come? Yeah. Yeah. Come on out. Come come
come come join us. She doesn't like to
be on. She's not even in our in our
wedding photos. Well, she's here now.
You might Someone can get me a hand mic.
Give me the hand mic if you don't mind.
Please have a seat. I'm going to ask you
this question if you don't mind. What is
it like? You don't have to leave. Oh, I
got You can go. No, you can go. She
loves you.
So So what what is it like? First of I
I'm you don't have to tell me anything
that's too personal. I don't want to
hurt either of you, but I am fascinated
that you have so much insight into your
OCD. I'm wondering what it's like being
in the family and working through this.
I mean, the visual of Howard Hughes is
painful. Oh, his humor gets him through
a lot of his issues. And I think the
laughter that we share together really
helps a lot. It does. And when he when
he gets too much into that and that he
starts bringing out that side of him,
then it can go away, too. So that really
helps our relationship and but she has
been the saint. This is the reason that
I'm even alive today. I mean this is a
person that is
no but you have no idea what I had to
learn in therapy. You know when people
suffer from mental health issues the
first place you go is outside. So if if
it's OC it doesn't matter what it is.
And I don't think there's anybody alive
that doesn't have a mental health issue
and needs coping skill. And even if they
deal with you if you if they have I've
had friends a lot of friends who've had
open heart surgery. I've had uh you know
heart issues and maybe we'll talk about
that a little later. You know even to
cope with that to cope with you know
they say depression maybe sets in
because you have something traumatic
happen to your body. We are not given
coping skills. And what is happening is
she has been my coping skill. You know
she's the one that when I'm panicked or
when I can't go on or when I don't want
to do it anymore she's the my
cheerleader. She's also the one that is
very strong and forces me to get help
when I think I can do this myself. The
key is that we all got to talk about it.
We all got to accept it and we got to do
something about it. You know, there's a
t-shirt with an SH and it goes sh
happens and it does and you got to and
it's going to happen and it happens to
everybody and you just got to take care
of it and this young lady takes care of
me for the last 45 years. That's a love
story. Thanks for calling me young.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good