Today on Oz, he is a notorious online
fat shamer bullying women.
>> These are posts you have. Men would
rather die than sleep with a woman over
150 lbs. Women were getting larger and
larger. It has to be stopped.
>> Dr. Oz fights back.
>> Fat shaming doesn't work. That's the big
message here.
>> The women he attacks sound off.
>> You don't know me.
>> Oz faces off. Coming up next on Dr. Oz.
There are monsters that lurk in the
shadows of the internet, shaming and
bullying people for the way they look.
It's time for them to come out from
behind their computer screens. Meet Roo
V. Now, he calls himself the leader of
the international fat shaming movement.
His goal to encourage others to join him
in publicly humiliating women for their
weight as a way to force them to conform
to his idea of beauty. The internet
makes it much easier than ever for
bullies to hide, but I'm not letting
them hide anymore.
Celebrities under fire. Kelly Clarkson
attacked on Twitter a year after giving
birth. Comedian Amy Schumer mocked by
web trolls for her weight. Now everyday
people targeted by fat bullies like
Shawn internationally humiliated for
simply dancing in public. All for body
shape and size. The internet's a
playground for fat shamers, and it's
getting much darker. Roo Valizad uses
the pseudonym Rou Fork to proclaim
himself a fat shaming activist and
organizer. So incendiary, he's on watch
list for embodying the dark underbelly
of the internet, full of venom and
vitriol. Rou claims men would rather die
than have sex with a woman over 150 lbs.
He has even declared jihad on fat women.
His mission, quote, to make it more
acceptable to shame, bully, and
humiliate fat women into thinness.
Now, he's calling for a worldwide fat
shaming movement, rallying his followers
to snap photos every time you see a girl
with a bit of muffin top and post them
to Twitter. Today, we unmask one of the
internet's most notorious body bullies.
Roo Valizad who goes by Roov V has
agreed to join us in studio. So if you
can explain the purpose of this fat
shaming movement. What's the intent?
>> Sure. Right now the intent is a reaction
to the fact that in the past 30 or 40
years people in the USA have increased
their size to such a point where
twothirds of people here are overweight.
Um, I think that fat shaming actually
will reduce the health concerns, the
health problems that people face right
now.
>> Yeah, I I I I don't I disagree and we'll
come back to that, but let me just so
people understand what you're doing,
just read some stuff. These are posts
you have and this is mater I think it's
hateful material personally. Uh, you
know, people hear what you say, but now
that you're not hiding behind your
computer, let's have an honest
conversation.
>> I do not hide. My name is out there. you
see me on on the internet. I do YouTube
videos. So I I don't hide. So I don't
want people to to think that.
>> Here's one statement. Men would rather
die than sleep with a woman over 150
pounds. How can you speak for all men
saying that?
For the men that I have met, men who are
thin, who go to the gym three times a
week, who lift, who exercise right, who
have good jobs, they do not want to date
a woman who is massively overweight
compared to a thin woman.
>> I'll speak just for myself, but I mean,
I work out three times a week. I do what
I can to stay healthy.
>> I love women whatever shape they're in.
It doesn't frankly matter to me what's
on the outside. It's a much deeper issue
that I'm searching for.
>> But you but you have to say that because
you have millions of viewers. I think I
am speaking in a way that men speak with
each other in the locker rooms.
>> You're in different locker rooms than
me, Rouge. And I'm not saying that
because I'm on the show. I'm on the show
because I believe that
>> if you were given an option between a
woman who is 300 lb and a woman who is
125 lb and all else is is is equal.
Would you honestly pick the woman who is
300 lb?
>> If you know first of all saying all else
is equal is a very difficult thing to
process. People learn through the
messiness of life.
>> I'm fascinated by people who are
overweight. I'm fascinating people who
are underweight and everyone in between
because we all bring less lessons of
life and if we listen to those stories
because the people in our life define
who we are that we learn from all of
them. On the other hand, here's your
comment on beauty since you brought it
up. Again, I'm quoting from your
website. Beauty on the inside. That's
just something that ugly people and
feminists say. You use such ugly words
to describe beauty. I mean, have have
you ever had a weight problem?
>> No.
>> So, how can you understand what they're
feeling? Because
how someone looks on the outside is
indicative of how they are on the
inside. If someone doesn't have the self
the self-control to exercise, to watch
how they how they eat. If they're big on
on on the outside, that is a sign that
there is probably some problems on the
inside.
>> Roo, we're all messed up.
>> If you can hear my voice, you're messed
up. That's who we are.
>> That's your opinion.
>> All right. Now, but but part of this but
but you fat shame men too.
>> We the first thing I tell men who come
to me when they want to increase their s
their their success in life is to hit
the gym. I have caused thousands of men
to eat right to go to the fat. So yes,
>> men they don't they respond to logic. If
you tell a man
>> in a faster way, if you tell a man that
if you're thin, if your muscles look
good, more woman, more women will be
attracted to you, they will sign up for
a gym membership in a day. Rouge, what
do the women in your life think about
what you're doing? What's your
relationship with them? Your mom,
sisters, cousins.
>> They love me for who I am. They don't
love me for the ideas. The ideas that I
push concerns dating between women and
men. I'm just stating a simple fact that
men like women who are thin.
I'm asking these questions cuz I'm
trying to figure out why you're so
screwed up.
>> Okay.
I mean, we're talking about fat shaming
and that's what you're responding to.
I'm trying to diagnose you. Let me just
go a second. You you've mentioned
several times that you're doing this for
altruistic reasons that you want to help
women and men
>> and men lose weight, right? I just did a
quick search. I knew you were coming on
this week. I actually went through these
papers. 50 papers. 50 papers. Here they
are.
>> 50 papers showing that fat shaming
doesn't work. It's the exact opposite.
What happens is when you fat shame
people, they feel worse about
themselves. Their self-esteem drops and
then they eat to comfort themselves.
What does work is making people realize
how special they are. That's the big
message here.
>> Does it does it work? Now, I I I haven't
seen that, but does the tips that you
share, the advice that you share, is it
is it helping? Because I see the obesity
epidemic is growing. So, what you are
doing, what good intentioned doctors are
doing doesn't work. So, we need to try
something else. And I believe shaming,
making a girl embarrassed to look the
way that she does
will help more than you giving a tip to
eat eat right.
>> You know, I'm not even going to have a
debate. Here are the papers. You go home
with the opportunity.
>> You don't have to read them. You won't
find a single paper that argues in your
favor. In fact, I couldn't find a single
person who watches the show who agree
with what you're saying. Not one. Just
give me one person in the audience now
who thinks that if I make you ashamed of
who you are, you'll lose weight. It's
not going to happen. I'm looking around.
I see no hands. This is a sampling of
200. What is it that made you get up one
day and say, "You know what? I'm going
to put out hateful fat shaming
messages."
>> I don't think that it is hateful, but I
will say that it was it was sad that
every year when me, a a straight man,
would have less options to date a thin
beautiful girl. Every year women were
getting larger and larger. It has to be
stopped in some way. I'm on the same
team as you. We just use different
medicine.
>> We're not on the same team at all.
Believe me, we you're on my team. We're
ending the game. What angers me the most
is that Roo is up in the ante by
encouraging others to take and post
pictures of women that they see who have
quote I'm giving this is your quote. A
bit of muffin top, bingo wings or
cankles.
>> Now I know how painful this is. So, I
found a picture on Twitter for one of
your followers, heavily blurted out cuz
I want to protect this woman. Here's
what the tweet says. This is what you're
proposing and supporting. Here's the
tweet. Fat pig pulls in front of me a
gas station and cuts off my exit and
blocks people on the right. I mean, what
do you say to women who are being
publicly violated in this way by
complete strangers who follow you? I
think we each thankfully we each have
the right to share our thoughts, our
opinions. If your feelings are hurt, you
know, I can't help that. But everyone
here has the capability to say something
to me which will hurt me as well. And
that's their right.
>> Mankind is your business.
>> Mankind is your business. The It's not
about a law. You can't legislate
morality or ethics or kindness. What
keeps all of us spinning on this globe
is because we have empathy for each
other. I wish I could scan your brain to
understand what's happening inside there
because there are pieces that are
missing and it's not even rational what
I'm hearing now. I said a lot. I want to
ask an audience members and so when we
come back some women in my audience have
a message for Roo.
Coming up next, Dr. Oz continues his
face off with the leader of the
international fat shaming movement,
bullying women all over the world on the
internet. What our audience has to say
to the notorious fat shamer.
>> You don't know what I do. Coming up
next, all new Oz.
>> Come on.
>> How road rage can wreck your health.
>> My heart rate jumped from 50 beats to 88
beats a minute. Plus, country music star
Tim McGra's mission to help save lives.
That's coming up tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
>> We're back talking with Rou who calls
himself the leader of the international
fat shaming movement. Please welcome
Janette, Erina, and Megan who've all
faced fat shaming in their own lives and
they're here to speak with you. I want
you to just process what they're saying.
Janette, what angers you the most about
some of these posts that you're seeing.
>> First thing, you're very disrespectful.
You're more It's morally wrong to make
fun of other people. I was one of the
people that was fat shamed. I went to a
bar a few months ago. Two guys taking
pictures behind me laughing. And guess
what I did? It doesn't hurt my feelings.
I turned around and let them have it.
Because after 40 years of dealing with
people like you, I what I there's no
we're done. We're done. We exist. We're
here.
And not only that, you don't know me. I
have a nutritionist. I am glutenree, fat
free, sugar free. You don't know what I
do. And I'm a mother and a teacher. And
I have to take care of the children that
you're messing up.
early enough.
>> Absolutely.
Absolutely. Um the articles, everything
that you're saying, it just it just
makes me livid. Like just seriously
angry because you don't know again what
people have to go through in their
regular lives. I argue, you know, what
did you go through in your life? Like
seriously, like is, you know, cuz I I
what I see is low self-esteem. I see
help self-hatred. I see that you know
you're struggling because one thing I do
know and I know for sure is that hurt
people they hurt other people. It's a
shame. It's a fat shame actually. It's a
fat shame that you think that this is
going to help um help the community.
It's not. There are children who are who
are struggling with obesity. Are you
want to are you do you prep are you
prepared to fat shame them as well?
That's it's it's absolutely it's
absolutely ridiculous.
>> Okay. Let me just get Megan in and I
want you to respond to all of them.
Sure. Megan, please.
>> Hey Rou, we must make you very
uncomfortable.
>> We are strong, confident, successful,
beautiful plus-size women, and we must
make you very uncomfortable. So, I'm
sorry for that if I'm making you
uncomfortable right now. But when I read
your website and I read what you do and
I see what your followers and your
leaders and your army does, I feel sad.
I feel sad for you and I feel sad for
them because in an industry where we are
finally taking the right steps to get
body acceptance and self-love, something
that's universal,
what you are doing is taking 10 steps
back because fat shaming someone and
making someone feel bad about themselves
is actually only turning the mirror
around on you. Okay, Roo,
>> this is going to be the first generation
where the life expectancy is shorter
than that of our parents and
grandparents. So wait, wait, please,
please, please.
>> So therefore, the kids that you you have
will see her mom for a shorter time
because the fat problem is un is
unsolved. If it were a health,
>> it's a health issue, but not the way
you're describing it. what you're
hearing from these beautiful women and
you are beautiful.
>> You are picking out the most extreme
things I've written. I mean, you you
haven't picked out how I'm teaching men
to go to the gym and eat right.
>> Rou, what you're saying at its very core
is wrong. And when people think that
embarrassing others gets them to change,
it means they don't know about people.
So, you know, I've had a very difficult
time sitting here letting you speak on
my stage.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, it is, I think, enough. Um,
certainly you're out there on the web
everywhere, but it's enough of my
audience to be able to tolerate this.
So, I'm going to ask if I can Jima,
you're a plus-size model.
You're trying to change the face of
beauty and you wanted to be here today.
So, the platform is yours. What do you
want to say to Roo?
>> Hi, Dr. Oz, and thank you for giving me
this opportunity to be here. And Roo,
um, I'm going to take the approach of
treating you like a human being because
you don't view me as that. um you and I
quote stated that um someone's weight or
the outward appearance is an indicator
of their character.
So because you're slim built and I read
a lot of the things you said, I'm going
to say your character is that of a jerk.
Okay? And I normally don't judge by mere
appearance, but that's what you do. So
I'm going to meet you at your level,
okay? And I want you to look at me. I
want you to look at me because I am
human. I have feelings. And I speak for
the plus-sized community. We're not
saying, and we're not disagreeing with
you, that we shouldn't take care of
ourselves. We're not saying that we
shouldn't um acquire a healthier
lifestyle. We're not discrediting that
at all. We're saying to accept yourself
who you are today. In 5 months or 10
months, you may be a different person,
but does that mean that you don't
deserve love? Does that mean you have
the right to judge me? and ridicule me
because I'm a size 12. Does that mean
I'm ugly? No. Beauty comes from within.
And I am not insecure. As a matter of
fact, I'm one of the most confident
people you will ever meet. Again, look
at me.
>> Can I say one more thing?
>> Yes. But I I I what I want you to
address,
>> please. Instead of hiding behind
>> fictional beliefs, false beliefs, what I
want you to address is whether you're
willing to rethink fat shaming.
>> As long as they are willing to accept
that fat acceptance is going to cause
additional health problems for millions
of people and shorten lifespans, then I
would also think about the feelings that
I am hurting. Roo, you I think you got a
complete ass backwards.
The way the way we get wonderful people
to be who they want to be is get them to
accept themselves and the weight will
come off. I believe that the reason we
hold on to so much fat is because it
protects us. And if you're attacking
women and children and maybe men,
although I haven't seen the fat seaming
because I in my heart think you're
misogynist.
>> I I really don't think we're going to
get there. This is your homework. These
are all the papers. I pulled them for
you. They're on the web. You know,
you're what you owe me back for this
conversation because I'm trying to help
you is just go through and find one
supported bit of evidence. Now, in
addition, you're welcome to leave if you
want, but we spend a lot of time to
prepare something then stay because what
I'm trying to do, and this is for
everybody out right there. You know, I
because I do think you're the problem,
but I think it's fixable. At its very
core, folks, bullies try to steal your
power because they have none. So, I want
you to take back that power. I'm
starting today an army to change the
words so we can change the conversation.
You're going to watch a video. It's inc
I feel incredibly compelling. If you
feel like circulating it, do it. But at
least take it to heart. Watch.
>> Words matter. Don't call me fat.
>> Don't call me skinny.
>> Call us strong.
>> Don't judge me by what I look like on
the outside because I'm all about being
healthy on the inside. I don't go to the
gym to look good for other people. I do
it for myself.
>> Think before you call someone fat
because weight shaming doesn't make
anyone thinner. It just makes you small.
Start using body positive language about
yourself and others. Join the movement
and
>> be body positive.
[Music]
>> Next, actress and Oscar nominee Lorraine
Broco. How her weight and depression
became her toughest role yet. The
turning point that changed everything.
>> I want to live as strong and fun as I
can make it.
>> How you too can lose the weight and be
the best you can be. Next.
>> Happy 1,000th episode. It is Ryan
Serest. Wanted to say we love you and
thank you for always doing the radio
show. Congratulations, my man. You
deserve all the success. Bye.
[Applause]
Lorraine Bronco. She's had an amazing
career from modeling, which I didn't
know she did, to her breakout role in
Good Fellas. I love that movie, and her
starring role in The Sopranos. But all
of her success didn't mean Lorraine was
happy. She found herself depressed,
overweight, and unhealthy. But now she's
fighting back, in great shape, and
feeling good. How did she do it? We're
about to find out. the rainco
[Applause]
[Music]
lot to very very well. You look
wonderful.
>> Very well.
>> Really?
>> Come have a seat.
>> Thank you. I feel good.
>> Yeah. You look happy, too. How How much
weight have you lost? May I ask?
>> 35 lbs.
>> It's pretty cool.
>> 35 lbs. But I did it slow and steady in
about over a year.
>> Well, you talk about it a lot. This is
Lorraine's new book. It's called To the
Fullest. It's about your journey towards
health. I am intrigued by the title to
the Fullest. Could you, if you don't
mind, I'd love if you could explain why
you called it that.
>> Because I'm 60.
It's time to fill up.
>> And the truth of the matter is is I'm in
the third quarter of my life and I want
to live every day as strong and hard and
fun as I can make it.
>> And you're doing it.
>> I am.
>> Let me go back a little bit because
there have been times where it was more
difficult and we always celebrate
success, but we also want to figure out
how you got here. Your co-star in the
Sopranos, James Gandalfini. Yep.
>> When you lost him,
>> uh it was painful for everybody. How did
that affect this this journey you're on?
>> Well, the truth of the matter is is, you
know, Jimmy was always a big guy. He's
was 6'4. He's a he's a big man and um I
I remember this so well. We were on the
red carpet for something at HBO and I
hadn't seen him in a while and I grabbed
his belly and I was like, "You need to
get rid of this." And he was like, "Ah,
it's all muscle, Lori. It's all muscle
muscle." And I'm like, "No, you really
have to pay attention." And you know, we
we laughed about it and he says, "I'm
working on it. I'm working on it. I got
a home gym now." And and whatever. But
the you know, he was the thing that
killed me about Jimmy is besides loving
him and and thinking that he was the
greatest sparring partner I ever had,
um, he was a decade younger than me.
>> Yeah. a decade younger and I was like
wow if that can you know if if you can
pass like that in in a minute well then
it can happen to to me it can happen to
anybody
>> and a lot of times it's the sadness in
our lives that lead us to do things like
medicating with food you've had sad
times in your life if I could describe
some of the circumstances in the book
could you help everyone understand what
was going on as you gained weight as you
were doing the things that were
unhealthy for you
>> well you know my parents started started
to fail and they were both 84. There
>> they are.
>> And they were never healthy and they
never did anything that they should have
done uh o over the years. And I swore on
my life when we buried them that I was
going to do everything to get my health
back and I'm going to go down fighting.
>> Yeah. Come back for a second. I want to
take you a little journey.
Uh, this is a picture of you, a very
different version of Lorraine. When you
see this, Lorraine, you see this?
>> Yeah.
>> What's going on? Describe that person to
me.
>> Well, unaware.
>> Unaware.
>> Unaware of her health and her weight.
>> So, how did this woman become this
woman?
I
I wanted to live the third part of my
life in in a in a big way. Not in a
little way. Not in a sick way, not in a
in a way where where I didn't have any
energy. I'm I'm a grandmother.
>> Oh, I love that. I love that.
>> And I know you are also. And
>> I'm a grandfather.
>> Well, yes. Yes. I've noticed.
>> Come sit down. It feels good to be a
grandparent.
>> Yes, it's special. But boy, you got to
have energy for them.
>> That little thing is around the corner
and back before I can turn around.
>> So, you have lots of tips in the book.
Very helpful anti-aging tips, but the
one that really caught my eye was to
don't was to avoid being invisible. In
fact, the tip is don't be invisible.
Well, the truth of the matter is is I
think a lot of women who are 50 or or
older feel that
they're no longer as powerful as they
were.
>> And I happen to disagree with that
because I think we are smarter, wiser.
I think we should run the world.
I think
I mean
we are the caregivers of the world. We
are the the the ones that give birth. We
we do incredible things. And to get to a
certain age and I think menopause is is
is something that women dread. And I
don't think that should be dreaded. I
think it has to be embraced like like
everything God has given us.
>> So as all this emotion happens in our
lives, a lot of us turn to emotional
eating. You did. That's probably how you
got there. Sure.
>> How do you recover from that? It's not
just a long-term motivation. There
tactical things you have to deal with
when you want to overcome emotional
eating.
>> Okay. Here's my trick.
>> All right. Oh, pay attention now. The
trick for emotional eating. trick is is
I will look at a piece of cake that I
really, really, really want or I will
look at a bowl of berries and I will say
to myself, well, I really want that
piece of cake and I could eat that and I
could probably eat another piece after
that, but what are you going to give me?
Are you going to give me any nutritional
value? And the answer is most of the
time, no. I want that bag of potato
chips. I I really do. But you know what?
I look at my berries and I go, "Oo,
antioxidants."
>> They're whispering to you.
>> They they they talk to me.
>> She's the berry whisperer.
>> And And you know what? I make my
decisions that way. Now, listen. I'm I'm
not a crazy person. I still eat a lot of
things, but
I on a daily basis turn around and say
I'm gonna have a protein, a veggie, and
fruit.
>> And I'm proud of you. And you also like
to exercise. So, I've saved this for the
end. I want you to demonstrate exercise.
>> I never said I like it.
>> I misinterpreted.
>> No, no, let's get extreme.
>> I misqued the book.
Come on over here. Show me what you do.
You don't like it. What do you like?
Well, I like to move and I think moving
is important, especially if you want
energy. I want energy. That's my whole
thing. I'm taking my high heels off.
>> I like we can go dancing now. Perfect.
>> Boy, we could get in trouble.
>> Yes, we
>> Now that you're free, demonstrate. This
is Lorraine's favorite activity to teach
us today. This a 30day plank challenge.
>> That's correct. So, I think this is
really hard because it works your entire
body. You're coming down. I'm coming
down with you. Yep.
>> Go, Dr. Arms.
>> I'm going. All right, we're getting in
PL. Regular plank.
>> Look at you. You know it. So,
>> ready?
>> Look at that posture. That's Look at
that form.
>> Look at that tushy.
>> All right. Now, how do you do this? The
first day, this can be hard to do.
>> It's very hard to do. Very hard to do. I
agree. So the thing is is no matter
where you are in your life, you can do
this for five seconds.
>> Yeah.
>> Do it for 5 seconds. The next day do it
for 10. Do it for 20 and fight it. I
mean, my whole body is shaking. Okay.
But you know what? I'm going to I'm
going to fight through it.
>> See how stable you are? Oh, she's like a
rock. Oh my goodness. You cannot tell.
She is not invisible today. The Ray
Braco, where are you going? And I'm I'm
going to do a child's pose
>> so I can knock you over.
>> The Ray's book to the fullest is
available now. Check it out. It's well
very well done. You can also see you
Lorraine on Resilient Isles on TNT.
We'll be right back.
[Applause]
>> Coming up next. Your health is
priceless, but you don't have to break
the bank to feel like a million bucks.
Learn to pinch your pennies at the
drugstore with smart alternatives to
feel good and look great. The broke girl
solution to expensive health products.
Coming up next, look and feel younger in
minutes. Dr. Oz has the secrets to fight
aging the safe and healthy way. Visit
draz.com to learn more.
All new Oz.
>> Come on.
>> How road can wreck your health. My heart
rate jumped from 50 beats to 88 beats a
minute.
>> Plus, country music star Tim McGra's
mission to help save lives. That's
coming up tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
[Music]
Your health is priceless, of course, but
you don't have to break the bank to feel
like a million bucks. Today, I'm going
to reveal the broke girl solution to the
most expensive health products. Here to
give us her two cents worth is the
author of the Frugalista Files, Natalie
McNeel. Now, she calls herself the
Frugalista, but you weren't always so
savvy about saving money, were you?
>> No. No, I wasn't. I had $20,000 worth of
debt. I never I always ate out. I never
cooked at home. I had credit card debt,
car loan, student loan, and I decided,
you know what? This can't be my life.
So, I decided to live a frugal and
fabulous life within my budget and got
rid of all that debt.
>> Good for you. And why is it women make
such a big mistake when it comes to
health purchasing? They spend so much
more money than they have to.
>> Women, we're problem solvers. There's
something wrong. We want to get it
handled. We want to look good, feel
good, we want to have the best in life,
so we'll buy a lot of products to do
that. It becomes almost an addiction.
You have a problem, you want to buy it.
But we can do all that stuff, but we
have to decide what we want and what we
need and do it in budget.
>> Right? Let's do this. Ready? Come on
over here. The first expensive health
product that we can avoid if you're a
frugalista is for allergy medications.
So, what's the broke girls solution for
allergies?
>> Allergy allergy medication is so
expensive. But the thing is, if you're
serious allergy person, I wouldn't
recommend this. But there's another
alternative you can try from buying
over-the-c counter allergy medicine.
>> And it's nettle tea.
>> Yes,
>> it really does work.
>> Yes, of course it works. Nettle tea
relieves sneezing symptoms of sneezing,
itching eyes, all that stuff that you
deal with when you have your allergies.
And the cool thing about it is that most
of us don't have serious allergies. So,
when you know it's allergy season coming
around, buy nettle tea. Don't buy an
expensive box of allergy medicine that's
going to sit on your shelf for another
11 months. Buy this instead.
>> It's an acquired taste, isn't it? I put
I put a little sugar in here if I could.
All right,
>> but it works. That's the main thing.
>> Let's compare the cost. Now, this is a
discount of about 80% off of what you
normally pay. It's a pretty big
difference.
>> So, super savings. Okay, now this is my
favorite one. There's a super expensive
mistake we make a lot. It has to do with
shaving gel and razors. And
unfortunately, most people don't know
about this. So, how do you cut corners?
What's the broke girl solution here?
>> Well, think about it. We're furry
people. People shave all the time. And
so, we have to be careful about that. We
spend 72 days out of our lifetime
shaving.
>> 72 days.
>> Yes. That's a lot of time and a lot of
money. So, you have to be careful.
>> So, what's the solution? What should we
be doing?
>> Dish soap is your friend.
>> Oo. You shave with dish soap.
>> Yes. Instead of using shaving cream, use
dish soap for shaving. You save so much
money.
>> All right, let's put this to the test.
We had Jennifer from our audience. She's
here trying her best to do this. Thank
you, Jennifer, for doing this. So, walk
us through. You've been doing this
apparently for a week.
>> Yes, for a week. So, you only need about
maybe a quarter's worth in your hand.
Uh, you lather it on and you could see
it has it definitely has a a layer on it
and then it's pretty easy. There's no
cuts. Nothing happens. It's completely
smooth. You could literally feel the
difference between the one and the
other. My husband loved it. He said, "My
legs feel just as smooth as using
regular shaving cream." It's really
cheap. You can buy any brand you want.
So,
>> you mentioned your husband. Does he mind
that you use his razor?
>> Nope.
>> I'm bringing it up as a personal
question.
>> No, whatever. Any razor works. Even a
two-blade razor is fine as well.
>> So, let's just take a moment here and
talk about this issue because there's
actually two schools of thought about
what razor you use. There's the, you
know, the pinkness argument, right?
Right. It's got to be pink is better.
It's worth this. It comes up, right? I
hear that argument a lot, but I don't
actually see it endorsed in my home. In
my home, my wife says, "Doesn't matter.
As long as it's a razor, it's a razor."
>> Absolutely.
>> Is that what do you think?
>> Because this is a big issue. You think
we are wise to go pink or should we use
our husbands or spouses razor? Just buy
the male versions.
>> There's a thing called gender pricing.
And sometimes companies will market to
women. They'll use pastel colors and
they'll slap a flower on it and jack up
the price. And I'm not buying that at
all. When it comes to shaving, think
like a man, shave like a man. Buy men's
shavers. There's no other way to go
about it.
>> So, look at the savings here, folks.
Amazing. So, shaving gels plus the with
a man's razor plus the dish soap saves
you 37%.
37%.
>> Jeff, thank you very much. Nicely done.
I appreciate it. We'll be right back.
How do you save money on your health and
beauty routine?
>> Instead of spending money on expensive
conditioners, I use coconut oil. I've
been adding it to my hair for years, and
I always get compliments on it. It's my
little secret. Well, our secret now.
>> Tell us on facebook.com/d.
Coming up, you've seen them on the
internet. You've witnessed it on the
streets. And if you're lucky enough, you
could be on the receiving end. Real life
acts of kindness, powerful and
unexpected random deeds that will
restore your faith in humanity. Coming
up next,
a daytime television event. Emmy
award-winning Dr. Oz celebrates his
1,000th show with Hugh Jackman.
Thursday, May 7th.
That's coming up next week.
[Applause]
All right, question for the audience.
Listen carefully. How many of you would
have a friend that who would help you
out no matter what? Someone who makes
you say, "I wish I could be that good."
Put your hands up. Someone you really,
really, really, really admire. So that's
my friend here, Dan Leeski. He is so
kind, he named his company after it. In
fact, when you eat a kind bar, that's
actually him. Welcome to the show, Dan.
All right. Now, he's in the book called
Do the Kind Thing. But just to be clear,
uh, and I love people to get this
message. It's kindness is not just a
company name or a book name. It's
actually your mission in life. Why is
that?
>> Um well, I was reflecting a little bit
about what I wanted to contribute to
society. I thought a little bit about my
upbringing and my father. He was a
Holocaust survivor. And from an early
age, I heard about stories not just of
the horror of what he went through in a
concentration camp, but also of how he
survived through the selflessness of
others that took risks to to help him.
It kind of really marked me and my
siblings throughout our lives to feel
that we need to build bridges and to try
to help u make those connections with
people. So, one of the reason I want to
do this segment today is that research
continues to show that tiny acts of
kindness, small little things you
wouldn't think were that important, have
a much larger impact because people get
motivated to pay it forward. So, today
we're going to celebrate real life acts
of kindness. And the first video comes
from a story that made headlines all
around the world.
Images of the devastating blast that
leveled three buildings in New York's
East Village shocked the country and the
world. In the terrifying moments before
those buildings collapsed in a fiery
inferno, a woman began screaming,
trapped on her fire escape.
>> As smoke began billowing ominously, a
brave stranger emerged from the crowd
gathering below.
Oblivious to his own safety, he climbed
the ladder, grabbed the woman's hand,
and led her down to safety.
Isn't that kind? So, what struck you
about this real life act of kindness?
>> I mean, what what what really is
beautiful is the selflessness of the
person that didn't know the stranger,
risked his life, and the more we go out
of our way to take that risk, the more
that we actually find meaning.
>> You know, you can also extend your life
expectancy, by the way, if you're kind
to others. We do this on the real age
survey, and it ends up giving you about
three and a half years of extra life if
you're living optimistically and kind
towards others. So, I saw this next act
of kindness on Instagram, and the
pictures, well, they speak for
themselves. These are Instagram pictures
from hair stylist Mark Butos. Every
Sunday, Mark takes to the streets of New
York to provide free haircuts to the
homeless, and he's joining us in studio
now. How are you?
>> I'm doing well. How are you?
>> You have very nice hair, by the way.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> So, what inspired you to go out and do
this? Um, you know, a couple years ago,
I traveled to the Philippines to visit
family with my girlfriend and um, her
father, who passed away a couple years
ago, used to get his haircut at a little
barber shop in town and um, I knew I
wanted to do something and and I rented
a chair in the in the barber shop and I
had less fortunate children come in all
day and I figured I need to bring this
back home to New York and no matter
where I go, it's not that hard to bring
my scissors everywhere I go with me.
Well, well, sometimes, as you all know,
a haircut's not just a haircut. It can
really boost your self-esteem. So, I
have a couple pictures that really
caught me. This is a client of yours
before. Now look at after.
Is that cool? Very dashing afterwards.
I love what you do. Millions of people
viewed this next kind act after it was
caught on camera unbeknownst to everyone
involved at this checkout line in Sou
Falls, South Dakota.
[Music]
A young mother shopping for diapers at
her local supertore was told by the
cashier that she could only get one box
at the discount price. Overhearing this,
a complete stranger stepped in. This
good Samaritan, the one wearing blue
pants, immediately opened her purse and
offered to pay for the young mother's
extra diapers. All the woman asked for
in return was that she paid forward to
someone else one day. The heartwarming
random act of kindness left a mother in
tears.
>> D, why is it important for us to reach
out and help people we know nothing
about? I mean in this day and age m the
challenges that we're going to face as a
society to climate changeobia
nuclear threats cl you know the problems
with resource scarcity water scarcity
we're only going to be able to tackle
them if we recognize our shared humanity
and connecting with one another helps us
shatter cultural stereotypes helps us
discover each other's humanity and it's
just really also very fulfilling gives
us so much more meaning it gives us a a
better enjoyment out of life. Now I know
why I love Daniel. Thank you very much.
His new book, Do the Kind Thing, is out
now. It's a very inspiring read. Check
it out. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
[Music]
>> Do you have a health question for Dr.
Oz?
>> What is the best way to de-stress? I
have a stressful job. Many times when
I'm trying to sleep, I can't stop
thinking about work. Go to dr.com for
the answer and ask your own question
with #question.
Road rage,
>> come on,
>> is on the rise.
>> Aggressive drivers, myself included, are
everywhere. How it may wreck your
health. My heart rate jumped from 50
beats to 88 beats a minute.
>> And how to pump the brakes on a
potential blow up. Plus, country music
star Tim McGrath and his new mission to
help save lives. 30 million Americans
are living with diabetes.
>> All new Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
And we've all been there. After a
workout or a smoldering day out in the
summer sun, the sweaty stench sets in.
We can be strong. But now, brand new
research has a solution to our
embarrassing odors. Now, get this.
They're working on a breakthrough
perfume that makes you smell better the
more you sweat. Not only does it contain
an ingredient that activates as you
sweat, can also remove the bad odors,
not just cover them up. So, sweat it out
because new science has apparently got
you covered. Congratulations to all the
scientists doing this. Now, it's time
for in case you missed it. First, the
broke girl solutions for expensive
health products. There's one genius
hack. I love this one. I want you from
now on to try this soap instead of
shaving cream on your legs. Believe it
or not, it works just as well as that
fancy shaving cream you've been using.
And you know what? Stop buying your own
women's pink razors. Buy men's razors.
Men's razors less expensive. Why bother
paying more for pretty packaging? It
works just the same. Men need to shave
carefully and closely as well. It'll
work for you. Take advantage of these
hacks. You save over 30% of the money
you would have spent otherwise. Next, a
shout out to my friend Dr. David
Promoter. new book comes out today. It's
called Brain Maker: The Power of Gut
Microbes to Heal and Protect Your Brain
for Life. And I'm excited Dr. Promutter
will be a guest on the show soon to tell
us how we can change our mood through
our gut. You don't want to miss it. And
lastly, and this is really important, I
want to start an army for change in
fighting the fat shaming that's going
on. The internet makes it easier for
shamers to hide, but we are going to
change our words so we can change the
conversation. Take a look at this
powerful new PSA that we debuted on the
show today.
>> Words matter.
Don't call me fat.
>> Don't call me skinny.
>> Call us strong.
>> Don't judge me by what I look like on
the outside because I'm all about being
healthy on the inside.
>> I don't go to the gym to look good for
other people. I do it for myself.
>> Think before you call someone fat
because weight shaming doesn't make
anyone thinner. It just makes you small.
Start using body positive language about
yourself and others. Join the movement
and
>> be body positive.
[Music]
>> That video is live right now in dr.com.
Share it and be body positive. I'll see
youall next time.
[Music]
[Applause]