[Applause]
Could knowing your personality type be
the key to unlocking your hidden
potential? A groundbreaking new quiz
says yes. Understanding the truth about
character traits like compassion,
enthusiasm, openness can help everybody
better cope with the unrelenting chaos
of the day and set yourselves up for
success. Today, clinical psychologist
Dr. Jordan Peterson is here with a
personality type quiz you need to take.
It'll reveal new things you didn't know
about yourself and the people around
you. Read some books. Learn to talk.
Learn to think. Make yourself into
something. Get the hell out there and
make the world that put you here happy
that you were put there. Jordan
Peterson, professor, author, disruptor,
and controversial figure. The often
called provocator, is a Canadian
psychologist whose YouTube lectures and
podcasts have taken the internet by
storm. With more than 68 million views,
he often explores and ignites fiery
discussions on faith, personality,
self-empowerment, and identity politics.
Jordan's book, 12 Rules for Life, has
sold millions of copies. It challenges
readers to stand up straight with their
shoulders back and accept the terrible
responsibility of life with eyes wide
open. An unconventional hero to some,
he's become an outspoken critic to
others. Jordan is someone who's not
afraid to ruffle feathers and go against
politically correct culture. Yet,
despite backlash, Peterson fills
auditoriums with followers who say he's
brought order to the chaos of their
lives. Dr. Peterson has renewed my faith
in the fact that there really is and can
be and should be more than one
perspective in a situation. Jordan is so
passionate about his work and the
positive effect it has on others, he is
sometimes moved to tears. Some kid jumps
out of his car and comes rushing over
and tells you how much better his life
is because he's been working hard on the
basis of your recommendation to fix his
relationship with his father. They had
their arms around each other and they're
just smiling away. Today, Jordan
Peterson is here to tell you how to
reach your full
potential. Welcome to Dr.
Peterson. For many viewers, it's going
to be the first time they've heard about
you, so I'm glad they got to see that
little piece. Uh, and you become a rock
star for a lot of folks. I'm just
curious, what is your hope of how you
can get people to change their lives for
the better?
I'm hoping that I can help people
understand that they can find deep
meaning in their life. That that's
better and more nourishing, let's say,
than the pursuit of happiness. And that
they can find that meaning mostly as a
consequence of voluntarily adopting
responsibility. And so that seems to be
going quite well at the moment, that
idea. The idea is resonating with a lot
of folks. But there are critics who who
don't like your philosophies of
psychology. they find them provocative
and and controversial is probably the
word that's most associated with you.
Explain that to us. Well, some of what's
controversial in relationship to the
personality quiz, for example, is that
credible social scientists,
psychologists know that there are
differences in personality between men
and women and that those can't only be
attributed to socialization. And so
that's apparently become a controversial
issue. The idea that there are
fundamentally five personality types,
let's say, or traits, that's somewhat
controversial as well. Um, the idea that
these have biological roots, that's also
controversial, but the science is
wellounded and so and and people need to
know the truth as far as I'm concerned.
So, I'd like the audience to hear this
out and try to incorporate into their
lives and take what works for as always
is the case. So, let's talk about
specifically our audience. What are the
biggest mistakes people watching right
now are making as individuals when they
try to live the life of chaos that so so
often engulfves us? Well, I think
there's two two fundamental problems.
One is it's really hard to see yourself
as other people see you, you know. So it
it's it's not easy to get an objective
view of your personality and it's
helpful can help you understand your
strengths and weaknesses better and
rectif capitalize on your strengths and
rectify your weaknesses. I think also
that people don't do as much conscious
planning for their life as they might to
think out into the future and decide
what they need and want and then to work
strategically towards that. Uh those are
both and the other thing people lack too
they lack a really good vocabulary for
personality you know and to think things
through clearly you have to understand
the proper terminology and it's not
surprising that people don't have that
because it hasn't been that long since
personality psychologists have converged
on a stable a stable vocabulary. So this
is the goal today to give folks some
words that we can all use to describe
ourselves to understand what's really
happening in your life and hopefully
react to it. So, we got a quiz. It's
going to reveal your new personality
type, right? It's going to help you
achieve your goals. Audience, you all
have clipboards. Are you all interested
in participating? All right. So, all you
got to do is pay attention to these six
questions. They're they're the ABCDE.
Circle the ones. Everyone at home, you
can follow on dot.com. It's pretty
straightforward. These six questions uh
are all going to help us figure out at
the end what type of personality you
appear to have. And Marissa's going to
start us off. How are you? Good. How are
you? What are your goals that seem to be
just out of your reach right now? Well,
just like everybody else else my age,
I'm trying to find the perfect career
that really suits my personality. That
it job that I just love. So, how how can
your quiz help her reach her goals? Ma's
not alone with that goal. Well,
generally speaking, it's better to find
a job that matches your personality than
it is to match yourself to the job. Now,
you have to do a little bit of both,
obviously, because life is about
negotiation. So, if you know who you are
and what your personality is, then you
can find a career that not only will you
find more meaningful and engaging, but
you're likely to do better at, which is
also obviously of crucial importance,
assuming you want to do better. You
ready? I'm ready. Take it away. The
first question, Dr. Peterson, is choose
a word from this list that describes you
best. A talkative, B kind, C anxious, D
efficient, or E imaginative. Right,
Marissa, your best answer. I would
definitely have to say a talkative. I'm
a social butterfly in every situation. I
can sort of see that. All right,
audience, keep track when keep moving.
Go ahead and label yourself. Again,
you're doing it. Don't cheat on it
because it's going to be your wisdom
that you're going to share with yourself
later on. Dr. Peterson, the next
question. Think about your best friend.
What single word from this list would he
or she use to describe you? A.
Enthusiastic. B cooperative, C
worrisome, D organized, or E creative.
Right, everyone has your letter. Pick it
whatever suits you that you as you feel
you describe it. Marissa, what would you
pick? I would definitely say that I'm e
creative. I'm always coming up with new
ideas in different situations that are
thrown at me. Right now, actually, your
best friend is in the front row of the
audience. May I audit your answer?
Absolutely. You okay with that? All
right, Kayla, it's up to you now. Be
tell me the truth now. No one's gonna
know if you don't. Go ahead. No, I
definitely agree with Marissa's answer.
She's the most creative friend in our
group. I love to bounce ideas off of her
all the time. Oh my goodness. I think
she likes you, too. We're best friends.
All right. Thank you for being honest
about those. Next quiz question is
actually one that I wrote up. Take a
listen. Here's the next question on the
new personality type quiz. Pick the
activity that sounds most like something
you would do. A, plan a party. B, donate
to a charity. C, share a problem with a
close friend. D, make a schedule for
your week. Or E, create a piece of art.
All right, everyone, circle your
answers. Dr. Peterson, what answer did
you circle? Let me ask the doctor. Make
a schedule for the week. D. Yep. All
right. It was a bit of a tossup because
I could have answered E because I do
engage in creative activities. It's
probably common that you could pick more
than one. So, you're looking for
proponence. You know what you leaning
towards most of the time. Exactly. All
right. Coming up, the final three
questions you don't want to miss. You'll
find out what personality type you are.
So, stick around. Hi, it's Lisa Oz and
I'm here with the next question on Dr.
Peterson's personality type quiz. Are
you ready? Okay. Here are some addages
to live by. If you could only choose
one, would it be A? Spend as much time
as you can with friends, B. Take care of
those in need, C, safety first, D, do
your duty, or E, beauty will save the
world. Remember, circle the answer that
best relates to you.
All right, once you guys all circle,
right, I hope you circle one of home as
well. That was my wife Lisa with one of
the questions of the new personality
quiz that can help you unlock your
hidden potential. Now remember, pay
attention to the letters of circling. We
got all the stuff on dr.com. Got two
more key questions you don't want to
miss. Dr. Peterson, take it away. If you
had to admit to a single fault, what
would it be? A. I dominate
conversations. B. I let people take
advantage of me. C. I worry too much. D.
I can be a
perfectionist. E. I can be
scatterbrained. Audience, how many bees
were there? Out of curiosity, bees.
Yell out your answers. What was it? Just
yell them out.
Perfect. Everybody's different. I mean,
that's part of the the beauty of this.
We're supposed to be different. And just
to be clear, it's not about tolerating
each other. We want differences. It
makes this the bulla base taste better.
All right. Actually, you know what? Come
back here. Jill, how is that your name?
I'm Jill. Yes. What' you pick? I uh can
tend to be a perfectionist. You're a
perfectionist. I contend to be. Yes. Oh
my goodness. Some people give you a hard
time for that. Um not so much anymore.
I've been working on it over the years.
We'll see. But why is it important to
focus on your faults? Because if you do
things badly, then you're going to run
into trouble in life. And so you have to
understand that with every gift that you
have, there comes a an equivalent risk.
And you want to manage the risk and and
amplify the benefit of the of the
positive. And so it's very useful to
know when you can go too far. If you're
conscientious, you make you're a good
manager, you're a good administrative
type, you can organize things, but you
might manage people to the point where
they can't work with you. And so that's
that's when you've gone too far. Every
good thing can go too far. So my wife
calls me the medddler. I'm a D2, by the
way, on that. You know, I'm a
perfectionist. And so I get into things
I shouldn't be getting into, like what
time the kids are getting picked up,
right? And then she'll put me say, "Put
your cape on, Mr. the medddler, right?
The superhero that you don't want to be
one. And I think that's important
though, you know. So, these aren't all
good or bad. They're what you make out
of them. They're the cards you were
dealt. Well, if you're conscientious
like that, sometimes you have a hard
time seeing the forest for the trees,
right? And that's a problem if you need
to concentrate on the forest. You're not
speaking to me personally, are you?
Well, maybe. All right. The last
question. Dr. Peterson.
When faced with a problem, I tend to
approach it A
energetically, B
cooperatively, C nervously, D
dependably, or E
curiously. Why is that important? Well,
there's lots of ways to solve problems,
which is why there's lots of different
personality traits and types. And so if
you're an extroverted type, then you're
going to be able to rely on your ability
to use your social skills to bring in
information and solve problems. If
you're more on the nervous end of
things, you're going to be you're going
to be concerned with security and
safety. And that can be very useful in
lots of occupations. If you're
agreeable, then the fact that people
like you and you like them is one of
your skills. If you're organized and
conscientious, then you can use that
that scheduling ability and to move
yourself ahead. And if you're open, then
you can think laterally and creatively.
And you need to know which of those is
your forte and and and to understand
that those are all valid means of
solving problems. You ready for the
answers? Coming over here. Okay. We're
going to give you the truth about your
person personality type. But first,
let's reveal how to interpret your
answers. Tell up which letter you
circled first. If you did mostly A's,
then you're a personality type that's
called extroverted. That's the most
dominant one. That's what Dr. Peterson
was just speaking about. If you answered
mostly B's, then you're mainly an
agreeable person. Mostly C's means you
are
neurotic. But let me be clear about
this. This is not a bad thing. You need
some neurosis. We all need a little bit
of it. That's one of the things that's
most interesting. We don't have the
vocabulary. As Dr. Peterson was
mentioning, we need to have the words.
If you're a neurotic person and you know
how to use it, right, it's a wonderful
asset to have. You have to be sensitive
to risk. Yeah. Exactly. And we all and
we need one member of the tribe to be
sensitive to risk or else we all get
eaten by the saber-tooth tiger. Most
ED's you're conscientious and most E
your dominant type is
openness. Now what do these personality
types mean? And how do you use your
dominant trait to harness your hidden
potential? That my friends is next. Dr.
Jordan Peterson says there are five
major personality types and uncovering
your truth about who you really are can
unlock your hidden potential. Did you
find out you're an extroverted type? If
so, that means you're often assertive,
enthusiastic, and
social. Extroverts are energized by
contact with others in a big group.
However, highly extroverted people can
also be highly impulsive and not
consider future risk. What about the
openness type? If this is you, that
means you often think outside the box
and are highly creative.
But people who are high in openness can
sometimes find it hard to find a sense
of self because of their diverse
interests. So try to zero in on what
really makes you
happy. Those are two of the personality
types from our new quiz that everyone
should take to unlock their hidden
potential. Now it's time to break down
the three others. Clinical psychologist
Dr. Jordan Peterson is back. Some of
these personality types may have
negative connotations. So I'm going to
start with one which is neuroticism. And
Monnique, you tell us that that's what
you uncovered. Yeah. How do you react to
that? How do you deal with that
possibility? Is that how you would
describe yourself? Not at all. I
definitely always look ahead for things
and I'm, you know, always planning for
the future, but I never would have
called myself neurotic, but I'm neurotic
apparently. So, so that's not a bad
thing. Dr. Peterson, help Monnique and
others who are It also sounds like
you're conscientious. Yes. And so,
everybody scores on all five traits. So
the thing about neuroticism, it's the
negative emotion dimension. And people
who are higher in neuroticism feel more
anxiety and emotional pain than average.
And but the advantage to that is they
can make you very risk sensitive and
watching for where things of danger
might lie. And so if you're planning
your future for example, you can see
pitfalls and then you can avoid them
which is a big deal. Yes. Who ever would
thought we would celebrate neuroticism
is a good thing. Thank you Monique.
Thank you. Okay. Come on over. Now, the
next personality
type, well, it's mine because when I did
the survey, I end up being the
conscientious personality type, which
is, you know, seemingly good, but not
good in all the different ways. So,
please explain the goods and the bads.
And I know that all these have a little
bit of each. Well, you can rely on
conscientious people to do what they say
they're going to do. We have duty and
responsibility. Yep. Duty and
responsibility. Um, they're reliable and
organized, but they also have a Hey, how
do you like that? Yeah. Well, it's a
very organized show, so you can see
that. But the downside is that people
who are high in conscientiousness have a
tendency to micromanage. If you have to
know what's going on all the time, then
no one else gets to step in and do that.
But I hear that voice all the time that
I have to cuz I'm not sure anybody else
will. So, how does someone like me deal
with that? Well, partly what you do is
do what you can to surround yourself
with people who are reliable. It it
involves a little bit of a risk, but you
got to pull back if you're
micromanaging. I started writing down
things that I had to do, not things that
because I wanted to, not all the things
that I needed to do. And that's one way
I began to triage my life cuz I would
have just gone down the rabbit hole.
Okay, we got Holla here. Her dominant
personality is it being agreeable. Okay.
So, that seems like a good thing to be
agreeable, but as I read more and more
of your work, I begin to think that's
not always a plus. So, you describe
yourself as being agreeable. I do. I
like to keep things like light and
positive and when it comes to like going
out with my friends, I'm always the one
that's like down for whatever, you know.
Are you a warm person? Um, I am. I am.
I'm the one that people confine it in.
Right. There you go. That's part of
agreeableness. Yeah. So well the so the
downside of that that's the
self-sacrificing element is that it's
harder for agreeable people to argue on
their own behalf and it's easy for them
to get resentful you know because you're
kind of caring for the world and maybe
you assume that that's going to be
reciprocated or maybe you care for other
people more than you even care for
yourself that's harder for agreeable
people
there you go I tell you now this is a
call to action this is really important
clearly so for people who are agreeable
thank you for being agreeable but make
sure we're doing the right thing by you
as well so agreeable abled people often
don't make as much money and part of the
reason for that is it's harder for them
to negotiate on their own behalf.
They're not as demanding in situations
where they need to be and it can be a
bad medium to long-term strategy. Oh, I
love these insights. Go ask for a raise
right after the show. Right. Yeah. Well,
thank you very much. I hope that's
helpful. Dr. Peterson been
extraordinarily valuable. Thank you very
much. For the per for the full
personality test, you can go to dr.com.
You can hear more in Dr. Peterson's
book, 12 Rules for Life, an antidote to
chaos. And he has joined me on a series
of podcasts that I think will be very
helpful for a lot of folks watching in
order to figure out what they should be
doing in their lives. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good