Who could ever forget the sudden and
untimely death of Hollywood actress
Natalie Wood? The starlet's body was
found floating in the Pacific Ocean
hours after a leisurely night on her
yacht with her husband Robert Wagner and
co-star Christopher Walkin. It was
considered a tragic accident.
Last year, Robert Wagner was officially
named a person of interest, but to this
day, it has never really been clear what
happened that night. and it will reign
as one of the darkest unsolved Hollywood
mysteries of all time. Today, Nancy
Grace is here to take a new look at the
evidence. We're asking the question,
what does Natalie Wood's autopsy report
reveal about how she really died?
With do-y innocence that evolved into
smoldering sensuality, actress Natalie
Wood made the leap from child star to
Anjenu and leading lady to international
icon with ease. Her tremendous talent
and beauty made her a superstar. Her
love life made her a tabloid staple.
Married, divorced, and remarried to
actor Robert Wagner, the telegenic
couple became one of Hollywood's most
tumultuous duos, ending with Natalie's
untimely and tragic death in 1981. Her
last night alive was spent with Wagner
on their yacht with their guest, actor
Christopher Walan. After an evening of
drinking and alleged quarreling,
Natalie, who was unable to swim and
terrified of deep water, somehow went
overboard,
6 hours later, her body, floating face
down, was recovered a mile away. She was
43 years old. Her last moments on the
yacht fueled rampid speculation and
innuendo. The Los Angeles County
Coroner's autopsy would deem her death
an accidental drowning, but note that
her body was covered with bruises. The
yacht's captain, Dennis Deiver, also
reported hearing Wagner and Wood loudly
quarreling before her death. No charges
were ever filed, but the case was
reopened in 2011, and Wood's death was
reclassified to drowning and other
undetermined factors. And just last
year, Robert Wagner was named a person
of interest by investigators.
Now, more than three decades later, will
there finally be answers about Natalie
Wood's untimely and tragic death?
Join me now is Crime Online founder and
former prosecutor Nancy Grace. Thank you
as always for being here. Now, there
were three people there, only three, the
night that Natalie Wood drowned. The
captain, Dennis Dabvern, was Christopher
Walkin and Natalie's husband, Robert
Wagner. Now, their stories differ.
You've interviewed Natalie's captain,
Dennis Daburn. How is his story
different from what Christopher Walkin
has said in the past and Robert Wagner
as well? Well, can I tell you this, Dr.
Ros? I have questioned and put on the
stand and cross-examined well over a
thousand people and that's being on the
low side. I think I know a liar. I'm
sure you do. Dennis Diver
is not lying. Now, I know he lied at the
get-go, but according to him, Robert
Wagner said, "Stick to my story." And he
and Walkin did. Now, Natalie Wood and
Walkin, Christopher Walkin, were
starring in a new movie, Brainstorm.
Okay. They were scientists that married
each other. And Wagner was very jealous.
And he admits that. Mhm. All right. So,
the night before all this happens, it's
so bad that Natalie asked Diver, the
captain, to take her ashore. And they
slept in a hotel, separate rooms, the
night before. She was so upset with
Wagner being jealous of her. So they go
back, they have a nice breakfast, she
cooks it, blah blah. It's like nothing
ever went wrong. That night, Wagner,
which he didn't tell us at first. He
said at first it was because of the
motion of the boat. Then he comes out
and it's in his book. He takes a wine
bottle. They were all drinking too much.
You know, too much booze gets you in
trouble. He gets the wine bottle,
crashes it down on the table with
Natalie Wood and Christopher Walking
sitting there. I mean, can you imagine
your husband doing that? Well, Walking
got up right then and he went to his
room and shut the door and that's what
everybody says happened. So, Walkin
stayed in his room. So, I believe
Walkin. He doesn't have anything to add.
After that, Diver tells me that he heard
loud arguing, physical arguing, like
motion. Then suddenly everything goes
quiet.
He gets up and goes to the aft deck.
Wagner, he says, is leaned back against
the wall, says, "Natalie's gone. You
better look for her."
He runs around, looks, can't find her.
This is what Diver tells me. And then he
says, "We got to turn on the spotlight.
The dingy's gone." This is Devurn
talking. And he goes, "No, I don't want
any bad press. I just let's wait. They
don't turn on the spotlight." So, long
story short, the story is she went, got
mad, and went out on the dinghy. So,
some of this became evident years ago,
and I understand the very beginning none
of it was really clear, and they've
slowly been putting pieces together. So
what happened after 20 years that
prompted the police to reopen the case
of Natalie? Additional witnesses, two
witnesses on two separate v vessels, two
boats, separated, they're not together,
claim they hear a male and a female
voice that they say they believe is
Wagner and Natalie. Mhm. They say they
hear them fighting outside on the deck,
which is completely
opposite of what Wagner says happened
that night. So, what stuns me still is
that decades after the original event,
just now, we're beginning to put these
pieces together. How how common is that,
for example, for these witnesses to
suddenly come out who I suspect, you
know, they must have known or sus or
been aware that they could have been
helpful back in 1981. you're not going
to like this. But there are almost
always witnesses that the state doesn't
find. Not because they're not trying. I
mean, at that time, uh, he's a
superstar. She's, "Oh, listen to this.
This is what a fan a relative told me
that relative of of Natalie that Wagner
would say. I'm just a TV like, where do
you guys want to go? Ask Natalie. She's
the movie star. I'm just the TV TV TV TV
guy now. Why would you say that? I mean,
it was clear that resentment. And they
were divorced. Oz, they were married,
they got divorced, she remarried
somebody else, had a baby, divorced, and
then they got back together. And I
always say this to ladies, there's a
reason he's an ex. Remember that when
you want to get back together.
All right, up next, the woman who fought
to get Natalie Wood's case reopened. She
is here in person. What evidence does
she say she has from Natalie's autopsy
that may change everything? Stay with
us. We're back investigating how actress
Natalie Wood met a tragic end after a
fatal voyage sent her overboard in the
Pacific Ocean. Now, her death was
labeled an accidental drowning in 1981,
but later changed to drowning and other
undetermined factors decades later.
Since then, Wood's death has continued
to spark controversy. I'm back with
Nancy Grace. We're also joined by
investigative author Marty Roelly. She
has fought for decades to get Natalie
Wood's case reopened. Now, Marty is
close friends with Dennis Thaburn, the
boat captain, who was an eyewitness the
night Natalie Wood died. Thank you for
being here. You're welcome. Thank you.
Before I get to the details of this,
what got you involved in this? What
launched your lifelong desire to figure
out what really happened to Natalie
Wood? Well, I was always a fan of
Natalie Woods ever since I was a kid.
But my friend Dennis Stiver worked for
them. And when I heard of Natalie's
death the day she was pulled from the
water, it was worldbreaking news. I
expected a call from Dennis. We were
that close. It took 18 months for him to
call me in the middle of the night and
confess there was foul play in Natalie's
death.
So, I want to put my doctor hat on for a
second and go through this autopsy. The
case was reopened. A new coroner was
assigned to re-examine Natalie's autopsy
report. So, let's go up here together.
I'm going to show everybody what this
autopsy report reveals. And initially,
remember Natalie's case, her her was
death was determined to be an accidental
drowning. But closer look at the bruises
all over her body tend to paint a very
different picture. So, I'll explain
this, but you guys should all be
thinking with me. What could have caused
this? So, she had bruising up on her
forehead and her cheek, right? She had
bruising on her right forearm. She had
some bruising on her left wrist, right?
The front of her right and her left legs
had bruising, right? That's what this
writing all says. And then she also had
bruising on her left knee and her right
ankle, right? Left knee and right ankle.
And now those bruises also involved the
back of her legs. There are quite a few
back here. In fact, my team counted all
these bruises. There are at least 11
bruises to the back of Nalie's legs and
at least 28 bruises to the front of her
body.
Now, I'm trying to figure out how does
someone get bruises on their ankles and
their wrists, right? What causes that?
How do you get so many bruises on the
back of your legs? So, Marty, what could
this be? Well, when I received Natalie
Wood's autopsy report, the minute I saw
these diagrams, I knew I was looking at
a battered woman. I could not believe
that a coroner could have just let this
go for one fall. One fall can never
cause this many bruises. And objects
hitting you in the water, I highly doubt
it. But these bruises, I went over this
with a doctor. They look like Natalie
had been held at the ankles and dragged,
which could have caused the facial
abrasion. Her face was dragged along the
deck. So she's if she's face down Yes.
and the ankles are grabbed and she's
pulled along this non-stick deck. Yes.
That could explain some of these 28
bruises on the front. Many of them, but
especially the upward position facial
abrasion and the small circular bruises
at her ankles from holding the ankles.
Yes. Or or the wrists. And what about
the back of the leg? That could have
been from the fight in the state room
that Dennis was right above on the
bridge and he heard things hitting the
walls and banging and who knows what
kicking and punching went on in that
room. Now, there's one other item here
that I want to point out to y'all, which
was the bladder. This is a very
important detail. Natalie's bladder was
full
and this is important and it's crucial
issue for investigators to know about.
Let's put it in context. The average
human bladder 3 to 400 cc's, right?
Couple cups of of fluid. You all go to
the bathroom. You know how much urine is
in there, right? She had 300 cc's of
urine in her bladder during the autopsy,
which means her bladder is basically
full. Now, the theory was that Natalie
was fearfully drowning, right? She fell
into the water and if you're all in the
water, you don't know how to swim,
you're dreading around. That's it
creates a fight orflight response,
right? Which should that should kick in
because you're fighting for your life.
And when that happens, what happens? you
pee all over yourself. You've heard that
phrase, right? You're going to pee. It
turns on all the autopilot nervous
systems of the body. But if that's not
what happened, but instead Natalie was
unconscious when she fell into the
water, then her body wouldn't have known
that she was in trouble, there would be
no fight orflight response, and
therefore it wouldn't appeared. The
bladder would be full. The autopsy is
more consistent with the bladder. Now,
this is pure speculation. pure
speculation, but it's interesting to
note that her bladder was full and
consistent. So, what was your reaction
to that Robert Wagner being named a
person of interest last year? I was so
relieved that that happened as well
because there's so much evidence in this
case. There's medical evidence, there's
scientific evidence, there's
corroborating witnesses, and there's
Dennis's eye and ear witness account.
And so many cases out there get
convictions with much less evidence
that's in this case. Nancy, as a
prosecutor, what does this mean to you
for Robert Wagner to be named a person
of interest? Well, it's not a suspect.
Once you're named a suspect, a whole
host of constitutional protections
surround you. But as a person of
interest, he should be worried. But when
uh you don't know a horse, Oz, look at
the track record. It's been all these
years, they've done nothing
and they're not going to do anything.
And I'm talking about LA law
enforcement. I'm calling them out. They
won't touch him. He was just out at a
fancy restaurant the other night with
his wife. He's not afraid of the
cameras. Why? He's got nothing to worry
about it because they're not going to do
anything. and Oz for nine years. I
worked at the Battered Women's Center as
a volunteer at night when I was a
prosecutor.
She left the yacht the night before,
right? She was so upset with the way he
was acting. It was so tense. She wrote,
she got a ride. She didn't take the
dingy herself. She stayed in a hotel on
land because she did not want to be with
Wagner. So, she comes back and she dies
the next night. Is that a coincidence?
And that night that she left the yacht
on Friday night, Natalie went on the
island with Dennis, she told Dennis she
was fed up with the way he was acting
and that she wanted to take a sea plane
in the morning and that never happened.
They ended up going back to the yacht
and right to the secluded part of the
island where Natalie lost her life. So
we reached out to Robert Wagner's
attorney. We did not hear back in time
for this taping. In 2013, 2 years after
the case was reopened, she said in part,
"Mr. Wagner has fully cooperated over
the last 30 years in the investigation
of the accidental drowning of his wife
in 1981. Mr. Wagner has been interviewed
on multiple occasions by the Los Angeles
Sheriff's Department and answered every
single question asked of him by
detectives during those interviews."
It's also important for us all to
remember that Robert Wagner has only
recently been named a person of interest
and he has never been charged in Natalie
Wood's death. Up next, an update from
Natalie's sister. Lana is here. She's
opening up about the sister she lost and
her ongoing fight for justice. Stay with
us. We are back with Crime Online's
Nancy Grace and investigative author
Marty Roelly asking what really happened
to Hollywood starlet Natalie Wood the
night she drowned. And joining us via
Zoom is Natalie's sister, her younger
sister, Lana's opening up about the
sister she lost and her fight for
answers. So Lana, after all these years,
what do you miss the most about your
sister and the life that she could have
lived?
H that's difficult to say the most
because it was such an encompassing
relationship that we had. Um Natalie was
my best friend. She was my surrogate
mom. She was I it she was everything to
me. I it just saddens me as to what the
relationship could have been today and
how it would have affected her children
and my child. Uh Lana, you think a lot
about your sister and there are lots of
theories about how Natalie died. What do
you think really happened to your sister
that night?
Um
Natalie was not having a terrific time
with R.J. They were going through a
problematic time. Natalie was working on
a film that she hoped would help her.
She had some issues with it.
Um, Natalie was angry
and preparing herself for bed. I believe
that Natalie and R.J. had a very bad
fight.
I believe that he is responsible for her
ending up in the water. I have always
said that I didn't think it was
premeditated,
that I thought it was anger out of
control at the moment. And that's the
only thing that I have left to hang on
to because it is the most horrendous
thought in the world that someone would
take the life
of someone else who means so much.
Um
Natalie Natalie was pushed overboard.
Natalie would not get in the dinghy.
Natalie would not leave. And I have
taken great affront to a couple of
things that R.J. has said, saying she
was probably, this is a direct quote
from you in his book, she was probably
going off to a party because she was a
woman like that. What a woman who went
to parties in her night gown.
The entire matter of um
how she got in the water is is just
ridiculous. She would not have gone
anywhere near. So you have worked
closely with detectives on your sister's
case. What new information are they
gathering right now? What insights can
you share with us? The only new thing is
they do have new witnesses. These
witnesses did not want to come forward
then and do not want to come forward now
and didn't. But these are important
people that know that Natalie and R.J. J
were the only two people on the back of
the boat fighting,
but they're willing but these witnesses
are willing to speak the truth now.
They're unwilling, but they have
they have spoken to the detectives.
Lana, thank you very much. I know how
painful this is to relive it. Good luck
with the case. Nancy, what would what
would justice mean for Natalie Wood? I
think justice would be the truth. Um,
like Lana was just saying, she does not
believe this was a a planned attack that
he took the boat there, the yacht there
in order to kill her, that it was an
anger attack. But whatever, Natalie is
dead. And I think her case should be
treated with the same respect and
dignity and effort that other cases are.
And it seems like her case has been put
in a file and shoved away.
I mean, why is he different? Because
he's a star.
Especially when I see the bruises.
Awful. Mhm. Makes it much more to talk
about on this. And this story is not
going anywhere. We'll be right back.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good