[Applause]
It's the latest health trend that
everybody is talking about, CBD oil.
Now, it comes from the cannabis plant,
and many believe it can help with
everything from anxiety and chronic pain
to diabetes, even cancer. We're in the
midst of a CBD oil boom with products
popping up everywhere. Today, Dr. Sanjay
Gupta is here to investigate what
exactly is CBD oil and does it live up
to the hype. But first, I asked
correspondent Marsh Evocmpo to find out
how big CBD has truly become.
CBD, if you haven't heard of it yet, you
probably will soon. The natural herb is
taking the health world by storm with
sales of the new supplement expected to
grow 700% in the next 2 years. Wow. You
just see great review after great
review. I mean, people seem to love this
stuff. 4,000 reviews, four and a half
stars. Short for canidiol, CBD is a
component of the cannabis plant. Yep,
cannabis. But unlike marijuana, CBD does
not contain any THC, the psychoactive
part of the plant, so it doesn't get you
high. Over the last few years, CBD has
started popping up in everything from
gummies to face cream to toothpaste.
There are even CBD treats for your pet.
So, what does it do? Research has been
limited, but proponents say CBD has all
the benefits of medical marijuana
without the intoxicating effects,
helping with insomnia, pain management,
and anxiety. There's a revolution, a
whole movement happening now with
plant-based wellness, which is our
primary interest, celebrating the power
of all plants, which have not been
properly represented. And the question
everyone asks is, is it legal?
Dr. Sanjay Gupta, CNN's medical
correspondent, the chief
one and as reporter on the latest
research behind CBD. So, you know what?
Break this down for everybody. I'd like
to take your thoughts on what it really
is so people can get this into their
heads. Well, you think about the
cannabis plant, marijuana. It's called
cannabis. Um, it really has lots of
different ingredients, but two primary
ones. One is THC. That's the stuff
that's the recreational drug. It's what
gets people high, gives them that
euphoria. And their CBD, which is
cannibidol, it's it's something that
doesn't cause a psychoactive component.
It's believed to be a medicine. It's
been used as a medicine in decades past,
and it's getting this resurgence, as you
just heard. So, just to be clear, we've
talked about medical marijuana in the
past. This is not that, right? CBD oil
is being sold all over the place. You
you you take the plant and you can pull
out certain components of it. So you're
just pull in this case, you're pulling
out the CBD component and you're just
using that and and therefore you're not
getting all those other effects that
people often associate with marijuana,
which is why I think 47 states so far
have said we're okay with it. How is the
medical community using CBD oil? This is
fascinating to me. I mean, if you would
asked this question 5 years ago, it
would have basically been crickets.
Nobody was really talking about it.
Within the last 5 years, uh you you had
a medication that was sort of known
colloially as Charlotte's Web. It was
for this little girl who had seizures uh
that just could not be treated by all
these different medicines she took. Her
mom essentially started taking CBD
herself in her kitchen sink and giving
it to her daughter. That is what was
known as Charlotte's Web. Within 5
years, it's gone from being that idea to
now an FDA approved drug in this
country. That that's fast. That's never
really happened that quick. The
government has approved a ver a one CBD
oil for one indication. Yes. And this is
from the plant. This isn't synthesized
in some lab. This is CBD that's actually
coming from the plant, from the
botanical. So that that that's a big
deal. You actually now have something
that's been considered illegal at the
federal level, also part of an FDA
approved drug. That's that's that's what
we're dealing with in this country. Can
you guys wrap your heads around this?
It's this is part of the disconnect,
right? The the federal government says
it's not legal. 47 states say it is.
Kids with seizures are being treated. I
mean, FDA says yes, we'll approve it.
But but still at the federal level, it's
illegal. What is starting to gain more
traction, I think, really is what's
happening with opioids in this country.
What they found, uh, Dr. Oz, was that in
several states that had approved CBD
legislation, they saw their opioid
prescriptions start to go down. So,
that's that's an area the medical
community is really really focused on.
As as a neurosurgeon, you you're good at
this stuff. Explain to me how CBD
actually affects the body. Well, we have
all these different receptors in our
bodies uh to to basically attract and to
have these these components activate,
but because those receptors are
everywhere in the body, you could get an
impact just about anywhere. Actually,
let's show this to everybody because I
made a little model to demonstrate what
Sanjay is saying. CBD produces so many
effects throughout the body based on the
fact it can bind to receptors in so many
of our different organs, right? Places
as far away as the intestinal tract and
your arm and your spinal column up up
into your brain. And that's why people
say it helps them alleviate pain, right?
Maybe help with seizures. It's a pretty
serious problem for a lot of folks.
Anxiety, pretty common problem that we
don't want to treat if we don't have to.
Even withdrawal from medications, maybe
even the opiates as San Andre mentioned,
but think about that. People think it
can do so many things because of the CBD
oil that is in there is touching so many
parts of our body. And I love your
thought that we evolved as as species
because we had access to these natural
plants and they understandably can
affect us. That's right. And we and the
receptors started to evolve in our body
as well. We even started making our own
form of CBD in our body. But sometimes
it's not enough just like other things
aren't enough in our body and that's why
some people seem to get benefit. So the
question then becomes do they work? So
there are products of CBD oil which
again you saw the theoretical argument
you just made but these products are
popping up everywhere and some of these
are everyday items that you can buy. I
have a bunch in front of him. Yeah, we
don't Sanjay and I don't sell anything
in the space, but they're shampoos,
their supplements, their gummies, their
muscle soothing creams, they're even
products with your pets, as you saw from
Mara's report. So, when you look at
this, Sanjay, and you realize as a as a
clinician how complicated CBD could be,
how do you decide which of these might
work? Well, you know, you know, it's
interesting. I'll tell you this, I think
in part uh from a physician's
perspective. First of all, I think that
there's a a legitimate medicine in here.
I think we're talking about something
that could actually really help people.
And I worry a little bit when you start
to see products like this that it could
minimize the importance of what CBD
could do for people because I don't know
what these products are. I don't know
what's in them. I don't know how much of
anything is in them. I don't know if
they they would actually do anything. I
mean, this is CBD shampoo. If I could
get shampoo like Dr. Oz, I'd probably
use it. But, you know, other than that,
uh, I'm not I coveret your hair. You
should go. I'm not sure, though. I I I
would have a hard time if somebody came
to me and said, "Hey, should I take this
CBD product?" as much reporting as I've
done on it, I would still have a hard
time, you know, saying that it's a good
idea. So the FDA is in charge, in fact,
it's charged by our nation to tell us
the answer to that question. What's
safe? What's not? Where are they with
all these things? They they So this is
an illegal substance at the national
level. This is illegal. Illegal. At the
same time, as you as we talked about
earlier, the FDA has said, you know
what, we think there's enough of a
benefit here that we're willing to
approve a drug specifically for epilepsy
that's based on CBD. And part of what
reason I wanted to cover this topic is
you can buy these products anywhere
really. You can go down your local, you
know, store in 47 out of 50 states, buy
it online pretty much anywhere you want.
And the government's not going to come
in and kick your door down. So whatever
they say in the, you know, at the
highest levels, we're still not actually
doing anything to stop people from using
these, which is a concern to me because
it's the wild wild west. It's completely
unregulated. That's right. So if it does
have all the potential that we're
talking about today, I want to
understand what could be in your best
interest with CBD oil. Up next, we're
going to continue our investigation. How
much CBD is actually in these products
and can it really work for you? We have
the test results and they might surprise
you. I'm back with Dr. Sanjay Gupta
investigating the CBD oil boom that's
now a 1 billion with a B billion dollar
industry and CBD sales are expected to
grow 700% in the next two years. I mean,
that's shocking. Proponents say CBD can
be used to treat everything from
anxiety, chronic pain to epileptic
seizures, even cancer. products like
these, the ones in front of us here,
they're widely available stores and
online, but are you getting what you're
paying for? So, where's the research?
You know, I I hear it talked about so
much, but whenever I, you know, get
called by somebody, I want to know
what's the actual data that shows that
it work. And you can't find that much.
It's it's very hard to find the data. I
think on epilepsy, seizures,
particularly ones that have not been
treatable by existing medications,
there's there's pretty good data. That's
why the FDA approved the drug. But just
about any of those other things you
mentioned, the anxiety, the sleep, even
pain, the CBD only research is pretty
limited. Let let me say though, part of
that doesn't you shouldn't immediately
say, well, it doesn't work because of
that. Uh part of it is that the research
is hard to do. If you have a substance
that is illegal at the federal level,
how do you get research done on it? It's
very hard to get people to actually
invest in that research. That's part of
the problem here. And rarely have I been
called by as many people saying it's
helped them. Yeah, these are folks who
don't have a vested interest. So it
makes me really curious and as a
physician I feel frustrated that we
haven't done more right to help them
out. Yeah. Absolutely. No, I mean we
need we need to get that research done.
Absolutely. So let me introduce you to
Dr. Todd Cuberman's founder of
consumerlab.com.
They do all the work so you don't have
to. And they've tested the most popular
CBD products on the market. Well, first
of all, you have a lot of things you
could be testing. Why did you decide to
look at CBD oil? Uh as you were saying,
CBD has become super popular. So, the
readers of Consumer Lab have been asking
us really what's in these products
because, you know, as you mentioned,
since it's illegal, um, if a product
actually says CBD and the amount on it,
the FDA will go after them as calling it
an unapproved drug. All right, let's
break it down. We have all the data
here. I'm fascinated to see what you
got. First, we wanted to actually figure
out how much CBD is in the CBD oil
product, right? So, how how much
consistency was there? Right. So, uh, we
found over over a 10-fold difference
between products. We found 10fold. Yeah.
As little as 2 milligs to up to 22
milligs in a suggested serving. So, some
of them had this much. Some of them had
that much. Right. It's stunning to me.
Are you surprised by this? I I'm I'm
pretty surprised. I I think the the idea
that you have no idea what you're
getting, if you're even getting it at
all. I mean, that's that's not even a
real probable dose. If you need hundreds
of milligrams for it to do anything, 2
milligrams not going to do anything. And
yet people are paying a lot of money for
it. What about the cost? Yeah, so on the
cost, we found that the price uh for a
10 milligram dose um ranged from as
little as 80ents to up to 400, sorry,
not 400,
$4.50 for the same amount of CBD. So
again, you know, you can if you if you
know what to look for, you can get it
for a lot less than than the 450. I can
give a 10 times difference in price for
the same is it different CBD? Um, you
know, it it it's really this it's the
amount of CBD. It's same amount of 10
milligrams of CBD in each product. Some
can have a little bit of CBDA, which is
kind of a precursor, but that's really
for amount of C same amount of CBD. And
what about this issue of toxins,
contaminants, heavy metals, right? Well,
good news. Um, none of the nine products
that we tested, and these are products
for people and and animals, um, taken
orally as pills or liquids, none of them
had any uh heavy metal contamination.
None of them had any any significant
amount of THC. So when you look at all
these products, you do you find that
they're adequately labeled? No, not no.
I mean, very few products are actually
labeled appropriately um in terms of the
amount of CBD. U most you won't know.
And and when you look at the labels,
they often won't say the amount of CBD,
so they'll use other terms like hemp
extract. That typically means they are
extracting some some CBD from from the
plant and you're getting some. If it
says just hemp oil, you're getting none.
Hemp oil has no CBD in it. Um, they will
often put it in hemp oil. So, you'll
have hemp extract with hemp oil. Oh my
goodness. It gets kind of confusing.
Folks, if you don't understand something
these days, it's because they don't want
you to understand it. It's not an
accident, which is a problem because I
really deep in my heart agree with
Sanjay that there's a medicinal benefit.
This stuff's been around since the dawn
of humanity and I don't appreciate the
fact that we can't even figure out the
basic rules to give you advice with. So,
give me your bottom line here. CBD oils.
What would you do right now if you if
you had a problem? The one of the ones
we listed. I I think that other than the
things that have actually been tested,
um you you're really probably better off
saving your money. I think ultimately
we're going to we're going to get more
information about this. It's going to
have to happen. There's too much sort of
anecdotal evidence of how this might
work. Right now, you're not even sure if
you're getting CBD, how much you're
getting of it. In these cases, the
products were safe, but sometimes they
may be contaminated with heavy metals.
People say regulation is a bad thing. I
think when it comes to this, it's
probably a good thing because if there's
regulation, it's going to force these
these these people who are making these
products to list it to to stand by it
and to make sure that they're safe. It
rewards the good guys. People who are
making high quality products will
benefit, I think, from having them have
scoundrels pushed out. Here's my
thought. They could work. I'm hearing
from too many of you right now that
they're getting benefits, but their
problem with how we access it. So, what
do you ought to do? Talk to your doc
about it. Get them to sit down with for
a second. Help them figure because
they'll help you. They understand this
stuff. They'll figure out which of these
CBD oils might make sense from you.
There are some reputable companies, I
suspect, that are beginning to get into
the medical community. But we've got to
make this happen. And it's not going to
happen from someone else doing it for
you. You got to step up in your own life
and do the investigation. For more
information on CBD products, we'll do
our best. You go to our website and
guess what? For the next 24 hours, you
can get the Consumer Labs complete
report for free there. So check it out.
Spread it with your friends. Thank you
for watching. Don't forget to subscribe
and turn on notifications so you never
miss out on new videos to live the good