Let's look inside the yolk of an egg. We
investigate brand new science. Now we're
discovering that it may have a dark side
that may change the way you think about
your morning meal. They create a toxic
chemical. Should we go back to eating
just egg whites again? Plus muscle hot
dog. Hot dog. It was a challenge, but we
finally found an Oz approved hot dog.
And the winner is coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you,
[Music]
[Applause]
Da. Today, we're bringing you brand new
science about your go-to protein power
food, eggs. Now, for years, I've stood
on this stage and told you there is
nothing wrong with eating the yolk of
the egg. But science, you know, it's
always changing. And some are now
questioning whether the yolk may
increase the risk of heart disease and
stroke. And get this, it doesn't have to
do with the cholesterol at all. When
news about something as important as
this breaks, I want to be the first to
bring it to you. So today, we are
investigating eggs and answering the
question, do we all need to go back to
eating egg whites again? Joining me now
is food investigator Alli Rosen.
This is this is crazy. In my in my short
career as a doctor, we've gone back and
forth, back and forth in contention for
decades. Yeah. So, what's going on now?
Why can't we figure out whether it's
good or bad for it's an egg, right?
Well, to start with, we have to take a
little trip back to the '9s to really
understand. So, the '9s gave us a lot of
great things like flannel and some of my
favorites, boy bands. Sorry. Um, but it
also gave us a very strict no yoke
policy and that really came from
cholesterol. We found that yolk had a
lot of cholesterol and so people stopped
having yolks and then we realized a
little later as you're saying science is
always changing. We realized that the
dietary cholesterol in yolks really has
nothing to do with our cholesterol. So,
but some people still haven't caught up.
So, that's why we see a lot of egg
whites on menus. So, just to be clear,
if your issue is cholesterol, with rare
exceptions, it's not the egg that's your
problem. No, not at all. And once we
realized they shouldn't be villainized
for cholesterol, then we started to
discover some really beneficial
nutrients that egg yolks offered. So,
let's look inside the yolk of an egg,
right? Beautiful egg here. And if you
take the yolk off, right, there's
something here that's really important
for you to know about. It's called
choline and it's found in eggs. And it
wasn't discovered until
1998. But once it was discovered, it
became the gold standard nutrient, the
one that's most important for a lot of
people. They think now it's essential to
our brain development, liver function,
nervous system, metabolism, you know,
all the stuff you need to get from food.
It's in this choline. And one of the
best sources for most of you, the best
actually is egg yolks. So choline
brought the yolk back into vogue. But
now we're discovering ally to your point
that it may have a dark side because
it's being raised as a concerning issue
for a lot of big-time scientists. My
good friend and chief wellness officer
at the Cleveland Clinic, Dr. Mike Royen
joins us via Zoom. Mike, congratulations
because a lot of this research came out
of your institution and it led you to
give up egg yolks again and you've been
hammering me on this. literally
confiscating eggs out of my refrigerator
when you come to visit. Why? What is the
issue?
That's right. Um, we've been worried
about the negative health effects of egg
yolks for a long
time. But it's not the cholesterol per
se. We were right, but for the wrong
reason. animal products. Some animal
products and egg yolks in particular
have a lot of what you've said, choline,
a specific choline. And it turns out
that that changes the bacteria inside
our gut. And when they get in the blood,
they can harm our blood vessel,
increasing our risk for heart disease
and stroke. Mike, choline, it's
essential as a nutrient for us. is
present in foods, I guess, for a good
reason. Is the research, in your
opinion, really strong enough to say,
don't get your choline from eggs. Stop
eating the egg yolks. Well, egg yolks
are very high in choline. But we need
more research on this. And until that's
done, I'm playing it safe. Egg whites
are fine, but at most one egg yolk a
week, especially if they have red meat
or other things in their diet that
change the bacteria and have those
bacteria increase production of that
inflammatory chemical. Dr. Rosen, thank
you. Go back to work. I see the blood
pressure cuff behind you. Take care of
some patients. Thank you. So, let's
let's take a closer look at how choline
can lead to blood clots. I'm going to
just put a little pictures behind what
Mike was saying. So when some people
ingest choline from foods like eggs, it
can interact. You put the egg in your
mouth, it goes into your gut. And
remember he said it can interact with
certain gut bacteria in their
intestines. The gut bacteria digest the
choline and they create a toxic
chemical. And this gut flora it differs
but that toxic chemical doesn't. It's
the same chemical that causes
inflammation in blood vessels which can
lead to the formation of plaques that
narrow the arteries. Right? It also
makes the platelets more sticky. And
those platelets are important for
clotting, which is good if you got a
cut, right? Skim your knee. It's
fantastic. But it's bad if you happen to
have a problem inside your artery
because when you have a cut in your
artery, your body then puts a scab
there, stops the flow of blood, and that
can cause heart attacks or stroke, all
kinds of headaches. Now, this sounds
alarming, but I don't want everyone
running scared of yolks just yet because
Ally has some hacks for how you can
potentially reduce the harmful effects
of egg yolks. and I like her ideas a
lot. So, walk us through a few. Yeah, I
do not want to only eat one egg yolk a
week. So, there's a few ingredients that
can kind of counterbalance the effects
of choline. Uh, cold pressed extra
virgin olive oil, balsamic vinegar, and
red wine. All things I love eating.
Yeah, exactly. So, apply them. How do I
use them in my food? Right. So, we've
come up with three recipes so that you
don't have to like drink a glass of wine
every morning for breakfast to help you
counterbalance your eggs. Um, this is
just a baked egg recipe. We use four
tablespoons of olive oil, which is
enough to counterbalance the choline.
Um, it has basil and some sunflower
seeds, and you just bake it in the oven.
So, that's a really great easy one for
anyone. This is if you want to get a
little fancier. These are balsamic
vinegar, deileled eggs, uh, which have
balsamic vinegar, a little bit of garlic
powder. Um, you know, you can use mayo,
but you can also use your favorite of
Greek yogurt. We've got your kale and
your Greek yogurt today. So, very
exciting. You know, these will be great
with the wine, right? Exactly. You drink
them with the wine. And then for a
little bit of breakfast for dinner, we
also do some red wine poached eggs. Um,
which is another great option. You
really just switch out the water for the
You switch out the water for the red
wine. You literally poach the eggs in
wine. Yeah, just same regular wine. I'm
going to have you put a little cheese on
top. Yeah, there we go. Little cheese.
And you can do a little bit of parsley
or basil to kind of give it that color
to go with that. Got to taste this. This
is unbelievable. I love poached eggs.
And this is one that's really great for
if you want to have a dinner party or
you want fancier. Yeah. And you have the
the yolk which Roy's going to go crazy
if he ever sees this. I know. Sorry.
Don't let him see. Thank you. He's back
in the clinic.
This is a real winner, Allie. Exactly.
Yeah. These are easy ways and then you
don't have to worry about your egg yolks
and you can have more than one a week
cuz that that scared me a little. All
right, coming up. You ever wonder what
the deal is with liquid eggs? How many
of you guys buy liquid eggs in cartons?
All right, left. makes life easy in
theory. We're going to find out. Stay
with us.
[Applause]
The doctor and nurse charged with
murder. I found him unresponsive of
their own son. I forgot how to do CPR.
But there are more twists to this story.
There was some head trauma. Classic
shaken baby syndrome. Plus, a sociopath
cop who prayed on women. How did this
police officer get away with this for so
long? And the whistleblower who brought
him down. A lot of officers start coming
forward. All new Oz.
That's coming up
[Applause]
tomorrow. All right. No yolk
substitutes. They come in cartons like
this, right? These no yolk substitutes
have only increased in popularity with
the low carb, high protein diet trends.
But are they as healthy? And could they
be even healthier than the real thing?
Food journalist Ally Rosa has looked
into these and she's here to tell us the
truth. Why do people like getting their
egg whites from cartons? Well, it's
really just about convenience, right?
Every time you want to make an egg
white, you've got to go in, it's messy,
it's hard, you got to do the like back
and forth, screw it up. Exactly. And you
know, it's just You missed some. I know.
See? Exactly. That's my point. So,
people like egg substitutes because it's
easier. All right. So, the question is,
are they really good for you? Let's look
into these liquid egg substitutes.
Starting out with liquid eggs whites.
Egg whites. They come in cartons now.
Adriano uses them every day for
breakfast. She says, "What do you love
about the egg whites in the carton?"
Because it's so easy, the simplicity of
it. I mean, I learned I mean, I've
learned and I've learned from you, too,
about how important breakfast is. And
it's like it's we're all rushing, you
know, trying to get somewhere in the
morning. And, you know, that thought of
having to do that with the eggs, I just
get, you know, forget about it.
protein in breakfast and you want to
avoid the embarrassment that Ally just
suffered through. Oh my god, I'm even
worse. Forget about it. So, what did you
find out about egg whites in a carton?
So, it's really important that it says
100% egg whites because then there's no
additives. So, if you see 100% egg
whites, that means that that's all
that's in there, but you want to just
make sure it has that. You don't want
any additional extras. It should be
achievable relatively easily. So, we're
generally in support of this. Yeah,
we're in support of it. You just have to
remember that it's more expensive. Eggs
are cheap and easy. And then it also you
have to use it within 7 days of opening.
So that's the only downside. Save me a
little bit. Yeah, I will. They're these
zero
cholesterol egg substitutes. I I don't
know much about these. I've never tried
these. Teresa says she likes them.
You've not let a single ed egg into your
house since your husband was told he has
a cholesterol issue. Correct. Shows your
love for him. Yes. Because you probably
could have gotten away with it. Maybe.
Ally, what do you know about these?
Well, so egg substitute is made with
real egg whites, but they're taking out
the yolk. So, when they're taking out
the yolks, they want to add back in a
lot of those vitamins and minerals that
come with the yolk. But the issue is
that they're also adding thickeners and
stabilizers and coloring to try and make
it look and feel like an egg. It can
have up to 31 extra ingredients. So, 31.
Yeah, 31 extra ingredients, which you
can see here. They're kind of all
scrolling by. So, uh you really, if
you're trying to eat clean, I would say
this probably isn't the best choice. and
just to do what's best for you and your
husband and those wonderful kids of
yours. My general thought is if you're
going to take something away and not eat
it anymore, like if you're not going to
have the yolk of the egg and just have
the whites, I'm okay with that. But
trying to pretend like you have the yolk
when you're not going to have the yolk,
it's often not worth the effort. Okay.
All right. Finally, there's a new vegan
egg substitute that Teresa, you might
like this even more. This supposedly
stands up to any of the runny yolk of an
egg that you may want to add to a
recipe. Sort of like, you know how with
the Impossible Burger, that burger
that's not with any meat but has actual
blood coming out of it. They made a
burger from vegetables. So, what are
these made of? How do they make powder
into a yolk? Yeah. I was a little
skeptical because it's, you know, it's
no egg. It's no cholesterol. It's no
fat. And I was kind of like, are we just
eating air? Like, right. What's left?
Right. But, um, it's actually mostly
made with pea protein. And then they add
in nutritional yeast, which is something
you see a lot in vegan food, which gives
it that umami flavor. Um, and then
there's a few, you know, guar gum and
zantham gum, um, beta carotene for the
color. Um, but it's mostly okay. So, you
make it just by, you have a little bit
of water, you put in this powder, throw
the top on, if you will, and then you
just mix it up.
That's it. And you let that go. And what
comes out? And then you throw it in the
microwave. And what comes out is this
substitute here. So that's it there.
That's it there. So it looks like an
egg. And you let me know if you think it
tastes like an egg. There. I made you a
little egg sandwich here. She's a little
dubious of it. I'm a little dubious,
too. Yolk, but it but it's vegan and the
protein source. We know it's vegan and
you know, pea protein is good. Still
some of those stabilizers. So, what do
you think? Good. Missing a little
something, but it will get the job done.
You didn't miss your shirt. I No, I got
it all over me. Yeah, I actually like
this, guys. I think I really do. I think
this is a winner. If you're vegan, it's
a good substitute. You know, if you're
looking for something and you don't want
to have any animal protein, it's a good
one to try. Here, I'll toast the stains
for any busy mom. We'll be right back.
We investigate iced tea. What's really
brewing in those store-bought bottles?
No guarantee that you're getting what
you think you're getting. That's coming
up Wednesday on Dr. Oz.
Today we are investigating one of the
most popular and controversial food.
Everyone is buying hot dogs. You can see
how excited the audience is. When you
see use the word hot dogs, they all
light up. We consume 20 billion of them
each year. But there's a lot of food
fiction about hot dogs, especially on
social media. Like what kinds of meat
are actually in there and do they really
cause cancer? We decided to look into
what's real and what's not and
investigate the question I get asked all
the time. Is there an Oz approved real
deal hot dog? You want the answer to
that everybody? All
right, I'm going to give it to you. Here
to help investigate is Chef Charles
Shen. So, give us a little bit of hot
dog history, chef. Where did this all
come from? Why did America get so
obsessed with hot dogs? So, hot dogs
have been around since the 19th century.
And one report says that they originated
from Germany. Then they were brought
over to New York and served in a push
cart. Next thing you know, they were
served in butcher shops and also sports
stadiums and people became obsessed with
hot dogs. The next thing you know, they
were actually served to the Queen of
England in 1939. Talk about
royalty. It's a famous incident. It's
really people talk about it was the most
American food they could give to the
queen. Yeah. So, I gota be honest
everybody, right? Even though it's a fan
favorite, most doctors don't like hot
dogs. We know there's health risks to
them. You had a big transformation. I
should say green brag on the chef. He
lost 100 pounds. 100 lbs. Here's a
before and after everybody. I mean for a
chef especially, you transformed your
own health. So you pay attention to
health issues. What worries you
Absolutely. about hot dogs and health.
So this is considered processed meat and
this has been linked to a bunch of
different health effects. So looking at
hot dogs, it has been linked to things
like high blood pressure, diabetes. One
study actually shows that eating one
daily serving of processed meat, which
is one hot dog, is associated with 42%
higher risk of developing coronary
disease, heart disease. Yes. So, and
that's not not even talking about the
cancer risk that I know the WHO's talked
about with processed meats. The question
is what's going down? Let's investigate
how hot dogs are really made. We'll
start off with the fear that a lot of
Americans have voiced to me, which is
they don't know what's actually in a hot
dog. What make makes a hot dog? No
animal looks like this. Yeah. So,
according to the USDA, traditional hot
dogs are made from one of the following
meats: pork, beef, and chicken. And
also, the packaging must state what type
of meat that you're actually eating. And
from there, they actually start with
trimmings are basically what the butcher
doesn't use as separate cuts. It could
be reasonable quality trimmings. Yeah.
And then they combine it all together.
And then also, if there's any byproducts
of kidneys, liver, or heart, they must
specify what types of meat and where it
came from in the animals in the
ingredient list. All right. Next thing
that that that needs to happen for that
transformation to occur is fillers,
which are things that I'm always worried
about because I'm not quite sure if
they're what I'm paying for. Yes. So, to
combine all this meat together, some
brands like to use fillers such as soy
proteins and also some cereal grains.
So, according to the USDA, hot dogs can
contain up to 3.5% of these fillers. But
this just adds to the idea that this
meat is super heavily processed. It is a
process. I as I look at it here, that
doesn't bother me quite as much as I
thought it would. What does bother me
though is this. The most controversial
of all issues around the hot dogs are
the nitrates. It looks so innocuous when
it's in this powdered form. Oh wow. But
it's a problem. Why are they in hot
dogs? So nitrites are actually chemical
compounds that are used as preservatives
in processed meat such as hot dogs and
they're used as preservatives for the
meat. Also add flavor and also adds with
the color. However, these nitrates and
nitrites can actually form
cancer-causing compounds in the body.
So, you got to be very careful. And what
about the I see a lot of dogs say
nitrate free. What are they using? How
do they accomplish that? Yeah. So, when
it says nitrate free, they're using
natural nitrates coming from celery, but
the amount of nitrates used is just as
much as the synthetic nitrates. So, you
still have to be very careful. So, even
if it's celery powder or celery juice,
it still has the same potential risk.
Yes. All right. So, because of all these
things we're talking about, there are a
lot of full hot dogs out there, like the
veggie kinds. You've heard the veggie
hot dogs, right? Turkey dogs and like.
So, this is an example what a turkey dog
looks like. Doesn't quite look as pretty
as that hot dog I showed you earlier.
Oh, yeah. Explain. There's a there's a
true veggie hot dog. These may not be
quite what they're cooked up to be. No.
So, I looked at a bunch of different hot
dogs on the market, Dr. Oz. And
specifically, I looked at uh turkey hot
dogs and also veggie hot dogs. Turkey
hot dogs actually contain mechanically
separated turkey, which means we have no
idea what kind of body parts they're
using in the hot dog. And then looking
at the veggie hot dogs, we actually
found they use seven times amount of
ingredients than regular hot dogs. So
say seven times seven times the amount
of regular ingredients. They found
things like sugar and also hydrogelized
proteins, which I don't know if it's
much healthier. So, I have searched far
and wide for a good hot dog replacement.
Even trying to make carrots into hot
dogs. Take a look at this effort. This
is the hot dog of my dreams. And this is
no ordinary hot dog. Prepare for your
mind to be blown by this hack. Who wants
one? Hot dogs. Hot dogs. Anybody? Hot
dogs. Hot dogs. Who wants a little hot
dog? Hot dog. Guess what? This in here.
Look carefully. It's actually a carrot.
Yeah, it didn't go over so well. I get
it. Nothing like the real deal. So, the
moment of truth. Can there really be a
healthy hot dog? Remember, hot dogs are
not a daily food. So, don't take us out
of context, but if you're going to
indulge once in a while, at least choose
wisely. So, Aaron from my med unit is
coming out. Come on, Aaron. You're going
to wheel out the winning hot
dog. I present to you
the best hot dog. Aaron, come join us.
Are you ready? And the winner is tada.
It's a 100% beef hot dog.
Now, what does that mean? The first
ingredient needs to be beef. It's say
100% organic or grass-fed beef. Avoid
the mechanically separated stuff that
we're just talking about with chef,
right? You don't you want to know what
the meat came from. The next ingredients
got to be water. So, it's meat. 100%
water. That's okay. And the ingredient
label should avoid common fillers like
the soy protein and cereal grains. we
talked about earlier and one last little
hack that Aeron's sharing with us. You
don't want more than 500 milligrams of
sodium. Why cause more problems for
yourself? So, where do you find these
hot dogs? So, we did a lot of research
on this and you can actually find them
in a lot of your local grocery stores
and even online. You can search for
them. So, it's they're pretty easy to
get. And chef, you got a special topping
for this better than usual hot dog. Yes,
absolutely. So, instead of using regular
ketchup, which has a lot of sugar, I
would use something like homemade salsa
or pico de gallo. Adds a nice tartness,
nice texture, and it's a win-win for
everyone. And there's no sugar. No. So,
we're going to call them salsa dogs. Who
wants a salsa dog? Salsa dog. Anybody?
My car didn't go over well. Salsa dog.
Salsa dog. Give one a shot. Give one a
shot. I want Go ahead. Give it a bite.
Give it a taste. The real Dr. Orzac, you
know. Hot dog. Hot dogs and beer. Dr.
Oz. Proof that God loves us.
I love you, too, guys. Enjoy it. That's
more here. Charles, thank you very much.
We'll be right
[Applause]
back. We all wish we could go back in
time and undo the health wrongs that we
made over the years. And today we are
telling you how with four easy
[Music]
steps. It's your favorite thing to
click, right? You go up there, you hit
the undo button. And as you hit it, oh,
feels so good. But is there an undo
button for your health? Can you go back
to a healthier version of you? Well,
there is an undue button to reverse
disease in our bodies. And thanks to my
next guest, we actually have proof. Dean
Ornish is a maverick. He's a visionary
who bravely challenged the status quo of
how medicine treats disease. Dean has
been a driving force and an inspiration
to me personally and many others since
my early days in medical school. Now, he
and his wife Anne, a health and stress
expert, have teamed up to take home all
this research that all the proven work
they've done and turned into an easy to
follow four-step plan to stop diseases
like heart disease and diabetes and
dementia right in their tracks. Please
welcome my friends Dr. Dean Orish and
Anne Ornish.
[Applause]
[Music]
and how are you?
It's so much fun to have you here. I got
to say before we get into the show, you
are really one of my heroes and I
remember vividly I was uh right the
beginning of residency and I went to
this big American Heart Association
meeting and this is a meeting where all
the best new ideas are planned out and
there was this room in the corner there
just packed you couldn't get into it and
I was crawling over people trying to get
inside because I knew you were speaking
and it was one of the first talks that
you gave that really threatened I say
that word on purpose because you were
challenging orthodoxy but threatening
the belief that so many in American
medicine had that when you had an
illness, it was yours. We could use
medications to slow it down, but you
sort of were going to live with that
problem for the rest of your life. What
gave you the courage, the confidence to
challenge the the American medical
establishment to argue that no,
lifestyles can actually reverse some of
these problems? Oh, well, thank you for
your kind words. I appreciate it. Um,
when I was in medical school, I did my
core surgery rotation with Michael
Debakei, the eminent heart surgeon who
helped develop bypass surgery. And as a
heart surgeon, you know, and I'm sure
you've had the experience of, you know,
you cut people open, you they they go
home, they do all the things that cause
the problem in the first place, you
know, eat junk food and smoke cigarettes
and not manage stress and their new
arteries clog up and you cut them open
again. I said, you know, there has to be
a better way. And bypass surgery became
we were literally bypassing the problem.
So I wondered what would happen if we
treated the cause. And so I went to the
li these things called libraries and
these things called journals, you know,
which no one use anymore. And I found in
dogs and cats and pigs and rabbits and
monkeys, you could cause them to get
heart disease if you put them under
these, you know, bad diets and so on.
And you could reverse it if you change
that. So why should people be any
different? So Annie, you argue that it's
not just about food. There's more than
that. Absolutely not. What makes this so
powerful is that it's a comprehensive
way of living. So what you eat, how you
respond to stress, how much activity you
have, and really how much love and
support you have are the simple choices
that we make every day that can either
create um health and well-being or uh
disease and suffering. So it's your
choice. Each each one of us makes that
choice every day, many times. Well,
we're going to make it easy to make the
right choice today. Let me put you on
the spot for a second. You debated the
famous Dr. Atkins years ago. Many times,
actually. Many many times. I remember
vividly one time and now we're seeing a
full circle come around again with paleo
and keto diet advocates arguing the same
things that Dr. Atkins argued. Yes. Why
why do you think those diets are not as
good as the Ornish diet and give us a
little bit of insight into why the
Ornish diet has probably been the best
studied of all of the diets for reversal
of disease? Well, because it's the only
diet, our diet is the only one that's
actually been proven to reverse disease.
It's why US News and World Report is
rated at number one for heart health
almost every one of the last eight years
since they've been rating diets. The
studies have shown that on a diet like I
recommend your arteries are clean. On a
standard American diet or has an actual
acronym of SAD diet, they're partially
clogged. And on an Atkins or Paleo or
keto diet, they're part they're severely
clogged. And it's one of the reasons why
when Dr. Atkins died, they published his
autopsy report and he had he died of
massive heart failure. And so the
problem is you can lose weight on those
diets, but you mortgage your health in
the process. Whereas on the diet, we
recommend you can lose even more weight,
but you enhance your health rather than
harming it. So, our partners at
ShareCare have worked to put Dean's plan
into practice for millions of you,
offering a comprehensive solution that
is so effective. Listen carefully. Even
Medicare covers it. I mean, insurance
companies cover because Medicare covers
it as well. That's right. Most insurance
companies are because you it took 16
years for Medicare to do that. But I
wanted to be available to everyone and
now it is. So, Dean's book puts a lot of
these insights, books called Undo It
into easy practice. So let me explain to
everybody why Dean Orish's fundamental
findings about undoing disease are so
important. So you all know these
diseases right? Asthma, heart disease,
diabetes, prostate cancer, you know,
ulcers, reflex, all this stuff. What
Dean sees is not a lot of different
diseases that look separate from each
other. He sees the same disease, just
one masquerading in different forms.
They all share the same underlying
biological mechanisms of inflammation,
oxidative stress, changes in your gut,
your microbiome. We've talked about
these things. So each one of these
things, right, is directly affected by
how we live. That's the one circular
path we have to go get into. And what we
eat and how much we exercise, it all
affects this, right? So what you eat
matters, right? How you exercise
matters. And perhaps most importantly,
how much love and support you have in
your lives. They all come together. And
we can change these variables. And if we
do that, we can actually reverse
disease. And there are four steps to the
undue plan that you can start off today.
The first step is to add low-fat
plant-based foods to your diet. Why are
plant-based foods the cornerstone of
your program of the Ornish diet? Well,
in simple terms, they're high in the the
substances that keep us healthy, that
have anti-cancer, anti-aging, anti-he
heart disease properties, and they're
low in the ones that keep us that cause
us to get sick. Keeps it simple. Really
simple. And wanted to make the plant
easy to follow. So they found prepared
foods in grocery stores. You don't have
to go into the kitchen and spend six
hours making the food. Walk us through a
couple of the examples. Well, so here is
some um tacos and um a lot of I I grew
up eating meats and loving meats. So if
this wasn't savory, it wouldn't be
sustainable. So there are so many
wonderful options. It's never been
easier to eat this way and be fully
satisfied. So, some of the the crumbles
that we like to use in pasta sauces, in
this case, tacos, these are a delicious
crowd-pleaser. And it's so easy to get
uh complete protein, enough protein.
That's a myth. So, these are just a
couple of examples of just be specific.
This is called textured vegetable
protein or TBP. That's what you'll see
it call that. Yes, we made tacos with
it, but as I mentioned, you can make
lots of other meals. It's a ground beef
replacement. Try it before you judge,
guys. I know you're out there saying,
"No, there's no way, right?" But
soybased proteins do work and and these
little, you know, bacon things are soy.
All right, let's take a look at what
this meal plan looks like in real
practice. Who else to call in here but
Renatha? Go to
testure. Renatha tells it like it is. I
just showed a couple examples. There are
simple hacks you can buy in the grocery
store, but these are actual meals we
made. And this is a go-to lunch option.
It's a lentil, chili, and greens. There
we are making. There's a lasagna to get
to in a second. Why is this your power
choice? Okay, so this was my favorite
because this actually mimics actual
ground beef. Yeah, I said it. Ground
beef. Okay, it's nice and thick. The
lentils actually replace the ground beef
option. And this is a winner for me. All
right, let's go over to this lasagna,
which I know you're waiting for. The
spinach lasagna, everyone's favorite.
This is a whole wheat lasagna. Noodles
though, right, are straight up whole
grain. And the tofu, right, is using
with nutritional yeast instead of
ricotta. So it this this is not ricotta,
right? And you guys cook with this
usually. Oh, yeah. It's delicious. Now,
I know you're not a big tofu fan, but
tofu takes on the flavor of whatever you
put into it. So, we're not you've
rotested many a dish for us. Your
thoughts on the spinach lasagna. Okay.
So, you know, so before I made it, I was
like, you want me to eat tofu, Dr.
Yes, that's exactly what she said. But
this has the pasta in it. It has the
tofu. The tofu and the the the yeast. It
takes on the taste of cheese and you
know we love our cheese. This is really
really fabulous. Yes. Yes. It's full.
It's thoughtful. It actually You
wouldn't know it wasn't ricotta cheese.
Absolutely. That's the point. Dr. Oz, a
toast to the ornishes on there. We're
going to put these recipes plus an
amazing blueberry banana smoothie which
I did not let you have yet on dr.com.
You're going to try it. There it is. It
looks so good. It could have been yours.
All right. When we come back, it takes
less than 30 minutes, but it could keep
you out of a doctor's office like mine
for the rest of your life. Stick around.
Fabulous. I love getting to talk with
you on my show every single day, but
when the cameras stop rolling, the
conversation is not over. I still have a
lot that I want to talk about. So
download the Dr. Oz podcast on Apple
Podcast or wherever you get your
podcast.
[Applause]
We're back with a brand new four-step
plan to undo the diseases that you dread
the most. Dr. Dean Orish and his wife
Anne have seen the effects change the
lives of their patients firsthand. And
now they're sharing it with you. We've
got food. We talked about that a little
bit. Let's take a look at what else we
need to deal with, including stress,
because the next step of the plan is how
to use mindful methods to reduce stress.
We pay a lot of lip service to this
concept of stress, but you've used
tactics to address it in these plans
that you and Shareare have all over the
country with unbelievable results. Yeah.
Well, stress, as you know, can activate
all the mechanisms you talked about
earlier that that really underly all
these chronic diseases. But the good
news is that the stress comes not just
from what you do. More important is how
you react to what you do. And the kinds
of things that Anne can talk about are
ways that we found you can be in the
same job, the same family, and react in
different ways and accomplish even more
without getting stressed and sick in the
process. And give us some hacks. Well,
you say a lot of us do it wrong. We have
this very intent desire to meditate, but
we can't do it. Well, I think that we're
if we're waiting for a meditation
retreat, that perfect moment where the
waters have been parted, that's probably
not going to happen. So, we have to take
advantage of the time that we do have.
And by just taking a moment to refocus
our attention, we can take the same
stressful moment like road rage, but uh
reorient ourselves by reorienting our
attention. Crazy as it sounds,
everybody, your new meditation space is
going to be your car. Think about it.
You're in there anyway, right? You're
driving America's commute a lot or going
shopping, whatever you're doing. Just
while you're in the car, keep your keep
your eyes open. Eyes open. The Dean's
always warning people to do that. But
you can actually get into a calm space
and use that positive energy to reshape
your life. When you talk about the
effect of stress, it's like you're
talking about the effect of food. That's
right. All those risk factors you
mentioned, remember there's one cause of
it all. That's right. It makes it a lot
easier to keep up with life. Okay. The
next step in the plan that you have to
use to undo disease is to fill your day
with short bursts of energy using
resistance. Now, Renata, who's not been
a big advocate of
exercise, right, has designed her own
resistance training mode, right? And you
wait now you've got a band there which
cost less than a dollar I think last
time I priced it out. So you want to do
a biceps curl. What are you going to do
for us? So I'm going to demo for you a
bicep curl sitting down no less. How
about that? Okay. So all you have to do
you get one of these little resistance
band. Like you said they only cost a
dollar. A buck in the store. Put it
around your foot right there. Okay. Get
that planted. And all you have to do is
sit here. And one. And two. Look at
these guns. Look at these guns. Yes.
Listen, the key is you can be sitting at
work tasks that you normally can't get a
lot of exercise on. No one's going to
know you're doing this. You can do pulls
be under the desk. Your legs can be
going like this under the desk. But you
need to get a little activity. You need
to get a little breathy for about half
an hour. And if you do that, it changes
a lot. Changes everything, you know, and
it's so simple. And you know, you can do
it anywhere as you say. All right. So,
there's a surprising effect that this
exercise is going to have that you're
going to enjoy. It's going to affect
your brain. Absolutely. And Dean, your
studies looking at, you know, again, I'm
so impressed that you've demonstrated
you can reverse heart disease and
actually early stage prostate cancer.
These are very seemingly very different
diseases with one common mechanism, but
the Alzheimer's story is the most comp
compelling to me. Well, Alzheimer's
shares the same underlying mechanisms as
all these other conditions. And I think
we're at a place with Alzheimer's that
we were 50 years, 40 years ago with
heart disease when we started doing
work. So, we're now doing the first
randomized trial to see if we can
reverse Alzheimer's disease. So, stay
tuned. We're uh we're hopeful. be part
of it, not listen. The final step is
pretty simple, is to find a way of of
loving and supporting people in your
life and making sure they do the same
with you. That's how you connect with
people around you. That's how I feel
about both you guys and thanks for being
lifelong friends. God bless you both.
You can check out their new book. It's
called Undo It. There's a picture of it.
It's available now. The thing is the
audience, I mean, they want to reverse
heart disease and prevent Alzheimer's
and deal with anything else that they're
meant. Can they have a copy? I think you
should give every everyone a You guys
want a copy of the book? You're all
going over the copy of Dean's book.
We'll be right
back. Up next, an investigation into
cough drops. Do they really work? We
reveal the results of our first ever
cough
[Applause]
experiment. The day of investigation you
don't want to miss this time of year,
especially if you're doing
this. Yeah, you know who you are.
Coughing away and you're desperate for
any type of relief right this second.
So, we're uncovering the truth about
cough drops. Do they really work? And
can you really get addicted to them?
Here to help me figure it out is my
go-to tester, Rena. How are you? Hello.
So, you may not know it, but Renatha,
she loves to sing backstage. I hear it
all the time. Yeah, you argue cough drop
chops are your go-to remedy when you
have a scratchy throat. They are my
go-to remedy. You know what? I'm so glad
you're doing this because sometimes when
I'm really horse, I there's about 20
pieces of cough chops in one bag. I'll
eat the whole bag in one day. The whole
bag? Yes, the whole bag. How many
baggers are there here people? We have a
couple baggers here. Yeah, there's more
than a couple. That's not That's not
uncommon. Yeah, we'll talk about that as
well. Come on over here. We've been
bringing internist Dr. Sandra Galbard.
She's been treating a lot of coals this
season. is going to help us uncover the
truth about cough drops. Let's start
with what's really in cough drops. Cough
drops, hard candies, compare them. So,
cough drops, just like hard candies,
often contain sugar, corn syrup,
artificial sweeteners, and
preservatives. So, let me tell you
something. You have three of these cough
drops. Just three, right? That's four
grams of sugar in each one of these
drops. That's the same number of sugar
as a donut. Shut up. Donut. A donut.
Think about that. Three. Three cough
drops. You're basically having a donut.
Keep that in the back of your mind. And
I get the whole bag in one day. Yeah. I
just did the math on me. That's seven
donuts. Oh, wow. Oh, wow. Dang, Ranatha.
Dang. At least have coffee with it.
Okay. All right. So, move on down here.
So, we understand that these are
actually more similar than we'd like to
admit. The other ingredient that we see
in a lot of cough drops is menthol. What
is in menthol, by the way? Menthol is
made from mint oil and peppermint. And
um it has a really soothing effect on
the throat because it numbs the throat
and it has a cooling adds a cooling
sensation. If that's the case, then why
do I see patients friends come back and
sometimes say that it actually makes it
a little bit worse? So there was
actually a recent study that showed that
too high of a dose of menthol can worsen
your cough by causing an increase in
mucus buildup and irritating the throat.
Like a bag worth might.
All right. So, we decided to do a little
experiment using some of the most
popular cop drops, their brains, and the
hard candies. We're going to compare
them. Are you ready for this? All right,
it's a big deal. We got participants and
we broke them into four different
groups. Here are the groups. Okay, group
number one, and find yourself here, the
peppermint lovers, right? Peppermint
candy. Now, this is a control group,
which means it doesn't actually have a
specific role in stopping a cough. But
and the question is, does sucking on
anything, just a piece of hard candy
actually reduce cough symptoms? That's
group number one. Group number two,
menthol people like we just talked about
with reda, right? The active ingredient
here provides that cooling sensation
that so many of us enjoy. Then there are
the people who like pectin. These are
the most popular brands. you can find
out, you know, which in which brand if
you want to look into it. But I see a
lot of people doing pectin solutions.
You know why? Because it coats your
throat, which again seems to be
effective, at least many would argue,
but we're going to put it to the test.
And then the fourth group, well, they
got a a product that had zinc in it. And
zinc has been shown to shorten the
duration of your cold, but does it
really help with the cough itself? So,
we have participants follow the package
instructions, right? to took one cough
drop, one of these four cough drops
every two hours and then 15 minutes
after taking a cough drop or the candy
because there's a control group with the
peppermint down there, right? They had
to give us a little rating. Did it work
for them or not? Verata, before we
revealed the results of the group, which
one of these were you randomized to and
how did it work for you? I was
randomized to the zinc. And the zinc
didn't do nothing for me, doctor. It
didn't. It didn't do anything for me. I
No, none whatsoever. We'll come back to
that because that's the one thing that
seems to work to shorten the duration of
the cold, but you're saying it didn't
actually help the cough, right? Okay,
ready for the results, everybody?
Excited. All right, the answer is right
up here. Three of the four groups had a
majority of people who felt a small
improvement. And you know what?
Interestingly, the zinc like you most
folks didn't see any change. That g how
is that? So the one the one thing with
all the data about reducing duration of
the cough didn't seem to actually affect
the cough. Right. Right. So zinc's been
proven to reduce the duration of the
common cold, but not necessarily the
severity of the symptoms. All right. So
that that in mind, I might actually want
to take zinc plus something else.
Correct. Theoretically. Yeah. So what do
you look for when you're buying a cough
drop? So I always tell my patients to
try and find a cough drop that's low in
sugar, corn syrup, artificial
sweeteners. So keep track of this stuff.
Don't go for the head fake. Get stuff
that's relatively pure. But if you
really want to take it to the next
level, you probably want some at home
solutions. So, up next, we're going to
give you those at home solutions that'll
get you through the cold season. Stick
around.
[Music]
[Applause]
The doctor and nurse charged with murder
of their own son. I forgot how to do
CPR. All new Oz. That's coming up
tomorrow.
[Music]
[Applause]
We've been investigating the truth about
cough drops and now I'm revealing the
atome cold relief solutions that really
work. My go-to tester is back to try
them out. Thank goodness I don't have
to. The first at home solution, it's
pineapple tea to relieve your sore
throat. Now, you all know I love tea
with honey, right? Honey is the oldest
medicine around there, but pineapple,
they might help your cold as well. You
think you might be able to put pineapple
and tea? Look at this. The pineapple has
bromelene in it. Bromelene, of course,
anti-inflammatory, pain reducing
properties. It also breaks down the
mucus. And adding it to your tea is a
great way to soothe your throat. Mhm. Do
you feel your throat coming alive?
Listen, I feel my health coming on.
Okay, let me
see.
Amazing.
Great. How sweet.
[Applause]
Oh, I will toast you and your amazing
grace. Indeed. Thank you so much. All
right. Now, if you're stuffed up, one of
my favorite go-to solutions is what?
Natty. Natty pond. Netty pot. Ni pot.
Why did you say it like that? Take a
look at my experience with it.
[Music]
What do you guys think? Should we do it?
Goes through your situses. It flushes
them out. And it's right. Don't move
till it comes out. And you got to hit
the You got to hit the ball. Oh, you got
it. You got it. Whoa.
Oh, that feels good. Is Rebecca doing it
or not? I can't tell. Engage your
nostril. Engage your nostril with the
tip of this thing. All right. You see it
coming out? Look what came out of her
nose. See the stuff floating around in
there? I know it looks crazy, but it
really works.
Oh, I like this. Oh, don't lie. I like
it. It feels good.
So, the old fashioned pot. One of the
oldest solutions known to man. Actually
2,000 years old probably medicine
experts are using this. But I've seen
lines. That's why it's important right
kind of water. Use the netti. A woman
used water in her ny pot just all
regular tap which of course sometimes
can cause problem cause a deadly brain
infection and while doctor it's very
rare you got to distill the
water or purify it or boil the thing for
3 to five minutes you just got to really
get it clean you got to put it up near
your brain the top of your nose touches
your brain so make sure the stuff is
clean but it does work for and it will
continue to work and I personally like
it a lot you can find all these
solutions at dr.com to get the changes
is happening. Our journey is just
beginning.
[Music]