Dog attacks caught on tape.
>> I could see him ripping my arm and I
could see the blood on his face
>> and how a simple paper cut almost turned
deadly.
>> It was a flesh eating bacteria eating
through all of the tissue.
>> Plus, Rev Run and his wife Justine open
up about their biggest relationship
battles. Does he have anything he does
that tests your faith?
>> Coming up next.
season 11 starts now.
[Music]
Today's show contains content meant for
mature audiences. Some of our discussion
may be inappropriate for teens and young
children.
>> We love dogs on this show. I always look
forward to playing with my dog, Khesi.
But what happens when a man's best
friend bites back? That's the question
today. Four and a half million dogs are
biting people and they occur every year
in this country. That's roughly one out
of 70 people being attacked. And many of
these attacks are caught on tape, giving
us insight into those terrifying moments
when a canine goes on the attack. Take a
look.
Not all dogs come with a warning sign.
It can take seconds for canines to go
from cuddly to attack mode.
[Applause]
These dogs were not afraid to go
head-to-head with the authorities as
they ripped off the bumper and chunks of
the tires in an apparent fit of road
rage.
>> In Minnesota, a woman was knocked down
and bit by a dog while taking out her
garbage. Grab it. Grab it.
>> Some dog bites can be fatal. There have
been hundreds of deaths from K9 attacks
in recent years. Terrifying surveillance
video captured a woman getting attacked
by a pack of dogs on her front lawn. And
what about a dog in your own home? This
woman was violently attacked by a dog in
her own living room, leaving her with
stitches, scars, and a harrowing
question. What caused this aggressive
outburst?
>> Sabrina, who you just saw on the tape,
joins me now. Thank goodness you're
okay.
>> Thanks.
>> You're a dog lover. I am.
>> And this dog that attacked you though
was not your dog. How did you come in
contact with it?
>> No, I was driving around in my
neighborhood and like I said, I'm a big
dog lover. So, I saw this dog and the
second time I saw him, I stopped and it
took a little bit to coersse him into my
car, but I got him and I took him home
and I gave him a bath and the next
morning I went to see if he was chipped.
Took him to my vets's office and he was.
So, I found the guy on Facebook and he
had moved to Peru and left his dog with
a friend and he ended up on the street
and that's how that's how I came with
him.
>> So, you you agreed to keep the dog in
your home, you made it a part of your
family, you slept in the same bed, all
the things that an owner does with their
pet.
>> When did the behavior begin to shift? So
after um about a month uh it was a
Thursday and when I wasn't home that day
my cat got out and my dad came home and
he had killed the cat.
He had killed the cat and that's very
tough and it's very hard to speak about
and that's the guilt that I deal with
today. But um I called the owner and I
said, "I need you to have someone come
pick him up." And he said, "Wait till
Monday." And this was a Thursday. And
then
>> I I got attacked on Saturday.
>> What prompted that attack?
>> So I was in my living room. We were all
in the living room and him and my 15
pound pickies got in a scuffle and it
was right next to me. But I knew this
dog was going to kill my dog. He was 90
pounds. Yeah,
>> he was 90 lb and he was going to kill my
pickies. So, I was right there and I was
trying to separate them, doing
everything I could and the dog changed
in a snap and I became his target.
>> You can see in this video that the dog
locked his teeth in Sabrina's arms, was
not letting go, dragging you around.
What was going through your mind while
he's attacking you like this?
>> You know, you almost kind of don't
realize it's happening.
I
it sounds crazy, but in my mind I was
thinking that he'll bite me and then let
go. Like it was just something quick.
>> But after a couple seconds I could see
him ripping my arm and I could see the
blood on his face.
>> Your blood?
>> My my blood on his face. And he was
trying before all before he locked on my
arm, he was trying to bite everywhere.
So, he took a chunk out of the out of my
leg.
>> Oh my goodness. I can see
>> he took a chunk out of my leg. And
>> this is actually This is a graft.
>> No, this is the graft.
>> Oh,
>> yeah.
>> Yes. This is skin from my thigh. And he
ripped it all apart. He took a chunk out
of here. I didn't even know he had taken
a chunk out of my leg.
But um when he was on my arm, I started
punching him, trying to get him off of
me, screaming, trying to get him off of
me. But of course, he just saw red.
>> That's the wound that the dog made right
after.
>> Yes,
>> they treated it. These are these are I'm
sorry. Gruesome. The show
>> that that picture is actually even like
not as there was worse worse. It was all
open and
>> really I can't even look at them.
They're so bad. I I I I didn't want to
use them for our audience either because
they are too gruesome. At least these
images I hope will share how severe this
is without becoming too grotesque for
the person watching to pay attention.
But I want to point it out because the
dog bit and does not like dog bites and
tears off.
>> Tears as he's as he has his jaw locked
on me, he's moving his head around just
like you know I became the prey. So
>> how did you get this dog off you? It
would have killed you. Okay. So, my dad
was home at the time, but he was outside
mowing the grass. He could not hear me
screaming. So, he was right outside when
I opened the door. He grabbed a broom,
started hitting him. He let go, but then
I ran
>> the broom. Look at this.
>> I ran in. Yeah. So, I ran back inside
and he um
and then the dog stays coming after me.
He was he was obsessed with just
attacking me.
>> Oh my goodness. And um next thing I knew
the ambulance was there, but they
couldn't get to me because they had to
go through the front door.
>> The dog's there.
>> And the dog is there. So I So I crawled
through the window because there was no
other way they were going to get to me.
And I could have bled out. I think I'm
>> the doctor. I'll tell you, you could
have bled out that with that injury.
>> And this as well. And I didn't even
realize this was happening.
>> You didn't damage the nerves or
>> Yes. The tendons were like hanging on by
a thread
and um my doctors did amazing work and
were able to save my arm. Save my hand.
Actually, not my arm. Save my hand.
>> I understand there's a silver lining
around this tragedy.
>> There is. Um so obviously the months
after I this happened to me. It happened
to me February 9th and the months after
I was in therapy. I was bedridden and I
had to do all that all those things
because when my hand my hand was in a
splint for uh like a long time and when
it came off I couldn't do anything. This
was me trying to move my hand.
>> It's not moving, right?
>> So I couldn't do anything. I went to
therapy obviously and now and it
impacted my life. I know what it is to
not be able to do the most simplest
things, you know, take a shower, get
dressed, um put on shoes, drive. I know
what it's like to not be able to do
those things and I am now in school to
be um an occupational therapy assistant.
So,
>> so
>> yeah,
>> you can do what they did for you.
>> I can.
>> Thank you for sharing.
>> Thank you so much. Thanks for having me.
>> Up next, imagine being attacked by two
dogs at once. Both vicious. How one
woman survived a terrifying assault and
what to do if a dog turns on you. Stay
with us.
[Music]
[Applause]
We're back with dog attacks caught on
tape. My next guest was out on her
morning walk when this was caught on
tape. Two dogs coming from across the
street and began attacking her on her
own front lawn. There she is trying to
run away, right? But she fell. She fell
and they jumped on her. Rhonda, the
woman in that video, joins us now via
Zoom to tell us how she survived. Now
Ronda, we just saw these dogs. They're
charging after you out of nowhere. What
was going through your mind when that
happened?
>> I was thinking at that point, where do I
go? What do I do? And
before I could complete that process, I
was being attacked.
>> And as the dogs begin, they started on
my lower extremities. The brown dog came
all the way up to my throat. I could
literally feel his breath on me and I
could just smell it
across the street. Luckily, the
neighbor's dog came and chased them off.
I was eventually able to get up,
run back to my home, and get in the
house. But at that point, I still didn't
feel safe.
I still do not feel safe today. But what
I also know is that through this
process, I'm still committed to living
my best life because my life is honestly
and truthfully changed forever.
>> Yeah.
>> But I'm committed to living my best life
and overcoming this obstacle.
>> Good for you, Rhonda. Thank you for
joining us. Let me bring in someone who
has insight into a dog's mind. trainer
and animal behavioralist Victoria
Stillwell. Bringing my little Khesi
here.
So, you know, in your experience, what
triggers these kinds of attacks from
dogs? It's so foreign to me, but one in
70 of us. Even in my audience, I pulled
folks in a little break. It's more than
that have been bitten by a dog.
>> These kind of attacks seem to me to be
like more like predatory behavior. But
in general, dogs will bite people to
keep themselves safe because of fear,
because they're protecting resources,
because they're in pain, or for some
other medical reason.
>> Let's walk through this. Some of the
reasons that a dog come may feel
territorial. A dog may want to protect
themselves or because they're in fear
act out. Yeah. So, the first is, and
these are all pictures I want you to
memorize. This is a growling or snarling
dog.
>> Yeah. And growling and snarling, all of
these showing teeth, they are warning
behaviors. So, those are very overt
signs that we recognize. We back away.
The next one,
>> showing the teeth. Look at them in
there.
>> Showing those teeth.
>> Please don't do that.
>> And snapping.
>> You don't want teeth like that.
>> Yeah, that's like a warning sign as
well. Showing teeth. They're all telling
you back away. Back away. Back away. And
then the the snapping sometimes is also
a warning.
>> And then the rig snapping. I guess
they're not their purpose missing you,
right? They don't miss you by action.
>> Well, sometimes they do, sometimes they
don't. Sometimes they show an inhibited
bite, sometimes they miss. you get out
the way. So, but here is where the the
body language that you have to look for
is sometimes the body is very stiff, the
tail is very rigid, but you can also
have tails that wag very quickly back
and forth. There are also some signs
that are much less, I would say, well,
very subtle that a dog is uncomfortable.
There's a lip licking
>> when a dog yawns. If you go to greet a
dog, a strange dog, and the dog goes on
its back and shows you its belly, it's
not saying, "Rub my belly." It's a cut
off signal. It's saying, "Don't come
near me. Don't I don't want to have
interaction with you." And that's why a
lot of people misconrue.
>> I would think that would say come
because if Kisa did that, I'd scratch
her belly.
>> She knows you, right? So my dog loves
having her belly scratched. But if it's
a dog I don't know and I'm going up to
that dog and that dog flips over on its
back quickly, I know leave it alone.
So, what should you feel? What would you
recommend that we do if we're in a
dangerous situation with a dog?
>> It's there. We're here. How do we avoid
a problem?
>> Oh, it's really hard. Stay calm. Don't
stare at it. And try and be boring. I I
teach a lot of dog bite prevention to
children and I teach them be boring
because then you're not fueling the
fire. You're not exacerbating any kind
of anger, frustration, or predation that
the dog might have.
>> What if the dog's already attacking you?
It's already lunging at you.
>> Yeah. And this is very, very scary. So,
look, we are pre-programmed to survive.
All right? As our dogs are, we will do
what we need to do in order to survive.
We will fight. If you have a piece of
clothing you can put over the dog's
eyes, if you have a bag you can put in
between you and the dog, if he gets you
on the ground, he or she gets you on the
ground, you can roll up like a stone,
protect your neck, protect your
vulnerable parts of your body, hope that
help comes. And here's the thing. the
dog is biting you, pull the sleeve. Or
if, for example, this is the dog biting,
instead of taking your arm away, feed
your arm into the dog. Because what
happens is that when the dog's biting
and you're trying to take your arm away,
which is our instinct, it's going to rip
the skin. You put your arm and you feed
your dog into the feed your arm into the
dog's mouth, it's going to do much less
damage. But that's hard to do.
>> But it makes sense. You get puncture
wounds rather than huge pieces being
ripped off as we just saw in the earlier
segment. Remember everybody, dogs don't
want to attack. They'd rather cuddle and
play like Khisa here. But I think we're
better off with our dogs by far. And if
you know them, scratch their belly.
Otherwise, I learned something from
Victoria. Be careful. All right, we'll
be right back. Thank you.
[Music]
Up next, unbelievable health nightmares.
From paper cuts that turned into a
life-threatening emergency to a runny
nose that lasted for months. Find out
how one woman thought it was just bad
allergies. Turned out her running nose
was from fluid leaking from her brain.
We've all suffered the pain of a paper
cut. Opening an envelope, grabbing
papers too quickly, and it usually heals
within a day or two. But for one woman,
her paper cut turned into a shocking
health nightmare. Within 48 hours,
Heather's tiny cut on her pinky turned
into this. She found herself in kidney
failure, fighting for her life. What
could have caused such a little paper
cut that turned into a big health
emergency? Well, Heather joins us now
via Zoom. So, Heather, how did you first
cut your pinky finger or orient us to
what was happening?
>> Hi, good morning. Um, well, we were
moving actually from one side of our
island to the other. And, um, in the
hustle and bustle, just being busy
unloading boxes, um, cleaning and
whatnot, I noticed a tiny cut in between
my, uh, ring finger and my pinky. And,
um, it started swelling. Um, I the pain
was just so bad. And then within hours
of that, I got a fever. And so they uh
diagnosed me with nefertizing fasciitis.
>> So let me show some of the photos of
what the paper cut did to your hand. So
I'm going to put a red circle here.
We're show a picture of your pinky where
the cut was.
>> And then the early stages of the flesh
eating infection are evident here. You
can see the skin's discolored. Uh and
this, you know, pretty aggressively
moving along. This happens very quickly,
by the way. And then after the surgery,
they removed the infection and they, you
know, sort of sewed you back up again,
but it was still very swollen. So,
Heather, when doctors were doing all
this and trying to save your life and
your hand, what did they say was causing
all the swelling in your hand and your
arm?
>> Um, so basically it was a flesheating
bacteria that was eating through um all
of the tissue. Um, by the time I got to
the hospital, it had already eaten all
the way through my tendons and basically
I was going into kidney failure and um,
I was really I mean if they couldn't
stop it, amputation was the first step
otherwise um, you know, they were going
to try to at least get as much of the
infection and save my arm um, and my
life.
>> Let let me show you what why you were
diagnosed with necroizing fasciitis and
what that really is. is more commonly
known as flesh-eating bacteria. And it
can start with just a scrape on, for
example, in this animation, your leg.
And in Heather's case, it was a tiny
little cut in your hands. These
bacteria, let's just say there these
green things on the surface of the skin.
There's the cut there in the blood
vessels, but the green bacteria come in
from outside and once they get in
contact with the wound, there's no
protective barrier. They just spread
out. They they create all kinds of
infection, inflammation in the
surrounding area. That's why it gets
red. And then they start to cause
closure of blood vessels, thrombosis.
And these can be devastating because
they shut off all the blood supply to
the area that's infected. That's why you
get parts of your body, your legs, feet,
your hands, arms, they start to turn
black. That's what this flesh eating
bacteria ultimately does. And ultimately
once it infects your extremities, it'll
put your entire body into a state of
shock which can cause the vital organs
like the kidneys and the heart to shut
down as you were describing. So,
Heather, you're you're not 100% you're
not sure exactly how you got this
infection, but give me your best guess.
>> Um, well, the rain water is caught uh
most times in Hawaii for bathing,
cooking,
um, uh, just washing dishes and whatnot.
We don't drink it, but there's big
catchment tanks and we catch the rain
water. And I believe that the rainwater
had bacteria in it and it just made its
direct entry through that little tiny
cut and that's what got me.
>> Can you believe that such a tiny paper
cut led to such a gargantuan health
nightmare?
>> Gosh. Um I was shocked that something so
minor would, you know, almost cause me
to lose my life. And you know, it it
just it really was something very
shocking and just happened so quickly.
But I just really I thank all the
doctors that saved my life and you know,
especially Dr. Pereira for, you know,
rehealing my hand basically.
>> Well, I'm glad you're doing well. Thanks
for sharing your story, Heather.
Whenever I get a paper cut, even if it
seems tiny, here's what I do. First off,
you wash your hands and you clean the
wound. The basics, what your mom taught
you to do. I would just rinse it with
warm soap and water. You don't have to
put lots of chemicals in there. Then dry
it thoroughly, cover it with a bandage,
and just let it be for a while. It'll
heal. Up next, another health nightmare
that will shock you. One woman discovers
the fluid running from her nose isn't
snot, but rather brain fluid that's
leaking. Stay with us.
[Music]
>> The public outrage facing rapper Ti Stan
on the controversial virginity test.
>> I think he did it out of protection.
>> It's up to you. It's your choice, your
body.
>> We are weighing in. It's a wakeup call
for the entire nation.
That's coming up Friday.
[Music]
We are back with unbelievable health
nightmares. Now, we've all had a runny
nose going through boxes of tissues due
to a cold or allergies. But what if your
nose wasn't running because of snot?
Andrea's nose was dripping for more than
seven months before she learned that it
was coming actually out of her brain. It
was brain fluid coming out of her nose.
Andre is joining us now via Zoom. So
Andre, when you first started noticing
that your nose was running, you were
told it was bad allergies, but then it
got worse. So please help everyone
understand how much fluid was actually
coming out of your nose.
>> Well, it started out dripping and then
it went to pouring out of my nose. So, I
went from tissues to paper towels and I
had to put them up my nose to because
there was just so much fluid coming out.
>> Oh my goodness. How when you went out,
what would you do? You just keep blowing
your nose.
>> No, I always had tissue in my hand and I
could kind of feel when it was going to
come out. It would kind of build up and
then I could feel it. So, I would just
quickly put a paper towel there or, you
know, try to catch it without anyone
knowing. I hit it pretty well. Did it
have a taste or a smell? What did it
feel like?
>> It just it looked like water. It was
tasteless and odorless there. You know,
there was no color to it at all. It just
looked like water.
>> And you see other symptoms then started
to turn your life upside down. So, how
did your health nightmare get even
worse?
>> Well, the whole time I had a sinus
infection. Um, so I started going to
doctors,
urgent cares, ERS to try to figure out
what was going on and they all just said
it was allergies. So I had to sleep
sitting up because if I laid flat, the
fluid would go down my throat and I
would wake up choking on it. So um, it
just it felt like I had pneumonia. My
chest was real heavy and I just I had
this horrible feeling that I was dying.
Oh my goodness. That's that's never a
good feeling to have. So, you actually
were able to find an answer. And there
are a lot of people who probably have a
story similar to yours who have no idea.
Let's meet her neurosurgeon, Dr. Michael
Lamole, who's actually the surgeon who
saved Congresswoman Gabby Gford's life
when she was shot in the head in that
horrible case in Arizona. He also
happens to be my brother-in-law. How did
you diagnose Andrea with her with her
her leak of brain fluid? Well, me after
we collected some of the fluid from her
nose, we were able to diagnose a
spontaneous cerebral spinal fluid
fistula or CSF leak.
>> And a CSF leak is when some of the
watery fluid around the brain is able to
go through a defect or a hole to escape
to the outside world, usually through
the nose or the ear.
>> So, here's the thing. These holes can be
caused by injuries. They can cause by
car accidents. They caused by surgery.
And your sister, my wife Lisa, when we
were first married, banged her head
against the stairs. Actually,
interestingly, the under foot of her
stairs when she was in, you know, under
getting something from a closet and then
she had this weird metallic taste in her
mouth for a long time. That's typical
>> typical for CSF leaks.
>> Yeah. And when she went upside down, it
would get much worse.
>> Yes.
>> Why didn't you tell us?
>> Now he's Now he's helping.
>> You couldn't help your own sister.
>> A bit more education since then.
>> All right. I want to thank Mike actually
because Mona gets really mad at me. He
protects me. Otherwise, that'd be it'd
be curtains for me. So to put this in
perspective, this is as much fluid as
our brain makes in a day roughly about
about half a liter roughly.
>> So how much would typically come out of
your nose if you were actually leaking?
>> In severe cases like Andrea's you could
literally feel the palm of your hand.
However,
>> it doesn't have to be that way. That's
what's so frustrating. Some some of
these cases are so subtle that you might
not see it right away and it could take
years to diagnose. But in Andrea's case,
in Lisa's case, you really need to meet
three conditions for this to happen. To
have a leak through your nose, you have
to have a tear in the lining of the
brain called the dura, the thick
leathery sack that surrounds the brain.
You have to have a hole in the base of
the skull. And you have to have a a
breach in the in the lining of the nose.
And when all those come together, you
have a leak. And like you said, that can
happen from tumors, from trauma, or it
can happen for no apparent reason, like
an Andrea is an idiopathic case.
>> And it'll look like this. So again, it
come right out of your nose and when
you're when you cough or sit up, it'll
it'll come out like that.
>> Right out like that. We'll actually ask
the patients to lean forward like
they're sniffing and you'll see it
literally come out dripping like that in
severe cases. And if they don't heal on
their own, like Lisa,
>> if you see this, by the way, please call
somebody. This is this is not a runny
nose from a little
>> That's not normal. And if if they don't
heal on their own, then we have to
consider surgical options like putting a
video endoscope up your nose, looking
for the hole, finding it, surgically
repairing it with our ENT colleagues.
And is that how you paired on Andrea's?
>> That's exactly what we did.
>> So, Andrea, how what did it feel like
when that that fluid was finally fixed?
It wasn't leaking anymore from your
brain.
>> Oh, I had a chronic cough. Um, I had
really bad chest pain. I was exhausted.
Um, and really dizzy, you know, kind of
in a fog and I had a lot of sinus
pressure. So, once it was fixed, it was
like night and day.
>> Oh my goodness.
>> Night and day. And Michael, if you
hadn't gotten Andre in time, what could
have happened? Because you're not
supposed to have a breach in the most
precious part of the body, the area
around your brain.
>> And and and the symptoms she had were
were dead on. The brain needs to be
bathed in this fluid. Not only does it
provide nutrients and take away waste,
but it literally provides a liquid
cushion to sit on. And when you drain
too much of that, like Andrea did, the
brain sags, the lining stretches, it
gives these terrible headaches and
symptoms. But the most feared
complication is menitis. And that's when
the bacteria from the nose literally
migrate up through that defect and
inflame the lining of the brain or the
brain itself. And if untreated, in worst
case scenario, this can rapidly proceed
to death.
>> Oh my goodness. Andrew, are you feeling
okay now?
>> I'm feeling a lot better. I take it day
by day. I am on disability now because I
do have chronic migraines and chronic
facial and sinus pain. Um, as well as
anxiety following the surgery. Um, so I
have my good days, I have my bad days,
but my family and my faith keep me
going. And I'm just really thankful to
Dr. Lamole for everything he did for me.
And I'm still able to be here with my
kids and my family. And I'm just very
grateful that I'm sealed. No longer uh
have a CSF leak.
>> Sealed and healed. I'm glad it worked
out. Congratulations, AJ. Mike, thanks
very much for being with us. Thanks for
having me.
>> All right, we'll be right back.
[Music]
>> Up next, hip hop royalty are here. Red
Run and Justine Simmons open up about
faith and marriage, and they win on the
biggest battles couples face. They're
caught on tape. Will you be on team
Revron?
>> That's me. Yes, me. Or team Justine.
>> That's me.
>> No, it's me. We'll find out. Me?
[Applause]
Here's a music mogul and a minister.
She's a media maven and the boss behind
the scenes. And together they are hip
hop royalty. Revron and Justine Sibs are
here. They open up about their marriage
and the power of faith and how they
healed from a health emergency they
never thought would happen to them. Come
on out my good friends Rev Run and
Justine Simmons.
[Applause]
Boom.
>> I want to do burger.
>> Burger fries. One more time. Burger
fries.
>> All right.
>> I love you, trusty.
>> You're in the middle, right? Okay. I'll
go.
>> I love this. He's He's producing
directors. Make sure the ladies first.
Well, thank you very much. You know,
before we came out, I you were talking
about how to greet each other, right? Of
course, people who are affectionate
towards each other want to hug and kiss
and but I like this burger fries idea.
>> It's got a little something going there.
It works.
>> I just did the elbow quick bump.
>> Elbow's so easy. You don't hurt your
hand that way. Yeah.
>> When guys fist bump, it can be painful.
You can
>> Yeah.
>> I'm always encouraged by folks of uh
faith and I saw this wonderful quote on
Instagram. God has a bigger plan for me
than I have for myself. Rev. You posted
that. What inspired you? Um, just
thinking about everything that was going
on around me, what's next? How do I
handle the kids? What's going I'm going
going to do the career? We did the
Grammys, all these different things that
are coming at me. And I wanted to know,
okay, what's next? How do I? And I had
to take I out of it and says, he has a
bigger plan for me than I have for
myself. That also encourages you.
>> Yeah.
>> You start to think, you know, okay, I
want to do this, I want to do that, I'd
like to do this. But what about the
times where you let go and then it comes
out better than you thought it would?
>> So faith is a big part of marriage. So
I'm going to test your faith in Rev.
Does he have anything he does that tests
your faith?
>> Oh,
>> I want to hear the truth here.
>> The nitty-gritty cuz when you live in in
in the same place, it's not always in
harmony.
>> Exactly. So Dr. Oz, he has this thing
where and why would you do this? Take
off your robe.
>> Put it on the floor. What?
>> Who really a man of faith?
>> You got to listen to the whispers so you
don't have to hear the screams. So
>> yeah,
>> first it's like
>> I say, Joey, don't put your robe on the
floor, babe.
>> And if I don't listen, then what
happens?
>> I go, Joey.
>> That's the scream. That's the scream.
You got to in order to have a marriage,
you have to listen to the whispers so
you don't have to hear us screaming
about the robe.
>> So part of the reason I wanted to have
you guys on, they have a a wonderful new
book. It's called Old School Love.
>> Yes. What does that mean, Rev? Old
school means love is a grownup thing.
Grown folks business, I like to say.
>> Old school opening car doors. Old school
>> holding hands.
>> Holding hands. Old school being
courteous before the divorce rate was
crazy. So, I believe that biblical
principles that are in this book and
some of the ways that we describe them
will work. Like, don't go to bed angry.
People think that's cliche.
>> Yeah, I used to. But that's a scripture
>> because the more we've we found out the
more you can be angry at somebody, the
more you can stay angry. So that one day
itself.
>> Exactly.
>> That's an old school principle.
>> How can two how can two walk together
unless they agree?
>> So that means and that's in the Bible.
That means that love is not so much
looking in each other's eyes, but it's
looking in the same direction. Oh, I
love that.
>> Yeah,
>> I love that. Not looking in your eyes so
much, but looking forward the same
direction. And if you get on the same
page, you'll have a great marriage.
>> So, you've had challenges in your lives.
And a lot of times, people are pulled
apart by the challenges. You lost a
child.
>> Yes.
>> Which is the most painful thing that I
think any couple can experience. You
lost a daughter a few hours after she
was born.
>> That's heavy.
>> And you said that that you felt lonely
for the child.
>> Yeah.
>> For a while.
>> Um, well, believe it or not, Dr. Oz
before I we decided to have a baby, I
went to Joey and said, "Do you want to
adopt?" And then he said he prayed for
wisdom and God made him reminded me the
first thing she wanted to do was adopt.
So when I went back to her when she got
home from the hospital and said, "Babe,
let's adopt." What happened?
>> Literally, all the pain went away.
>> A lot of couples see their marriages
dissolve in front of them with that kind
of adversity. You think you're cursed
instead of realizing there's some deeper
wisdom there.
>> It reminds me of a basketball team. If
they start arguing within, the team
falls apart. We've never considered when
stressful situations come, doctor, when
things are bothering us or things that
to fight each other.
>> We're always like sitting together
trying to fight the opposition, the
thing that's coming at our marriage. So
that's in all facets of life, not just
in this particular situation, but in
every situation that comes at us.
>> We're the team.
>> If I'm stressed, like, "Oh god, thank
God I got Justine as a wife."
>> See, my wife learned martial arts so she
could express herself to me differently.
>> Well, you don't want to get in the
middle of a karate chop.
>> No, it happens. Believe me. All right.
Up next, Revon Justine can break down
some of the biggest battles that couples
are facing. And guess what? We caught
them all on tape, so you don't want to
miss it.
[Applause]
[Music]
We are back with Rev Run and Justine
Simmons and we're about to reveal the
biggest battles couples face caught on
tape. Let's take a look at a first
couple who volunteered.
>> So, I came home the other day and I
overheard Nicole on the phone. So, try
not to make too much noise till I heard
my name. So I listen a little closer and
this girl is in there talking about us,
talking bad about us, talking about me.
Girl got the nerve to call me cheap. So
I had to do a little investigation, you
know, for my own personal information. I
went in her phone and I found all these
text messages. I could not believe.
>> He couldn't believe it. But he's here.
David and his girlfriend Nicole are
joining us. How did Nicole talking about
you behind your back affect your
relationship?
>> Uh, it it annoyed me. It makes me very
uncomfortable. It puts a lot of pressure
on me, as a matter of fact.
>> So, you actually mentioned the text. I'm
I'm going to show them with the
audience. Is that okay,
>> everybody? All right. So, here it is.
>> You did it.
>> She She texted he did that thing again.
Insert eye roll here. And then Nicole
went on to say something that's a bit
more provocative. I think I should say
something. The groups and coupons are
not the wave. It kind of aggravating me.
>> Really? Yeah.
>> So, Nicole, why do you turn to your
friends talk about things that are
bothering you in your relationship?
>> I mean, I talk to my close girlfriends
because I just want a safe space. I'm
thinking it's private. I just want to
vent. I don't want to hurt his feelings.
I just want to get it off my chest.
>> Was he like this when you met him?
>> Keep it real.
>> I didn't I didn't
>> notice.
>> Quite No. No.
>> I didn't quite notice so much. There may
have been a little
>> coupon came later.
>> Yeah,
>> they started coupon snipping later.
>> No, I were you like that when she
>> Were you always frugal?
>> I I always have a plan.
>> Okay.
>> I always I keep things a certain way. I
like to keep orderly and if if this is
the way that works best, I I see no
reason to.
>> Right.
>> That's one thing, Dr. Uh we have to
realize when we're in that dating stage,
if that's a red flag for for you, then
you just move on. You know, a lot of a
lot of times we just want to, you know,
okay, hope it away. Yeah. Hope it away.
>> So now you you have to meet him halfway
with this.
>> Nicole, I gotta say, yeah, the most
important thing that I've heard this
wonderful couple share and it's I in my
marriage as well, you better be clear
and honest about it because if you hold
your feelings now, you're just hurting
David.
>> Absolutely. We got some things to talk
about. We will.
>> All right. Now, you guys stick around
because you want to hear this next story
as well. This is our next couple's
battle. Someone in our audience is about
to get surprised by what was caught on
tape.
>> My boyfriend Roman and I made this pack
to get into incredible shape together.
We're an awesome couple. We motivate
each other. He's got an incredible body.
We just want to do this together. No
chips, no cookies, no carbs. So, we made
a pack. Let's do this together. Well, I
feel a little betrayed right now cuz I
just found some little secrets hidden in
Roman's truck. Chips.
Chips.
Chips. More chips. This chipaholic is
going to send me into a carb coma. I am
so upset right now.
>> Robot, you look like a gazelle. But
>> did he notice coming?
>> No. Are those chips yours?
>> No.
>> Who Who are you hiding those chips from?
The dogs? I saw them back there playing.
>> Yeah, I guess they gave me up. Uh, yeah.
Yes, they're mine.
>> They're yours.
>> What kids? Why Why does it bother you so
much to have the chips in the
>> Because we're supposed to be doing this
together as a team and getting in shape
together and I want him to motivate me
and
>> how's he going to do that if he's
sneaking junk food behind my back?
>> That seems pretty innocent, but let's
just talk about this. How since
something as seemingly minor as hiding
things from each other turn into
something much more important?
>> Let's ask Rev about that.
Well,
>> I have M&M's in my drawer. So, as far as
>> last night, what happened?
>> My grandson, I told him, I said, "I got
some M&M's for you." She said, "No, you
don't." I said, "Yes, I do." And I kind
of busted myself. So, the keeping
secrets,
>> I'm not that good at really helping this
couple because I'm him, you know?
Right.
>> So,
>> but
if it on on a on a true level, on a real
level, not just on the cookies and chips
level, which I I'm guilty of. Um, hiding
situations from each other is not
healthy. I mean, I do let her know like
she'll if if I'm eating something that's
wrong, I'm not really hiding that much
of it. I'll just do it in her face cuz
she's been off carbs for a minute and
she's like, "You're eating extra carbs
now. Everything's pizza and cake." Dr.
Oz,
>> at least I'm doing it in a face.
>> No, Dr. Oz, I can't have carbs.
>> But that you made that up, Lisa. We
wasn't in it together like that.
>> I didn't say I'm off carbs. I'm
listening.
>> You're not helping them. No, they're
learning from this. This is
intervention. You were the actual
intervention here.
>> He He He did He's not on carbs. But why
do the dessert all the time now? You
understand? He didn't do that before.
>> Yeah. Why was the dessert now?
>> I don't know. I think as she got rid of
carbs out of her diet, I just got a
sweet tooth out of nowhere. I don't
know.
So, but at least I'm not hiding it.
We're at dinner. I'm like, "Give me the
lava flow."
>> But if I say, "Okay, now he said, give
me the lava flow." Dr.
>> And I said,
>> he's going to help us. And so I said to
him, well, I I don't want anything. So
he, that's when he was like told the
lady, "Come on over." So then when it
came I said, "hm" like I was going to
>> and I was like, "Oh, you're off."
>> And then no, wait. Yeah. He reminds me
and I said, "Yeah, but I might want
something." He said, "You know what,
Jess? I'm not going to get nothing."
>> Oh, so it helped.
>> You see what I'm saying?
>> So you pulled me toward you
>> by saying no.
>> Yeah, but you just didn't want me.
>> Did we answer that question?
>> Sorry.
>> Okay.
>> You know what? I think you just did
fine. I love you both, dearly. I hope
that was helpful for you. Thanks for
being with us.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Listen, there's a lot more of this of
this in their wonderful new book, Old
School Love, as always wonderfully done
by this beautiful couple. And guess
what? You're all going home with a copy.
>> You get a copy. You get a copy. That
That'll really help you. We'll be right
back.
[Music]
[Applause]
>> Here's the question for everyone in the
audience. I want home. Think about this.
What kind of a chicken wing eater are
you? Are you a one? Right. Where I don't
know, took a little bite, didn't like
it. I guess threes, middle of the road.
Are you a five? Where you know it's just
the bone barely. Audience, which of the
choices are you? Let me see you. We got
ones, threes, fours, fives.
You're a one.
>> Really? A one?
>> A one.
>> You don't like the
>> I really don't eat them.
>> You don't eat them.
>> No.
>> All right. So, what do you think of
people who are ones?
>> Like the lady like the lady behind you.
>> They obviously don't like chicken wings.
>> There's a one over here. You don't like
them either?
>> I like chicken, but not the bone.
>> Not the bone. All right. Ones.
>> I'm a one.
>> Just one bite and let it go.
>> One bite. Yep. That's it.
>> I got to say, the food quiz has elicited
hilarious reactions from social media.
Christy Tegan tweeted, "I don't invite
ones or twos back to my house." Right.
Even my daughter knows better. She says,
and I have to say, when I indulge in
wings, I would never be a one. I got to
eat everything. Just get to the five. If
you like them, you like them, right? Am
I right? Where are the fives here? All
right. So, Annayia is a five, right? And
she's joining us here. She's going to
show us a technique for achieving
fivedom. Are you all ready to watch for
the ones out there? All right. Let me
see how you do it.
>> Wait, first, did he say five? That's
hilarious. Sorry.
>> Five. Five.
>> So, you have to dip it first, Dr. Oz.
>> Of course. Everyone, please.
>> And then you
work your way around.
>> Mhm. M you take your time.
>> Take your time
>> cuz you have to savor the moment. You
can't do too fast cuz then you don't
taste it.
>> And when you're done, it's just the
bone.
>> Just the bone.
>> But from the end, you're eating it.
>> Why waste time? Oh my. It's almost over.
It's a four already.
>> I'm a I'm a Caribbean woman. Sorry. And
I tell people all the time, I thought
this was the norm around the world. But
to see the one
>> Well, we got fours and threes around
you, so you're safe. You keep your one.
The power of change lies in the power of
you. Just one person, one voice speaking
the truth and you can all be fives.
There it goes.
>> There it is.
>> Goodbye everybody.
[Music]