[Music]
It's backyard burger season. Turkey,
chicken, and veggie burgers. You're
probably not getting the nutrition that
you think you are, but what's really the
healthiest option? You think veggie
burger has to have veggies in them,
right? And the ultimate Oz approved beef
burger. This is a cookout classic. Plus,
online memory boosters. What's really in
these pills? Are they helpful or
harmful? Coming up next.
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
[Music]
I love you, Da.
[Applause]
Today, an investigation into the hottest
debate about one of America's most
beloved and classic foods, burgers. We
all adore them, right? That's right.
Applaud them. Is there really a better
backyard burger? That's our question
today. And we listen. We got the beef,
we got the turkey, there's chicken,
there's veggie, right? Which one should
you be eating? We're revealing what's
really in the store-bought burger
patties that you're grilling and how to
find the perfect mouthwatering burger
that even a heart surgeon like me would
crave. Nutritionist Kellyanne Patruchi
and butcher Justin DeMarco have been
experimenting, you can see it right
there, with burgers in their own
backyards. And we had them buy, cook,
and taste all kinds of supermarket
burgers out there. Let's start with
Kellyanne's experiment with turkey
burgers.
Hey there. I'm out here grilling up some
turkey burgers. You know what? A lot of
people think turkey burgers are the
healthiest option when shopping for
burgers in the supermarket, but if you
buy fresh, and even if you buy frozen,
that may not be the case. These turkey
burgers may not be as lean and as mean
as you think. So, depending on the cut
or the type of meat, these turkey
burgers may actually have as much fat in
them as regular beef burgers. But now,
my real question is, why? Why? Why? Why?
Our turkey burgers so dry. Well, I am
gonna get to the bottom of that.
All right, Justinian are here in studio.
Just you looked into frozen turkey
burger patties. What did you find? As a
butcher, tell me the truth. Okay, so
what I found was that turkey burgers,
unless said otherwise on the label.
Majority of the ingredients are the
tenderloin, the thighs, and the breast.
What I also found in some cases was they
would add skin and fat to them. So, and
dark meat actually. So, what would
happen with that? it was an increase of
fat. In most cases, you would think that
would add to the flavor, but not
necessarily. So, so what they typically
do is they add dextrose, brown sugar to
try and beef up that burger flavor in
the turkey. You found another key
ingredient, Kelly, and I was concerning
because I thought it was just regular
old turkey. We all do. We all do. But
here's the thing. You could actually
have salt, sodium, and up to 900 grams
of this stuff. So, that's a lot. So, I
want everyone to put this in
perspective. That's like you go to a
fast food restaurant and you order four
mediumsiz fries. Okay. So, you can
imagine that's going to make you retain
a lot of water or could make you retain
water and that's going to make you feel
and look bloated, which doesn't make
good for a date night. That's right. It
is the worst thing for date night. But
is the purpose of the salt to increase
flavor as Justin points out that they
need to do something to beef it up, so
to speak. Well, perhaps that's one of
the the things that they can do and
there's but there's other ways that they
can do that. So, if they add some
spices, that's great, but salt is is
just not good. So, what do you look for
in the label? And then you give me a
hack to make it taste better. So, what
you want to look for is 90% lean white
turkey meat. That's the thing. And I
also look for organic because then I
don't have to worry about antibiotics.
It just kind of takes that off the
table. And if they add some spices in
there like rosemary or salt or something
like that, great. And they're in there.
I got to say my biggest concern with
turkey burgers is sometimes I mean they
get dry, right? Is that the big problem?
You're chewing on cardboard after a
while. But you got a hack. What do you
recommend? All right. So, Dr. Oz,
Kellyanne over here gave me a little bit
of information about you. And that
information was 2% Greek yogurt. Okay.
So, one pound of turkey chop meat. We're
going to do half a cup of Greek yogurt,
a little bit of bread. What that does,
it binds a burger together. And so, your
end result is a nice juicy flavorful
turkey burger. Cook it the same way.
Absolutely. Great idea. Next up, we
asked Justin to do a cookout experiment
with chicken burger patties. Take a
look. Hey, Dr. Oz. Justin from the Chop
Shop here with your chicken burger
experiment. If you see in front of me,
I've got two chicken burgers here, a
frozen and a fresh. Now, you asked me to
deconstruct these burgers to find out
what actually goes into them. Now, just
like turkey burgers, chicken burgers can
be made with different parts of the
chicken. They can have natural flavors
and even sugar added to them. Now, on
the other hand, have you ever had any
problems with your burgers sticking to
the grill? I got a surefire hack to help
you with that. First
thing, nice onion. Second thing, fork,
nice hot grill. Place it down. Couple
rubs. Grab your favorite chicken burger,
beef burger.
There you go. A non-stick burger. Dr.
Oz, that's your chicken burger
experiment. That is such a good hack,
Justin. It's so simple, right? Sure is.
Sure is. And the black gloves look like
a mortician, by the way. Well, it's kind
of my my my emmo. Oh, it is. I have
purple ones for you if you want. All
right, I'll grab you. When you looked at
the ingredient list, what surprised you
about these? Well, it actually surprised
me a lot, but in a good way because the
nutritional profile is really solid.
You've got about 150 to about 210
calories. That's great. And the protein
about 14 to about 25 grams of protein.
So that's a really good balance. That's
fantastic. Yeah. And Justin, what do you
look for when you're buying in the store
to make sure you get a tasty burger? So
what you do want to look for is
obviously the primary ingredient that
the first ingredient would be chicken,
which would you assume? The rule of
thumb, by the way, if the first word in
the label is not the first word in the
ingredient list, you got a problem.
Correct. So it's chicken. There should
be chicken and chicken. And then even
after that, it would be the chicken
obviously would be breast or thigh. And
then after that, you don't want to have
any other really ingredients such as
preservatives or salts or like Kellyanne
said, you want to add that stuff after.
And a big thing for me is is to have a
chicken burger that's made with chicken
that was raised without antibiotics.
Okay. So, you're both on the same page
now. Absolutely. All right. Next up,
veggie burgers. These are growing in
popularity. Now, to be fair, there's
some health issues to talk about, but
there's also some taste problems b with
burgers. So, I'm going to do a live
taste test right here on the set with a
butcher. Justin start eating away. I
want honest opinion from you. compare it
to actually don't compare it to a
regular burger. Tell me if it's good
enough on its own. Kellyanne, what did
you uncover about how many veggies are
actually in the burgers? Well, here's
what's interesting because you think
veggie burger it has to have veggies in
them, right? Well, a lot of the
companies do. They have things like
mushroom and they have kale and they
have beans and it's it's great. But then
a lot of the companies, believe it or
not, it wasn't until about the fourth
ingredient that veggies even showed up
in any natural form. What they did
instead was the first ingredient often
times was water. And then you get into
like soy protein isolate, soy protein
concentrate and processed proteins.
Yeah, it's processed protein. So if you
think you're getting something like
edetomame, you think you're getting
something like soy, but in fact you're
not. And while I'm not saying these are
dangerous, what I am saying is you're
probably not getting the nutrition that
you think you are. Well, speaking of
that, how does it stack up in nutrition
compared to what we've been talking
about to a beef burger, for example?
Okay, so let's start with a beef burger.
Start with the protein because we all
know that in a beef burger, we always
look to the protein. You're going to
find about 22 grams of protein in a beef
burger. In a veggie burger, you're going
to find about four to about 23 grams of
protein in there. Four to 20. It's a
huge It's a huge spread. So, here's what
you do. So, if you're thinking, you
know, I really want this veggie burger,
but there's not enough protein for me.
You want to pair it up. So, a lot of
times you'll pair it up with maybe a
side of beans or you do what I do, which
is you put an egg sunny side up. You
crack an egg over that and that works
really nicely. And then so we look at
the calories. So the calories in a beef
burger, you're going to run into about
350 calories for a beef burger. And for
about a veggie burger, it's about 100.
So better on calories. Actually, better
on calories. We can hack the protein.
It's good on the calories. Yeah. Okay.
Now the big question because the
audience generally thinks about veggie
burgers and say why bother at that
point. What do you think about the
veggie burger? Uh coming from a beef
perspective, it lacks a little bit of
flavor. Okay. But it's a good
alternative. If you want a healthier,
you know, kind of meal. It was a little
bit dry. A little dry. It was a little
dry. I could have added yogurt and
bread. You can you could you with this
you would add a condiment to it and
obviously a healthier one if you could.
But as far as you know, for my palette,
it was a little bit dry. Killjoy. Kill
joy. It's just not worth it. Would I say
I was I was trying to tempt you to say
this, but I'm going to say it myself.
Don't compare a veggie burger to a beef
burger. They're not supposed to be the
same thing. They taste different. Polar
opposite. Yeah. So, if you can get used
to it, is does it taste good enough on
its own is the question you should be
asking yourself. If you didn't have any
beef burgers in the universe, would you
be accepting of a big I would accept it?
Absolutely. There we go. Now we talking.
All right. Nutrition. Give me a list
down. What should you be looking for
when you're buying a veggie burger? So,
when you're looking The first thing I
want everyone to realize is that you may
think that you're looking or getting a
healthier option. You're not. Actually,
these are supposed to be eaten in
moderation. So, keep that in mind. You
want to look for USDA certified organic.
The calories you want to run at stay at
about 200 or or even below. And with
veggie burgers, you can get a little bit
of fiber. So, you want to look for about
six grams of fiber. All right. So, up
next, the investigation into backyard
burgers continues with the ultimate Oz
approved beef burger that everyone's
craving for for their summer cookout.
We're going to find out how you can save
calories and still be satisfied. Even
Justin the Butcher will be happy with
every bite. Stick around.
[Applause]
[Music]
We're back with our backyard burger
investigation. We just talked about
turkey and then chicken and we did
veggie burgers, but now it is time to
tackle the most popular and classic, the
beef burger. I know you're waiting for
it. There's nothing better than biting
into a big juicy beef burger. Even heart
surgeons love burgers once in a while.
Look at me here. This is actually true
footage. There it is. Look at the look.
Look at the eyes. They've ever seen me
so happy. Right. But there is an Oz
approved beef burger. The Sal the
Salibarios family has a summer cookout
every year and they say they're the
pickiest burger lovers. And here's what
they say are their complaints or beefs
with most burgers. I just want to taste
good meat. I don't want to wreck my diet
with just one burger. I really want a
burger which is not dry like a
cardboard.
I've got the best homemade juicy beef
burger patty right here. It's under 150
calories. Butcher Justin DeMarco is
back. Now Justin, he's a butcher. He
knows all this stuff. What kind of meat
goes into a good burger? This stuff
behind the scenes that we don't all see.
Okay. Okay. So, there's one thing that I
know about and it's burgers. Okay. So,
my inputs start with ribeye skirt steak
which lend themselves to being more of a
fattier kind of meat. Tastes good. in
sirloin and chuck. And as you can see
here, these have less fat. So what you
do is to combine all these wonderful
meats together. Set them through the
grinder. We'll add a couple more pieces
here. Give a little push on it. And as
you can see, some of that meat's coming
right out. And there you go. You have a
fresh burger. All right. So it looks
like this. The typical size of burger
should be what? Trends have gone from 8
ounces and now have decreased down to
like four to 6 ounces. And I think it
has to do with, you know, the
cholesterol and the fat and that's in
these burgers. It tastes so darn good.
It's good enough. But you don't need
four scoops of ice cream. One or two
scoops can most of us can be okay with.
After that, hedonism. All right. How
about the pre-formed patties that we see
everywhere? Now, these are Yeah, these
are they're fresh, but they're frozen.
Correct. So, there's two there's two
kinds. There's a fresh burger patty and
a frozen. If you have to buy a frozen
burger, obviously you want to look for a
burger that has beef as your primary
ingredient. Anything after that, any
preservatives or salts or or artificial
flavorings, it's just not the best
thing. And how about the these
pre-formed fresh? Are they okay? Same
thing. Obviously, beef is a primary
ingredient. You want to look for a
burger that's 4 to 6 ounces. And also
not so pressed. If the burger is
pressed, when you put it on the grill,
it tends to release a lot of the
flavors. And the sell by date. Sell by
date is 3 days prior and then a day or
two after purchasing them is the best
time to use them. All right, come on
over here. We have a cook, a studio
cookout ready for the ultimate beef
burger reveal. The Caliberios family is
here. They consider themselves the
piggiest burger lovers. You heard them
earlier. Remember, beef burgers are not
a daily food. But if you're going to
indulge, I want you to choose Wisy. So,
it is time for the big moment. Ready?
Drum roll,
please. For the first time ever, I
present the ground beef and chopped
mushroom mashup burger. Please. The
Salario family is eating tasty. Please
give us get a start here. We're going to
see what they think. They're the
experts. Justin, first off, why would
you com combine mushrooms and beef?
Well, one, it's a good binder. And like
a lot of mushrooms, for example, the
porttoella has a meteor kind of flavor.
So combining the two and the moisture
from the from the mushroom really makes
for a nice flavorful hamburger. Let's
talk about beef for a second, everybody.
Right. You ought to be buying the
perfect beef burger ingredients, right?
Make sure it's 100% grass-fed ground
organic beef. That's what you want. I
like the ground chuck. It's got about 15
20% fat compared to 25 to 30% in regular
ground beef. That's a good balance,
guys, between flavor and fat if you do
that. So, how do you make the mashup?
How do you bring the mushrooms and marry
them into the beef? It's super easy.
It's like making peanut butter and
jelly, right? You take a nice pound of
chop meat, dice up some nice mushrooms,
whatever you like, and then you add some
nice herbs. You could do some margarm,
you could do some some rosemary, garlic,
and there you go. Nice flavorful burger.
So, before I get your opinion on taste,
let me give you the numbers. A regular
beef burger like like Well, not like
this one, like the one you would
normally would have gotten about 350
calories. Okay. Lot of calories. It's
good. Tastes great, but a lot of
calories. The ground beef and mushroom
mashup burger that we revealed today has
a total of 147 calories, less than half.
Let's see what the Salario family thinks
of the taste. Will it live up to their
beef burger expectations? So, take it
away. Let's get the kids in there first.
What do you guys think? Oh, Mr. Dr. H.
Sorry, Dr. Okay, Mr. Doctor's fine. It
is so good. It's not It's not dry. It's
not dry like a piece of cardboard. And
it's not hard like a p like a hockey
puck. It cuz I just get I just grew
these teeth.
You have passed. You have passed my
flavor test. It's I passed a girl. Look
at that one. Never mind. I like that.
What do you think? I mean, when I first
saw this burger, I was like, "This is
really appetizing." And then I tried it
and it was just went above and beyond.
It's like really seasoned well and I
really like it. I also like mushrooms.
We should go into business together. And
we got our testimonials right here. What
do you think? It It literally checks off
all my boxes to have it be healthy,
delicious, low calories. I don't have to
feel guilty about having a burger. This
is a cookout classic. No doubt. I think
you said it right. There's some taste
that belong together, right? Peanut
butter and chocolate go together. Peanut
butter and jelly go together. I couldn't
add peanut butter to to beef. Maybe we
should try that next. But mushrooms and
burgers, they go to well. We put the
recipe on dr.com. Share with your
friends. Brag about it. We'll be right
back. Stop.
Up next, the Oz lie detector about a
secret that you're all keeping. We're
going to reveal our big shapewear
experiment. Find out what happens to
your breathing when you're wearing
shapewear. Today, the ugly truth about a
secret that you're keeping about an item
that millions of you rely on every
single day, your shapewear. We are
uncovering the biggest lies we tell
ourselves about these so-called slimming
secret weapons. Could they be causing
you more harm than good? Now, think
about this. Shapewear, and it comes in
all forms, has exploded over the years,
and there's a new dirty little secret
that more and more women are keeping
about their shapewear. Joining us now,
investigative reporter Marshampo. Mara,
explain what is going on with all this
shapewear. Yeah, a lot of women now are
doubling up. They are wearing one pair
of shapewear on top of another.
Celebrities like Gail King, Kim
Kardashian, and even Beyonce admitting
to this two at a time trick to get an
extra slimming effect. I'm guilty of it
too right now. But the question
absolutely, Dr. Oz, but the question is,
what's the cost? Yeah. Who else out
there is doubling up? Let me see. Show
hands. Any other sewear secrets? Oh,
here we go. How are you? We got two two
victims right here. How are you? How you
doing? What's your first name? My name's
Christine. Christine, nice to meet you.
You You feel good the way you are now?
Yes. Well, got to tuck in a little bit.
Tilt this way. Babe, why do you double
up? Bring it home for me. Hey, if it
works for Beyonce, it works for me. It's
pretty good reason. She does look good
in those photos.
And Christie, how long you been wearing
the doubled up version of shapewear? Oh,
a couple of months. Once I found out
about it. Before it was just one and
that was it. But when I heard about
doubling up twice, I was like, that's
for me. And what does it feel like when
you're wearing it? Oh, it's
uncomfortable. It's tight. It's the
worst. But it looks good. So paint is
beauty. That's all that
matters. H h how how many hours do you
generally wear your doubled up
shapewear? Depends what I where I'm
where I'm going. But honestly, I would
say at least like 5 hours. Five hours.
All right. So here's the deal. It's
going first covered the first lie about
shapewear that the pain is worth it. It
was funny, but is it true? While
shapewear may make you look good on the
outside, we wanted to investigate the
truth about how you feel on the inside
after using the shapewear double up
method. So Mara, God bless her, did a
12-hour shapewear experiment wearing two
pairs. There's a difference, right?
There's her baseline, the two pairs. I
mean, what we uncovered might shock you.
Take a
look. Shapewear has become a way of
life, offering the hope of form fitting
us into our favorite outfits. The
promise to flatten tummies and smooth
out lumps, making us look and feel our
best. Now, some are going as far as to
wear one body shaper on top of another
one to increase the effect. Recently,
Kim Kardashian revealing she'll wear two
pairs when she feels
heavier. But is there a downside to
doubling up? To find out, I'm going to
wear two body shapers at the same time
to find out what happens throughout the
day. I just heading out for the day. Um,
definitely feels really snug. So, it's
been a few hours now and I ate breakfast
and I'm drinking tea and I've been
sitting. Now, it's really starting to
get uncomfortable. It's like digging
into my sides. I made a mistake of
getting Celzer water, which I always
get, but the bubbles are making my
stomach really hurt in this double
shapewear. They keep rolling down on the
side and it's like impossible to pull up
because they're under my clothes. I am
dying to take this shapewear off. It is
killing me. But I still have 2 hours
left in this experiment. I'm eating my
dinner standing up because it hurts to
sit down at this point. Next, I wanted
to see how wearing shapewear was
affecting my breathing. So, I'm visiting
Dr. Sandra Galbard who'll conduct a
series of lung function tests.
I'm going to have you take a really,
really, really deep breath in. You can
sit forward. Absolutely. Okay, for the
first test, I'm not wearing any
shapewear. And breathe out. 6 seconds.
Out. Out. Out. Out. Out. Out. Out. Keep
going. And breathe in. Excellent. Okay.
Then I wear two pairs of shapewear for
comparison. Let's see now that you're
wearing two body shapewear garments if
you're more restricted with your
airflow. Okay. I can tell you it
definitely feels like I can't breathe as
well. Right
now, keep going. Keep going. Keep going.
And deep breath in. Excellent.
Dr. Galbard looks over the test results
and you won't believe what she found.
All right, it's time for the results of
Mara's breath test. Dr. Sandy Gellbart
joins us now. So, we just saw you test
Mara's lungs. She breathed out for six
seconds. Yeah. The best she could
possibly do before and after with the
with the doubling up of the shapeware.
What did you find? There was more than
half a liter decrease in the amount of
air she was able to do breathe out when
she was wearing the shapewear. And this
half a liter. Yeah. Really statistically
significant. So here we have the
baseline without the shapewear. You
know, it's over three liters and the
drops under of it's a huge difference.
What's it like, Mara, seeing that? To
me, it's it's worth it. You know, the
difference is so big. It's not my chief
correspondence here. Like my partner is
telling me she'd rather give up a couple
years of healthy life to but you look
marvelous because I feel so confident in
it that you know it's worth that
sacrifice. Maybe cuz I love you so much.
I'll just show you a little
demonstration of what's happening in
your body. This maybe might compel you.
This is what you're all doing when you
put shapewear on. Right. So normally
everyone take a deep breath. Everyone do
take a deep breath in. Right. What
happens is your chest expands. Right?
The lungs fill with air when the chest
expands. But when you put the shapewear
on, right? Let's put the shapewware on
this little Oh, look at it. It squeezes
everything. Right now, it restricts your
chest expansion. Therefore, you cannot
pull air into your lungs, making it
difficult for you to breathe, right? It
makes you feel lightheaded, tired, you
get anxious. So, let's go over this
again. Mar's lung function decreased by
more than half a liter. That's a lot.
Much more than I expected, by the way.
That's beyond what you'd expect in
between a person in the morning and the
afternoon, right?
way more than you'd expect between right
we see that in situations where people
are pregnant if they have scoliosis
wherever you're restricting the chest
wall or the rib cage so this was a big
finding and that was just you just had
it on for one day for one day and I do
this regularly the next slide about
shaper I want to cover is that you guys
are always telling yourselves squeezing
into a smaller size makes you
skinnier you've admitted to me that many
people I won't mention any names have
actually used the extra slim version by
making getting a size that they couldn't
possibly fit into. It has the opposite
effect. You are Yeah. You get an intent
you intentionally get a smaller size
because it makes you even smaller. When
you wear this over time, you're actually
weakening your core muscles. So, you're
you could be making your stomach look
worse. So, the bottom line is you're not
gaming the system. You're not getting
slimmer. You're just kind of putting a
band-aid on. Can you help me with
something? Where does the flab actually
go? All right. So, that's a very good
question. You're squeezing it like like
a toothpaste tube. Where does it go?
Yeah. So you're put you're compressing
it like if you were to push your stomach
in with your hands. I'm actually getting
short of breath right now because I'm
pushing even more on this. But what ends
up happening a lot of times is that it
gets pushed up and that's where you get
that dreaded roll over. And so all day
we're basically fighting to pull this
shapewear back up because the the fat is
trying to be free. All right, time to
go. It's free at last. Free at last.
Thank god
nobody go. Interestingly, despite the
fact you're an expert in this area, you
actually wear shapewear yourself. So,
you must have some hack, some
prescription for wearing it without
causing pain or other bodily harm. Yeah.
So, the first and foremost is wear the
right size. If you're a medium, don't
grab a small. Wear it for a limited
amount of time. Don't wear it days on
end. Sleeping in it, that's going to
lead to bad results down the line. I
understand the allore of wearing these
garments, but you have to wear them the
way they were intended to be worn. If
you're going to be squeezing into a
really tight shapewear, you may look
better, but down the line, you're going
to feel worse. So, the key question that
I'm taking away from this is the right
shapewear. So, up next, the at home
test. There are two of them to detect if
your shapewear is the right size for
you. You want to see this? Thank you
very much.
[Music]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your
podcast. Today, the biggest lies you
tell yourself about shapewear. You ever
get the dreaded roll over, right? or the
indentations in your skin from trying to
squeeze into your shapewear. We're back
with the two self tests to detect if
your shapewear is right for you. Fashion
expert Denise Cowwell is here. She says
there's a science to shapewear. Why is
that? Well, unlike a blouse or a dress,
Dr. Oz, your body shaper should actually
fit tight, but sometimes people don't
know the difference between too tight
and tight enough just to do the trick.
You want it to be cinched and secure,
but not where you can't breathe or move.
So, we just uncovered the two tests to
make sure your shapewear isn't too
tight. Shapeware fanatics Teresa and
Ivana are here to try them out. Thank
you for sharing the experience with the
entire audience. You're going to judge
how these tests work on you and we'll
all learn from that. All right. The
first test, the waist twist to prevent
shapewear rollover. Explain how it's
done. So, after you put your shapewear
on, you actually just want to move to
the side. Move to the side. You can even
go to the side this way, too. But you're
twisting your body. And then if your
shapewear starts to kind of dig and cut
into your skin or if you feel like it's
rolling down or bulging just a little
bit in back, you need to go up a size.
Got it. Got to go up a size. Three, but
it's not too tight. Does it feel okay
for you guys? Mine's a little tight. It
is on the side. It's a little tight. So,
I think I would definitely have to go up
a size. Go up a size. So, we got at
least a self check. Come on over here.
Second big test is it's called the leg
check to avoid skin indentations. So
Denise, I I'll stand, you guys sit and
demonstrate and explain. Yes. So
basically ladies, we're going to sit and
we're going to cross our legs just like
ladylike if you can cross all the way
over or just to your ankles. But the
thing here is you'll feel that band. We
all know sometimes our shapewear has
that band right here. If you feel that
band start to dig into your skin or it's
even causing an indentation in your
skirt and something that you don't
really want, then you should get a
bigger size. How's your shapewear feel
with this second test? Is it digging
into your thighs? Mine's good. Mine's
good. Perfect. So, it's just the waist
part. Just the waist. So, if it's if
it's dig How about if one you pass one
but not the other? Well, they have so
many different types of shapewear. They
have them where they're shorts. They
have them a little bit longer like I was
talking about the you have you can have
some that stop right at the waist or
some that are higher up. So there's
different ones and then they have ones
with straps. So you kind of have to have
an arsenal of shapewear in your
underwear drawer. All right. So find the
ultimate shapewear buying guide on
dr.com. We'll be right
[Applause]
back. Up next, an investigation into
memory boosters and brain games being
pushed online. Can they really help
optimize your brain's cognitive
function? or is it just a big scam? Stay
tuned to find
[Music]
out. We are stopping scammers in their
tracks before they get to you and your
family. Now, whether it's a game, an
app, or a pill, everywhere you click
online, someone is trying to sell you
another memory booster, and you're
buying them. Sales are in the millions,
and they're climbing every day. But, do
brain boosters really work? And are they
safe? Trisha from our audience is here.
Thank you for playing this little game
with us. How's your memory, you think?
Not good. Not good. No, not at all. I'm
a busy mom and I'm always multitasking
and I'm trying to, you know, do grocery
shopping and just doesn't work. How many
kids do you have? I have two kids. You
sure? You remember that, right? Yes. See
how bad it is. All right. So, ready to
test your memory? Yes. All right. So, I
showed you a card before the show.
There's some pictures on the card,
right? All right. I'm going to ask you
some details about those pictures. to
see how much of the detail you remember.
Okay, first question. All right,
everyone at home, you can see the card
right now. It's in front of you, but
we're not showing it to you. Okay. All
right. What color was the flower?
Yellow. What time was the clock set to?
Oh,
3:00. 3:00. Do you remember? No, I
didn't think so.
What was the finger pointing away from?
Um, the to the right of the hamburger.
Oh my goodness. That's good. What color
was the dog? Brown.
You know what? I want to bring in the
author of the Alzheimer solution, Dr.
Ali Alisher Sarzi. Dr. Sai, come on over
here. Hi. That was pretty good. That was
really good. You did very well.
Absolutely. Now, you say memory lapses
are normal. I mean, how do we know
what's normal and how do we improve on
it? You know, memory lapses, you know, a
few of them are okay. And especially for
you, I'm a mom. I understand you have
kids. You have a lot of things to take
care of. And multitasking, you know,
there's no such thing as multitasking.
It's doing multiple things badly. Uh but
you know they're of no concern. Um the
brain is a very complex organ and
there's so many ways you can actually
make it healthier. Getting half of them
right which is what you got. Yes. That's
that's that's okay. Yes. Absolutely. And
a lot of memory is affected by focus and
attention. You know um focus is actually
the gateway to memory. And there's so
many things you can do to improve your
attention and focus. Right? So you're
going to move from knowing there's a
clock to knowing what time the clock
was. Right? Knowing there was a dog to
the right color. Okay. Thank you very
much Trisha. Pay attention. It's
important. Becca Sherzai, who is using
these online memory boosters and what do
they claim they do? A lot of people, a
lot of smart people are using these
memory boosters. Um, college students,
entrepreneurs, athletes, and a lot of
baby boomers and elderly people who are
afraid of going down the path of
cognitive decline, Alzheimer's, dementia
are using these. All right, let's get
into the investigation about whether the
memory boosters are legit or a scam.
First, we're going to look at these
memory pills. What specific pills are we
talking about? So, we're talking about
the types of pills that people can order
online, and you can find them over-
theounter at differentarmacies, in
health stores. They come in the form of
pills, capsules, syrups, etc. These are
over the counter. What's really in these
pills? And you broke it out for us here.
Right. So, I'm glad that we're
explaining all of this. It's a it's a
combination. It could be one compound or
it could be a concoction of different
things together. So, you know, they
might have vitamins like vitamin B12 or
which is the same thing as
cyanocobalamine or vitamin B5, B6, um
thamine, but they'll put all the names
there. It makes it sound legit. These
vitamins do have a role by the way, not
in everybody, but in some people. So,
there's the vitamins. And then, and then
we have chemicals. We have chemicals
like Larginine, which is a non-essential
amino acid, and it has been implicated
in many different brain diseases. Um,
and then the other category is, you
know, herbs and foods. So things like
mushrooms, you know, mushrooms are
incredible and there are extracts of
mushroom including it. We have black
pepper, we have green tea or uh coffee
extract and then different types of
foods and herbs like menthol,
ginokaloba, caffeine. You know, a lot of
these memory pills are just dressed up
caffeine pills and that's why when
people take them, they initially get a
boost of energy. They think, "Wow, I
feel really good." But you know, it can
affect you negatively in so many ways.
We know what caffeine does to our sleep
patterns and we know how important sleep
is for memory. Right? So some pour of
these some combination is used. They're
all different obviously but let's go
inside the body to see how they're
supposed to work in theory. Now these
pills are all different. We just told
you a bunch of different things that
might be in them but generally when you
look inside this is what they're
supposed to be able to do to your body
in theory. Now they say these memory
pills can help with circulation right?
So that actually changes the oxygenation
of the blood. oxidation of blood goes up
into your brain. So your brain has more
of that oxygen. Theoretically that might
be beneficial. Some also claim to change
brain waves. Now brain waves are
interesting. There are certain brain
wave frequencies. It can shift your
cognitive state, right? This can be
something that puts you in a deep sense
of calm, right? Or highly focused place.
So you can concentrate. That's like
classic caffeine effect, right? And then
when it comes to older individuals,
right, these memory pills claim to
enhance communication and cognitive
abilities, right? So, lots of things
they potentially could do. Dr. You spend
a lot of time trying to figure out what
makes sense. When you study the brain,
you learn about things that work and
don't work. Are you concerned about
these? I am, and I'm so happy that we're
talking about this. So, your best
recommendation when it comes to
purchasing memory pills online. I think
it's very important for people to be
cautious. Now, if there are specific
factors that have been studied and it's
backed up by research and your physician
or doctor recommends it, then go for it.
But you have to be careful because a lot
of them have, you know, um compounds or
things that haven't really been studied.
They even found trace heavy metals in
some of these uh memory pills, you know,
and they could be very dangerous and
people actually can suffer from the side
effects of these uh compounds, you know,
having things like gall stone,
pancreatitis, kidney stones, etc. So, be
very very careful. If you're thinking
about pursing memory pills, you want to
look for the ingredients Hupersia or
Bakopa. Those two have been found to aid
in brain function to some degree. So at
least don't waste your money. Next, we
investigated games to help the brain
because these brain games have gotten
super popular. This, by the way, is what
it looks like when I talk to my kids. I
see the tops of their heads. So I see
the top head, top head, top head. How
many of you are you all living the same
life I am? So there's been a surge of
recent brain training apps that have
gone out there. They're all over the
place. Every smartphone user out there
uh has brain training games. The
question is do they have any real
cognitive benefit? So there are some
brain gains and they have been studied
and they have been able to show
scientists have been able to show that
participating in those brain games can
be helpful. But then on the same side
there's a lot of controversial data
showing that you know all of these games
don't really affect anything and it
doesn't really affect successful
cognitive aging per se. All right so
here's the bottom line everybody. If you
like the brain games is a way to
de-stress. I'm fine with that. Just set
a screen limit, time limit so you're not
dealing with all this that I'm dealing
with right now. People aren't paying
attention otherwise. Memory pills, brain
games, they're not the only things to
get your memory in check. When we come
back, investigate some natural ways for
you to boost your memory with items you
have right at home. So stick around.
[Applause]
Drink up. We've got an Oz approved 3-day
tea. We took all of the best teas and we
combined them with food. Get results
safely without feeling hungry. Next, Oz.
That's coming up on
[Music]
Wednesday. We were talking about memory
boosters and brain games are being
pushed online. Now, Chef Nikki Dinky,
author of Meat on the Side, has some
natural memory boosting recipes you're
all going to love. The first natural
memory boosting recipe is golden milk
overnight oats. I've heard of golden
milk and heard of overnight oats, but
only you could put them together. Well,
I've been loving this idea of overnight
oats. Um, it's been very trendy.
Recently, I've been doing this golden
milk latte thing, which is basically
just a nutmilk combined with some ginger
and turmeric and all these warm, just
delicious spices. So, then I thought,
why not just put them all together, make
it super easy and super nutritious, and
thus we have our golden milk overnight
oats. As a neurologist, thoughts,
lectures, there's turmeric in the oats
now, right? The oats potentially
beneficial for the for brain function.
Yes. F first of all genius combining
both of them together and then my
goodness um I mean turmeric it's a
potent anti-inflammatory and it actually
binds to the bad protein amaloid that is
involved in Alzheimer's disease and gets
rid of it. So put both of these
together. Is it true they have less
Alzheimer's in India? Maybe because of
the turmeric the curry sauce that they
they eat. There is there's a perspective
there. Yes. Because of the curries that
they eat and they combine it with
different kinds of spices. So you get
anti-inflammatory effects of all of
these different spices in your food.
They make it pretty straightforward. You
say just you mix it like you normally
would. Yeah. All this stuff pretty much
just goes in the jar. Your oats, your
milk, your ginger, turmeric, cinnamon,
vanilla, and honey. And you let it sit
overnight and you have this beautiful,
super nutritious breakfast. Is this
chia? Yeah. And I love to top with
something crunchy like some chia, some
walnuts, and maybe some fresh
blueberries just to keep it kind of
popping. All right, the next natural
memory booster. You all have these
things in your homes. Use them, right?
Doesn't cost you a lot more. It's a
salad with fish oil dressing. Now, you
all know fish oils are essential. I
never thought about putting it in a
salad dressing before. You know, I used
to take a lot of this and you know,
whether it's in a pill, you're putting
it on a spoon, it's not the most
pleasant thing. So, I thought, how can I
get this into our food? And by combining
it with things like Greek yogurt and
orange juice and honey, you can really
make a very delicious salad dressing
that of course you can use on salmon.
You could use it as a spread on
sandwiches. And it's just such a fun
alternative way to get that fish oil
into your body. I don't know why I don't
taste fish oil so much. You know, we're
using a lemon flavored fish oil, so
that's already taking out a little bit
of that fishy taste. And then I think
the Greek yogurt is key. That just kind
of mellows it out and makes it something
that, well, we want to eat. diabolical
diabolical and it makes sense for the
brain. Absolutely. It's a synergy
between the last memory booster where
we'll have to see if it appeals to your
taste buds is a shot of beet and ginger
juice. So, Dr. Sherz, before you take
the shot health benefits, why is it so
good if you can do it? I love beets and
beets are an incredible vegetable
because they are very rich in nitrates
and so the nitric oxide that you get
from beets actually expands the arteries
so you get more blood flow to your
brain. It's basically like Viagra for
your brain. It's an amazing thing.
Quickly, Dicky, quickly. Okay. Okay.
Okay. All right. I'll toast to you guys.
Everyone wants Viagra for the brain.
Audience, you want some Viagra for the
brain? All right.
Oh, it's a Oh, it's got some punch to
it.
Oh, please. Wow. Don't let me force you.
You're young. You may never forget this
shot. Be sure to head over to dr.com for
my natural memory boosting prescription
plan. If you remember, we'll be right
back. What do you think?
[Music]
Whoa. Many people in my audience have a
pair of glasses with them right now. May
I see? Let me see. Oh, I see you. Even
better like this. Right. All right. So,
glasses are something we take for
granted. For those of you like me who
use them for reading, you can get them
for just a few bucks. I buy a bunch of
them, right? Get them at the pharmacy,
leave them everywhere, so I don't even
think about them. But what if the world
looked like this?
little out of focus, right? And he
didn't have access to glasses to get it
back into focus like this. The simple
things you do every day from reading to
driving a car to seeing your loved ones
would become impossible. It's a reality
for billions. That's right. Billions
with a B of people all around the world.
Joining me now are two people who have
teamed up to help us see the world more
clearly. Optometrist Dr. Jordan Castelo.
Welcome, Jordan. Thank you, Dr. and
Rabbi Jennifer Krauss.
First off, Dr. Castle, I just described
the problem as affecting billions. Put
some numbers, put some meat into this
thing. Set it up for us. Well, as you
know, Dr. Oz, vision is our most
critical sense. 700 years since the
invention of glasses, most people in the
world still don't have access to
glasses. Our research shows that a
simple pair of glasses can increase
someone's productivity by 30%. Oh my
goodness. Increase their educational
performance and decrease road traffic
fatalities. Is there road traffic
fatalities? That's correct. How so?
Well, 59% of road traffic fatalities
have a visual component associated with
them. So, if you can see clearly, you
can be safer on the road. So, it
benefits not just you, but the people
around you then. Absolutely. So, what's
your vision and why did you get so
passionate about this? Vision, pardon
the pun. What do you hope to do? How are
you going to make a difference? Well, I
started an organization called
Visionspring. Our goal is to ensure that
everyone has access to affordable
glasses throughout the world. We deliver
eyeglasses and vision services right to
people where they live, work, and go to
school. Last year, we helped over 1.2
million people get glasses. And
collectively, over 5 and a half million
people in the world, Vision Spring has
provided glasses for over the last
number of years. Why we're doing this is
I've always wanted to live a life that
had a deeper purpose beyond just myself.
And I discovered that purpose when I was
a student. I joined a mission to Mexico
and I met a seven-year-old boy from the
school for the blind. In fact, though,
he wasn't blind. All he needed was a
really strong pair of eyeglasses. And
when I put the glasses on his face and
he saw for the first time, it was a
moment that changed both of our lives. I
gave him his vision and he gave him and
he gave me my vision. Oh my goodness.
And it was just a wonderful moment. And
it's a way that I can make a difference
as an eye doctor and we all can make a
difference as well. Rabbi
Jen, the benefit of giving is more than
just acred by the person who gets the
gift. It actually benefits us
spiritually, emotionally. How so?
Absolutely. So there are studies that
show that when we do something for other
people with some consistency that we
sleep better, we're less stressed. We're
more connected to the people we love. So
when we do something to heal the world,
we heal ourselves. Beautifully stated,
Rabbi Jackson, guys. It's right there.
This is a great excuse. Pick something
you want to do. But I tell them like,
and just to be clear, I checked into
this. For five bucks, all loaded,
including the examination and everything
else, and getting the glass to the
person, you can take a kid out of a
school for the blind and make them
productive, which I love is feasible.
So, for more information how you can
helps the world see clearly, please
check out Vision Springs website. We got
a link to it on dr.com. You can check
out Rabbi Jen and and Dr. Castello's new
book, Dare to Matter: Your Path to
Making a Difference. Now, it's part of
the proceeds of that book will go
towards helping people get access to
glasses as well. Together with everyone,
change is happening. Show up in life.
Our journey is just beginning.
[Music]