See how stars keep their famous faces
smooth and bodies beach ready. I consult
with top dermatologists and fitness
experts to find the celebrity health
secrets that really work. Cinnamon for
fuller lips. Big old juicy lips. Brown
sugar for softer skin. It's like a
baby's bottom. And how beer can repair
your hair. Happy hour hair. Celebrity
summer health secrets coming up next on
Dr. Oz.
You ever wonder what the stars do to
keep their famous faces smooth and their
billboard bodies fit? I scour the
glossies and I consult with top
dermatologists and fitness experts to
find the celebrity health secrets that
really work. Here reveal of the star
secrets is a woman who has done her own
red carpet research. Entertainment
reporter Tena Ree. Welcome to the show.
Hello. How are you? Welcome to the show.
Thank you. So, how much can we believe
from all the glossies, the magazine
pictures we see of these folks? Well,
the magazine's job is to know any and
everything about the celebs, so trust
them. Plus, I did my own research. Dr.
Oz, I talked to some doctors, some
stylists, as well as all my experience
on the red carpet. These celebrities
know what they're talking about, and I'm
listening. All right, let's go to it.
Over here, we're going to start with
famous faces. The first famous face is
Lupita Nongo. The queen Lupita. Well,
let me tell you, her skin is
effervescent. She illuminates from the
inside out. So, we're going to listen to
what she does. She's all about avocado
oil. Yes. What she does is she uses it
as a moisturizer all over her face and
she just really gets all shiny and glowy
and delicious. Well, she looks
beautiful. She does. How do you How do
you apply it? Well, it's easy. You want
to wash your skin with a regular facial
wash and then you slather it on your
skin like moisturizer. It's much like
lotion except for way better and
natural. You know, Leita likes to be
organic. But most importantly, it's thin
enough that it will penetrate the skin,
but it's thick enough that it acts as a
protective barrier and that's why it
works. Yeah. Absolutely. Okay. Next
famous face we'll talk about and but but
I should point this out. Avocado oil has
restorative processes if it's cold
pressed which is what you want to look
for. So you approve? I approve. Okay,
great. Jennifer Anderson's been on the
show. What is her health secret to keep
that skin of hers looking so darn
smooth? Yeah, she's amazing. She's 46
years old. She looks half her age. So
again, you want to listen to what she
has to say. And her secret is petroleum
oil. Super cheap, super easy. You can
get it anywhere, even a gas station.
Petroleum jelly. Where does she put it?
Petroleum jelly. She puts it right under
her eyes so that she can moisturize her
under under eyes and wart away wrinkles,
which is what every girl wants, right?
Yes. And then on top of that, for a
twofer, she fills her sink up the next
morning. She wears it all night long.
She fills up her sink with ice and cold
water, sticks her face in it so she can
reduce the puffiness of her eyes. That
makes a lot of sense cuz then if you do
that, the blood vessels, they narrow
down a little bit. So it stops any
swelling you might get. So no wrinkles
and she's It's so easy to do. petroleum
gel. I'll do I have big bags. I'll start
doing that. All right. You look great.
One more famous face. Lisa Rena. What's
her secret? Our favorite new housewife
in Beverly Hills. Now, Lisa Ra is known
for a couple things. She's gorgeous. Her
body and her pucker, right? Big lips.
Big old juicy lips. Well, what she does
is she adds cinnamon to her beauty
regime so that she can keep them nice
and plump and kissable. Cinnamon. You're
kidding me. How does it work? Well, what
she does is she puts her lip gloss on or
lipstick and she just takes a pinch,
just a little bit. It goes a long way.
And she dabs it all over her lips,
mushes it in, waits a couple minutes,
and boom, pow, kissable lips. Cinnamon
must be the most useful thing out. I'm
serious. You use it for everything. One
little cautionary thing cuz I play with
this a little bit. Don't put it on dry
cuz it can irritate your skin. So, make
sure, as you say, put it on your, you
know, something with some Yeah. Make
sure there's a barrier. Put your gloss
and it's a twofer. It tastes good on top
of looking good. Absolutely. Let's go to
health secrets for the Hollywood hair
you all want. We've got three wonderful
victims here. Jennifer, Lindsay, and
Stacy. We're putting them all to the
test. Jennifer's going to get the
Katherine Zetta Jones approach. What do
we know about Katherine Zita Jones?
Well, her hair is long, shiny, and
gorgeous. Right. So, we want to take one
of her tips, and it happens to be beer.
A nice cold beer. Yes. You're kidding
when she drinks it. No, no, no. She
doesn't drink it. Don't drink the beer
for shiny hair. What she does is she
puts it in her hair, rinses it through,
kind of leaves it in for about 20
minutes, and then she shampoos and
conditions it like normal. She doesn't
smell like beer all day long. She might,
but I don't think anybody has a problem
with that, right, guys? No. I like And
what what kind of beer do you use? You
know what? It doesn't matter what kind
of beer you use, but it shouldn't be
right out the refrigerator. It should be
warm and flat. So, when your husbands
are leaving beer around the house, we
finally have a good use for it, ladies.
We like it. Yeah. You know, I didn't
realize this was true, but stylists have
been using this for years. So instead of
paying a lot of money for that, use as
you mentioned the used up stuff for the
the damaged hair repair kit that you
want. Absolutely. It leaves your hair
shiny until it's the proteins in it.
Really happy smell. Sure. It's happy
hour hair. It is happy. That's exactly
what it smells like. Just came. What do
you think about it so far? I can always
use something for dry ends and for more
shine. So I love beer. We're enjoying
the beer. You can drink the leftovers,
by the way. Good for you. Cheers. Oh,
you can't get it. You can't drink. Next
up is Lindsay. She's trying the Denise
Richards healthy hair secret. Yes.
Denise Richards has gone to the avocado.
Good fatty acids in avocado. And what's
great, she has her shower cap wine. What
she's going to do is she's going to mix,
mash up one ripe avocado, pour in a
tablespoon of olive oil, make a paste,
and put it on her ends. You know, our
ends get really dry, ladies, especially
with the weather. So, she's going to put
it on her hair and then put the shower
cap on and bake it in there for about 20
to 30 minutes. And how often do you
normally have to do that? Well, you
should do it about twi once every two
weeks unless you are a flat iron or blow
drying addict, which most of the people
in this audience probably are. And you
should up that avocado and do it maybe
once a week. How often would you have to
use it? Um, well, I I need to I deep
condition my hair every couple months
because I get highlights. So, I think it
would be important for me to do it every
couple weeks at least. And when you have
something left over, chips and dip
always look. Exactly. Yep. Chips and
dip. Chips and dip. Thank you, Lindsay.
All right. Last up is a Hollywood secret
from Blake Lively and Stacy's trying
out. What's Blake's secret? She has it
now. Well, Blake literally got this from
her mama. What it is is mayonnaise,
which is filled with fat as well. A lot
of us have balayage. We have highlights.
You probably have highlights all through
your hair, but the most dangerous part
is the bottom. It really gets ratty. So,
you take matte mayonnaise, you put it at
the bottom, you massage it in. Now, this
is different than the avocado. What
Blake does is she goes into the shower,
shampoos her hair with the mayonnaise
on. And usually what shampoo does is it
strips the dirt and the oil from your
scalp, but it also when you're washing
the bottom, it doesn't strip the oils
from the bottom because the mayonnaise
the mayonnaise protects it. Oh, I love
that. What do you normally do for your
split ends? Oh, I have to put lots of
conditioner at the bottom, lots of
product, and flat iron it. Well, this is
cheaper. I got to say it's cheaper. Very
good. A good use. Another good use for
mayo. Absolutely. Thank And how long do
you keep it on? You keep it on about 20
to 30 minutes before you go into the
shower. And then you shampoo it and
condition as usual. The summer time
especially, you need this, right? You
know what I love about it? It has
natural oils in it. So, it actually will
help lubricate the hair, moisturize it
as well as your scalp. Let's get a
little closer up there. All right. Thank
you very much, D. Next up, let's get to
the Billboard Beach Bodies. The first
up, because you guys always want these
bodies. Yeah, these are great health
tips, especially during the summer
times. The celebrities are out playing.
We are going to take their tips. First
up, we have Before you, I think take you
through three. I'm gonna have them come
out from behind the curtain. They have
tried these treatments cuz I actually
want to see what they look like. Kim
Kardashian's health secret. What is it?
I mean, we're going to follow anything
she does apparently with all her Twitter
followers. She is all about sugar. A
little bit of sugar goes a long way.
What she does is she takes sugar and
puts it in her body wash. Washes her
body all over from head to toe. Smooth,
glowy skin. That simple. That simple.
Kristen, tried it. Come on out.
Oh, she's dressed. How do you feel? Out
of the cabana. She's sweet, but you
smell sweet. Yes. So, how did it go for
you? It was great. Like, what I did was
I just put it on um I mixed my sugar
with my body wash.
And I put it on like that. Right in the
shower. Right in the shower. Put all
over your body. Yeah. And then I rinse
off and I feel just like a Kardashian.
She feels like a Kardashian. Well,
there's lots of products out there that
have sugar scrub, but this is chemical
free, totally organic. This is the way
to go. But, you know, I use brown sugar,
by the way, which is not an accident.
You should use brown sugar over
granulated sugar. It's a little less
irritating, especially if you got
sensitive skin. It's a great idea. Here,
take the rest of sugar with you can have
it all. Parting gift for Dr. Thank you
very much. The least I could do,
literally. All right, let's get to
another health secret for a beach buy.
This one is from JLo. What's her secret?
Oh, well, JLo, again, we all watch
American Idol just to see how gorgeous
she is. She's so smart. that body of
hers at age 46.
She sniffs grapefruit extract. Okay. To
suppress her appetite. What do you think
about that, Dr. Als? Do you approve?
Well, she was on the show and that's
when I learned she was doing this. And
there's actually data. It's in animals,
but it works. But she's data in her that
it works, too. So, I like the idea. I
wanted to ask Latrice, who's in our
audience, to try it out. She's in the
comic. Come on out, Latrice.
Well, she looks wonderful. Hungry. I'm
always hungry.
So, we gave you some of this grapefruit
extract. You've been using it for a
while. What do you think? You know what?
It is so awesome. What I do is I sniff
it every time I'm hanging out with like
my girlfriends or different things like
that because I'm always hungry. Peer
pressure eating. Major, major, major.
And then they want to know, "How do you
stay so slim?" And I said, "I'm using
grapefruit extract." And my girlfriend's
like, "Give me some. You always have it
in your purse." I'm like, "Uhuh. You
have to go get your own." Exactly.
Right. You fight for a claw at it. You
do. So, actually, you know what? I feel
that I look better than you know Dr. Oz.
Pose girl pose. I like that. I like
that. She twirls. Go ahead. Go ahead and
give it to us. Give it to us.
They again, it's hard to study this
stuff in humans, but as I mentioned,
they use this in rats and it shows that
it actually lowers appetite. And for
that reason, the rats ate less. Yes.
Thank you very much. Snack on, girl. All
right. One more celeb health secret.
This one is from Selma Hayak. Selma's 48
years old and looks fantastic for her
age. What is her secret? Yeah, this is
actually my favorite, so listen up. This
is called dry brushing. Now, the same
sort of idea of sugar scrubbing the dead
skin off of your your skin, your arms,
your body. This you do before you get in
the shower and it gets off all that
extra layer. So, you go in there already
smooth and then you can do the sugar
afterwards. This is She swears by it.
She gets in there and she's yummy. Come
over here. I'm going to I'm going to
fence you on guard. Yes. Do we have a
subject? Cassie, please come out, my
dear. There she is.
Hi. So, you've been trying this and if
you if you bear with us, we're going to
actually show everyone else what we've
been doing to you. So, use which side?
The hard side like this or No, this is
not it's not dominatrix. We're not
spanking anybody. This is to slough off
dead skin. So, how do you do it? So, we
go brush up. We brush up. How does that
feel? Not too bad, actually. Okay. I
actually like it. I think it feels
really good. And I It feels kind of like
a massage. Yeah. You get addicted to it,
I have to say. And you start going,
"Where's my dry brush? I need to slough
off some if you go like this." No, no,
no, no. You don't want to do that. You
really want to do it towards the heart
for circulation to let the blood flow.
And you do it on your legs, too. I'll do
it, too. Like, why not? I don't want to
be left out. Actually, I just wanted to
cuz it feels so dang good. You can get
it work for you. Did you enjoy it? I
did. It really It's really nice. Feels
good when you're doing it and afterwards
as well. And you feel soft and smooth.
It's like a baby's bottom. And I think
that's what we're all going for, right?
Soft and smooth. Thank you very much. It
was a real pleasure. Thank you very much
for all the advice. You can get all
these simple celebrity health secrets at
dr.com. I'll be right
back. Coming up, some may argue that
faith and health are unrelated, but this
doctor says that the power of prayer can
reduce the risk of stress and add years
to your life. Can the power of prayer
help you heal? Prayer can cure disease.
Coming up next, suit up for summer with
detox week. All week long, I'm going to
show you different ways to detox your
body to feel healthier, be happier, and
to look slimmer. Swaps to lose weight
and the food to jumpstart your energy.
That's coming up on Monday.
God saved my life. A direct answer to
thousands and thousands of prayers.
The big conversation today, can the
power of prayer help you heal? Kent
Brantley, the doctor who was treated for
Ebola and recently released from the
hospital, credited prayer and God with
helping him heal. I've seen too many
miracles as a practicing surgeon to
ignore the potential power of prayer.
And I'm not the only one. The doctor
you're about to meet has tangible
evidence that the power of prayer can
actually help you heal. Meet Dr. Harold
Koig. I am a trained medical scientist
and a physician. My primary training is
to conduct research in an objective and
scientific manner. But I do believe that
there is something
more that is the power of prayer. A
professor of psychiatry at Duke
University, Dr. Harold Koig is a pioneer
in connecting the worlds of medicine and
spirituality and identifying the link
between prayer and health.
He's even seen the effects of prayer on
his own well-being. Prayer has helped me
a lot in terms of dealing with my own
chronic pain that I've had for 20 to 30
years. Dr. Koig is convinced that people
who are religious lead much healthier
lives and that the power of prayer is so
profound it can add 7 to 14 years to
your lifespan. He didn't learn about it
in medical school, but Dr. Koenig firmly
believes that practicing religion and
prayer can be for many people a crucial
key to healing. People need more than
just medicine or surgery, it helps a
lot, but it's not enough. And that's
kind of where faith enters into the
picture. The world's top expert on
religion and health, Dr. Harold Coney,
is joining us. Do you think prayer can
really heal or cure disease? I think
that prayer can heal and cure disease.
But you know, it doesn't happen very
often that it that a person prays and
the disease is gone. Most of the time we
pray and and we we get the strength to
endure the condition. And you know, when
we're coping better with a condition, we
actually do better
physiologically. So it's been preciously
difficult to actually find hard data in
this area. I've done research in this
area. others have as well. But I want to
show you if I can some, you know, very
new research that's just come out. These
are images from a recent study u that
Dr. Con brought to my attention. And
they did a study looking at people who
are at risk of depression. Uh this image
uh shows the area of the brain that that
makes decisions, the area that senses
things. This is the area down here that
remembers things. Now this image is a
compilation of people's brains who were
depressed and had not done any prayer
around that issue. And the purple
signifies that there's actually a
thinning of the part of the brain. Let
me show you the second scan now. Same
kind of thing. They collected images of
people who are high risk for depression.
For example, their parents were
depressed. Uh and these people had
prayed. Notice the red and the yellow
marks. These yellow areas and red areas
show us that the brain is actually
thicker. It's compensated by being able
to cope better with what's going on.
This is the first evidence that I've
seen of the power of prayer on the brain
that's physically actually changed our
brains. It's as though the brains were
doing bicep curls in order to make it a
bit stronger. And in part because of
this, some researchers have argued that
prayer can help reduce the incidence of
depression, a very difficult to treat
problem by 90%.
That's a big statement. Now, what about
people who aren't overtly religious but
are spiritual? Does the impact seem to
reside there as well? Well, you know,
people who are spiritual and who are not
particularly religious, um, they are
going to derive benefit from things like
meditation where it's not so much
focused on religion. But you know uh
when people pray in the context of a
relationship with God with with with the
with God whom they see as a friend who
can come into their lives and give them
strength and hope that really seems to
make an additional difference. I noticed
that the military is doing work on on
spirituality. They actually have
concluded that it's important for the
resilience of folks in the military who
are struggling. You've actually given a
number out of how much benefit prayer
might offer to us quoting a number I
believe around 7 10 maybe even 14 years
of longevity. How do you get those
numbers? Well, you know, religious
involvement including prayer seems to
affect our bodies in many different
ways. It affects our minds in terms of
how we cope with stress and illness. It
affects our health behaviors, how we
live our lives, whether we exercise,
what we eat, uh our smoking habits, our
drinking habits, and it also surrounds
us with a faith community to provide
support for us during hard times. So,
all of those factors seem to affect our
physical health and extend our
longevity. I I called my buddies who
work at real age, which is a great way
of assessing how old your body thinks
you are. And their numbers were not too
different from yours if if it reduces
stress, which is a big part of this
because we don't want it to be an a
stressful process to incorporate this
into your life. We showed Dr. Ken
Brantley earlier. He's been very vocal
about the power of prayer. Uh he's
argued that it helped him heal from
Ebola. There are some who question
whether that's true or not. How would
you have an argument with them? How
would you defend Dr. Brantley's beliefs.
Well, I think that his beliefs are
powerful for him and because they are so
powerful for him. Religious beliefs are
one of the most powerful factors that
you can imagine in a person's life and
in their health because he believes that
that probably has affected his immune
system in various ways that have made
him stronger and more able to resist the
virus. Now you know can we say that this
is not a miraculous
Godcaused cure of him? No, we can't.
Science cannot answer that question. But
what we can do, we can say that because
of his positive attitudes that his body
was probably more able to fight off this
virus. Dr. Thank you very much. You
know, religion is a deeply emotional and
personal topic obviously and some may
argue that faith and health are
unrelated, but the connection has always
seemed very real in my practice. In
fact, I think practicing medicine
without a spiritual or religious element
is a departure from the norm of history
since the first healers, all of the
first healers pretty much were spiritual
leaders as well. So, religion does help
cope with social problems. It helps cope
with uh with life in general. And I
think we ought to embrace every tool
that helps as long as people don't feel
judged or uncomfortable in the process.
That's an important element because I
don't want people feeling that way. Tell
us what you think. You can join the
conversation at dr.com and tell us if
you think the power of prayer can help
heal. We'll be right back.
Next. Are you waking up in the middle of
the night? Mind racing? Heart pounding?
Welcome to the 4 a.m. club. You're not
alone. Uncover unique stress remedies to
stop your mind from racing and keep you
fast asleep.
[Applause]
[Music]
Next. It's happening all over the world
and you may be a part of the club and
not even know it. I'm talking about
women on the age of 50 who wake up in
the middle of the night with their minds
racing and their hearts pounding. Sound
familiar? Yeah. A lot of nodding heads.
Comedian and author Annabelle Gerwitch
calls it the 400 a.m. club. I'm
Annabelle Gurwitch. I'm a 52-year-old
mother, wife,
comedian, author, and I happen to be the
founding
member of the 4:00 a.m.
club. It doesn't take much to be a
member. Whether you had too much coffee
during the day or you're waking up
thinking about what you have to do
tomorrow, we've all been there. We're up
at 4:00 a.m. And it's great to know that
when you wake up in the middle of the
night, you're not alone.
Annabelle's 4:00 a.m. club. We're open.
What's up, Annabelle? Annabelle.
Annabelle. Annabelle. It's 4:00 a.m. and
I'm wide awake. Me, too. I'm up again.
You can check the temperature in your
room, but I think you're just having a
hot flash. I think cookies are like
needed right now. I don't know if
cookies are a sleep aid. Do you have any
book recommendations? I have a great
recommendation. I just wrote a new book.
It's called I see you made an effort.
Annabelle. Annabelle. Annabelle.
Right on target. So, what wakes you up
at 4:00 a.m. in the morning? Okay. At
4:00 a.m. I start to wake up and I'm
thinking about the things I forgot to do
2 days ago. The things I forgot to do 25
years ago. Did I give my kid enough
greens? And why did I go to bed with a
sweater wrapped around my waist? And
then I realize it's not a sweater, it's
my waistline. Now it's grown on you.
It's everything. Now you've fielded lots
of calls from women who complain about
this 4 a.m. scenario and there must be
common themes. Yeah. You know, I mean I
since I started the book tour, I've met
women all over the country and I think
it really boils down to stress. We're
really stressed out at this age. So
animal decided to try some rather
unusual stress relievers to help out our
fellow 4omemers. Take a look. Ladies,
thank you so much for coming over. I've
come up with some stress relievers that
will help us get a little extra sleep
tonight. Are you ready to try something
unconventional? Yes. Are you ready to
get dirty? Yes. Not that kind of, you
know, the right kind of There's a lot of
research that says that singing and in
particular singing together releases
endorphins and that's one of those
happiness hormones. So, I've arranged
for a singing instructor to work with us
and the best part is you don't have to
be a good singer. Well, thank qualify.
[Music]
Hey ho, nobody home.
Hey, nobody home. Meat, no drink, no
money.
Hey, nobody home. I forgot what I'm
singing.
Hey, nobody home for a first try.
I could see singing at 4 a.m. and being
very happy. Not so much my neighbors.
Meditation has been shown to be relaxing
for the brain and I like a moving
meditation. So I thought of dervish
whirling. Dervish whirling is an ancient
technique. It's from the 13th century in
Turkey. You guys, are you ready? 1 2 3 4
5 and da da da. And d my skirt's not
going out. Okay. All right. Wait.
[Music]
I
overwhelled. People have been doing mud
baths since Roman times, right? People
say it improves your digestion. It
relaxes muscles. This is going to be the
thing. This is going to the amazing
thing is it helps us sleep. I'm going to
help you guys stir up this brew, but I'm
not hopping in. It feels kind of
amazing. It does. It's like playing in
the dirt. This is just so out of my
comfort zone of the normal day that it
just feels so good. Thank you for
inviting me cuz I'm not going to be a
member of the 4:00 a.m. club tonight. Me
neither.
I might be cleaning up till 4:00 a.m.
I'm so glad it worked for you guys.
Some very extreme measures. It looked
like dung you were putting into the mud
bath. And it was mud. It was mud from
the Baltic Sea. And my father's from the
part of the world in Turkey where they
actually do the whirling dervishes. But
you get dizzy at age 52 doing that kind
of work. Yes. I I have to say that is
not my distresser. It was the singing
for me. You know, you get so caught up.
You're not you chores, bills, working,
kids, and we were just so joyful and
playing together that we forgot about
those things. And I slept really well
that night. Think about that, folks. I
know it sounds like who has time to go
play? A little bit of it if you can
sleep at 4 in the in the morning is
probably worthwhile. Okay. You got an
emergency kit for all the the folks on
the edge of 50 who might be suffering
from not only 4 a.m. scenarios but other
things as well. Yes. It starts with I'm
supposed to hold this. Is this right?
Yes. Granny panties.
Right. They come. I hold it like this.
Those might be your size. All right.
Exactly. All right. Come over here. Come
on here. All right. So, what do you do
with these? Okay. Why do I Why do I need
granny panties? Well, the granny panties
are really for a sense of humor. Just to
remind you to laugh because in menopause
you need your sense of humor. And if you
also if you wanted some carbohydrates,
you might need those too because you
gain weight so quickly at this age.
Okay. Inside here. All right. You ready?
Tweezers. Okay. Tweezers. Tweezers. On
any given day, I can end up with more
chin hairs than my teenage son.
Tweezers. At this age, very important.
Then I've got a great selection here of
reading glasses. I don't need to tell
you why, right? I lose my glasses all
the time. Usually I'm wearing them when
I'm looking for them. You have to hide
these around the house. I do that too,
by the way. Always. Great. Okay. Then
the most important thing in the kit is
the phone. Why? You're looking at me
like why, Annabelle? Why this? Right.
Well, what I have really found that I
need at this age is community. I need my
girlfriends. Now, my new trick is
exercise dates twice a week. Standing
dates with my girlfriends. So, you get
two things. You get your girlfriend time
and your exercise time together. I have
a well thought through. Lots more of her
wonderful insights. And I see you made
an effort. It's a wonderful book is out
now. Be sure to visit our Facebook page.
Enjoyed it on Annabelle's 4 a.m. Club
Conversations. Here's a home phone
number, by the way. We'll be right back.
[Music]
How do you make sure that you get a good
night's sleep? Meditation. Every night
before bed, I make sure to take at least
15 minutes to meditate. It helps quiet
my mind and relax me. Share your story
with us on
facebook.com/d. Next, it's often called
the silent killer. One in every three
adults lives with it. High blood
pressure. What you can do to get it
under control and how you can monitor it
right from your own home. Coming
up, suit up for summer with detox week.
All week long, I'm going to show you
different ways to detox your body to
feel healthier, be happier, to look
slimmer. Swaps to lose weight and the
food to jumpst start your energy. That's
coming up on
[Applause]
Monday. A third of the audience is
standing. Now, why is that? Because they
represent the one out of three adults
with high blood pressure. Now, this
season, I'm asking you to take simple
steps to better health. Today, we're
focusing on the very first step I want
everyone to take to get their blood
pressure under control. Now, before I
tell you exactly what that step is, I
need a little help from my assistant of
the day. How about seat number 73? 7. Is
that
you? Well, how are you? Everyone else,
you have a
seat. Oh, good. Come on down here. Let
me put this on you real quick. What's
your first name? Joanna. Joanna. Uh, is
that your family back there, friends?
That's my friend Karen. Oh, she's I bet
she was down here. Now, your blood
pressure, what is it? Uh, typically it's
normal. 110 over 75ish. Oh, you have
good blood pressure. Unless I'm really
excited. They're like, "Now, come come
sit. We're going to check your blood
pressure." I have a remarkable effect on
people. I can raise anybody's blood
pressure. All right. So, here, put your
arms right through there and let me just
see what it is. And you sit there and
try to make the world a calm place with
all these people watching you. and we'll
put these numbers on. And while I tell
you this about this a little bit, you
you ignore me. You're just concentrating
on your blood pressure and relaxing
yourself. Now, you want to use a wide
range cuff. These cuffs I just put on
are designed for different sizes of arms
so you don't get the wrong number for
yourself. And remember, the blood
pressure is the number everybody of the
blood rushing against your blood
vessels. The top number is designed to
tell us exactly how hard your heart pump
blood into your blood vessels, how
pushed them out and engorged them with
blood. The lower number tells us when
your heart's not pumping, when your
heart's relaxed, how much you relax, how
much your blood vessels are able to open
up and let blood flow through them. So,
the ideal blood pressure is anything
below 120 over 80 over there. That green
light that I'm identifying. Anything
between 120 and 140 over 90 is called
the orange area. That's called
prehypertension. You ideally don't want
to be there. It's better off if you're
not there. You want to be in that green
light area if possible. Anything in the
red zone, 140 over 90 or above, we don't
want that. and your blood pressure.
Well, your lower number is great, 76.
Your higher number, because of me, I'll
take the blame on this, is 163. But, but
that that's because you're a bunch of
folks around you in your life. The
beauty of what I'm going to talk to you
about today is the fact that when we go
to doctor's offices and we have that
white jacket that you're wearing on, we
raise your blood pressure. When you're
rushing to get to the office, it goes
up. The best place to take your blood
pressure is at home. That's when it's
going to be nice and low, especially to
keep your spouse out of it and let
everything happen. But the reality is
because so many of us have high blood
pressure and we don't have symptoms.
It's called the silent killer. It's the
most important thing to pay attention
to. If you don't know your number, you
can't deal with it. All right, let's get
you up. Let me walk you over here
because I'm going to show you why I care
so much about blood pressure. And you're
going to love this. And it has to do
with your blood vessels. So, we got two
blood vessels here, right? And both
blood vessels are normal. They both
could take you to your old age or having
any problems. But the water which is the
blood in your body can either come in a
very gentle way sort of like like this
gently massaging the inside of the blood
vessel you know interestingly touching
it delicately nudging it right that's
what you want a blood pressure that's in
that green zone like there won't have
any damaging effects to your blood
vessel so you don't have to fix poles
and problems but if your blood pressure
is that of a fire hydrant right and
instead of being that nice number that I
mentioned earlier You're more like, I
don't know, have like a jet engine,
right? And you do this to your blood
vessel wall. Watch what happens. You see
ripping off the edge there. Tearing it
up. Exactly. Right. And as you tear it
up, now you're left with a blood vessel
wall that's got a big gap in it. And
when that gap is there, see all this
down here? This material, this is the
blood vessel that's being ripped. And
your body has to fix this. So see this
dark area that's left without a
covering? This teflon like covering is
missing. Your body has to repair that.
It puts down plaque with cholesterol.
All kinds of bad stuff happens when this
delicate lining is ripped off with high
blood pressure. So, we don't want that.
Instead, what we want to do is to figure
out ways of preventing it. Now, under
these sheets, I've gotten examples of
what happens over the long period of
time if we tolerate that. You put your
purple gloves on. The first specimen is
pretty riveting. I'm coming down again
if we have to. We'll do it at the very
end. How's that? I'll race you for blood
pressure at the end. Okay. This is the
aorta, the major tube that carries blood
in the body. And you see these little
chips? Yes. Go ahead and touch those.
That's like the torn up red in there.
Well, that's what happens when that torn
up red is replaced by plaque. These are
little
plaques. Little chips here. Describe
them to everybody. They're uh hard.
Yeah. Much hard. Bony. Much harder than
I expected. Bony is interesting. It's a
good way to describe it. It's not
supposed to be like this table. It feels
like the table. It's supposed to be like
a very rubbery substance and it's not
that anymore. And then over time as this
becomes rigid and unable to allow the
blood to pass normally, your heart will
change from this beautiful little baby
size of your fist, nice and elegant,
right? About the right size to this. Oh,
this is a heart that's faced high blood
pressure and burnt out from working hard
every single day. Since I've been
talking, your heart's beaten a couple
hundred times. All of ours has. And if
we're pumping against that high pressure
that I showed earlier, it's a problem.
So, we don't want to have this in our
life. We don't want to experience any of
this. And the first step, the first step
is to know your blood pressure and
monitor at home to avoid crazy numbers
that aren't accurate. So, take your
gloves off here. Let's go through this.
How often do you check your blood
pressure? At the doctor, once a year. At
the doctor, once a year. Yeah. You know,
we you know why we used to do that? It
was the only thing we had available.
There was no other way of doing it. But
research without any question shows the
best place to do it is at home. So, I
could come visit you at home. Sure.
Sure. Okay. But but most doctors aren't
going to do that. The best thing to do
is to figure out an atome blood pressure
monitoring system that works for you.
I'm going to give you my guidelines real
quickly. You're going to settle down,
sit in your in place for five minutes
without moving with your feet on the
floor with no one bothering you. And
then you're going to start off initially
by taking your blood pressure in both
arms because they can be different. And
you want to know if there's a
difference. There are lots of reasons
for that, but you should know that. And
if there is a difference for more than
10 millimeters of mercury, then you
actually want to be to call it to your
doctor's attention. You can use a wrist
monitor if you want. And if you use a
wrist monitor, this is an example of
one. You want to put it up by your
heart. It'll tell you there's a little
light on there. It'll tell you where to
put it like you're pledging allegiance
to the flag. And that little light will
light up and it'll let you know that
you're in the right spot. So arm or
wrist, they'll both work great. You want
to do this for a week, twice a day. Then
you'll know what your true blood
pressure is. You we all have ups and
downs, but you'll know generally. And
then after that, you can go, you know,
to once a month or more regularly,
depending if your blood pressure is high
or low. Does everything I'm saying makes
sense? Yes. And yeah, we live in an era
where we can know this. Why not take
advantage of it? All season long, the
Dr. Oz show and Walmart are teaming up
to bring healthy back. That's our
mantra, bringing healthy back. And
Walmart pharmacist Amber Binham is here
with some exciting news from them. So
share it with us. Take it away, Amber.
Dr. Oz, we're so excited. We have the
Walmart Healthc Care Begins here event.
It's going to be held this Saturday,
October 11th, from noon until 400 p.m.
at participating Walmart locations
across the nation. We're going to be
offering free blood pressure screenings,
free blood glucose readings um by
licensed healthcare professionals, and
we're going to do what we talked about
today, going above and beyond and
providing information about those
numbers so that we can help people live
better. And I'll add one more little tip
because I think it'll help everybody.
Beginning tomorrow at 3 pm Eastern time,
you can go to dr.com to be one of the
first to win one of 300 free rely on
blood pressure monitors or one of 50,000
Walmart coupons for $10 off any Omron
blood pressure monitor. Take advantage
of it. It's there for you. Be the world
expert in your body. Audience, I could
not leave you alone without going home
with these devices while you're all
going home with a clean blood pressure
monitor to rely on and online. And
thanks to our sponsorship partner
Walmart for being there for us. Be right
back.
[Music]
Coming up, learn the tips to shop like a
pro and change your family's health. My
husband lost 10 lbs. I couldn't believe
it. Insider supermarket secrets to buy
what's best for a healthier family.
Coming up
[Applause]
[Music]
next. Now, I've been telling you that
small steps can make a big impact on
your health. One mom and her family are
proving just that. Lisa Leak overhauled
the food in her home and change her
family's health. How'd she do it? She
shopped the supermarket like a pro, and
she's here to show you how to do the
exact same thing. Welcome to the show,
Lisa. So, how'd you overhaul your
family's food? Well, a few years ago, we
had a huge wakeup call when we started
researching the foods that we were
eating and realized that a lot of the
foods we thought were healthy were
actually highly processed. So we
challenged our family to take a 100 days
of real food pledge. 100 days. Yes. Now
how do they respond to that? Well, we
certainly explained to the children that
we were doing this for our health and I
think children generally want to do the
right thing. So they were on board once
we told them the reasons behind it. What
kind of results did you get? Did the
folks feel healthier or not really? You
know, we didn't expect to have any
immediate changes to our health. So we
were really surprised when my husband
lost 10 pounds. I had more energy. My
youngest daughter's constipation
basically went away overnight. Also, her
asthma improved so much and my good
cholesterol, the number that you want to
be high went up by 50%. I couldn't
believe it. Yeah, that's ab and this is
again small steps done right. The way
you describe it makes incredible
impacts. Come on over here. Okay, let's
get to the tips on how to shop the
supermarket like a pro. The first thing
you are you need to do is to buy fast
and easy food staples, things that you
have to have on your shopping cart. Yes.
Now, while it's ideal to shop the
perimeter of the of the store and to get
lots of fresh produce, it's not always
realistic for a busy family. So, these
are some of the staples I do buy from
the middle of the store. Starting with
um whole grain crackers and cereal.
These are 100% whole wheat pas. These
fruit leathers are a great little snack
and treat for my kids. And also, you can
find fruit and nut bars that only have
two or three ingredients, so I always
have one of those stashed in the bottom
of my purse. And I love popcorn. I also
love that it's 100% whole grain snack.
And I want to show you a little trick.
You can take just a third of cup of
kernels, put it in a brown paper lunch
bag, and then you just fold over the top
and you can microwave this and make your
own microwave popcorn with no additives
or unwanted chemicals. So, you just put
it in for about 3 or 3 and 1/2 minutes
and it's done. And folks, doesn't cost
very much. It's a paper bag basically.
You got it done. All right. And over
here we have foods that you think we
shouldn't be getting. These are are food
you are because they make health claims.
you might want to be wary about.
Exactly. So, like this says it's all
natural and it might be, but natural is
not a term that's regulated. So, you
have to read the ingredients to be sure.
So, it was difficult for us to figure
all these things out, but once I figured
it out, it's so much easier now. And you
teach the kids. Okay. Lastly, you say
shop in season. Yes, that is a great way
to save money. And I have a tip for you.
So, berries, for example, they are
definitely a better deal when they're in
season in the summer. And I actually
freeze fresh local organic blueberries
and eat them all winter long. And they
are so much better than the frozen
packaged berries that you get from the
store. And another great tip to get your
kids involved is if you're in the
produce section, give them a dollar and
tell them they can buy whatever they
want. And that's exactly how I got my
oldest daughter to eat a cucumber for
the first time. And she now loves them.
So I think just because she was able to
make the choice with a buck. If you can
get do that, we're well to do. Okay. So
after shopping, doing all these smart
things, you said you've could put a
couple meals together just as an example
to tantalize you how cool this could be.
So for breakfast, what do you have for
us? Well, this is a recipe for my new
book. These are whole wheat banana
pancakes. And the great thing about this
recipe is that the bananas are so sweet.
It's a great introductory recipe for
someone who's just getting used to the
taste of whole wheat. So, and for lunch,
you've got pita pizzas, which every
child loves. Yeah, these are so easy.
You just take those whole wheat pas and
I use jarred organic tomato sauce from
the grocery store and grated mozzarella
and you can toast them in the oven or
the toaster oven. And I actually make
big batches of these in advance and
freeze them for my kids school lunches
and I pack them cold and they love them.
They eat them up and this looks like a
lot of work. This is a slow cooker.
Yeah, this No, this is so easy. So, this
is the most popular recipe on my blog. I
call it the best whole chicken in the
slow cooker. You basically rub some
spices on the chicken and you put it in
the slow cooker with an onion. No need
to add any liquid. And then you cook it
on high for 4 hours and is like tender
falling off the bone. This cannot be
that good. It is so good. And especially
if you have a recipe where you need to
use cooked chicken, this is how I always
make it. And then the best thing to do
is you take the bones after you're done
eating the chicken, put them back in the
slow cooker, fill it with water, leave
the cooking juices in there, add some
veggie scraps, and I make homemade
chicken broth overnight while I'm
sleeping. So, you make something with
ingredients you would have thrown away
anyway. I love it. And finally, popcorn,
which I think is the best snack for
those of you who have issues late at
night. This is this you is that is that
cinnamon on there? Yes, this is cinnamon
glazed popcorn. And just because you're
on a real food diet doesn't mean you
can't have a sweet tooth. I love to make
this. You just mix melted um butter and
honey and cinnamon and ginger together
and you bake it on a low temperature
together. And I always give this to the
teachers for holiday gifts every year
with a little recipe card and it's a big
hit. Does it help with the grades at
all? They're getting good grades to
begin with. I hope I am very proud of
you. You invested a little bit of
effort, made those small steps, and now
you changed the life for you and your
family. Yes. And the next generation,
too. Congratulations. You had all of
Lisa's recipes in her new book, 100 days
of real food. It's absolutely fabulous.
I'll be right back.
All new Oz. Suit up for summer. Detox
week kicks off with a summer cleanse
almost anyone can do. All week long, I'm
going to show you different ways to
detox your body to feel healthier, be
happier, and to look slimmer. Swaps to
lose weight. We made ice cubes that have
blackberries in it. It's very clever,
very refreshing. And the summer food to
jump start your day. I feel amazing. I
have a lot more energy. All new
Oz. That's coming up on Monday.
[Music]
It is time for In case you missed this.
First up, it's our big conversation
point today. Can the power of prayer
help you heal? Religion and health
expert Dr. Harold Coney says yes, and
he's emphatic about it. He believes that
prayer can promote healing by reducing
stress and anxiety, and it actually even
helps depression by 90%. Now, studies
have found that physical changes in the
brain happen in people who are religious
and pray. And some may argue that faith
and health are unrelated, but the
connection has always seemed very real
to me in my practice. Next, shop the
supermarket like a pro. One way to do
this, and this is, I think, pretty
simple, is realize that it's not
practical to just shop the perimeter of
the store, although it's a good place to
start. You can buy fast and easy food
staples everywhere. For example, and in
these packages, I'll give you some some
of these. You can have whole wheat
crackers. There's pa puff rice cereal.
Again, check the ingredients. Fruit
leathers, these nut bars are fabulous.
Again, look to make sure you don't have
25 synthetic things in there, but these
can be easily found with a little bit of
homework. Um, and even with things like
popcorn, you can prepare them as a
wonderful late night snack. So, let me
close with a warning. Please be careful
about what you buy online, especially
weight loss pills. There are some
dubious people online that pray on folks
like you who are trying to do the right
thing for your health. Sometimes they
even try to make it seem like I'm
endorsing their products. I don't. To
see a full list of our trusted
sponsorship partners, please go to
drought.com. I'll see you next time.
[Music]
[Applause]