What you are about to see is graphic
footage from a real medical procedure.
Viewer discretion is advised.
[Music]
So see all this? Mhm. This is all fungal
debris. Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
[Music]
Do you see that?
Yeah, you're all a little bit unsettled
now. First you told me, right? First you
told me you couldn't get enough of
pimple popping, and now we've taken it
to a whole new level cuz that was not
pimples that were being popped. These
are some of the videos the internet
cannot seem to get enough of. They're
from the foot specialist known as the
toe bro. He's a sensation and he says
there is nothing he won't clip, slice,
or scoop off your feet. Jonathan Tinto,
also known as the toe bro, is here to
reveal the number one thing everyone
needs to stop doing to their feet so
they don't end up looking like this.
Look at this. You don't want to look
like this, right? That that's an ingrain
ingrown nail being whacked out, which we
have to do sometimes. So, why are you so
passionate about foot health? My dad was
a foot specialist for over 30 years. So,
as a kid, I've been going to work with
him since a little boy. And in my
summer, if you can believe it, he made
me go to work. And my job was to take
off the shoes and socks for everybody.
Oh. Oh, no gloves, no nothing. There's
dad. Hey, Dad. Look at that.
I hope he was good at taking your shoes
off with no that that's actually
sometimes a dangerous thing to do cuz
you see stuff when those socks come off
that you wish you hadn't. It It was
raining on me. That's right. It was It
was tough. But when I finished school
and I got to see how important feet are.
And really, people don't realize how
important feet are until something
happens. So, what's the number one thing
you say we're all doing wrong with our
feet? just going to tempt us here. I
think it's cutting our toenails. A lot
of people don't know what's the right
way or how they should be cutting their
toenails. So, um whether you do it
yourself or you go for a pedicure, you
could be trimming them wrong. And when
you trim them wrong, you have a high
risk of getting an ingrown toenail. All
right. So, the toe bro filmed someone
who let their toenails grow a little too
long for about 2
years. Take a look.
[Music]
I mean, that video goes on and on. I've
always wondered, how long should our
nails be? Well, the one thing you you
want to make sure that you never leave a
sharp corner when you're cutting your
toenail. So, that's number one. Number
two, you you really don't want the nail
to go that long like that video. That
could be really dangerous in your shoes.
So, what we always want to do is kind of
leave the nail just one or two
millimeters just above the edge of the
skin just to have a little bit of extra
nail, but obviously none of those three.
Come over, show us how to do this,
right? You got a little hack. Let's say
we have an ingrown toenail. Yes. What do
we do? Well, there's a few things you
can do. If that toe is really painful,
we can soak the foot in some Epsom salt
and warm water for around 15 minutes
twice a day for a few days. It's going
to help soften the skin, soften the nail
so it's not so tight and as painful.
then we can actually apply an overthe-c
counter antibiotic ointment to help
trying to prevent any sort of infection,
keep the area relatively clean. If
that's not working, if the pain's still
going on, then we can go for the big
guns. And that's trying to get some
cotton ball underneath the edge of the
nail and the skin to try to lift the
nail. Cotton ball is the big guns. Yeah,
it's the big gun. So So you roll it up.
Exactly. We'd make a thin little almost
thin little line like that. Yeah. Let me
see this one. Like that, I guess. Yep.
Just like that. even a little bit
thinner. You put it on the side of the
nail. I'll show you got a good one. You
put it on the side of the nail and you'd
actually push it underneath the nail to
raise it up. You show that to the camera
if you don't. So, put it like that. Can
you all see that side of the nail? Then
you take this thing. Yep. And you just
push it in like this. Exactly.
Underneath. And that's going to help
lift the nail so it's not going right
into the skin. The whole goal for us is
try to get that nail to not grow in the
skin and be above the skin. Dad, you
proud of him? Yes, sir. He is. You did a
good job. Thank All right, up next. Have
you ever experienced dry, burning,
cracked heels that look like this? Take
a look. Yes, yes, yes. That could be one
of your feet. The toe bro has an easy at
home trick that anyone can do to
alleviate these cringe-worthy cracks. So
stay with us. I am back with Instagram
sensation, the toe bro,
Jonathan. Before the show, applaud
because he's going places we've never
gone before. Before the show, the toe
bro scoured our audience for the driest
and most cracked heels with our foot
cam. There it is. the foot cam looking
looking looking and guess what we found?
We found these feet. Whose feet are
these
feet? Come on now. I know who it is. If
you won't tell me, I'll tell you. This
is
Janelle. Janelle, my
dear. So, how your heels feeling right
now? Really dry, doctor. Very dry.
Little itchy.
Is there anyone you want to kick with
those feet right now? We have turned you
like look look at them. I'll just just
look at them. Just take a look. Well, I
think hold a second. Well, they are a
little dry, but maybe we should turn to
the person who turned you in. Avery,
come on up here. Tiger. Thank you. I
would put your shoes back on. You get
kicking into him now. So, what do the
feet feel like to you? I'm sorry. He
says quite he goes. I'm I'm really
sorry. So, what does Janelle's feet feel
like to you? What what bothers you about
them? Well, sometime. Well, she she
complains all the time. And because I
love feet, like I have like a little
miniature foot fetish. Not not like a
creepy one, but a a good one. I just
like them cute. I just like them cute,
that's all. So, you know, um 2 3 days
after she come from the from the nail
salon getting a
pedicure, like, "Babe, what happened?"
She like, "I don't know. I forgot to put
lotion on." I'm like, "But you just got
them done, you know." So, but they do
feel like the um the horse out of
velcro.
You're in worst trouble I can imagine.
To bro, come on over here. Why Why is it
we get cracks on our feet? So, I've got
this is I guess this is normal skin.
Yeah. There's two reasons why. Number
one, think of skin as an elastic band.
So, when you have a nice fresh elastic
band, you know, the skin's properly
moisturized, it can stretch. No problem.
That's what we want skin to do. But if
you have skin that's dry that you're not
moisturizing properly, when you put some
tension on it, it can snap. That's how I
feel. That's the big issue. So, we have
to make sure the skin is properly
moisturized. The second reason is
pressure. It's pressure that's causing
that skin to expand. And if it's dry,
it's just going to crack. But you've
come to the right place cuz Toe Bro has
a hack for you. Come on over, guys. You
might as well join us. You see how that
that elastic band snaps? Trouble. Yeah,
she might do that to you. Snap on you.
All right. So, have a seat here. What
can Janelle and everyone else do who
wants to get rid of their their cracked
heels? The big thing that we can do, we
can actually make a little homemade uh
foot soak to help soften some of that
hard feet in there. Yeah. So, what we're
doing is just a cup of vinegar, a cup of
mouthwash, and warm water. And
mouthwash. Mouthwash. So, this is going
to help soften the skin. And we're going
to do that for around 15 minutes. And
then after that, the puma stone. Get to
work. Hey, come on, Mr. Foot Fetish.
Let's go. Come on now. Not the creepy
kind. Not the creepy kind of foot
fetish. The good kind of foot fetish.
So, what I really want you to do after
those heels are nice and soft, you're
going to grab that foot like you like
it. There you
go. Get that pummelone to the dry skin.
And come on, you're a big guy. Put some
muscle in there. There you go. But what
you want to do is not too hard. Not too
hard. You don't want to damage the skin.
Thank you for being part of this. Toe
bro, very proud of you. And your dad is
proud, too, which is probably the
greatest honor of all. Good for you.
Thank you. Be sure to check out
Jonathan's show, The Toe Bro. It's on
A&E. There he is. Toe bro. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good