It may be the most famous cold case of
the last century. This unknown serial
killer claimed to have murdered 37
people. He flaunted his crimes by
sending letters like these to the police
and the press. The mystery surrounding
his identity has inspired countless
books, movies, and TV programs. He is
the Zodiac Killer. But 50 years after
he's believed to have murdered his first
victim, could new DNA technology finally
identify him? Today, you're going to
hear exclusive details and insights from
investigators who believe they may
finally be able to bring this infamous
killer to
justice. In the 70s, as it was
happening, a lot of us probably thought,
gee, there's a lot going on. But looking
back at a decade of violence, it was
just crazy. It was crazy time. Most
serial killers don't make any effort to
involve the media or investigators.
They're very secretive. They don't want
attention. They almost want their crimes
to go unnoticed. But the idea of
committing a crime and then calling up
the police and bragging about it, that's
a whole another level of terror. A man
who wore a medieval style executioner's
hood who has baffled the police and
baffled the media. He seems to crave
publicity. He sent letters and
cryptograms to newspapers and the
police. Subject stated, "I want to
report a murder." No, a double murder. I
did it. Here we are 50 years after the
first Zodiac killing. In today's world
of forensics, old cases are being
solved. We're talking about probably the
most famous cold case in the last
century or so in terms of its drama and
being unsolved. Who doesn't want to know
how it turns out?
Dear editor, this is the Zodiac
speaking. If you do not print this
cipher by the afternoon of Friday, 1st
of August, I will go on a kill rampage
Friday night. I will cruise around all
weekend killing lone people in the
night, then move on to kill again. The
best part of it is that when I die, I'll
be reborn in paradise, and all that I
have killed will become my slaves.
Wow. Matt Frederick and Payne Lindsay
are here. They're the hosts of the
podcast Monster the Zodiac Killer. Pay,
there's been so much written about this
monster. So much said about him. Why do
you want to tackle this cold case? Well,
man, it's been 50 years. 50 years since
the first Zodiac killing. It's unsolved.
Police have never arrested anyone for
these murders at all. Imagine that. All
these people dead. Nothing known about
it. Matt, the randomness of these crimes
is one of the biggest problems it would
seem if I was law enforcement. It is.
Yeah. Each one each of the five
confirmed attacks where people were
killed. They all occurred in different
jurisdictions. So, I mean, at the very
beginning, you have to have all of these
police departments working together,
which is a difficult thing to do. So,
for years, the the primary most
scrutinized suspect was a man named
Arthur Lee. Allen. Mhm. Matt actually
spoke to a father and son who knew him.
So, let's listen to what they had to
say. I knew Arthur Lee Allen in school.
He was uh a half a grade behind me, but
we knew each other. And um and then
later on he would come in his shop once
in a while. He worked on his car. So, he
did blacksmith work. He came in one time
and and said, "Hey, I have this letter."
He just said that he was no longer a
suspect in the Zodiac case. He also told
me once that he needed that letter cuz
he kind of couldn't get a job. Yeah, it
was just weird to think that I knew the
guy as a kid. I knew my dad knew him. It
It's one of those things that I would
love to know what the real answer is. I
would love to know if it was him. I've
seen other suspects name, but obviously
the only one that is in my head is is
Lee Allen. I certainly believe he could
have been
So Matt, the these two had never spoken
out before. Why was it important to hear
them? Well, these guys had just a
personal perspective on the man Arthur
Lee Allen. And this is this is a guy
who's there's so many stories told about
him. There are so many um
ideas that say he's the guy. And it's
all it's almost all circumstantial
evidence when you look at him because
when police officers actually
investigated this man, they couldn't
connect any of the actual evidence to
him as being the Zodiac Killer. And
hearing uh the perspective of a person
that knew Arthur, that was Carl Lubner
you were listening to. Uh it lets you
see the person behind kind of the myth.
This letter is sort of strange. I I
didn't know you could go to the police
and get a letter saying that you're
innocent of something. Yeah.
I don't know if they still do that, but
is was it legit? Well, yeah. There was
there was so much press surrounding this
man, and this is in the '9s when this
occurred uh when he brought in the the
letter to show them because he had been
there, you know, he had been
um thought to be the Zodiac. In a lot of
people's minds, because there's so much
press, people think this is the guy. And
if he's going to go out and, you know,
get a job somewhere, you're going to
interview and say, "Yeah, possibly the
Zodiac Killer. You need something I mean
you need something official that says no
I am not according to the police.
Although that at the time the gathering
of of information of evidence wasn't
quite so good. So he could have been Zad
killer just not have been tied because
they didn't have evidence that we have
today. But part of what comes to my mind
is Mark's memory that the young the
younger the son's memory in that video
you just listen watched and listened to
of the school bus was important because
he had a fear and that fear came from a
letter where the Zodiac killer wrote I'm
going to quote him. I think I shall wipe
out a school bus some morning. There
were police who were following school
buses around. But in a later letter, he
seems to have changed his his mind and
his heart when he wrote, "If you cops
think I'm going to take on a school bus
the way I stated I would, you deserve to
have holes in your heads." What struck
you the most pain about not just this
letter, but his whole attitude towards
law enforcement and the public? This guy
is just pompous. He's cocky. He doesn't
care. He He wants to taunt the police.
He wants to brag about these murders.
He's not hiding the fact that he's a
killer. Did you believe that he may have
wanted the attention, Matt, because
there there was another killer in the
area at the time? Yes. Uh a man named
Charles Manson that you might recognize.
Uh he he was making
headlines right after the Paul Stein
murder, which is uh 1969. and and he
begins writing letters to the Chronicle,
the San Francisco Chronicle, as all of
these front page stories about Manson
are occurring. And it's almost as if he
wants to get the attention back. That's
what it really feels like because, you
know, after that point, while the
Charles Manson story is occurring, he's
not writing any details about killings.
So, there are all of these people that
he claims to have killed, but there's
absolutely no evidence that he had
anything to do with it. How many people
did he claim to have killed? It was I
think 49 is what Robert Gaymith writes
down in uh the book Zodiac. Oh my
goodness. Pay, what do you hope people
listeners get from your podcast? Because
you guys do a really detailed dive into
all the clues out there. I think it's
been so long. We we wanted a place where
all this information could live. It's
been 50 years and if there's a missing
piece of information out there, if
someone saw something or heard
something, now's the time to give us a
call. Hey, even the Zodiac Killer
himself, if you're in a retirement home
watching this on TV, write me a letter.
Let's get all the information out there.
Uh, time's slipping. I mean, not all the
people in this case are going to be
around in 10 years. It's not your ally
in this case to have time. Up next,
who's a Zodiac Killer? We investigate
the theory surrounding his identity and
how he might finally be caught. Stay
with us. The boy thought he was going to
wasn't going to make it. He wanted to
tell give a description to the guy best
he
could about the best he could give us
that he had a hood over his face and a
he was a big guy.
U 6 foot of better over 200 lb. That's a
clip from 1969 of a police officer
reporting on a survivor's description
Zodiac Killer. And we're back with this
cold case that has frustrated
authorities for 50 years. The Zodiac
Killer terrorized Northern California,
claiming to have murdered 37 people. He
has never been identified, but now DNA
technology could change that. Here to
help unravel the mystery surrounding the
Zodiac Killer is our true crime panel.
CRAM correspondent Melissa Moore,
retired police sergeant and host of
Breaking Homicide on Investigation
Discovery, Derek Levasser, and former
homicide prosecutor and host of True
Conviction on Investigation Discovery.
An NLI ana 50 years, a long time. He was
pretty good at covering his tracks. All
this time we've been searching for him.
What does that tell you about him? Tells
me that he benefited from the days. This
is the days before DNA. We did not have
video surveillance like we do today
everywhere. So whether is that he is
incredibly savvy, which we know he's
intelligent from the way he went about
his letters and these cryptograms, these
puzzles he put in them, but it's also
right place, right time. He committed
his crimes at night. I would like to
believe that today we would not have
what some have called this greatest
America's murder mystery on our hands
because he would not have benefited from
the lack of technology that we now have
today. And Derek, in addition to being
very well organized, he was incredibly
random in his acts. What does that tell
you about who he is? Well, it may not be
random at all. You know, serial killers
can have a pattern, but I believe they
tend to look for victims of opportunity,
right? So, when they see someone who's
vulnerable, they tend to act upon it.
When you think about the first killing
associated with the Zodiac Killer, it
was uh December 20th, 1968, 11:30 p.m.
Two victims were teenagers. You had
David Faraday and David Faraday and
Betty Lou Jensen. They were teenagers.
They were parked in a car in a dark area
and they were shot and killed. Do I
think the Zodiac Killer knew they were
going to be there? No. But he saw an
opportunity to kill two people without
being apprehended because nobody was
around and he took advantage of it. But
they were on Lover's Lane, I believe.
Right. So, he knew there would be young
people who loved each other. They were
together. They could pray on, Melissa,
looking at this cold case file. What
stands out to you? Well, what stands out
to me is just the time lapse in the
killing. Like, this happened in the 60s
and the I think the last one was in the
early 70s that he he killed. So normally
ser serial killers don't go underground
for that long. So I'm curious why the
long lapse in time that he hasn't killed
again unless he hasn't talked about it
and he actually has killed again. Do you
think the Zodiac Killer could still be
alive? Absolutely. I think he could be
alive. We just recently found the Golden
State serial killer and he's obviously
older but we believe that he started
killing. The Zodiac started killing him
in the mid 20s. So from age 25 to 35. So
he's he definitely could still be alive.
So over the years several people have
been interviewed as possible suspects
based on circumstantial evidence and in
some cases pure speculation. So Arthur
Lee Allen was portrayed as the prime
suspect in the movie Zodiac. That was
what we just talked about that
gentleman. Was he really a serious
potential suspect for police? He was
absolutely a serious suspect. This is a
case that over 2,000 people have been
named as potential suspects. But he came
up over and over again for several
reasons. One, he was actually seen in
the vicinity of a couple of the murders
that happened about 6 months after the
Zodiac spree began, or at least that we
know of. A friend of his reported only a
year later that he had talked about his
desire to kill, that he liked using the
name Zodiac. Strange coincidence if they
were. He had a watch that was by the
brand Zodiac. He talked about wanting to
put a flashlight on a firearm so he
could see better at night. Now, several
search warrants were conducted of his
home over the years. When he died, which
was in
1992, they did a search of his home and
took evidence. I also think it's very
important to point out in fairness that
when they did look at a partial print
and a partial genetic profile DNA of
his, they were not a match to the
Zodiac. So, that means that that
certainly wasn't him. Does it
conclusively prove it wasn't him? No.
And the fingerprint, who knows? It could
have just been an arbitrary fingerprint.
I don't There was so little evidence,
it's hard to tie that all together. In
fact, there are a lot of conspiracy
theories, Melissa, because of that,
because there's an easy way of making up
stories about who the Zodiac Killer is.
I think the most absurd one is that the
theorist is that the Texas Senator Ted
Cruz is the is the culprit. But, I mean,
he was born two years after the first
known killing, so that's not possible.
Then you saw like there's also Manson
that they think members of the family of
the Manson uh were, you know, committing
these crimes. Uh, also lately there's
been a lot of people saying my relative
is the Zodiac Killer. So this is this
call. It's screaming for some help.
Derek the Zodiac Killer like other
serial killers was taunting the media
taunting police. So as a police officer,
retired officer, what do those what do
those actions tell you about his crimes
and and who he is about his identity?
Well, he's not much different than
killers today, right? It's not it's
about notoriety. It's not enough just to
commit the heinous act. They want people
to know they got away with it.
Ironically, that self-confidence can
sometimes lead to a false sense of
security, which will ultimately get them
caught. You look at the uni bomber,
right? He started getting cocky. He
started writing these letters, this
manifesto, and that's why he was
ultimately arrested. So, it could end up
coming back to bite him in the end. Can
Can I ask you a difficult question? You
know, that's it's it's one that I think
might startle the audience. He claims to
have killed 37 people, right? Five we
actually know he killed, but the other
ones we we're not sure about. How many
people could he have actually killed?
The numbers are unlimited. I mean, we
may never know exactly how many people
he killed. Sometimes serial killers will
tend to take credit for murders they
didn't commit to kind of create their
own narrative and and boost their own
egos. Um, but at the end of the day,
when investigators are looking at it,
there may be cases that look similar to
past killings of the Zodiac. They may
associate it with them. And then there
are outliers that aren't exactly the
same exact situation. You may have a
different type of victim, manner of
death, but they are connected. So, as
far as pinpointing the exact number, we
may never know. So, so what percentage
of murders go unsolved in America? Well,
the national number number is
approximately 40%.
How how many of you knew that 40% of all
murders go unsolved?
They're like five people max and we have
the smartest audience in television.
True. That that's that's remarkable.
That's absolutely remarkable. Well,
that's why we do what we do. That's why
as a private investigator you try to
help out because again a lot of
situations law enforcement is inundated
with cases and they can only spend so
much time on it. They follow up the
leads and they kind of have to put it
aside and wait for a lead and you know
but we can't do that. We have to keep
pursuing it for the hopefully technology
today can help us look back which is
exactly what you're hearing here with
the success of the Golden State DNA.
That is exactly what prompted people to
now start looking at this again to see
if advancements in technology. Homicides
are never closed. Every family deserves
an answer. So, let's hope that we can
look back and solve more of those that
are why we do the show cuz forensics
science is playing a bigger role. So,
don't get any ideas. Up next, could
those popular DNA tests be the key to
cracking the Zodiac Killer mystery? Stay
with us. We're back asking the question,
who is the Zodiac Killer? After 50
years, police may have finally found the
key to identifying the serial killer who
terrorized Northern California and then
seemingly vanished. Our true crime panel
is back. Melissa Moore is our crime
correspondent Derek Leasser and Ana
Nicolazi. So, let me ask if you you
brought this case to us and and
highlighted the fact that this may be
the next case we solve with DNA
technology. What are what are folks
thinking? Yeah, there's two stamps on
different envelopes that we have DNA
samples of and it's now being privately
investigated in the lab. So, we are in
an age though where we can take these
sol these these crime cases that have
haunted us for decades and actually
solve them. So Derek, if investigators
actually can get the saliva for DNA off
the stamp or even I guess you had to
close the envelope, right? Back then you
had to lick it and and we can actually
identify that's from a Zodiac killer.
Are you confident we'll find something?
It's possible. I mean I I can say this
that science and technology in the 1960s
is not what it is today. So if they have
something, they should absolutely retest
it. However, I will say that the
collection and preservation techniques
of evidence back then are not what they
are now. And we do know that based on
how it's preserved, evidence can break
down. However, if they have something
that's viable, it may be our only chance
at identifying the Zodiac. So, here's
the game plan. Investigators will
hopefully run whatever DNA they get
through genealogy sites in the hopes of
finding a family connection, which is
exactly how the Golden State Killer was
finally caught. We talked about that on
this show. So, using DNA this way is
cutting edge. But, but how would you go
about prosecuting this kind of evidence?
Let's talk to a prosecutor. Ana, what do
you think? DNA is every prosecutor's
friend. However, it's not going to end
there. What they're doing right now is
they are hoping to get enough of a
profile that they can get a match. If we
are so lucky, that is going to get a
prosecutor in the courtroom if they can
show that everything else around it
matches up. Where was this person in the
time? Were they in the vicinity of these
crimes? Can you show that they were out
of the country, out of state? If I'm a
defense attorney, that's the first thing
I'm going to do. So, there's going to be
a lot of connecting the dots.
Especially, you have a case, as you
pointed out, Dr. odds 50 years have gone
by. You have to talk about the
preservation of evidence that although
people didn't look at preserving it in
the same way that we can still be
confident in the way that this evidence
was maintained that a jury can still
rely on it because that's what it all
comes down to. Proof in not only this
case but in our system comes down to
reliability and that the jury can trust
what we're bringing into that courtroom.
Melissa, is this the last chance to
catch the Zodiac Killer? I believe it
is. Look at how many years have gone by.
witnesses are de deceased now. Memories
are fading and if we can't catch it with
DNA, I don't I don't know unless we have
another a confession. I don't know how
we could process in the future, which is
very often how we get it. The prosecutor
and the optist and me has to remind
everyone that no homicide is ever
closed. There is always a chance down
the road. I've told victims so many
times, their families that because we
don't see anything for a long time,
people do talk. the person out there
misststepped somewhere. We might never
get the answer, but I believe and hope
that someday something pops. DNA would
be a great resolve to this case using
science, but there's never a hopeless
situation. Melissa made a great point,
too. The Golden State Killer is a great
example of good police work and not
giving up hope. We have a guy in custody
now. He's a criminal. He's where he
should be and hopefully we can have the
same result with the Zodiac. Thank you
very much for joining us. I just want to
thank Matt Frederick and Paint Lindsay.
New episodes of the iHeart Real Podcast.
Monster the Zodiac Killer are available
every Tuesday wherever you get your
podcast. Thank you for watching. Don't
forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good