[Applause]
Welcome to the show. If you're a dog
lover like me, and yes, that's me and my
dog Khesi. She's so cute. Then this is
very familiar to you, right? We love our
dogs so much. All of our pets, we let
them lick us all over it. It's how they
show their love. We all like this,
right? But what you're about to see next
may have you thinking twice. When I saw
these headlines about amputations and
even death from dog licks and bites, I
needed to understand what's going on.
Today, we're investigating a medical
mystery. How can a dog lick be deadly?
And could you be at
risk? You see it every day. Pet lovers
playing with their dogs and letting them
lick their hands and face. But beware,
that playfulness could be deadly. A
58-year-old Wisconsin woman made
headlines this summer when she was
nipped by her puppy. 4 days later, she
was dead. Greg Mantifal's wife, Dawn, is
grateful her husband is still alive.
They think possibly the dog licked him
and he touched his mouth or touched his
eye. Within days of petting a dog,
Greg's face began to turn black and
blue. Doctors would later have to
amputate his forearms and legs.
Jackell went from this to this. He lost
his legs, fingers, and part of his nose
after his beloved Cocker Spaniel bit
him. Robin Sullins was separating two
family dogs to a roughousing when she
got nicked. Within 48 hours, she was in
kidney failure. Experts say these
infections from a dog or even a cat's
saliva are extremely rare and can be
hard to diagnose. But dog lovers like
Robin say don't blame the dogs.
This isn't about the dogs. This is a
call for the medical community to be
aware of symptoms when people come in.
Angela and Chris Young agree. Their
2-year-old son, Liam, had symptoms so
severe that his legs and fingers had to
be
amputated. What caused this? For 2 and
1/2 years, doctors had no answers.
Liam's parents, Angela and Chris, are
here. Angela, let me start with you.
When did you first realize there was
something wrong with your son? Um, back
in October of 2015, uh, he had fell what
we thought was the flu. So, he ran a
high-grade fever, had thrown up a couple
times, and then two days later, his
color changed, and his liver and kidney
started to fail. So, it's pretty fast.
It was it was 48 hours from the time
that he started being sick until he was
being medflighted. So, we're going to
show some pictures of your son.
Everyone, these images are a bit
graphic, so just be prepared, but the
the reality of what happens sometimes.
So, what did the doctor say to you when
you brought him in? Um, well, my husband
Chris when I first took Liam to the
emergency room, um, the ER doctor came
in the room, Dr. whack. And he said, "I
called for the helicopter to come up and
get him from Iowa City. He's extremely
ill. Um, we don't know what's wrong with
him. All I know is we need to get him to
Iowa City because we won't be able to
treat him here." What's it like to not
know what's wrong? It's the worst
feeling in the world. I mean,
cuz you never know if it when you don't
have an answer as to what caused it. We
didn't know if it was going to happen
again. We didn't know if we could
prevent it or anything like that. Was
Chris, was was Liam around dogs
frequently? Yes, he was. Um, we had a
family pet named Freya, a boxer. Um, her
and Liam were best friends as you can
see from the pictures and they they were
inseparable.
Did Did either of you ever sense that it
could have been a dog? Did the doctors
ever bring up the possibility that it
could have been your pet that was
responsible?
We were in Liam's room in the pediatric
intensive care unit when one of the
specialists came in and said, "We
finally got something to show up in one
of our blood test." And what we had show
up was caposphaga.
Say it again. Capnostophaga.
You any of you ever heard of that
before?
I can tell you most doctors have it
either. And we're going to talk about it
in a second. And that's kind of exactly
his response is this is the first time
we've seen it show up in a person's
blood work. We're running it again and
we'll let you know the results. Well,
they came back in the room later and
said we didn't get it to show back up,
so we're uncertain if that's the
bacteria that caused his infection.
Did Did you think your son would survive
this?
For the first 10 days, we didn't know if
we'd walk out of the hospital with him.
Um, and then as things started to slowly
improve, things looked better. But for a
while, we didn't know. Um, he was in
critical care, critical condition, and
they didn't know if he was going to make
it. It's one thing to be at risk. It's
another thing to be facing the unknown,
which is why after that many days, you
get into a spiral. So, 78 days, that's
it. 78 days in the hospital. That's how
long they spent before Chris and Angela
were finally able to take Liam home. But
for two and a half years, what caused
Liam's illness was still a
mystery. How did you even begin to think
that it might have been the dog saliva?
Well, considering that was one of the
tests that uh had first popped up that
said it could have been a possibility
for the
caposphica.
Um,
however, nothing came back conclusive.
So, they said they weren't sure that's
what it was.
I remember receiving a message um
through my email from a lady that does
gen uh genetic testing and she said, "We
seen your son's case and we're wondering
if you would be willing to enroll him in
this genetic testing because we have a
theory that we think might be causing
his illness." Um so immediately we got
him enrolled in that program. Actually,
I got the letter that came with Liam's
results and because you're good enough
to send along this information, which is
great, not just for Liam, but also
because it can help us with other
children, other adults. Here's what the
letter says. I'm going to pull out one
sentence. It says, "We hypothesized that
Liam has a genetic variant that
predisposed him to
capnocyto. That's a bacteria I had never
heard of
before." We're going to talk about it
today because I think you all need to
from now on. The doctor doesn't know it.
At least you should know it to remind
us. So, how's Liam doing today?
Wonderful. You doing well? He is uh a
spitfire of a 5-year-old boy
who he is just like every other
5-year-old boy. He jumps, he plays. Um
everything's
wonderful. He's just missing a few
fingers and toes is all. Yeah, Chris.
Yeah, he's wonderful. He's perfect.
That's He's perfect the way he He's
perfect the way he is. You all want to
meet Liam?
Yeah. I thought so. Well, you're going
to get to meet Liam and the science
behind a dangerous dog lick. So, I'm
going to talk about that when we come
back. How safe is your family? I had my
dog Kis you just saw tested for this
bacteria results when we come
back. Today, we're investigating the
medical mystery behind the shocking
headlines. How can a dog lick lead to
amputation and even death? And we just
heard from the parents of a little boy
who lost his legs and most of his
fingers. And we're going to meet him in
a moment. But first, how is this even
possible? Well, it all starts with a
specific bacteria in a dog saliva. And
what is this bacteria? How common is it?
How often does it get spread to people?
Dr. Casey Barton Bear Ravish is here to
help. She's a senior veterinarian at the
CDC's National Center for Emerging and
Zunatic Infectious Diseases. So, please
break this down for us. Sure. So, what
we're talking about is a bacteria called
capnoscytophaga. In animals, it's very
common. In fact, in dogs, 74% of dogs
can carry this bacteria in their mouth.
About 57% of cats can carry this
bacteria in their mouth. And it's
important to mention that these pets
appear perfectly healthy and happy, but
can still be carrying a germ that has
the potential to make people sick in
rare cases. And what kinds of people are
more likely to get ill from this
bacteria that I've never heard of
before? People who are more likely to
get ill are those who have a weakened
immune system. So for example, they
might be undergoing treatment for cancer
or have a disease like diabetes. Also,
people who've had surgery to have their
spleen removed are more likely to become
infected. Typical symptoms when someone
gets infected just so we can be alert to
it. Sure. It can start off like anything
else with you don't feel good, you have
a fever, you feel kind of flu like, but
in one to three days it can rapidly
progress to serious illness where the
bacteria gets in your bloodstreams. It
can affect your organs and tissues and
even lead to brain infection. This is
pretty scary to me. You guys feel a
little unquited by this. We all love our
pets. So, let me if I can show you all
how a dog lick or bite can become
deadly. So, dogs and cats normally have
bacteria in their mouth just like we do
by the way, right? And it's not harmful
usually, but if you look closely,
they're there. They're bacteria. Let's
say you're out there playing with your
dog and the dog scratches you by mistake
or nips at you or even licks you, right?
And then the bacteria gets into the skin
into your body through any opening. You
might just touch your mouth and now it's
in your blood. And once it's in your
blood, your immune system usually fights
off the bacteria. Not a big deal. But if
it can't keep up, sepsis can develop
where there's complete loss of your
blood pressure. Your organs begin to
shut down. You can't even get blood down
to the limbs, which means the limbs
begin to die. And when too much tissue
dies, amputation may be needed or even
death can occur to you if the tissue
dies too quickly. Now again, serious
infections from this kind of bacteria
are rare. So Dr. Casey, education is
something that's important, but from
what I can gather, most doctors, and
again, I'd never heard of this, are
probably like me. So to what extent is
this is this real? And how much time do
we have once someone is you touch their
mouth after being licked if they do get
sick? Sure, this infection can have
devastating consequences. I was trained
as a veterinarian and in veterinary
school we learned about this because
it's a risk for us. We are at risk for
being bitten and scratched by our
patients. So it's important to know that
we can get this. There is a need for
increased awareness among the human
medical community and I'm very glad
you're covering this on your show to get
the word out. I I bet you it's a small
fraction of people doctors know this
which is why we need all you spread the
word. The smartest audience in
television if someone gets sick and
we're not sure why just ask this. But
we'll come back in a second. First thing
I want to know how much of risk am I at
my home because I've got the three
grandkids running around a dog and a
cat, right? So, I'm curious if they had
the bacteria. You said 74% of dogs have
it. Is Kisia one of them? So, I I
actually had the vets come over to the
house and had them test my pets and then
they said the swabs that that's Kesia.
That's baby cat there. Not not she
wasn't He's not very happy with that,
right? And I have the results in my
hand. I haven't seen them. So, we're all
going to find out together. Be
supportive, guys. All right.
Khesi came back negative. Oh, one in
four dogs. I would have to applaud
her. Now, baby cat, who's the more
mysterious of the pets, that's the She
came back questionable. It says she has
a different kind of bacteria. They were
worried about it, but it wasn't that
kind of bacteria, which I'm good. I'm
good to go. So, what's important? Oh my
goodness.
What's important is that people should
not be afraid of pets. Animals, whether
they're covered in fur, feathers, or
scales, have the potential to sometimes
carry germs that can make us sick.
Capnoscyophaga is one of those. And it's
important to know that your dog might be
negative today, but maybe you take her
to a dog park tonight, she shares a toy
with another dog, licks another dog,
drinks out of a shared water bowl, she
could become infected. So, there's some
simple things you can do to make sure
you and your pet stay healthy. So, if
people going to protect themselves,
they've got a couple action steps. First
off, don't run away from your dogs. Dogs
are actually very good for us. There are
a lot of reasons besides the fact that
you love them, they love you back, but
babies that are in early contact with
dogs and cats, 30% less likely to get
colds. I wish we had a pill that could
do that. So, it's not bad to be around
pets and once in a while get lick
usually. And I've got to say this, if
you go to a hospital and there's some
strange thing happening that resembles
one of these infections you were talking
about, just tell the doctors, "I've been
around pets. I may have been licked."
That's all you got to say, right?
Simple, straightforward. Seriously,
you'll be surprised how simple clues
like that dramatically change where we
are. To learn more about the CDC's
Healthy Pets, Healthy People program,
you go to dr.com. Dr. Casey, thank you
very, very much. Congratulations.
Godspeed. All right.
Hey, y'all remember earlier we talked
about Liam? Are y'all ready to meet
Liam? You want to meet
him? Liam, come on
[Applause]
out. Oh
my. Can I sit over here? I'll sit next
to
Liam. Can I sit next to Liam? You can
sit next to Liam. How are you? Good.
Good. Are you excited to be here? No.
Now, I understand kindergarten's
starting pretty soon for you. Are you
excited?
Oh, oh,
don't. He's a 5-year-old. All right.
What do you got there for me?
You hold this for one second. I've got
it. What does my shirt say here? It
says, what does it say? The Liam
Project. Oh my
goodness. Uh, skids. Kids steers for
kids. Good for you. And
you really move around. Come on over
here. Look at him go. You don't even
need this wheelchair. And what is What
is this? Can you tell that what that is?
What is this? The skid steer. What is
it? Skid skier. Skid steer. It's a skid
skier. Are these guys all raising money
to help you? Those are actually all the
people that I work with on the line that
build the full-size units. Um we created
a nonprofit called the Liam Project and
we raise money through the people I work
with in different um areas in the
community and we donate those to
different hospitals throughout the
Midwest for the children patients. Good
for
you. You should be very proud of your
parents cuz they're proud of you. Enjoy
kindergarten. He's going to raise hell
there. It's good for him. Oh yeah. All
right. M you're amazing little boy.
Thank you for watching.
[Music]