Today, the twisted love triangle that
led to the murder of a Marine's wife.
This is Aaron, a shy small town girl
from Tennessee. Described as the animal
whisperer by family and friends, she was
gentle with a big heart and kind blue
eyes. She loved horses. Ear first met
John at a neighborhood barn. At only 16,
John asked her parents' permission to
take her on her very first date. After
graduation, he enlisted in the service,
and she would become a young Marine's
wife. But Aaron's fairy tale romance
would soon become riddled with secrets.
Secrets that would end in her
disappearance in California's largest
desert. Take a
look. 142 mi east of Los Angeles, the
last stop on Highway 62 is military base
29 Palms. It's where 19-year-old Aaron
and her Marine husband John Corwin
settled after
eloping. The newlyweds rented an
apartment in a complex just like this
and became fast friends with their next
door neighbors Nicole and Chris. The
couple spent endless hours together.
According to Aaron's mom, sometimes they
would be up, you know, the couples would
be up the majority of the night and then
they make breakfast together. And then
Aaron got some wonderful news. she was
pregnant. She proudly announced it on
Facebook, which made it all the more
devastating, her mom said when she
miscarried. Part of me wanted to go out
there, but I also didn't want to
overstep my bounds. You know, they
needed that time to work together.
But Aaron thought John wasn't
sympathetic enough and started to
withdraw from him. To help with her
depression, Aaron spent a lot of time
here, a rescue horse ranch located near
the military base. She often rode horses
with her new friends Nicole and Chris.
But the owner of the ranch noticed that
Aaron and Chris were getting extremely
close. And she was right. Aaron and
Chris were having a romantic affair.
Ultimately, the affair was exposed. And
shockingly, John forgave his wife and
Chris. John decided he was going to work
through the marriage and work through
this.
And then some good news. Aaron found out
she was pregnant again. Aaron told John
that she was going to wait and tell her
mom in person. So on the morning of June
28th, 2014, Aaron came here, the Joshua
Tree National Park. She told John she
was scouting places to bring her mother.
and the man she was having an affair
with, Chris, was supposed to be at the
same park that day on a hunting trip.
Later, Chris came home, but Aaron never
did. The police had two suspects, her
husband, John, and her boyfriend,
Chris. Bestselling true crime journalist
and author of Secrets of a Marine's
Wife, Shana Hogan, is here. She spent
years in the front lines of this story,
interviewing Aaron's family or friends,
pouring over court records. She knows
this story inside out. Shann, thank you
for being here. Thank you for having me.
Give me a snapshot in the two men in
Aaron's life. Let's start with her
husband, John. What kind of a person was
he? Describe him to us. Yeah, John was a
really quiet, reserved guy. He didn't
really express his emotions. And Aaron
was obviously the um horse whisperer
type girl where she connected more with
horses than she did with people. So that
really bonded them and brought them
together. Um you know a year he he had
early aspirations of joining the Marines
and about a year after he joined the
Marines Aaron joined him in 29 Palms and
I don't think she was prepared really
for how military life really hardened
him. Um they faced financial struggles
in the beginning and um of course the
biggest wedge that drove them apart was
when she had her miscarriage. Yeah. And
he wasn't there for her I guess. um he
just wasn't able to really express the
same level of grief that she was and
that kind of drew them apart. So, let's
go back to that love trial again. The
other part of it is Chris with whom
Aaron had an affair. So, how was the
affair exposed? Yes. Um well, Nicole, uh
Chris's wife started to get very
suspicious of the time that Chris was
spending with his next door neighbor.
And so, um, one night she took the
memory card from his cell phone and put
it into her computer and was able to see
all these messages that Chris had kept
hidden from her. Um, and everyone knew
sadly except for John. And then one
night, um, they were all getting
together for a cookout and Nicole,
Chris's wife, confronted John and told
them about the affair and a a big blowup
fight ensued. Um, and it ended with
Nicole chasing after Aaron, saying, "If
you ever have anything to do with my
husband again, I'll kill you myself."
So, after the affair, I guess,
supposedly ended, what was the state of
each of the marriage? Were they able to
get back together again? Chris and
Nicole were um Chris was about to be
honorably discharged from the Marines.
And so, he told Nicole he wanted to work
it out. He went through counseling and
um they were set to return back to
Anchorage, Alaska, where he was going to
uh go back to school and she would raise
their daughter. Um at the same time next
door, John had forgiven Aaron. Um they
decided that they were going to work
through it. Um and they were seemed
pretty happy. Um and then Aaron found
out she was pregnant again. And that uh
was something that John was very happy
about. He called his dad and said,
"You're going to be a grandpa." And
Aaron decided to wait one week to tell
her mom in person. So, let's go to the
day that Aaron disappeared. What was she
doing in the desert that day? Why had
she gone out there? Aaron had told John
that she was leaving. She was going to
Joshua Tree National Park to scout out
scenic locations to take her mom when
during that upcoming visit. Um, at the
same time, coincidentally, supposedly,
um, Chris was heading out to that same
park, Joshua Tree National Park, for a
coyote hunting trip with his downstairs
neighbor. But the odd thing about it was
once he had got to the desert, um, his
neighbor tried to call him several times
and Chris had turned his phone into
airplane mode. Uh, he texted, he spent
like three hours looking for Chris and
that night Chris came home and Aaron
never did. So, the plot thickens. Yes.
Up next, Aaron's mom, Laura, is going to
join us. Plus, a bombshell police
interview with Aaron's best friend from
home. Reveal something that no one else
knew about what happened that day in the
desert. Stay with us. I love you, Mom.
These were the last four words Laura
Havlin heard from her daughter before
she received the phone call. A phone
call no parent should ever have to get.
her 19-year-old daughter, Aaron, our
Marine's wife, had gone missing in a
desert in California after supposedly
scouting places to bring her mom on an
upcoming visit. And she would soon learn
it was a secret affair that led to her
daughter's murder. Now, Laura joins us
via Zoom. Laura, I know this is hard to
talk about and thank you for being here.
Aaron was not only a Marine's wife, she
was the daughter you fell so much in
love with that you decided to adopt her
after taking her in as a foster child.
What kind of person was she?
Aaron was um very shy and
um she
she even as a baby if someone came up to
talk to her and she didn't know them
she'd kind of give them a drop dead
look. But she was an animal whisperer
and animals could pull her out of her
little reserved self. So, how did you
learn about Aaron's disappearance and
what was going through your head when
you found out?
Um, Aaron's husband, John, called us
about 11:00 that Sunday morning, the
29th of June, and he had asked me if I
had heard from Aaron. I'm like, no, you
know, not. We had talked on Friday. Um,
I had texted her on Saturday and she did
not respond, which was kind of strange
because we texted in, you know, at least
daily, um, and talked on the phone quite
a bit. Uh, then he told me that she was
missing and I'm like, what do you mean
she's missing? And then he told me that,
you know, she had gone out to the desert
to look for places for us to um, take
pictures and stuff when I got there and
she never came home.
That's it's sad. I know it's uh it's
even to talk about it now is painful.
When when you found out about Aaron
having an affair, you thought it was
extremely out of character for her. What
do you think led her to that point? And
how do you think it was connected, if at
all, to her disappearance? I still have
a hard time wrapping my mind around that
because that's just out of character for
her. But I just felt like, you know, she
was going through depression. And I felt
like maybe John didn't know what to do
to help her through that. And
honestly, you know, having lost two
daughters, my husband and I certainly
did not grieve the same way. and being
19 years old, 19 and 20 years old, I
think it
just somehow someway they just could not
be there for each other the way each
other
needed. And so I feel like
um I feel
like you know she was she found someone
that was going to comfort that comforted
her her and quote unquote said that he
understood
her and
um and I just feel
like he used that as a
manipulation to
um gradually pulled her towards him. So,
at this
point, you're at home. You you're on the
phone. You've heard this. You're dealing
with two big issues. Your daughter's
missing in the knowledge she had an
affair. The police have two lead
suspects. Aaron's husband, John, who
you've just spoken to on the phone, who
took a whole day to report his pregnant
wife was missing. And we have Chris, the
man she had an affair with. when the man
you say pulled Aaron, your daughter,
towards him, who also went to the very
same park the day of Aaron's
disappearance.
Yes. Did you have any strong sentiments
about either one of them at that point?
Um, I never suspected
John. I didn't know
Chris, you know, so I didn't have any
way of knowing one way or another.
Um, I feel
like when they found her vehicle without
her near it or in
it, that's when I knew that something
had happened to her.
Laura, thank you very much for sharing
something that's so raw to you. I
appreciate it.
So, let me show all of you a police
interview with Aaron's best friend from
home. Her name is Jesse. He revealed a
secret that would lead police to their
suspect. It is recounted here in the
podcast, Case Closed.
Jesse told the police the affair between
Aaron and Chris had never ended. Aaron
believed she was pregnant with Chris's
baby. When Aaron found out she was
pregnant, did she did she think it was
Chris's or did she think it might be
John's? cuz she was pretty sure. She was
like 90% sure it was crazy. And she told
Chris right away. I know she told him
because they were at one point talking
about
Chris knew about the baby and not only
that, Aaron told Jesse that Chris wanted
to take her somewhere special as a
surprise to celebrate her being
pregnant. They planned to spend the
whole day together. So when Aaron went
to Joshua Tree National Park on June
28th, she was planning to meet Chris.
And on Monday, June 30th, the detectives
found Aaron's abandoned blue Corolla
about 5 miles outside Joshua
Tree. Did police have their suspect? The
answer is next. Plus, an inside look at
the police interrogation tapes that
involve a confession that you have to
see to believe. We are back talking
about how a twisted love triangle led to
the murder of a Marine's wife. Aaron
Corwin. The police now have a lead
suspect, Chris Lee, the possible father
of her child from their secret affair.
In this clip of his interrogation,
you're about to see. Look what happened
when police asked Chris if he had
anything suspicious in his phone search
history. Take a look. I was having a
conversation with one of the guys in the
duty there. Um, it came up randomly, you
know, random Marine talk about the best
way to dispose of the body. And how long
was that? Um, it was the last time I was
on
duty.
So, before I went on
leave, probably just under a month ago.
What' you search on? Uh, we were using
Google on my phone and uh his phone. I
think that their phone. Yes. Okay. What
were the results? What'd you find out?
Um, pigs. Pigs? Mhm. What does it say
pigs do? They eat them. Are you serious?
Mhm. I've never heard of that.
Capitalism. Mhm.
Shocking, huh? Seems pretty clear. Chris
searched for ways to dispose of a dead
body on his phone. That was just a month
prior to Aaron's murder. True crime
journalist Shana Hogan is back. And the
lawyer who prosecuted this case, Shawn
Derty, is joining us via Zoom. So,
Shana, the police at this point were
convinced Chris was Aeron's killer. Why
did all the signs seem to point to him?
Well, first it was Chris's changing
story. Um, you know, after they talked
to Jesse, they knew that Chris was the
one who intended to meet Aaron out there
in the desert that day. Um, then there
was the evidence that was found in the
minehaft. Chris had borrowed a propane
tank and that was found at the bottom of
the mine shaft along with Aaron's body.
Um, also when he was arrested, they
discovered that uh a homemade garat uh
in his mother's car and it was almost
identical to the one that was found
wrapped around Aaron's neck. Also, at
the bottom of the mine shaft, um there
was some DNA evidence that was
collected. There was a sprite bottle
that had Aaron and Chris's DNA mixed.
And then finally, um it turns out that
he was trying to incinerate her body.
So, uh, he had made a homemade torch out
of a Marine Corp t-shirt and that had
his DNA exclusively on it. Oh, so the
propane tank was to throw on there and
he was going to light it on fire
remotely with that? Yes. To try and
incinerate her body. Oh my goodness. So,
Sean, what made prosecuting a case
against Chris so difficult when these
facts seem so cut and dry?
Well, I think anytime uh in a criminal
case, I have the burden of proof beyond
a reasonable doubt to convince 12
people. Um cases really aren't cut and
dry when you get to court. Um initially
the challenge was when I first came onto
the case or learned about the case was
we didn't have a body. Um which leads to
the suggestion she may have ran away. Um
a and when a body and when evidence is
in the desert for that long in such a
harsh environment um evidence tends to
be lost. For instance, um there was no
evidence that Aaron was in fact pregnant
because her body was too decomposed.
I see. So Sean, the defense only called
one witness to the stand and that was
Chris himself. Why was this defense sort
of unusual? Why this tactic is not
common?
Well, his defense essentially was that
one night after um his wife was giving
his daughter a bath, they noticed some
redness on the crotch area of their
daughter. Um his wife, Chris Lee's wife,
wondered aloud if, you know, maybe Aaron
had caused that. Um
he admitted to being in the desert with
her that day. um finally on the stand um
he asked her um you
know essentially the culminated in him
asking her did you touch my daughter
um and did you molest my daughter and he
claims in his testimony
that Aaron said yes but and that's the
last words he heard
um what he was trying to convince the
jury of was that he acted in a blind
rage age. So, it's commonly called a
crime of passion defense.
Um, but really it's a provocation and
you're provoked into this rage. Um, so
in that
respect, it was not only unusual, it was
in my view just disgusting. Um, for him
to make that
claim, knowing that she's not there to
defend herself and knowing that all he
had done to plan it and to even get to
that point. Just to be clear everybody,
Chris admitted that he approached Corin
from behind and strangled her for at
least five minutes with a grat made up
of two pieces of rebar and a cord that
looks like this. Now, Sean, you I
understand you brought a life-sized
dummy into the court to show this murder
was premeditated and deliberate. And if
you can recount that to our audience, I
would appreciate it because it was vital
in the ultimate decision of the jury.
Sure. I
um as I said, I had some indication that
he was going to go with well, I did it,
but I was provoked. Um so, uh I decided
to bring a life-sized dummy into court.
I uh created a Grot on my own. And
during cross-examination, I asked him to
show us how he did it. And I used the
dummy
um and put the Groat in his hands
directly in front of the jurors. uh and
he showed us how he did it uh there in
front of her.
So that's what I did and and I think it
was effective in showing at any given
moment he could have stopped but he
didn't because he thought about life, he
thought about death and he chose to kill
Aaron. Was his defense successful at
all?
No. Um the jury found Tim guilty after
about an hour and a half of first-degree
murder and they found the special
circumstance of a line and wait true. Um
so line and weight is essentially waited
for an opportunity to act
and from a position of advantage killed
the other person in this case Aaron.
So Shannon Chris has been honorably
discharged from the re at this point.
He's planning on returning to Alaska
with his wife the week following that.
Why? Why? Why just go up and run away?
Why kill her? What was the point? Yeah.
At this point, he uh didn't want the
responsibilities of paying child
support. And it's it's really actually
common that women who are killed by
their lovers and their boyfriends to get
rid of the baby to um not have that
responsibility and not have to take care
of it. Just underline that. Did you all
hear that? Murder is a top cause. Among
injury related deaths, only car
accidents are greater than murder for
pregnant women. It's something I'd never
thought of. It's unimaginable. And the
prospect of a new child, particularly if
the pregnancy is unwanted, not only
brings on stress, it also represents a
loss of control, which is what I suspect
was really going on in Lee's mind. So,
if I can ask, what happened to Aaron's
husband, John? Where is he now? And also
Chris's wife, Nicole. Yeah, John um was
honorably discharged early from the
Marines because of this tragedy and he
returned home to Oakidge, Tennessee,
where he um went back to school and got
a job as a welder. Um he ended up
meeting a nice young woman and got
married and has a child now. Oh, good
for him. And Nicole is more of a
mystery. Throughout the trial, she
actually defended Chris. Um she wore his
dog tags to court. At one point, she
confronted Lore outside of the
courtroom. um defending her husband. And
so at this point, I know she's back in
Alaska raising their daughter while
Chris serves a life sentence in um
California, but she has maintained, you
know, stayed stayed by him. Um but the
defense, the detectives and the
prosecutor had actually looked into, you
know, her as a possible co-conspirator
in this murder and at one point, um you
know, we're looking pretty heavily. Um,
so if any new evidence surfaces, there's
a good chance that there might be a
second trial in this case with Nicole as
the defendant. Shana, thank you very
much. Sean, congratulations on your good
work. Shana's book is called Secrets of
a Marine's Wife. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good