He's known by three letters,
BTK. Bind, torture, kill. The notorious
serial killer terrorized America's
heartland and murdered 10 innocent
people. Dennis Rder was living a double
life as a soft-spoken family man and
church leader. And he's been writing to
me from prison. Lots of insights here.
We have these letters today. What do
they reveal about his psyche? and his
daughter Carrie is here finally opening
up years after learning the truth about
the man she thought was a loving
father. For over 30 years, the area
surrounding Witchah, Kansas, lived under
the dark spectre of a serial
killer. One who taunted authorities with
poems, depictions, and clues boasting of
his twisted murders bearing his sadistic
signature, "Be
tind, torture, kill." His reign of
terror began January 15th,
1974. The day 15-year-old Charlie Otero
returned home from school. Moments after
his brother Danny, 14, and sister
Carmen, 13, to discover unspeakable
horror. Alerted by Carmen's screams,
Charlie would find his parents,
38-year-old Joseph and 34year-old Julie,
bound with rope, suffocated, and
strangled to death in their bedroom.
Charlie tried frantically to revive
them. Finding the house phone dead,
Danny ran to a neighbor for help.
Responding officers would find the three
eldest Otto children sobbing on the
front lawn of their home. Inside, they
would later find their little brother,
9-year-old Joseph Jr., bound and
affixiated in his bedroom. Their
11-year-old sister, Josie, would be
found hanging from a pipe, bound and
partially clothed in the basement. Their
brutal, senseless, and sickening murders
would send shock waves through the quiet
Midwestern community. They would be the
first in a series of 10 unsolved murders
that would torment the area and
authorities for more than three decades
as the killer played a twisted cat and
mouse game with the media and law
enforcement before finally falling prey
to his depraved desire to be
acknowledged for his murders when a
floppy disc would link the killer to his
crimes in
2005. The suspect would be shocking.
Dennis Rider, an Air Force veteran and
family man known for his role as a
church and cub scout leader. The
accusation would blindside his wife of
34 years, their grown son, and their
daughter, Carrie. In court, Raider's
gruesome recounting of his killings
would further devastate the families of
his victims and his own. Today, Raider
is serving consecutive life sentences in
prison. But the daughter he raised
continues to struggle with the reality
that the father she thought she knew,
she now knows as a serial
killer. Dennis Rder's daughter, Carrie
Rosson, joins me now. I know this is
difficult to go through and I appreciate
you coming on here and talking honestly
about your dad and your relationship
with him. What kinds of thoughts keep
you up at night when you think about
Dennis Rder? um since the arrest of 14
years ago. I mean, the initial just
running it through my head trying to
figure out was this true and could he
have really committed these crimes, you
know, and who was the man that raised
me? Um like now I still have night
terrors. What happens during your night
tears? Um, so I it's usually I fall
asleep too quick, you know, or I'm very
tired and then within like 30 minutes to
an hour I'll wake up screaming like
screaming full on waking up the house.
Um, I always think there's somebody in
my room there in my bedroom there to
hurt me and I'm it's like I'm trying to
fight them off. Let's unwrap this a
little bit. By the way, night terrors
are pretty common for kids to have,
right? Probably 40% of kids have them.
They said your autopilot just goes
crazy. It's it's it's wired to relax the
lamp, but yours doesn't. Therapy
actually does work often times for it,
but ultimately you got to deal with the
demons, right? Some of the ones that may
be left behind from the interactions
with your dad. How would you describe
what kind of a person he was? He's been
labeled labeled a serial killer, right?
But that's not how you probably saw him.
No. No. Um he was a pretty much good dad
most of the time. Like we camped and we
fished. He was basically my best friend,
my buddy. We would walk the dog
together. That was just something I did
with him. Garden. We built tree houses.
We would run to the hardware store. He
and he didn't just do things with you.
He taught you. So, he taught me about
the outdoors. He taught me how to plant
a garden. He taught me how to fish. And
I was very, very close to him all up
until the day of his arrest. But there
was also that other side of like
occasional anger in our houses, flashes
of eruption, you know, like you were
scared sometimes of who was home and
what he would do. He was like could
undercut you with abuse, emotional
abuse, too. Did he ever physically hit
anything that you ever saw you, a pet?
He did not ever hit me. Um, but my mom
had made this wonderful like dinner of
manakotti and we got into this fight on
the table and my dad like leaped out of
his chair and grabbed my brother and put
his hands around my brother's neck like
from the front and started to try to
strangle my brother at dinner. And when
my dad did that, it was like like it
wasn't my dad for a second. His face
changed. It was like full of rage and
cold and his eyes would narrow. And then
when he we pushed him off, he his
shoulders slumped and you could tell he
felt sorry and realized what he had
done, you know. But honestly, like that
that happened one more time a few years
later, but I don't ever remember talking
about it with my family after that. Ju
just to put it on in context, your
father had actually murdered people
before you were even born, right? He
committed seven murders, including a
family of four, leaving orphaning three
older kids for the Oo family. And then
after the Otteros, he murdered Katherine
Bright who was young over by the um WSU
campus, the college campus in ' 74. Then
he stopped. Then my brother was born.
Then in 77, he married Shirley. He
murdered Shirley Vianne Ralford. She was
a mom and he murdered her in front of
her children. He locked him in a
bathroom. Then in 77 when my mom was
pregnant, um she was three months
pregnant with me. He murdered Nancy Fox.
And I found out in therapy in 15 that
when he murdered Nancy Fox, he took his
belt off and strangled her with his
belt. When I and then I I in therapy
then working through like she took me
back to that and I remembered when I was
four, dad had taken his belt off and
threatened me and I could still see him
loomed in the hallway with a light
behind him snapping that belt at me and
I had completely suppressed that. And
then I and then when I realized what he
had done to Nancy, like the therapist
said that was a major breakthrough to
like pull that back out and have that in
the open and put it in place. There are
these isolated moments. Many of them
you've obscured, you've blinded yourself
to. A lot of us do that in our lives. We
forget the the harmful things we've
experienced. So if you didn't know that
your father was a serial murderer, what
would you say you love the most about
him?
um just that he would spend time with
you and he was kind and like like he
loved you and like he would go to any
any effort to take care of you. So when
I was in college I was 2 hours away and
I didn't have a car so he was the guy
that would drive after work on Fridays
and come get me. The man everybody knows
after '05 doesn't match my father at
all. you know, like when he was
arrested, I tried to alibi him and say
like you got the wrong guy. Like, you
know, he's a church leader, boy scout
leader, a really good dad, except, you
know, for a few incidents, you know, and
nobody would believe me. And my mom said
the same thing, like she was sitting
there with the police on the day of his
arrest saying, "You've got the wrong
man." You know, my all my family told
him that, too. But, you know, and then
you come to find out
like you never knew that person, you
know, but nowadays I try to tell people
like the only man I know is my dad and
that's why I still love my dad because I
have to hold on to that or I'm going to
die or I would be dead, you know? And so
I don't know BTK. It's
taken 10 years in and out of therapy to
even be able to say BTK or look you in
the eyes and say that and sit here and
talk to you. That's why I've never done
media before because I wouldn't have
been able to handle it. So people think
I'm crazy that I still love my dad, but
I don't know anybody else. That's the
only person I know. You know, I think I
think you're very brave for telling your
truth and don't let anyone take that
away from you. It's not your fault your
dad did what he
did. And when we come back, the moment
6-year-old Carrie realized a murder in
her town would change her life forever.
We'll be right back. We're back with
serial killer BTK's daughter, Carrie
Rosson. So, when he was terrorizing that
Kansas town? Mhm.
You were there, right? Were you fearful
as you heard about these crimes, not
knowing it was your own father in your
own house? Well, in so in ' 85 I was 6
years old and our neighbor U Marine
Hedge, she went missing and um 10 days
later they found her body strangled out
in the country um a few miles east of
our church. Somehow at 6 years old I
knew she had been abducted and I knew
she had been murdered and strangled and
a six-year-old shouldn't know that. Did
your father know you were scared about?
did. And I didn't know he knew I was
scared until I read it in Ramslland's
book and he said it worried him that
like the murder of Mrs. Hedge was
affecting me even though he had done he
had done the murder but he also got off
on it.
Got off like narcissist like sexual
sadistic high. That's what he is. This
is a sexual sadistic psychopath. So,
he's basically getting a power trip
because his daughter's now got trauma in
her house. So, I'm six. I knew dad was
gone that night because I knew he was at
a scout camp out and I had slept with my
mom because I was scared cuz we had a
thunderstorm. I knew that at
6. Then when the police come in 2005 to
my house, the FBI, they're telling me
and I'm like, "No, no, you've got the
wrong eye." And I said, "What are the
dates?" Then my then I remember Mrs.
Hedge. my guts just sear in half. And
that was like that first moment that oh
my god, I think my dad murdered Mrs.
Hedge. And and then it came to find out
like a few hours later my dad confessed
to Mrs. Hedge.
When your when you learned that your
father had
confessed, how'd that affect you? You
know, I'm so out of it. I'm so I'm
physical shock for 5 days. I'm shaking.
Come to find out, my dad had taken
jewelry and driver's license from his
victims, and he had hid them in a false
bottom space underneath our um catchall
in the hallway where we rode out
tornadoes. So, I mean, our three
bedrooms were there in the bathroom was
a small three-bedroom ranch. So, you're
walking past where this evidence is for
26 years of your
life. And like, I think the FBI knew to
tell us that so we would know it was
real. So my family knew quite a bit more
before the public did. So we knew we
knew very early on my dad was guilty.
And so then we spent months riding my
dad trying to convince him to plead
guilty. You know, I'm like, you know,
you're guilty. Tell them you're guilty.
Like save the victim's family, save the
community, save our family from like
millions of dollars and two years of
trial, which you see what Golden State's
going through right now. Yeah, like like
just take the plea.
Up next, the day Carrie will never
forget. She's taken us back to the
moment she realized her father was a
serial killer terrorizing their town and
how her DNA helped put him behind bars.
Don't go away. For decades, the BTK
killer had toyed with the Witchah,
Kansas police task force trying to catch
him, sending them taunting letters,
twisted clues, and even asking advice as
to whether a floppy disc could be traced
to a particular computer. Raider
believed the lieutenant who claimed it
couldn't, it could. And when BTK sent a
floppy disc to a local television
station, it was quickly linked to a
computer at Dennis Raiders's church. But
DNA testing would link him to his
killings. Prosecutors subpoenaed a
tissue sample from a papsmear done on
Raider's daughter, Carrie, at a student
clinic near Kansas State University,
which he had attended 5 years earlier.
DNA tests on that sample matched DNA
collected at BTK's first murders more
than 30 years ago. It showed beyond
doubt that Carrie Raider was related to
BTK, that the man responsible for the
brutal murders of at least 10 people was
her
father. We're back with serial killer
BTK's daughter, Carrie Rosson. So, it
was your DNA that helped put your father
behind bars.
Were you aware that your DNA was being
used? No. Um, when the FBI agent knocked
on my door on February 25th,05, I was
still even in my pajamas and the FBI
agent is dropping like the bombshell of
bombshells on me in my kitchen, telling
me he's like, "Your dad is BTK." Like,
he just dropped it like that.
So, we talked for about an hour and then
we got up to leave and the agent says,
"Well, we need your DNA to match it to
some things." And I was like, "What
things?" And he's like, "Evidence." And
he and he didn't know how to collect
DNA. And I said, "You know what? Well,
on CSI, like they grab swabs and swab I
literally said that like swab your
mouth." So, we grabbed Q-tips and swab
my mouth. And I was like the one that
told him how to do it.
This is so bizarre. Now they they had
actually they had already taken my DNA.
So then I think just so they they got
they you had a papsmear, right? They had
actually subpoenaed the papsmear which I
didn't know they could do but without
your knowledge and they got the DNA from
that and that's how they figured this
out. The swab I guess was to confirm
that. I think it was also to kind of
cover their rares like like just in case
in case it wasn't be allowed to be used
in court. Exactly. And so then that was
Friday and on Saturday night CNN ran an
article that was that said I had turned
in my father and I had given blood and I
knew those two things were wrong. I was
very angry and I felt betrayed because
my father had betrayed me. These
institutions that I loved and adored. My
father had betrayed me. Now a few weeks
the media was betraying me. An
institution that I loved journalism. I
love journalism. Now they're stalking
me. So I'm I'm betrayed by the media.
So, I wanted to make sure people
understood at that time that's how I
felt. And it took 10 years before I was
able to talk to a journalist and not be
angry.
I'm glad you're not angry today and
talking to me about stuff that matters a
lot. Right. When was the last time you
saw your father? 2004 in December. We
were home for Christmas. And so, dad
came out of the bathroom. He was in his
brown compliance uniform. He looks like
a county sheriff. He's all got his his
belt his belt on and his gear and his
nightstick. He's like way overdone for
his compliance job. And I hugged him. He
smelled like Old
Spice. He hugged me really tight. He
said, "Um, I love you." Which he hardly
ever said, rarely ever was affectionate
verbally. He said, "I love you and I'll
see you soon." Because they were going
to come up and see us again. And I said,
"I love you and I'll see you soon." And
that was it. He's gone. And
so in ' 05 when I knew I was never going
to see him again, even though I I was
falling apart, I knew to seal that
memory tight. I knew to go back and try
to remember like how he smelled, how he
felt. And I can like still feel him
today because I'm never going to have
that again. And people people are
knocking me still like they're saying,
"You don't have the right to talk about
him. You don't have the right to suffer.
you didn't lose anything. He's a
monster. You don't have the right to
talk. You don't have the right to write.
You don't have the right to
grief. And I would never say that to
anybody about anything. You know, it's I
lost the man that I loved. I lost this
massively important person in my life
and he was taken
away. And I was never allowed to grieve
because you can't how do you have a
funeral for someone that's still alive?
And how do you grieve publicly for
somebody that everybody
hates, you know? So, what do you do? You
just you gather up with the people, you
know, your family, and you try to hold
on and
survive
because I mean, you're not you're not
allowed to do it publicly, you know, and
people are like, "You shouldn't have
wrote about that good decent man." And I
said, "I had to write about the good
decent man. I had to find him again. I
spent years going back in those memories
to find him again because I needed to
find my dad before I could write about
BTK.
Writing books is often therapeutic. It's
cathartic. If you're okay with this, I'd
like you to read an excerpt from
something you wrote. Dear Carrie, I'm
starting to enter a phase in life that
mom may not accept me, and her loyalty
is beginning to weaken. I sent her a
birthday card, Mother's Day card, and no
letter or thanks. Her last letter was a
month ago. Do you think I should still
write? It hurts to write and not get any
reflection.
You write you you say that those letters
anger you. But what angers you the most?
I mean, the letters anger me because you
see the narcissism and I'd never saw it
before. You see, it's about him and why
aren't people calling me? Why aren't
people visiting me? why aren't you, you
know, supporting me in my time of need
in the prison, which, you know, I'm
sitting here trying not to roll my eyes.
Um, what really angers me
are like that public perception that my
family was culpable and that we were
hiding something. And we've always said
that if we had any inkling he had harmed
someone, let alone murdered anyone, you
know, we would have gone screaming out
that door to the police. You don't sit
down with a man and serve him manakotti
if you think he's murdered like even
harm someone
you know and at the very most when I
shared about him hurting my brother like
we thought that was the whole iceberg we
didn't realize it was the very tip and
that there was psych psychosis
underneath it
right the other thing that angers me is
that my dad now tries to throw like his
mother my grandma Dorothia under the bus
like blames her for something wrong with
my dad. My grandma Dorothia and his dad,
my grandpa Bill were the most amazing
people. It's very brave of you to talk
about this. Probably painful as well.
What is your hope? What is your goal
coming public for the first time the way
you are? I want one I realized when
I for 10 years I prayed to God and I
said I want a quiet peaceful life. I
want the media to go away. I want to be
left alone. And God granted that. The
problem is all of that suffering, pain,
everything I'm telling you about times a
thousand embedded in me and it was
rotting inside
me. So it wasn't until after I forgave
my dad, I came back to started to come
back to myself in 2012 and I forgave him
for what he had done to me. The
betrayal, not for the crimes, those are
not mine. Those are the families to
forgive. I forgave him for what he did
to my
family writing. That's how I heal. So I
went and did it to heal. And then
everybody, a lot of people reached out
as soon as I started talking and saying,
"You're helping us like abuse victims,
crime victims, people with criminals in
their family, war veterans with PTSD."
They were privately reaching out and
saying, "Something in your story is
positively helping us with our own
trauma. And after this book, this book
came out a week ago, I am flooded with
messages of people saying you're helping
us heal." Well, I think you did that
today. I thank you for coming on and
stay strong, okay? No matter what. Okay.
You can find Car's book, A Serial
Killer's Daughter. It's available now.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good