An all new Alzheimer's alert. We're
giving you an insiders guide to the
latest Alzheimer's breakthroughs that
you've been seeing in the headlines.
Could your body type determine your
risk? We've not talked about this on the
show before. One body type is at a
higher risk of getting the disease. It's
going to surprise you which one. Plus,
is pasta now a health food booth? The
truth about the new protein pastas.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you back.
[Music]
[Applause]
My team is in direct contact with the
most respected researchers on the
forefront of brain research and
prevention in order to keep you one step
ahead. And today, we're giving you an
insiders guide to the latest Alzheimer's
breakthroughs that you've been seeing in
the headlines with a power team of
experts to give you practical steps you
can use now to reduce your risk. Dr.
Rudy Tanzy is here to tell you what you
need to know about the new Alzheimer's
drug he co-developed that the whole
world is watching right now. Dr. Isaiah
Sherzai, who is going to break down the
latest research revealing how your body
type could affect your chances of
getting the disease, and bestselling
author Max Labir, who made discovering
and sharing Alzheimer's research's
mission after his young mother was
diagnosed. Now, today, Max has three new
genius foods from his book that can help
reduce your risk of Alzheimer's disease.
Max, thank you as well for being here.
Thanks for having me. So, the
interesting thing about this food
pyramid is that you interviewed hundreds
of experts. So, it's a lot of work.
Hundreds of experts thinking that food
is medicine, right? And it turned out
that you literally could turn things
upside down with this food pyramid. What
did you find? Yeah, Dr. Oz, that's
exactly what we should be doing. You
know, we've been given dietary advice
over the past couple of decades that was
upside down, you know. So, what I think
that we should do is invert the food
pyramid. And, you know, we can make some
modifications, too. I think, you know,
vegetables should really be the base um
for most people. But the central thing
that I've learned amid all of the
interviews that I've given is that the
one question that every doctor should
ask their patient is what are you
eating? And this applies certainly to
brain doctors. New research is beginning
to show. Let's get into some details.
So, first of all, this overarching
approach to eating is gaining a lot of
traction among Alzheimer's researchers.
It's called intermittent fasting. Now,
we've talked about fasting
intermittently for people who want to
lose weight, but you say it's actually
essential for brain health. So, walk me
through this metaphor. We got a car.
Yeah. So, your brain, I like to say, is
like the universe's most advanced
hybrid. And like a hybrid car, your
brain can run off of two fuel sources.
Okay? So, for one, we've got gasoline.
In the brain, the gasoline is like the
sugar, the glucose that the brain uses.
And then the other fuel source that the
brain can use is sort of like the
brain's battery, the brain's
electricity. They're called ketones.
Yeah. Now, I like to say that when the
brain is running on electricity, it's
sort of like a Tesla, okay? A very fast
car. On the other hand, when the brain
is using sugar for fuel, it's sort of
like a jalapy. It's chugging along.
Sugar produces exhaust. It produces
toxic byproducts essentially. And
ketones, on the other hand, can be
thought of sort of as like a clean
burning fuel source. So again, the
metaphor is simple. Your car can use gas
and batteries. Your body can use sugar
or ketones. One's a little better than
the other. And as we realize that, we
get to appreciate the power we have as
individuals. So to become more ketone
using, yeah, you suggest intermittent
fasting. And I just put a clock up here.
Walk us through an example of how this
might work. So, when would you stop
eating? Yeah. So, typically what I would
do is I would stop eating by 6:00 p.m.
And then I wouldn't eat anything else. I
would drink water, of course, but I
wouldn't eat any other calories until
8:00 a.m. the next day. What that
essentially does is it allows your body
a chance to rev up that ketone
production that again is like the
electricity for your brain. It's a very
clean burning fuel source. And the
latest research suggests that's actually
a a really great thing for the brain.
Yeah. So guys, is it hard? I don't know.
I Yeah, I I I think it could be a little
bit of a challenge, but getting
Alzheimer's is pretty difficult, too. I
actually am doing a 12-h hour
intermittent fast. So, I'll stop eating
at 8 in the evening, and I'll start my
breakfast at around 8:00 in the morning.
And that's not that hard. Yeah, Dr.
Ross, a really good way to think about
it is that at a certain point in the
evening, like when it gets really dark,
a few hours before bed, the kitchen
closes in the body, so to speak. So at
that point, you kind of want to like
taper off your food consumption and then
start it up again during the daytime
because humans are meant to eat during
the day, not at night, especially not
before bed. Yeah. And then like food
sits in your small intestine. It begins
cause all the problems, but most
importantly for the brain, it changes
the fuel source that we have. So now
that you know when to eat, let's talk
about what to eat. Mac has Max has three
foods that everyone at home ought to be
eating today. He calls them well, I
mean, they're special, but let's clarify
what these genius foods are. You're not
going to actually be smarter
immediately, right? You're not going to
get rid of all dementia with this. You
might feel smarter. You might feel
smarter because you're being smart in
what you're eating. What does it mean to
be a genius food? Yeah. So, these are
foods that have a strong body of
evidence to say that they're going to
boost the way that your brain works
today and also help give it a little bit
of a sword and shield against aging
tomorrow so that you can help fend off
some of these conditions like
Alzheimer's disease. All right. The
first genius food everybody simple in
order to cut your risk of Alzheimer's is
cacao. Right? Cacao is a great source of
polyphenols. We love chocolate. Anyway,
I personally, nobody likes chocolate
here. Thank you. You're going to rush
the stage to get these. How does it
actually help with brain health? Yeah,
so it's one of the top sources of
magnesium, which is very important for
brain health. Keep talking. What you
eating back here? Yeah, it's full of uh
what are called flavonols that um
research shows can actually boost the
way that the memory works. And so, we've
got this delicious cacao powder here. Um
the key when uh you know buying cacao is
that most frequently it's processed into
chocolate. That's typically how we
consume it uh in the United States and
and around the world. Thank you. You
just want to make sure that the
chocolate bar that you're getting has a
high percentage, a high cacao percentage
so that it doesn't contain a lot of
sugar because the more sugar is in the
bar, that sugar is going to negate the
benefits of eating cacao. So you want as
little sugar as possible. We didn't add
sugar to this. Thumbs up or down? It's
good. It's good. M they're happy happy
people. These are made simply with Yeah.
I mean, frankly, it's smart just to eat
them. Period. You might be smarter.
That's up to you. All right. Next. This
genius
food arguably will help with
Alzheimer's, but it's one of my favorite
foods of all, and I have never talked
about it on the show. It's herring. Now,
this fatty fish has landed on the top of
Alzheimer's researchers lists of the
best fish to have, which I didn't
realize. It's even more reason to eat
it. Now, I don't know how good it's
going to go with the chocolate that I
still have in my mouth. But there's
always room for herring. I Oh, this
summer I was eating all kinds of fish. I
was posting on Instagram continually,
but the herring was what got my
attention. I would eat it for breakfast,
lunch, and dinner. It's a top source of
DHA fat, which is an incredible building
block for healthy brain cells. We now
know that the adult brain, you can grow
new brain cells up until your last day
on Earth. So, it's incredible. And the
other bonus feature of herring that uh I
think is super cool, herring is the top
dietary source of a compound called
creatine, which basically helps
supplement brain energy. It helps
support brain energy metabolism. Who has
never had herring before?
[Laughter]
Let me see. Let me see your hands up
again. So many people. All right.
Challenge. Take it there. Okay. Let's
see his smile. Here also he finally
admitted it. Okay. Never had it before.
Watch their eyes. Yes or no? It's a
thumbs up. Not sure. What does it taste
like? It It tastes very fishy and they
can pickle it. Yes. I I taste the
pickling aspect of it. If you like fish,
this is what you want to have. But
herring is inexpensive. Yeah. I'm
hearing not bad. All right. So, the
audience is lukewarm, but I understand
you've never had herring either, Max.
Yeah, I've read about it. I've read
about the benefits, but uh you know, I'm
I've never tried it. So, your your
assessment? My assessment is it's
definitely good. It's it's very pickled.
Um it's it's it's very tangy. Uh and
with that slimy fishlike consistency, um
you know, and with the chocolate that I
had in my mouth. No, Max, stop making
excuses. If you like fish, you guys see
he actually liked it. No, you're going
to like it. It's very It was good. And
you know, just give it a one shot. I
don't have to get everyone in America to
like hear her, but I want it to be on
our radar screen cuz you guys have
forgotten about it. And it is so good.
So good. Take the herring challenge. The
herring challenge. Yes. We'll call it
the lug herring
challenge. The next genius food is
portoella mushrooms. I mean, I love it.
Mushrooms anyway, but why are they so
good for the brain? Mushrooms are a
nutritional powerhouse. Dr. Oz, they're
a potent source of um a powerful brain
antioxidant called glutathione. And you
know, mushrooms are just across the
board. They're full of vitamins. They're
a very low carbohydrate food. You know,
one thing that I like to do, so we've
got porttoella mushrooms here. It's a
really great uh healthy swap to use the
cap of a porttoella mushroom as the bun
on a grass-fed burger. Yes. Yeah. Think
about this. You remember that movement
we had in the '9s? We wanted people to
replace their hamburgers with these caps
of mushrooms. Did anyone go for that?
Like two people in the back and they're
being stoned, right? It didn't have
impressive results. People just didn't
do it. So, we're flipping the script.
We're going to break the stem off.
Right. You can cook this too, by the
way, separately. This becomes your bun.
A non-carbohydrate bun. And then put the
burger on here that mayo, lettuce,
mustard, whatever else. Another one. It
is fantastic. In fact, the bun will be
the burger. And we're going to prove it
to you. We got a recipe video that
you're going to love as we head into the
break. Plus, what your body type says
about your Alzheimer's risk. It is going
to shock you. That is next.
[Music]
[Applause]
Hey,
[Music]
hey, hey.
an all new true crime
investigation. How could one surgeon
harm so many?
I take the fifth. That's coming up
tomorrow.
We're back with Dr. Aisha Sherzai,
author of the Alzheimer's Solution with
another Alzheimer's alert. And pay
attention because we're going to show
you how your body type, the way your
body's proportion, can actually
determine your risk of getting the
disease. Now, take a look at this. One
of these women is more at risk or could
be more at risk than the others for
Alzheimer's. Can you spot the one who's
at risk for their brain health just by
looking at their
body? It's confusing, isn't it? Right.
There's a new study that suggests one
body type is at a higher risk of getting
the disease. It's going to surprise you
which one. So, Dr. Shzai, what would the
research say about which body type is
most dangerous? Can you tell by looking?
I can't, but it could be any one of
them. It actually depends on how the
body stores fat. So, the term skinny
fat, it actually is a legitimate medical
problem where your percentage of body
fat is higher than your muscle. And that
actually puts you at a higher risk for
Alzheimer's disease. So any of these
women Exactly. All right. So being
skinny isn't the goal. No, no, it
doesn't, you know, it doesn't mean
anything. It all depends on how your
body's fat is stored and what is the
difference between the amount of fat and
muscle in your body. All right. So you
call that body fat composition. Exactly.
And just to elucidate this, your body is
made up of muscle and fat. And yes,
there's some water, but we're going to
focus on the muscle and the fat right
now. And the best way to measure your
Alzheimer's risk is actually to look at
this body fat composition. And here's
why. This is a cross-section, for
example, of the thigh, right? And so you
can see that someone can be the same
weight, right? Same same width of thigh,
but this person has a lot of muscle and
not much fat. It's lean. This person has
got no muscle, but a lot of fat, but
they weigh the same, right? Muscle
weighs more than fat, by the way. That's
why fat floats. So you can have a little
bit itty bitty muscle in there with a
lot of fat around it, and you won't
weigh very much. So are the traditional
ways that we look at how much you weigh
and whether you're thin or not, your
body mass index, they don't seem to
work. Absolutely. And and for
Alzheimer's, so what is what should we
be doing? So the most important thing
for us to understand is that muscle
building is very important. A lot of us
may look at a person and you know he or
she may be skinny, but that doesn't
necessarily mean they're healthy. The
content of fat is very important. If
they have more muscle, they actually are
metabolically more active and they're
very strong. They actually have bigger
brains, better brains, and they lower
their risk for Alzheimer's disease. All
right, so if you can't jump on a scale
and figure this out, if you can't look
at a picture and figure it out, yes,
you're left with a whole another way.
This is really important. We've not
talked about this on the show before,
there's a very effective way of
measuring your body fat percentage, and
it has to do with this. Come on over
here, show everyone what this is. This
is a caliper. Well, this is a wonderful
little um you know, you know, thing that
you can buy for five or 10 bucks off of,
you know, the internet or anywhere, but
it actually is quite accurate to tell
you the amount of fat that you have. And
there's a particular way, there's
several ways to measure your body fat
composition. But the easiest way, as far
as I'm concerned, is you check the body
fat in your in your arm. Actually, we're
going to do it together with Leanne,
who's backstage right now. She
volunteered to have her body fat
composition measured. So, we're going to
do it. I'll do it here. She'll do it
there. I'm gonna meet her here in one
second. Excellent. Okay. For those of
you who are at home, you don't have a
way of take of making measurements yet.
We've got a simple checklist, but pay
attention to this because these calipers
are going to be part of what you they're
great for parties. Get them. You can
measure your friend's fat. They're going
to love you. Okay. So, sure they will.
So, so you measure in three places,
right? Okay. So, you're going to measure
it so it relax your arm. So, you
basically find a midpoint between your
shoulder and your elbow and you pinch
your fat. Gosh, it's kind of difficult
to pinch. You don't have any fat. She's
patronizing me. No, no, it's true. Okay,
let's just go and give an example. Give
give the one that everyone's embarrassed
about. This isn't bad. Okay. And then
you do it in the belly. So, you know,
about 2 in uh over your hipbone. So,
somewhere here, you take a diagonal
pinch and then you basically pinch it
like that. And then you hear a little
click and that kind of tells you to
stop. And then you measure it. See, for
example, for you it's about a centime
about, you know, a less than a
centimeter. A little bit. Yeah. And then
you do it in the thigh again. And you do
it in the thigh. You know, a point
between your knee and your hip. And
there's a chart when you get these
things and they are about five bucks.
They're not much these calipers. We'll
tell you where to put numbers and you
can calculate your body fat percentage.
So Leanne from our audience is here now.
Now before the show, she was measured. I
saw you backstage. Hi. How are you? How
are you? Hi. How are you? I have the
calipers, but I'm not going to use them
on you. Okay. What What did they find?
Do you know? I don't know what the final
number is, but I know that I um I am
this skinny fat person you're talking
about. Yes, I heard that. So, what are
you going to do differently with these
results now that you know that you're
skinny fat and you're not alone. A lot
of folks are. Well, I mean, I get a lot
more active. I do I actually have a gy
gym membership. Um, and I go, you know,
occasionally say hi. Um, but I tend to
um I tend to like go straight for the
treadmill with the intention of getting
to the weights and doing all that kind
of stuff, but then I start looking at
the time or I spend more time on the
treadmill than I thought and I just, you
know, kind of ignore them as I walk out
the door. But it's also true for people
who go walking. There folks who go
listen do something that's the benefit
and please do that but in addition we're
asking women especially to do something
that actually allows them to lift their
own body weight. There are many reasons
to do that. We know more and more that
frailty is a major killer but that's not
what we're talking about today. The
frailty was going to hurt you is the
frailty that causes your brain to
atrophy and not be as strong. And the
best news of all was big thighs, big
brain. Absolutely. Hallelujah to that.
All right, everybody. I love that. We'll
be right back.
[Applause]
an uplose look at Alzheimer's in the
brain like we have never seen before and
how these new insights help develop a
new drug that you're going to want to
know about. Stay with
[Music]
us. He's been called a rock star of
science, credited with co-discovering
the first three Alzheimer's genes and
several more since. and now he has
co-developed the new Alzheimer's drug
that the whole world is watching. Please
welcome Harvard neurogeneticist and my
friend Dr. Woody T. Thank you for being
here. I got to tell Dr. Ted recently
told for a quote. He said we'll have a
solid plan for eradicating the world's
eradicating Alzheimer's disease by
2025. I I really trust you. No, I do.
And so when someone like you says that
means a lot to me. What makes you so
confident? Well, I think you know on one
hand we have to cure patients with
Alzheimer's, but we have to also stop
the next generations from getting this
disease. I think there's a true chance
to end this disease over the next decade
because there have been several major
discoveries just over the last few years
where now we know what's going wrong in
the brain 10 or 20 years before the
symptoms occur. So we eradicate it
early. Early detection, early
intervention would be the mantra. All
right. So Dr. has developed a new
promising drug using a brand new
technique that you're going to want to
see. Now, until now Alzheimer's has only
been studied in animals, right? You get
an animal, you create a model for
Alzheimer's, you try to do your best.
But Dr. Tanzy actually created a mini
human brain with the disease. He calls
it Alzheimer's in a dish. And this has
never been shown before on television.
We're going to show it to her for the
first time here. I wanted Tina to be
here. How are you, Tina?
because I think Tina like so many of you
has concerns about Alzheimer's and I
think this will help shine a big bright
light on the problem. So what is your
story? What makes you so worried about
Alzheimer's except that you're like the
average American? My grandmother passed
away from Alzheimer's last year. So I'm
very concerned about I watched her
deteriorate over the years and took care
of her and I'm very concerned of course
if I'm going to get it my mother my
daughter one day. So a preventative
would be great. Well, you know, you
really aren't alone. It's the single
most common concern that Americans are
telling me about. And so, when I see
that many folks worried about it and I
see someone like that who's got some
answers and real opportunities to change
the the course of human history, I want
to bring it together. But I've never
thought I'd see anything like what I'm
about to show you. Right. So, if you
don't mind, walk us through what we're
seeing this brain in a petri dish and
explain why it's so important. Well, you
know, for a long time, we were just
stuck with studying this disease in
mice, and most of us argued mice are not
people. So now we can take human nerve
cells made from stem cells. That's these
and that's it. And we're growing them in
a gel that mimics the brain because the
brain's like jell-o. And these nerve
cells are are interacting the way they
should and forming networks. And then we
can put into them the Alzheimer's genes
we discovered and have them create
Alzheimer's pathology in a petri dish in
a mini human brain organoid. That orange
blob is a plaque. And we know that's
amaloid plaque. That's amaloid plaque
forming in the dish around the green
blobs that are nerve cells. And then we
know that these amaloid plaques form in
the brain 20 years up to 20 years before
the symptoms occur. So this is the enemy
number one we have to hit first. So 20
years gets sort of close to home,
doesn't it? Yeah. Is your mom still
okay? My mom's still okay. All right.
But you start to worry with 20 years.
That's the head start that you need. All
right. So I'm going to show you
something now that really caught my
attention. So these little green things
are are are brain cells. And notice
there's a brain cell here with a little
green line going to, you know, out to
the distance where it talks to other
brain cells. Right now this is the part
that's sort of cool. These are all those
amaloid plaques you showed. Oh, these
are the little uh uh what are called
micro gleal cells. They're the they're
the they're the sentinels and
housekeepers in the brain that normally
keep the brain clean. Got it. Like
during deep sleep. All right. So you
have a green good brain cell, good guy,
and you have these garbage men or
sentinels. Yes. Okay. And normally
they're cleaning the brain, but when
they sense something's wrong, like the
plaques and the plaques in in the dish
called cause what we call tangles inside
the nerve cells, they say, "We got to
wipe out wipe this area out. We got to
take these damaged nerve cells and
remove them." Even if the nerve cells
are helping you, even if it's your best
connection to what your grandmother's
name is, that's the issue. Collateral
damage. Uhhuh. See? So watch this video,
okay? Watch this green line. Watch what
happens to this cell. So these guardians
now, they start to attack it. See them
eating away at it. And as they do, they
chew it up and all of a sudden you begin
to invade the space of the of the brain
cell. And so now you understand what's
going on, right? So these so these cells
that normally are protecting the brain
when they sense something's wrong, take
it out. They're taking out the bad nerve
cells, but by friendly fire, they take
out the good ones too. And now this is
when you go downhill. Now this has
significant implications for how you do
stuff because Dr. Tany has a new drug
that he developed that's designed to
stop this from happening. Right? Right?
So the tangles that confuse the
guardians don't ever form. The neurons
never die. Right. And and the whole idea
here is to do it early enough before the
symptoms occur just like we do with
other diseases. Alzheimer's has to catch
up to that. I hope that's helpful. I
hope so. Thank you so much. Glad you
come on over here.
And I want you all to understand this
mindset because it'll give you great
confidence. You actually described
amaloid fighting, you know, pushing
those plaques away similar to the way we
think about cholesterol. So you're
actually calling it a statin for the
brain if we can make a medication to do
it. Yes. My colleague uh Dr. Steven
Wagner at UCSD San Diego and I developed
a drug that will bring the amaloid
levels down in the brain. But it has to
be very safe because this is a drug like
a statin you might have to take for 10,
20, 30, 40 years. And that drug was
developed with the help of this dish.
And now we're going to be heading into
clinical trials hopefully by the end of
this year or next year. End of this year
uh if things go really well. But
definitely we think by next year. Yes.
Can I just show you what Dr. Katan is
talking about when it comes to these
cells. So I've got a regular old match
here. Okay. And I light this match and
this match as it gets lit up, right? It
imagine it as a formation of amaloid,
right? That's the equivalent. Now it's a
precursor to what will become full-blown
Alzheimer's, which in the case of this
match is like a forest fire erupting
behind me, right? So this big fire is up
there and drugs in the market now are
essentially are blowing out this match
in an attempt to extinguish the force
fire. Does that make any sense? Right?
It's not it's not going to work. You
need to do something a lot earlier to
make a difference before the symptoms
have gone so far. We need to stop the
amaloid plaques 10 to 20 years before
the person shows symptoms. And that's
what this drug is called GSM. GSM. Yes.
Yeah. That's that's the idea. So we
would use the GSM in someone who has
high plaque in their brain but no
symptoms with early screening. Right now
it's brain imaging but blood tests are
on the way. So just like you test for
cholesterol, you test for your amaloid.
Bring it down if you have to. That's
going to be the future of ending this
disease. Oh my goodness. So it raises
one other major question. When we come
back, should you get the Alzheimer's DNA
test right now since we have something
you might do about it? Stay with us.
Very well done.
Dental scams. Six cavities when I was
told I had none. You just don't know who
to trust. All new Oz Undercover. We were
shocked at people being overcharged or
they're being overdiagnosed. That's
coming up Friday on Dr.
[Music]
Oz. Should you get the Alzheimer's DNA
test right now? The FDA has approved
direct to consumer genetic testing, but
is it right for you? How many people in
the audience would be interested in
their genetic test for Alzheimer's?
Yeah, it's a lot of folks, but not
everybody. How are you? Hi, what are
your thoughts about this test? Um, I'm
very interested in taking the test um to
see if I'm at risk. So, any concerns,
for example, if we come back positive?
Well, yeah. I see people how they
deteriorate when they are diagnosed and
I just want to know if there's something
I can do um ahead of time to prepare
myself and my family. You're a very
thoughtful woman. This is not the way to
think about it. But I want to take Dr.
Tany through this so you all understand
exactly what these tests are and what we
can do about it. Is that good? Yes. All
right. So, Dr. Tang is going to walk us
through three things everyone needs to
know before taking the Alzheimer's DNA
test. The first is your DNA is not
protected by HIPPA, right? So, it's not
confidential really as much as you might
want it to be. Well, yeah. I mean, the
problem is if with life insurance or
long-term disability, theoretically a
life a insurance company can ask for
your genetic data, even if it's from a
direct to consumer test. And um you
know, that could in the future, we don't
know, that could lead to denial or or or
increased premiums. So, you know, once
that information is out there, it might
go anywhere. Personally, I'd rather
know. You know, I get all the
theoretical issues that's been told to
me in the past, but I want to know
because it's my life I'm talking about,
and if someone else finds out about it,
I'll deal with it then. All right.
Second big issue is that your genes are
a measure of risk, but this is
important. They're not a diagnosis,
right? So, there are very rare genes we
discovered um that can cause Alzheimer's
for sure at a very early age, but that's
only 1% of cases. In most cases, it's
genes that have common variations in
them that increase your risk, like
ApoE4. that that gene variant increases
risk two to threefold if just one parent
gave it to you. If both parents gave you
one, then your increased risk is 10 to
14fold. But here's the thing, not
everyone is the same. Other genes can
offset the risk. Your lifestyle can
offset the risk. Yeah. So, just again
said if the APOE E4, that's the thing
you were just saying about if it's
positive, which is the test that is
being looked at right now, that's what
you'll get back when you spit into the
tube. It's not a diagnosis. No, it just
says you have increased risk and in some
people it can can create a lot of panic
as you might imagine. But you have to
remember there are about three dozen
other genes that can offset that risk
and your lifestyle can offset that risk.
So APOE4 positive is not a death
sentence. It doesn't mean you're
guaranteed to get the disease. People
need to know that. It means you have to
be more diligent. Early detection, early
intervention, keep track of what's going
on so you can take care of yourself. But
let's address the not what because
whether you have it or not, you got to
be doing these things. But especially if
you have APO4, you got to pay attention.
So Irene is joining us. You did one of
these mailaway DNA tests. Yes, I did.
Are you okay sharing your results or Oh,
absolutely. No, it's fine. It shows that
I have a propensity to get the disease.
So, I'm concerned because my f it's in
the family. My father passed, his three
of his siblings passed on the male line.
I have two brothers still living and my
son. So, I'm concerned for them and
myself. So, again, you got dealt a bad
card, but you're allowed to shuffle the
deck again. Yeah. That's really what
we're doing today. So you want to walk
us through? Sure. Sure. So we like to
call this shield and each letter start
stands for something. S is sleep. Sleep
eight hours. During your deep sleep
after you're dreaming, this is like
mental floss for the brain. It's when
the brain cleans itself out like scrubby
bubbles. So you have to get try to get
eight hours of sleep. Even if it's not
all at once, even naps are good. Handle
stress. Meditation practice. Stress is
bad for the body. It's bad for the
brain. So dealing with your expectations
of others or or meditation practice is
great. I interact with others. You have
to interact. Friends, family, don't stay
home, right? You have to get out there
and talk to people. Your brain loves
that. It's good for the brain. And your
loved ones who had Alzheimer's probably
became isolated. Yes, they did. Right.
In during the course of their illness,
and that just accelerates that I fall
off the cliff then. Um and and the E
stands for exercise. We just had a big
uh uh paper in the journal science
showing exercise induces the birth of
new nerve cells in the brain where
Alzheimer strikes and in mice can
reverse the cognitive problems and it
also gets rid of the inflammation. So
that's a exercise has never been more
important. Learning new things like we
are right now that means you make new
connections in the brain and Alzheimer's
dementia comes from losing those
connections. So the more you make in
advance it's like money in the bank. So
you want to learn as many new things as
you can and finally diet. Nothing's
better than the Mediterranean diet. And
that's that's not just because I'm
Italian, but but but seriously, a
Mediterranean diet that's more
fiberbased, plant-based, nut- based,
less red meat, more fish, or even a
vegetarian source of protein is great
for you because that fiber is what feeds
your bacteria in your gut, your gut
microbiome. And believe me, there may
be, you know, probiotics people take,
but there's nothing better for your gut
microbiome than feeding the ones you
have and keeping them happy with fiber.
When you give them fiber, those bacteria
make chemicals that reduce inflammation
in the brain. You're worried about your
dad, I understand. Yes, I am. Because
when I first realized there was
something wrong, he was watching the
same movie over and over and denying he
saw it and it shocked me to the core.
And I cried. First of all, I know what
it's like. We all had roses like that.
But when I see something like this up
there, Yeah. stuff that you can begin to
incorporate into his life right now.
Yes. That can give a little extra time
at Dr. Tanzy. That's the power that you
have, right? That's why this show
exists. That's why all the folks
watching right now can make a
difference.
We're going to put a one sheet with the
full shield plan. Shield. Remember that
the acronym on dr.com. Dr. Tandy, thank
you very much. He's got a fantastic
book. His latest one's called the
healing self. The man's a wonderful
writer. He actually play he's a
musician, right? You going to brag or
should I brag for you? Oh, you can do
it. Aerosmith. Now you think about that.
A true true rock star. I'll be right
back.
[Applause]
Up next, the food investigation. You've
been craving the truth about new protein
pastas at your supermarket. Is pasta
really now a health
[Music]
[Applause]
food. All right. Is protein packed, high
fiber, low carb. What am I talking
about? Vegetables, right? No, not now.
I'm talking about the latest claims
surrounding pasta. New protein pastas
out there make it sound like everyone's
favorite carb could be a health food.
But are they really? Today, a new food
investigation. The truth about the
protein pasta trend showing up in your
supermarket. They're all around the
place. Here to help break it down, food
journalist Mark Scher. Everybody knows
that pasta's been on forever. Public
enemy number one for dieters. Mark says
pasta's everywhere again with these new
noodles. So, are they really the answer
to everyone's pasta prayers? I think
they are an answer. Now, the first thing
I'll say is I think regular pasta can be
part of a healthy diet. Some people
really struggle with carbs. They get
carb cravings. They don't like the way
carbs make them feel. A lot of people
have been trying to reduce the amount of
carbs in their diet. Well, the pasta
industry has responded. We've got these
pastas. I would also say though, you got
to use your you got to use your head a
little bit. Eating these pastas is not
permission to have two or three bowls.
It's also not permission to have a
double cheeseburger with extra cheese
for lunch the next day on the side. Be
smart. Yeah, they feel like regular
pasta. They look like regular pasta.
Find out about them. I got some carb
loving pasta fiends over here. They say
they are boiling with questions. Pardon
the pun. Are you ready? Pasta lovers.
Yeah. What do you want to know? We're
going to start off with Nicole. What's
in them? What's actually in those pastas
I was just holding. All right, Maddie,
your question. Is it actually healthy
and low carb? Is it worth it to switch?
Which is my key question to you, Serene?
Ooh, how's it taste? That's That's the
big one for me. How does it handle? All
right, so we're gonna ask you all, but
let's start our investigation. We're
going to start off with Nicole's
question because it's important. What's
actually in these protein pastas? So,
you researched this and how do you take
beans and turn them into bean pasta? How
does that magic happen actually? Well,
and it depends. They're not all the
same. So, sometimes it's just one
ingredient. These beans with water
become these. Other manufacturers start
adding things. They'll add things like
Zantham gum, tapioca. They're trying to
get the texture to be more like regular
pasta. We found one brand that had 15
ingredients. 15. That's always my
hang-up cuz when you make something
synthetically resemble what it comes
with in nature, that's the problem with
gluten-free foods for me. Exactly. Is
this just another example? I think a lot
of consumers are getting a little edge.
You start to get that alchemy. So, but
what I would say people need to do, read
the label. The shorter the ingredient
list, the better. But the number one
thing is if you're buying a black bean
pasta, then black beans should be the
number one ingredient. What I get
worried about is somebody's just going
to start adding a little black bean
powder to a regular pasta and say, "Hey,
it's black bean pasta." So here you have
bean, bean flour, and water. That's
that's like the ultimate. And and the
shorter the better. And there are brands
that just have those. There are brands,
yeah, that are that simple. That makes
it easy. You can pronounce all those
ingredients. Okay. Next question we
heard is, are they really that much
healthier? Let's start off with the
protein element, right? So regular old
pasta comes in two main forms. here,
right? The we look at a lot of major
brands out there to figure out. So, what
do we find out with regard to protein
just between regular pasta and whole
wheat, which is today the standard for
being healthy. Okay. So, yeah, good old
regular pasta is six grams of protein
per cup. Six. Now, things improve a
little bit with whole wheat pasta. You
get up to eight grams of protein per
cup. Well, that's a big difference.
Yeah, sort of. We'll see. It gets more
interesting. All right, the quick
question. Which pasta that we're talking
about today had the most protein per
serving? So, it the brands vary, but
consistently the one that came out on
top was red lentil pasta. Red lentil 14
grams. And you like cooking with red
lentils? Absolutely. Why so? Okay. The
first thing I like about red lentil
pasta is that it's made from something
real. What I'm not into are these things
where they add like a protein extract
and and everyone's pretending it's all
the same. The second thing I like about
this is the way it tastes. Now, this
issue about taste is critical. A lot of
folks say, "Well, does this compare to
my my friendly neighborhood simolina
pasta, the traditional one I grew up
with?" That that's the wrong question.
The question is, is this good enough by
itself? And we need to start asking the
question that way. That way, we stop
having these false decisions about
whether it's good enough. Exactly. And
don't don't pretend it's something that
it isn't. Embrace it for what it is. All
right. Next up, a lot of these pastas
argue that they're high in fiber. Some
are better than others. What is the best
in terms of fiber? Best across the board
is black bean pasta. If you're looking
for fiber, that is the choice. All
right. And for years, the the folks who
were pastic argued that the carbs were a
problem. Which of these new protein
pastas is the lowest in actual carbs?
Yeah, the lowest in carbs is a relative
new player. Pasta made from green peas
has 27 gram of carbs per cup. That's
like half of what you get in regular
pasta. So, that is a significant
difference. Yeah. I would thought the
beans would be lower, but in peas, peas
we go. All right. Pasta lovers are here.
They're trying this now. Pastors, before
you taste, you've heard the whole
presentation. We've answered all three
of your questions. High level thoughts,
but have we changed your in your first
instincts about protein pastas? Uh, yes.
I'm curious to try them. Curious enough
to try. That's a step forward. These
people are skeptical. The caller makes
me really nervous that it's bright
green. Yeah, it is a weird color. But
you do see that in Italy they make pasta
with spinach. Yeah. All right, Mark.
Thank you very much. Lots more in his
book, The Dorito Effect. Check it out.
It's very well done. and check out the
full guide to healthy pasta. Dr..com. Up
next, the taste test results are
revealed. Plus, Chef Rob is here with
the protein pasta cooking hack is so
darn good, it tastes like eating the
real thing. There he is working hard.
Chef
Rob, I love getting to talk with you on
my show every single day, but when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your
[Music]
podcast. If you love your pasta, but you
stay away from it because of all the
carbs and calories, well, get ready
because we have the skinny on the latest
protein pastas taking over your
supermarket. We've been investigating
the truth about these new noodles and
now the tasty tricks to making these new
pastas taste like the real thing. And
who better than chef Rob to teach us
about this.
There are so many folks complaining
whining. We heard our taste testers at
the bike club earlier speaking about the
fact they don't like the color, they
don't like the texture, this and that.
What's the key to making these new
proteinrich uh pastas taste like the
real thing? Well, I personally don't
mind them at all. You know, I like peas.
I like uh what was it? Lentils and black
beans, all these things. So, it doesn't
bother me at all. Um, what I like to do
is just pair it with a simple sauce. So,
um, you know, it's it's fall, so I'm
thinking, you know, butternut squash,
right? Oh, it's the best. So, so what I
did was I made a butternut squash pasta
sauce. You know, that this is the star
of the show. Um, so I take butternut
squash, a little bit of celery, carrots,
onion, and garlic. Toss it in a bowl
with some olive oil, salt, pepper, pop
it in the oven. So, this is basically
your tomato equivalent cuz it's the
fall. Well, yeah. Yeah. I mean, tomatoes
good all year round, but I wanted it to
be, you know, everybody expects a tomato
sauce, so, you know, get funky with it,
right? Get funky with it. Perfect. Okay.
So, so I roast it all up. Okay. You put
it in a blender with some veggie stock,
a little tomato paste, a little either
raw uh honey, which is my favorite, or
maple syrup, natural sweetener, right?
And some goat cheese in a blender. Blend
it up. Pop it in a pot. It's warm.
You're done at that point. All right. I
give you some numbers here. I think look
that I I love the taste of the pasta
sauce. I love these pastas anyway. But
here's what I really love. of the health
benefits. 211 calories and 40 grams
normally for your regular old flour
noodles right for these pea pasta
various 191 calories 27 gram of carbs
and you're cutting it by 30 40%. It's a
big big deal. Absolutely. But I've
learned after 10 years of making this
show they don't actually taste my taste
buds as much as they taste their taste
buds. Right. So I brought three of our
harshest critics here who have been
chowing down. My pasta lovers are back
for a taste test. All right. Who wants
to go first? Nicole, you're up first.
It's really good. It's
um a good way to get my daughter to eat
her vegetables. You can't even tell. You
can't even tell. No. Oh my goodness.
That's a That's a real tribute, Maddie.
It's really hearty and filling. Like I
feel like cuz that was the one thing I
was concerned about if I would feel as
full. But I feel like with this you
wouldn't feel like as bloated and things
like that after sometimes you eat pasta.
It's re It's really great. And you get
the ultimate vote here. A thumbs up or
thumbs down for Chef Ro's creation. You
might be up to something here.
Is that three of three? That's three or
three. Three of three. And and and if
you want to get really funky with it,
you know, when I did it at home, uh I
put I put a little bit of corn in there.
I sauteed some mushrooms and I I took
some smoked salmon and just like cut it
up and folded it in there and I made a
lot of people happy. Yeah. The guests
are still there. Yeah. I I'll make it
four for four. This is really really
great. But you got to admit the
underlying pasta is a superstar. Right.
A toast Chef Obe. Yeah. All right. Thank
you. Thanks to all my pasta lovers. You
can get the recipe for this butternut
squash bis pea pasta on dr.com. I'll be
right back. Eat these protein
pastas. An all new crime investigation.
How could one surgeon harm so many?
I take the fifth.
That's coming up
[Music]
tomorrow. Today, breaking nut news. I've
always celebrated the health benefits of
walnuts and
pistachios, almonds, but now there's
even more reason to indulge. Brand new
research has found that nuts like these
may have fewer calories than we thought.
Here at the scoop, food journalist Mark
Shazer, how do we finally discover the
truth about these? I have been bragging
about them. I personally eat them by
probably my most common source of
calories and now I get a discount. Yeah,
it's really interesting. So, here's what
happened. Scientists at the Agricultural
Research Service looked at almonds,
walnuts, and pistachios. They asked an
interesting question. How many calories
are in them? But also, how many calories
are getting in our bodies? What they
found, there's actually a lot of
daylight between these two. That a lot
of those calories that we eat nuts are
going right through us. And that's good
news because a lot of us are trying to
cut back. Take us through this. Let's
find out how many calories our favorite
nuts have. We'll start off with almonds.
Almonds. So, about 23 almonds in an
ounce. That's a quick warm-up for me. We
thought that was 160 calories. Turns out
it's 129. Way less. Yeah. Big, big
difference. 30 calories less. Yeah.
Almost 20%. Absolutely. And it gets even
more interesting. Walnuts. Now, walnuts
have always been good because they're
high in omega-3s, but 11 walnuts, 1 oz,
has 185 calories. There's always this,
oh my god, they're so high in calories.
Turns out wrong. 146 calories. 40
calories up almost. Yeah. So that's
that. Yeah. It's it's a it's a
significant difference. And then over
here with pistachios, not as big of a
difference. We thought 1 oz had 162.
Turns out
154. It's about 5%. Not insignificant.
5% is still something, you know, worth.
And it's about 40 pistachios in an
ounce. Is that right? Yes, exactly. So
you get, you know, you get give rough
idea of how much is normal. So why does
it matter that you're
showing somewhere between 10 20%
difference in most of these nuts? Yeah.
Well, you know, nuts have always been
confusing because on paper they were
high in calories. So a lot of people are
running around saying, "Don't eat nuts.
Don't eat nuts. Nuts are terrible." A
lot of people got frightened of nuts.
They were considered junk food. But then
other realms of science were giving us
these interesting signals. People who
would eat a lot of nuts, they would lose
weight. It seemed to be part of a
healthy lifestyle. So what's going on?
Well, now it seems we have our answer
that there's actually we're not getting
all the calories from the nuts that we
eat. So, does this mean we can eat as
many nuts as we want? So, here's what I
would say. If you if you hear a piece of
nutritional news and your first reaction
is, "So, you're saying I can eat more?"
Maybe not the best strategy. But what I
would say is find a way to incorporate
nuts into your diet. If you like to
snack on potato chips in front of the
football game, have nuts instead. If
you're a little peckish an hour and a
half after dinner, just grab a little
handful of nuts. They're satisfying,
they're delicious, and they're way
better than we thought. It's brings so
much more clarity to my mind. Mark,
thank you as always. Everybody remember
change is happening. Our journey is just
beginning.
[Applause]
[Music]