Today on Odds, $1 fast fixes for summer.
A dollar may seem like a small amount,
but today I'm going to reveal some big
ways it can help you see how to soothe
sunburn. The $1 solution for the pain of
sunburn is get bronze without the burn.
Use coffee grouch, prevent bug bites, is
much cheaper than buying a cottonilla
candle, and so much more. Plus, simple
tips to slim down for summer and beyond.
Coming up next on Dr. Oz.
[Music]
In a
world where everything costs a lot of
money comes a new world order. Where a
dollar is more than just 100 pennies.
You don't need to spend a lot of money
to get healthy. It's the fast fix
solution your health never saw coming.
So, I'm going to show you another dollar
fast fix and it works for Oh. from the
creators of $1 fast fixes part one and
two comes the health blockbuster of the
summer. Who's had a banana today? You
rub it on the areas that are, you know,
dried out, the damaged skin. This is
amazing. It's the best. Starring Dr.
Mett Oz and Oh, great. his viewers.
World premiere today. It's the best $1
fast fixes for summer as you've never
seen them before. You may never look at
a banana the same way
again. It's
fast. That's right. A dollar may seem
like a small amount, but today I'm going
to reveal some big ways it can help you.
It's the $1 fast fixes for summer show.
Let's get right to it. First, the summer
sun. I love being out here getting all
this. But sometimes we got problems like
Debbie over here. You have a $1 solution
for a sunburn. And here's why. Because I
understand you actually got a sunburn.
Yes. What happened? How could this
happen to you? I went out for one hour
to take a walk. And who knew in one hour
that I could get burned that badly? It
was just this week. Here's the picture
of her. And the $1 solution for the pain
of sunburn
is aspirin. You used aspirin, but not
the traditional way. No, we used it
topically. Uh, my daughter, her friend,
we were all burned, so we decided to try
the aspirin. I know you're a big fan for
its
anti-inflammatory capabilities. So, we
decided to see what we could do
topically. And we smashed it up, simple
as that, into a fine powder and added a
little bit of water and made a paste.
And it was as simple as that. We just
put it right on the burn. And how long
did you leave it on for? Maybe 20
minutes. Okay. Are you ready for a
before and after picture? You saw the
before. There was an ugly red burn just
a few days ago. This is 24 hours later.
Isn't that amazing?
I love that. What is it? I got to say my
advice is to avoid the burn in the first
place. But I know I know you want to get
some color. So I had Dalia who watches
the show post a $1 fast fix to help you
get bronze without the burn. It's a
self-tanner. You want to know how she
did it? How do you bronze without the
burn? You use coffee grounds. Had you
ever heard of that before? No, never.
So, she made a little video so you
wouldn't make any mistakes. Take a look.
Hi, Dr. Oz. My name is Delisa and I want
to be bronze while staying healthy. So,
my $1 summer fix is for self-tanner. I
take one cup of coffee grinds and mix it
with three to four tablespoons of olive
oil to make a nice thick paste. I take
the paste and rub it all over my body
and wait 15 to 20 minutes before rinsing
it off. I towel dry and voila. Look at
the difference.
That is a great result. You want to try
it? Sure. Okay. Grab my speech chair. I
It's all yours. Get working on cuz I
want no more burns for you or your
family. Set set the right example for
those kids. Enjoy yourself. You'll wipe
it off later. Try it. I'm saying it'll
work. Trust me. All right. Next, let's
get to the summer lumps and bumps. Hya
is here with a $1 fast fix for blisters.
You want to show show it to everybody?
Yes. It is deodorant. And this with this
deodorant, if you come over here, I'll
show you real quick. You pop your
sneaker off. You find your trouble
spot and you just put the deodorant in
your shoe. You do the shoe and the foot
or just the shoe? Just the shoe. And
that's going to prevent the friction
between the shoe and the foot. And that
will stop the blistering. And you can do
it on the toes, on the heel, wherever
your severe blistering spots are. And
why do I have to put it on the shoe and
not on the sock or my foot itself? It
needs to have the stability so it can
prevent the friction. Not on the sock.
On the sock. Do it right on the sock.
Yes. You got to put it on your foot. I
like your authoritative approach to
this. It's good. All right. And and you
you apply it every time you put the shoe
on. Um you only should have to do it
maybe once or twice. And even for people
who wear heels, you know, you're having
that hot night out and you suddenly Oh,
my foot. Just get a little bit of
deodorant, stick it on the back of your
heel, dance all night. I like that hot
night hot move you were giving me.
That's good. All right. Thank you very
much. Appreciate Dalia. Next story is
here. She's a $1 fast fix for vetting
bug bites. Yes. What do you get for bug
bites?
Dr. Oz, I'm a holistic health coach, so
I'm always looking for ways to avoid
chemicals, right? Lucky for us, bugs do
not like the smell of lime and cloves.
Oo. So, this is much cheaper than buying
a citronanella candle. Obviously, much
safer. Your children and your pets won't
be injured if they um touch lime and
cloves, smell it, smells like Christmas
in July, right? That's really strong.
You can put that with that uh deodorant
over there. You know, people know you're
coming by. I know. So, you can place
these around your deck in the yard. You
can even have your children help you
create these. A fun little project. They
can be your centerpiece. Yeah. What ever
gave you the idea of trying this? I
actually learned this in school. In
school? Yeah. So smart. Congratulations.
Thank you very much. I love it. Kathy's
got a $1 fast fix for razor burn. Very
common this time of year. Yes. I have
spent probably most of my adult life
looking for a solution for those red
bumps that you get. So, um, my solution
is the cucumber and milk and I mix it
into a froth that I apply actually more
in almost like a shaving cream and I use
it as I shave and then I also apply it
topically afterward for about 10 minutes
and I have no bumps and no burn like I
used to in the past. It's just locked in
there. Yes, it smells good. It does. You
just put a thin little layer on. I do.
It actually it it applies really nicely
and it it softens your skin. So, it's
it's a great fix. And is this store in
this pretty well? It it stores well. I
like this. These are all wonderful tips.
I appreciate it very much. Thank you.
All right. Now, we're going to move on
to the barbecue area. My favorite part
of summer. Same as a $1 fix for a
healthy kebab. I love kebabs. You know,
Turks, they eat kebabs all the time.
Yeah. Yeah. Barbecue. Pure with metal
and everything. Yeah. Or the wood. Or
the wood. That's good, too. But we have
a new one. You do? Rosemary. Rosemary.
Yes. Yes. Oh my goodness. Rosemary.
What? Why rosemary? Because it has so
much more flavor than just metal or any
wood. And then it's very affordable. You
guys don't have to spend as much. Show
me how you do it over there. Okay. Plus,
if I bite into it, I won't break my
teeth, which is sort of nice. Right.
Exactly. So, you want to get a nice
thick strong stick and then you can fill
it with all of
your [ __ ] right? So, you can fill it
with all your favorites. I see there's a
lot of vegetables up here. You're a
doctor, but I personally I would want
like a lot of meat, you know, give me
some chickens. Well, compromise, right?
Chickens, right? You screw the whole
chicken with this thing. Yeah. Pieces of
chicken. Yeah. Some beef up there.
That's great. So, yeah. Basically, yep.
You want a nice thick stick and you just
you might want to sharpen the edge a
little bit. These are pretty sharp. How
much you going to do with them if
they're any sharper than that? I mean,
it's not put an eye out with these
things. This Yeah, but you know, I think
the taste will be really cool with with
the sage as well. Yes. It gives it so
much more flavor. It's wonderful idea.
Thank you very much.
And that's you got a $1 fast fix for
cleaning your grill. May I show it to
everybody? Yeah. This I got to say I I I
heard about this. I did not think it was
possible, but I just demoed it and this
is really cool. Amazing. It is simple,
quick, and healthy. So, I from
California, we grill all the time.
Backyard barbecues, we barbecue at the
park. And you know, who likes dirty
grills? And cleaning up the dirty grill
afterwards. It's It's so long and it
takes a long time and it's so hard. But
I have a simple solution. So, you can
just grab an onion and all you do is cut
the onion in half and you lay it flat on
the grill and you just scrub it
down. Just scrub it all the way. Now,
look at this, guys. This is so
cool. cow. And then look at that. It
comes right off. Wow. Isn't that
something else? Yeah. That's a good use
of an onion. Enjoy California with All
right. And a bonus $1 fast fix. This
dates back to the times in ancient
Egypt. They used to use this to treat
sore throats. It was a marshmallow
plant. How many of you seen marshmallows
growing on
plants? One person in the back. So, you
know, that's what a marshmallow plant
looks like, that little picture. But
it's not to say marshmallows obviously,
but the marshmallows that you recognize
and that I love that you usually grill
all the time for dessert, you can
actually use marshmallows to soothe an
itchy, sore throat from summer allergies
works differently than the ancient
Egyptians version, but it still works.
Today's marshmallows work because they
have gelatin in them. The gelatin may
coat your throat, which can relieve any
of that pain in the back of your throat.
Just don't overdo it, obviously, because
you'll be wearing these on your hips
otherwise. I love getting these fast
fixes from you. They work so well and we
love spreading them around. So send me
your favorite $1 fast fixes for summer
on my Facebook page and they may end up
on the show. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
[Music]
What's your favorite and effective home
remedy? Whenever my children have a sore
throat, I make them gargle with salt
water for 1 minute and then drink a big
mug of hot tea with honey. It works
every time. Share yours on
facebook.com/dos.
Next. Is bathing suit season making you
anxious? Summertime is a great time to
jump start a healthy lifestyle. Don't
rely on short-term fat diets. Eat your
way naturally to a better weight. The
forever slim down plan to prepare for
the summer and beyond.
Next, the anti-aging plan to look and
feel like a 10. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz,
we're tackling the biggest signs of
aging from the inside out. Fine lines,
wrinkles, dull complexion, and thinning
hair. Plus, the total 10 just got
easier. Dr. Oz has the shopping list of
everything you need. Stock up on the
fundamentals. It's the next step in
dropping those pounds. That's coming up
tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
Oz. Next Wednesday on Dr. Oz. I go to
bed late and I wake up early. I really
need something to get me going. Sound
familiar, folks? Reclaim your energy.
Dr. unveils the busy woman's oneweek
recharge in less than 4 minutes a day.
And you know what? It's actually kind of
fun. A plan to keep you going all day
long. I stand on my feet for 9 hours a
day. It just gives me that extra push.
That's coming up on
[Applause]
[Music]
Wednesday. Beach weather. It means it's
time to slim down for summer and you
don't need to rely on short-term fat
diets to do it. So today we have a
forever slim down plan from My Good Life
magazine created with the worldrenowned
experts at Canyon Ranch. It's going to
help get you ready for summer and
beyond. And stick around. We're going to
also tell you how you can enter for a
chance to win the ultimate wellness
getaway at Canyon Ranch. All right,
nutritionist Carrie Glman is here to
walk us through this forever slim down
plan. So, why is summertime the perfect
time to jump start a healthy lifestyle?
It's perfect because the sun starts to
shine and the tank tops come out, the
bathing suits come out, and people think
crash diet. Well, we know that leads to
yo-yo dieting, and that's not a good
thing. I like to think of summer as the
perfect time to not crash diet for, but
implement the behaviors that will be
long-term and long lasting for
sustainable weight loss. Remember,
stuff's cheaper that's good for you,
like fruits and vegetables, and you also
have the motivation, those tank tops and
other bikini like items to look better.
All right? And the sunshine and you want
to exercise more, right? Let's go over
to talk about it being a VP. VP means
volume produce. You want to fill up on
all this stuff. Summer produce again,
it's high in flavor. It's the best
nutrient content you're going to get all
year long. What are the stars of the
program? Okay, so I love veggies
because, as you just said, high in
volume, water volume, fiber volume. I
love veggies. Like we've got zucchini
and cucumbers and lettucees and onions
and tomatoes and peppers. All of these
veggies are going to fill you up, keep
you fuller longer because again, when
you're enjoying the sun, you don't want
to feel hangry. That's right. And so,
one of my favorite ways to fill up is
with a salad or a soup before the meal.
Soup actually will help you eat less
calories at the overall meal altogether.
So, something like a spacho loaded with
vegetables and again that liquid volume
there will help fill you up. You've got
also the benefit of the fiber in there
and the antioxidants will als which will
also help protect your skin from the
sun. Little little bonus there. A little
kick in it. And it's got a kick which
also by the way the spiciness which
we'll also find in this corn salsa over
here actually also helps to satisfy you
when something spicy that alone can help
reduce your appetite. So this corn salsa
I also love cuz first of all corn is in
season. Delicious. Again, all the
vegetables for the uh water and the
fiber volume. And again, so much better
than those creamy fatty dips that you
see at BBQs. Well, I love both these.
We're going to put the recipes up on
dr.com if it's okay, so you can all make
them yourself. Now, I want to talk about
the next big item. I want you to eat in
threes to balance that carb cravings.
It's an important step. I'm going to
show you. I have a little seesaw I built
for you. I want you to remember this.
When we eat carbs alone, like a Danish,
for example, they initially spike up
your energy, but then when the blood
sugar comes back down, you have nothing
left behind. It wears off quickly. You
have to eat a lot more carbs. You not
just one dish, but three more. And all
those continue sort of weigh down on
you. Not only do you gain weight, but
you don't have the energy because
there's no lasting power to the carbs.
But when you choose the right carbs and
you pair them with healthy fats and
protein, your seessaw of life, your
energy, it balances out. Stable blood
sugar, stable energy, and guess what? It
makes it much easier to burn off any fat
because you're going to feel like
exercising. So, you want to eat in a
balanced way like this. I think if we do
this the right way, it makes it
enjoyable. So, we sent a recipe to Jill
from the experts at the Canyon Ranch,
and here's what she made for us. Now,
you're just your regular audience
member. No formal training. No formal
training. You just took the basic expert
nutritional advice. And what have you
made for us? So, Dr. Oz, when I got this
recipe, I was so excited to find out it
was oatmeal. My family and I love. It's
oatmeal. Oh, it is. Yes, it is. But it's
better than just regular oatmeal. So,
this recipe you actually make the night
before. I don't know about you, but the
mornings are crazy. in my house. So,
it's fabulous to be able to just get
something to go. So, it's basically
Oops. You make the recipe with rolled
oats, Greek yogurt, milk, and chia seed.
You put it in the container, you put the
lid, you put it in the refrigerator
overnight. Next morning, you stir it,
mix in berries, flaked coconut, nuts,
whatever is your preference, and you're
ready to go. I love that. Fabulous. I
love that. It's perfect. It's a perfect
balance. You're getting the carbs from
the oats and the berries. You're getting
the protein from the yogurt and then
you're also getting the healthy fat from
the coconut and the seeds. Delicious.
Perfect balance. Long lasting energy.
And it was so yummy. I made a couple. I
actually had one last night for dinner,
too. Perfect. Eating in threes works.
Thank you very much for sharing with us.
Thank you. All right. Appreciate it.
Next on the
tip idea has to do with a different way
of thinking about dessert. I want you
thinking about a fruit as dessert. What
you make for us, Carrie? Okay, here's
the thing. If you're going to fire up
the grill, you might as well get use out
of it right through dessert. And we know
that all those chocolate chip cookies
are not really or pies are not the best
thing at a barbecue. So, I love grilling
fruit. So, here we're going to throw in
some lime juice. We've got some honey
here. You can whisk away. You told me
you're a good whisker. So, I I've
high cinnamon. Whisk away there. And
then we can just brush on the pineapple.
Show the wrist. You know, Carrie, it's
an excellent job. Look at that. Look at
that whisking. About everyone can whisk
like that. Amazing. And then we're just
going to brush on right here onto the
pineapple. Just like that. I like to use
the whisk for that. And then perfect,
perfect, perfect. Excellent job. And
then right over here, already already on
the grill, we have the pineapple. And
all you need to do is grill it about 3
to 5 minutes on each side. Absolutely
delicious. I mean, actually, when I was
looking at this before, I was thinking
that this could almost be the main
course instead of the burger. It looks
so satisfying. Let's Let's Let's cut
that baby up and see what we got. Let's
do this. Here. I'm going to cut this up
for you. I'm a sloppy barbecue guy, but
I know how to eat. Okay. Here. I'll I'll
let you cut your You know, I've been
replaced in my house. My My 15-year-old
is a better barbecue than I am. I was
going to say most families have the
master griller. I was going to ask you,
are are you the You're not You're not
You've been replaced. I have trouble. I
never was. I'm not patient enough. I
never wait for the charco the charcoals
to get hot. Oh, it's so good. Delicious.
Right. can totally take the place of
those cookies or the pie with the
whipped cream. Guys, what we just gave
you is a very straightforward plan. It's
effective. It works. You go to dr.com.
Enter now for your chance to win
roundtrip tickets for two and a four
night stay at a Canyon Ranch resort.
Take advantage of it. And be sure to
check out my magazine, The Good Life.
News stands now for more natural ways to
slim down. You know what audience? I
love you guys so much. Everyone is
getting a copy today. We'll be right
back.
[Applause]
Thank you.
[Music]
How do you stick to your diet? I allow
myself to cheat one day a week. It keeps
me focused on eating a healthy diet for
the other six days of the week. Plus, I
never feel like I'm depriving myself,
which is key to keep me on track. Share
yours on
facebook.com/dr. Next. Not feeling so
hot about fitting into your summer
wardrobe? It's right around the corner
and you need to get into those shorts.
The fitness guru is back with his thigh
and booty blast. The workout regimen to
get you ready to make a big splash in
your summer attire. Next, Dr. Oz's
newsletter delivers information right to
your fingertips. Get Oz's daily tip,
recipe, and a sneak peek of today's show
in your inbox every morning. Sign up at
dr.com. The anti-aging plan to look and
feel like a 10. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz,
we're tackling the biggest signs of
aging from the inside out. fine lines,
wrinkles, dull complexion, and thinning
hair. Plus, the total 10 just got
easier. Dr. Oz has the shopping list of
everything you need. Stock up on the
fundamentals. It's the next step in
dropping those pounds. That's coming up
tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
We just found out what to eat to slim
down for summer, but if you want to get
back into your shorts, you got to move.
So, fitness guru Richishi Masusa is back
with his thigh and booty blast. So, why
do you sing out the thigh? The legs and
the thigh area. Why is that so
important? It's all about the booty
right now. The booty is in. I mean, pop
stars are singing songs about the booty.
They're doing music videos about the
booty. Everyone's posting pictures of
themselves on Facebook and Instagram
showing off their fabulous booties. I
mean, seriously, who doesn't want to
turn to the side, look at themselves in
the mirror, and think, bam. Right now,
that would hurt. To get that pain, I
hurt. You got to work those glutes. You
got to work those outer thighs, the
inner thighs, and the quadriceps. All
right, so we want some ladies who want
very attractive thighs and tushes, too.
Come on out, ladies.
[Applause]
That hurt me. Ow.
That hurt. All right, take it away,
Richie. We want to do squats with the
booty bounce. Okay, so we're going to do
squats with the booty bounce. So, we're
going to put our feet about a shoulder
width apart. Now, we're going to make
pretend we're sitting down in a seat.
Sit down. Now, come up and tighten that
booty and down. And booty. Now, this is
working the quads and this is working
the glutes and down. Now, we're going to
add some flavor. We're going to spice it
up. You're going to go down. Now, you're
going to lift that leg back and down.
We're adding spice. And backice and
down. And back. And down. And back. Now
we're going to come down. We're going to
hold it. Time for the booty bounce. And
one, two, three. Booty bounce. Five,
six, seven. Up on eight. And repeat. And
down. Two. You feeling that burn,
ladies? How often you do this? You're
going to do these every other day. And
up. I mean, Benny's two season's right
around the corner. So you got to work
hard now. No time to waste so you look
fierce in your swimsuit. All right, side
series. So now we're going to do the
side series. You're going to lay on your
side. And now you're going to bring your
legs into a tabletop. You're going to
reach that top leg straight out. And
you're going to flex that foot. Now
you're going to lift that leg up and
down. We're working the outside leg, the
abductors or the abductors. And lift up.
And lift up. And hold. And little
pulses. Up. Up. Oh, it's uncomfortable.
Yeah, that's right. Burn, baby, burn.
And now we're going to stack the knees
on top of each other. We're going to go
to a dog and a fire hydrant. We lift
that whole leg up. Now lift the whole
leg up. Don't pee on your leg. And down.
And up. And down. And up. And now up.
And hold. And little circles. Ah.
Circle. Circle. That's right. Oh my
goodness. And circle the other way
around. This is uncomfortable. Did you
guys expect this? All right. Now cross
that top leg on top. Reach that bottom
leg down. Flex that foot. Now you're
going to lift that bottom leg up and
down and up and down. This is for your
inner thigh July. Up and down. It
doesn't move and
leg and little pulses. It doesn't
move. Now we move up. Up and hold. You
got to be kidding. You got it. And relax
down. Oh my goodness. That's good. So,
now we got one more exercise to do. You
good, ladies? We're going to do donkey
kicks. You're going to bring your hands
right underneath your shoulders. Now, if
anyone has any wrist problems, you can
modify this by going on your forearms.
Okay? So, now we're going to reach that
right leg back. You're going to bend the
knee, flex the foot, so you're in a 90°
angle. And now, you're going to pulse up
and up. Now, this is what's going to
give you that bam look, ladies. And hold
it up again. And up. up. This is working
those glutes. Now hold it. Booty bonus
up an inch. Oh god. And relax down.
Child pose. We got to go right to the
other side. Now lift the other leg up.
And you're going to reach up. Up. Now
how long yours is so I get my booty to
be like yours. Well, it's got to be in
shape for the summer. So you got to work
now. And you got to do both sides. We
don't want to see any lopsided booty
judies out there. So you got to lift up
and hold. Booty bonus of an engage and
relax down. Now you guys got to do these
exercises. If you commit to them, you'll
be the one posting those pictures, those
bootylicious pictures on Facebook and
Instagram. It doesn't hurt anymore. Look
at that. Right. Take us to stretch as we
stretch. All that booty work. We got to
do a stretch. So lay back down on your
back. You're going to do the figure four
stretch. You put your f your your your
ankle over the thigh. You're going to
reach that right hand through the hole
and you're going to grab onto the back
of the leg and get that nice stretch. It
feels so good. I like this. And now
switch it to the other side, guys.
Listen, while we're doing this, you can
watch Richie's full summer stim workout
on dr.com. Oh, this feels good. We'll be
right back.
What do you use to measure your fitness
progress other than your weight? It's
not a metric, but I can always tell how
I'm doing by how I feel while I'm
running. If I still feel good after
three miles, that's how I know that I'm
doing a good job on my fitness routine.
Share yours on
facebook.com/d. Coming up next, most
women don't get enough of it. An
ingredient that can not only help you
lose weight, but it might protect you
from heart disease and colon cancer.
Find out how much you should be getting
in your diet. Quick and easy ways to get
the fiber fix every woman needs.
Next, the anti-aging plan to look and
feel like a 10. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz,
we're tackling the biggest signs of
aging from the inside out. Fine lines,
wrinkles, dull complexion, and thinning
hair. Plus, the Total 10 just got
easier. Dr. Oz has the shopping list of
everything you need. Stock up on the
fundamentals. It's the next step in
dropping those pounds. That's coming up
tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
Then on Thursday, she went from PTA mom
to the heroin addict next door. I knew
through my high school kids who was
dealing it. He showed me how to smoke
heroin for the first time. Are
overprescribing doctors the root of
addiction. That hopelessness of knowing
you're going to die and in such a dark
place when you do. The nationwide
problem that's finally getting
attention. What was your rock bottom?
When did you realize that a PTA mom had
become a junkie?
That's coming up on
[Music]
Thursday. Hipped inside this box is the
one food almost 90% of you aren't
getting enough of. To give you an idea
what that means, that's this entire part
of the audience. Only you folks are
getting enough of this stuff. Just a
little bit of us are getting it. It's an
ingredient that will not only help you
lose weight, but may protect you against
heart disease and colon cancer. And it
is pretty simply stated, fiber. All the
foods that have fiber. So, today I have
a fiber fix for every woman because many
of you need it. Mary is joining us. How
are you,
Mary? So, look at all this all this
fiber that we're missing in our lives.
And a lot of people don't think about
fiber too much. When they do think of
it, it's not a good story. So, what
comes to your mind? I think of those
bland, tasteless fiber bars, like
cardboard. Yes. Why would anyone eat
that? I don't know. I don't like them.
But, you know, fiber is so much more
than that. And that's why we're here
today. We're going to talk a little bit
about it. Come on over here. I'm going
to play a little game with you. I put up
pictures here, foods that a lot of us
like. Some of us, some of us may know,
they sort of look healthy. Which of
these foods do you think has a lot of
fiber? Pick three that you think is are
rich in fiber. Um, broccoli.
Broccoli. Apples. Apples. Raspberries.
And raspberries. Well, what do you
think? Pretty
accurate. That's a very mixed response.
It was actually a trick. They all have a
lot of fiber. Every one of these things,
the oranges, the peas, the beans, they
all have broccoli, you happens to have a
bunch, but raspberries have even more.
Pears, big rich source. Nuts, all of
them. The question then becomes, how
much do you need? And why aren't we
putting this into our diet? So, I want
to change your mind about fiber. I
brought an expert in nutritionist and
author of the healthy mind cookbook.
Rebecca Catz is here. Hi, Rebecca. Hi,
Mary. Nice to meet you. So, why do you
think people aren't getting enough
fiber? I think people have a real
misconception about fiber. I think
people think it tastes like cardboard,
wood chips. Yes. Right. But some of
those words we used earlier today. Yes.
And I think you know fiber is like
little the food that has contains fiber.
It's like little vacuum cleaners.
They're going to make you regular, make
you feel good, make you feel satiated.
How much do we need for a woman? Well,
we need about 25 grams and we're
probably getting somewhere around 14.
All right, let's move on here. Rebecca
says they're quick fixes. We have to get
those again. 25 grams of fiber. You're
only halfway there roughly. This is
something that I really like a lot. This
is pistachio nuts. I don't know if you
eat them very often. I like pistachios.
Explain why pistachio nuts are a
favorite of yours. Well, they're like
eating. They're like the butternut.
They're incredibly satiating. So, you
could make a basil pistachio pesto. You
could make a kale pesto. You could just
carry them around in a little bag and
just munch on them. And a quarter of a
cup has got about four grams of fiber.
So, you're on your way with these little
tasty bites of yum. It's pretty good.
So, if you look at these things, they
have three times more fiber than, for
example, cashews, which I happen to also
like a lot. And if you just eat once one
ounce of them a day, it's 50 pistachios.
You can spend a lot of time opening 50
little things up. So you won't eat too
many of them, which is good news as
well. So it's a fantastic way of dealing
with a snack or you get the fiber you
needed. You can put a little garlic or
chili pepper on them, spice them up a
little bit. Customize them to what you
like. But I'll tell you what, pistachios
don't taste like cardboard to me. No,
not at all. Right. Second big uh fix for
fiber is avocado. And avocado is sort of
interesting food because a lot of folks
don't eat that many of them. Are you a
fan of avocados? I'll have it on a salad
or a sandwich or guacamole. Does Does it
taste like cardboard to you? Not at all.
I like avocado. Thank you. Audience,
question for y'all. Just real clear on
this. Is are avocados fruits or are they
vegetables?
Why are they fruits?
Oh, the smartest audience television.
It's a fruit because they have pits.
They are fruits. So, so it's one of
those fruits you can have, but it
doesn't, you know, there's not a lot of
sugar in them. What do you Why do you
like these so much? Again, these are so
satiating. I mean, oh, it's like again,
it it's just like little magic carpets
going back and forth on the taste buds.
So, you know, you can put them on
sandwiches, you can make a guacamole,
you can make an avocado cream and use it
instead of mayo. And one avocado has got
10 grams of fiber. Okay, the last one is
a controversial fiber fix. It's Brussels
sprouts. So, what is it about Brussels
sprouts that give them a bad rap? Well,
you know, as a chef, I can tell you that
in the old days growing up, I think we
all
experienced boiled Brussels sprouts that
were kind of stinky and they look like a
Seattle drizzle. But really, the best
way to cook a Brussels sprout is to
roast it. So you toss it with a little
olive oil, a little maple syrup, a
little dijon mustard, put it on a sheet
pan, roast it for 15 minutes, and one
cup of Brussels sprouts roasted, which
are like nice and sweet and a little
crispy. That's about three grams of
fiber. They're great for irregularity
for everybody out there. The one catch
on these is they sometimes cause a
little gas. Does that ever happen to
you, Mary? I avoid them for that reason.
You is that right? Oh, that's Look, gas
is a natural process. Everyone in this
room has already passed gas once. You
probably have too since we've been doing
the show. Get your Brussels sprouts in.
You can find 50 more fiber fixes on
dr.com. We'll be right back.
[Music]
[Applause]
What's your favorite fiber richch food?
I've loved prunes for years, and now
that I know they're packed with fiber, I
love them even more. I make sure that my
kids eat some throughout the week as
well. They really like the taste. Share
yours on
facebook.com/dos. Coming up next, she
found strength and courage to not become
a statistic and found inspiration while
in a jail cell. A visual power to change
her destiny. The inspiring woman
teaching you how to make your dreams a
reality. Coming up next, the anti-aging
plan to look and feel like a 10.
Tomorrow on Dr. Oz, we're tackling the
biggest signs of aging from the inside
out. fine lines, wrinkles, dull
complexion, and thinning hair. Plus, the
total 10 just got easier. Dr. Oz has the
shopping list of everything you need.
Stock up on the fundamentals. It's the
next step in dropping those pounds.
That's coming up tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
[Applause]
Oz. If you ask Lucinda Cross how she
found the inspiration, strength, and
courage to fulfill her dreams, she'll
tell you without any shame or drama.
Inspiration came to her in a jail cell.
It's all about going from vision to
manifestation. Lucinda Cross has always
been a go-getter. If you give me that
one talent, I won't turn back. If you
show me what that one talent is, I
promise I won't disappoint you.
She's an internationally known
motivational speaker and best-selling
author. But long before her success, she
admits to making a big
mistake. One that stopped her life cold.
I was young going to college, freshman,
made some poor choices, struggling
financially, and it landed me in big
trouble.
Lucinda was caught transporting drugs
for a Nigerian drug cartel. She spent 5
years in a federal prison inside. No one
talks about dreams and goals and
visions. There's no aspirations. There's
no hope and there's no programs for
empowerment.
So Lucinda used what she had, glue,
pictures, and paper. In prison, she
created her first vision board, a tool
to help visualize her goals and achieve
the things she desired. I had a fear of
being judged. I had a fear of being
rejected. I had a fear of being looked
down upon. And so I cut out pictures of
people in audiences cheering with their
hands up. So I imagined that they were
cheering for me. Another vision board
while in prison, getting an education. I
knew I needed my degree. I knew I needed
higher education. That vision came true.
After leaving prison, she went back to
school and got that degree. And that
inspired Lucinda to create more vision
boards to reconnect with her family, get
a job, and find true love. I wanted that
man, that night and shining armor. And I
started to see the things that I put on
my vision board come to
fruition. My goals, my aspirations, it
started to come to life. To pay it
forward and to show others the power of
vision boards, Lucinda regularly hosts
vision board parties. She also created
Activate, a leadership organization to
encourage women to activate the power
within. You got to pump yourself up to
get in the ring of life every single
day. Cut out the vision. Cut out the
images. Cut out the life that you desire
and you'll be living it before you know
it.
Send the cross is here. What a crazy
story. How difficult is it to have
dreams when you're in jail? It's
extremely difficult. No one talks about
what you can achieve when you're
released. They only focus on what did
you do to get there. And many people,
even myself, you feel like your name is
tarnished and you just want to give up.
You didn't want to be a statistic, which
I can completely understand because
that's how many folks, whether they're
in jail or not, feel. How did you use
these vision boards to change that? I
used the vision boards to just get me
focused. I used the vision boards. They
the boards taught me that what you focus
on, you become. And you know, I'm
becoming something great. It's sort of
like the law of attraction, which I know
a lot of folks have talked about in
different ways, but if you select
positive pictures and words, you're
going to be able to and begin to
manifest those things into your life.
So, listen brought two of our vision
boards with her today. Come on over. I
want you to walk us through these.
Explain how these work for you. There
sort of examples what folks can do at
home. Absolutely. So, it's more than
just cutting and pasting. So, one of my
vision boards is my 2015 goals. And
that's the far one over there. That's
the far one over there. my goals and and
I put words and put them as a focal
point so that I can focus on them as if
I've already accomplished them. Got it.
And then there's my professional board
which I'm extremely excited about
because I made a bold move and I put my
face on the cover of Essence Magaz Oh my
goodness. That's pretty cool. Yeah.
Just to show you this in this vision
became a reality. This is an issue of
Essence magazine from this year. There
she is. just where she put
herself. So, let me ask you the the
tough question. I mean, anyone can, as
you say, cut and paste, put pictures
together, they can paste their face on
top of of a model on a magazine cover.
How do you take that vision board and
make it into reality? So, just to be
clear, it's more than just cutting and
pasting and creating this pretty
collage. You have to take action. You
have to believe in yourself. And you
just have to know that, you know, the
things that you focus on can come to
fruition. Um, and I go through something
called the five Fs, you know, faith,
family, friends, finance, and fitness.
And making sure that health is number
one because without health, Yeah. is
nothing. It's a good life vision board.
I love it very much. You've inspired
many people that you don't even know to
reach their dreams. We've got people
writing to us wanting to thank you for
that. How does it make you feel? Oh my
gosh, it feels amazing. It does. It
feels amazing to know that you're
working in your life's work. You're
fulfilling your calling. You're doing
what you were called to do and at least
changing a small portion of your world.
I love when people have been to hell and
have come back and tell the story of
success. God bless you, Linda. Thank you
very much. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Whoever said a doctor's visit isn't fun
has obviously never been to the Dr. Oz
show. Is that right? Make your
appointment today. Go to
dr.com/tick and sign up for free
tickets.
All things Oz are online. Watch the show
clips that you love and exclusive
content that you won't find anywhere
else. Hit play at
dr.com. The anti-aging plan to look and
feel like a 10. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz,
we're tackling the biggest signs of
aging from the inside out. fine lines,
wrinkles, dull complexion, and thinning
hair. Plus, the total 10 just got
easier. Dr. Oz has the shopping list of
everything you need. Stock up on the
fundamentals. It's the next step in
dropping those pounds. That's coming up
tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
Oz. Next Wednesday on Dr. Oz. I go to
bed late and I wake up early. I really
need something to get me going. Sound
familiar, folks?
Reclaim your energy. Dr. Oz unveils the
busy woman's oneweek recharge in less
than 4 minutes a day. And you know what?
It's actually kind of fun. A plan to
keep you going all day long. I stand on
my feet for 9 hours a day. It just gives
me that extra push. That's coming up on
[Applause]
Wednesday. The anti-aging plan to look
and feel like a 10. Tomorrow on Dr.
We're tackling the biggest signs of
aging from the inside out. Fine lines,
wrinkles, dull complexion, and thinning
hair. Plus, the Total 10 just got
easier. Dr. Oz has the shopping list of
everything you need. Stock up on the
fundamentals. It's the next step in
dropping those pounds. That's coming up
tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
[Music]
This is not hocus pocus. Researchers
have found there's a medieval concoction
that may actually help cure the MRSA
superbug. The recipe, which dates back
from the 10th century, calls for, listen
carefully, garlic. That's the book it's
in, by the way. The garlic. Put the
garlic in there. Minced up a little bit.
A little bit of onions. Imagine making
this thousand years ago. Some leaks.
That's all pretty normal. You could do
that at home right now. Then they add
the wine. They had to have wine. They
didn't have water that was clean, so
they always used alcoholic beverages for
that purpose. But here's the part that
might be hard to find these days. This,
my friends, is is bile. It smells like
bile. Bile from the stomach of a cow.
I didn't make this thing up. There it
goes. Right. Put the whole thing in
there. And all you got to do is mix it
up. And then this mixture, you brew it
in a brass vessel, purify it through a
strainer, and you got to let it sit for
nine days. It sounds ridiculous, doesn't
it? Scientists found that this potion
kills 999 of a thousand of these MRSA
bacterial cells in mice. They have no
idea why it works, but a thousand years
ago, they made this thing up and it
still works today. So, I'm intrigued by
it. Now, it's time for in case you
missed it. First up, we talked about
dollars. The dollar sounds doesn't sound
like a lot of money, but you'd be
surprised at how far it can go for you.
Summer's almost here and many of you are
probably opening up your grill for the
first time in months and probably need
some cleaning. So, instead of buying
expensive cleaners, today's $1 fast fix
is to use an onion. Cut the onion in
half like this. And then rub it like
that. You got to heat up the grill a
little bit first. Don't burn your hands.
And watch what happens. That, my
friends, is pretty cool. You can get
your grill clean. Everyone's happy. You
haven't spent any money. Next, if you
want to slim down for the summer and fit
back into those summer shorts, you got
to move. Got two wonderful victims here
today. You You know the moves today?
Okay. So, we're going to do this is a a
thigh booty blasting move. If you do
both of them together, you can do it
anywhere you want. It starts with squat.
Everyone stand up for a second here. You
guys can do this part. It's so easy to
do. So, you know how to do a squat. So,
three squats down. Remember, your knees
don't go in front of your knees. One,
two, knees right on top of the toes. And
then three. And here's where it gets
hard. Bounce up and put your left leg
straight back. You guys can't do that so
easily. Oh, stop complaining and whining
up there in the top row. Other leg down.
The other leg again. One more time. And
then back to the right leg. And then you
end it with the booty bounce. Ready? Go
down. Boom. And just keep bouncing right
out the commercial. I'll see you guys
next time. I like your booty.
[Music]
[Applause]