As the cost of medicine skyrockets,
people are going to dangerous lengths to
get their prescriptions. That's a real
issue for me. We go undercover into the
black market of diabetes medication. I'm
on my way to buy a box of insulin pens.
I really have no idea what I'm walking
into. Plus, dollar store beauty finds.
We'll show you what to avoid. Those are
red flags. Coming up next.
[Music]
season 10 starts now.
What if the medication your life
depended on tripled in price seemingly
overnight? There's a lot of anger and
desperation as the prices of insulin
keep being hiked up, forcing frustrated
families across the country to make life
or death decisions, including buying
insulin on the black market. Today, an
undercover investigation into the black
market of diabetes medication. What are
you really buying?
[Music]
Insulin prices are skyrocketing, some
increasing by almost 600% over the last
decade. A vial of this essential
life-saving diabetes medicine selling
for around $35 in 2001 can now run
upwards of $250.
As insulin prices surge, so does the
black market. With private individuals
illegally reselling insulin online, I
see why buying this way is attractive.
Price differences are significant. The
average cost for a 100 units of one
brand is around $35.
But on a classified ad website, someone
was offering it for $100.
I wanted to find out who is doing this
and why. So, I began making purchasing
arrangements. I appreciate you getting
back to me so quickly. Most of the time,
they only want you to sell on the black
market. I don't want to do that. I want
to sell it to somebody that needs it.
Right off the bat, this supplier started
telling me why she had insulin to sell.
I got my prescription and I also sent
into the patient's assistance program
and they sent me 12 free. Oh, they under
a certain amount of money.
Throughout the seller kept talking
nervously about the black market. I
don't want the black market. I mean, I
hope it's kosher. And as my conversation
with this seller continued via email,
she became suspicious and the deal was
called off. Two other exchanges by email
and text did lead to meeting
arrangements.
And the next day, I prepared to go
undercover to buy insulin.
I'm on my way to buy a box of insulin
pens. They would normally sell for about
$400. I'm expecting to pay about a
quarter of that. Now, I've only been in
touch with the seller online, so I
really have no idea what I'm walking
into. I don't know anything about this
person. I don't even know if it's a man
or a woman, and that's a little scary.
The seller communicated exclusively
through email, telling me to send an
email about 20 minutes prior to
arriving. I did, and after 10 minutes,
another communication. It will be a
black jacket with orange accents. Then
the seller arrived. Are you looking for
Angela? Hi, how are you?
As he rummaged around hunting for the
insulin, I asked a critical question.
But are they cold?
Cold.
They do have a white. You don't have to
in the fridge all the time though. Okay.
But I'm a little Do you mind if I just
take a look
on the bottom? The transaction felt
matterof fact, as if the seller had done
this countless times before. He headed
out with $125 and I had five insulin
pens in a sealed box. So, this is the
box that we just bought. I'm getting a
chance to take a look at it. It is still
sealed in original packaging. Couple
things that I'm noticing, though. This
looks to me like there was a
prescription label here. My guess is
that we are buying someone else's
prescription medicine.
As night fell, we headed to the next
meeting place to wait for another black
market insulin dealer. Are you looking
for Angela? Yeah. Hi. This next seller
was clearly all business. Is that just
one? Yeah. Okay. Do you mind if I take a
look at your inspiration? You package
perfectly. So, this is 140. Yeah. I
wanted to find out where this insulin
was coming from. Are you getting these
from like reputable places? Like only
refrigerator.
Okay. I'm not going to worry about So
they're coming like from the pharmacy or
like they fell off a truck like
Okay. Okay. Okay. Great. Thank you. Have
a good one.
As the dealer left, my big question is,
"Is this insulin safe to use?"
Up next, our investigation continues.
What did we uncover about the insulin
being sold on the black market? Plus,
what can you do to save money on your
family's insulin costs?
[Music]
This best-selling author claims her
husband was poisoning her. Why would
your husband want to kill you? I'm worth
a lot more dead than I am alive. How she
foiled his plot. People are getting
poisoned all the time. They don't know
it. Plus, what hangry leads to violence.
Toasted razor.
We're not condoning bad behavior, but it
is a real medical phenomenon. All new
that's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
Insulin prices are skyrocketing. And as
the cost of this life-saving diabetes
medicine surges, so does the black
market, where private individuals
illegally resell insulin. I appreciate
you getting back to me so quickly. In my
investigation, I arranged to buy a box
of insulin pens that normally sell for
about $400, expecting to pay a quarter
of that.
I went undercover with hidden cameras,
hoping to find out more about how these
black market insulin dealers operate.
I've only been in touch with the seller
online. So, I really have no idea what
I'm walking into. I don't know anything
about this person. I don't even know if
it's a man or a woman, and that's a
little scary.
Are you looking for Angela? Hi, how are
you?
The transaction felt matterof fact as if
the seller had done this countless times
before.
So, this is the box that we just bought.
I'm getting a chance to take a look at
it. It is still sealed in original
packaging. Couple things that I'm
noticing, though. This looks to me like
there was a prescription label here. My
guess is that we are buying someone
else's prescription medicine.
That was our undercover investigation of
black market diabetes drugs. Join me
now, Dr. Carol Levy, who is an
endocrinologist at the Mount Sinai
Diabetes Center and also happens to have
diabetes herself. Also, correspondent
Marshia Compo, who did that wonderful
undercover investigation. Thank you.
What surprised you the most as you were
dealing with those guys about the black
market in diabetes meds? I was really
surprised at how easy this was. It took
us just minutes to find multiple sellers
and we were able to set up buying
arrangements immediately. It frankly
would have been harder for a minor to
buy alcohol than it was for us to buy
insulin on the black market. And just
get the pricing right. You these are the
actual items you bought. Yes. Right. So
you got, you know, this one you said was
$125. 25 for the first one. And you can
actually even you the prescription was
ripped off here, but you can see the
actual prices here. It says $391. $391.
So that's what the pharmacy is supposed
to sell it for. We got it for 125.
That's a significant savings. And there
as you did your research on the
undercover market, there were some
dangerous things you identified. You
highlighted one when you started pushing
that guy about how it was stored. What
were the red flags? Yeah, as you well
know, how insulin is stored is a very
big deal. When he showed up, he had this
underneath a garden hose in his backpack
and I asked him about the temperature
because there was no cooler, no ice pack
inside. He says, "Don't worry, it's been
in the freezer." Dr. Oz, it says on the
box, "Do not freeze." Yeah. I'm sure.
She says that literally on this box
right here, do not freeze the
instructions for handling. And this is a
life-saving medicine. So, it's scary to
think that people are relying on sources
like this as their supplier. Yeah, this
is this isn't magic fluid, guys. This is
insulin. It's got to be treated the
right way. Dr. Levby, what happens if
you freeze this insulin? Yeah. So, it
loses its potency and effectively is no
longer effective. So, someone might, if
they purchase prefrozen insulin, have
insulin that is no longer effective and
they've just paid $125 for it. explain
to everyone what what does that mean? So
for someone with diabetes who does not
take their insulin appropriately or is
not using effective insulin, what can
occur are very elevated blood sugars.
For some people with type 2 diabetes,
which is the adult type of diabetes,
that could be a few weeks and they'd be
in real trouble. Severely high blood
sugars at a point where they'd need to
go into emergency room. For someone who
requires insulin to stay alive, that
could mean within a week that person
could be in the emergency room and
possibly die. So freezing is one way you
might end up in this not even realizing
that the stuff doesn't work. What are
the other risks you worry about as an
endocrinologist if I buy insulin on the
black market because I am going to save
twothirds of my money maybe more. Right?
So the the concerns are severalfold.
Number one, you are very careful
consumer when you went in there to
purchase this but people could sell the
wrong type of insulin to to a patient.
For example, certain brands of insulin
come in a regular version, a mixed
version with different dilluent and
different features of it. So, what does
that mean? Is you might think you're
buying a certain insulin, but you're
actually buying a different one, which
could be very dangerous for you to
utilize if you were using the wrong one.
Now, you have your insulin pump. I just
noticed as you walked in here. Yes, that
is correct. Is there anything would ever
get you to buy uh a black market
insulin? So, that's a really interesting
question. The answer is I have health
insurance right now. So, the chances are
that I could have a prescription covered
by my insurance. This is a fear that I
always have. What if we lose our
insurance? What if I don't have a way to
get insulin? And of course, if I had to,
I would buy insulin on the black market
if there was no other way for me to
afford it or get it. But there were
grave concerns about that. So, I wanted
to have an audience full of people who
had bought their insulin on the black
market. I probably could have filled the
audience, but you know what? You could
have. It's illegal to purchase
prescription medications from an
unauthorized dealer. So, I couldn't
invite you because you would have been
breaking the law by admitting that.
However, price gouging is not illegal. I
have learned. Up next, why is the price
of insulin so high? We investigate
what's really going on.
[Music]
Comedian Jay Leno pays us a house call.
They've recently found that laughter is
not the best medicine. In fact, it
doesn't work at all. But get serious
about his own health. High cholesterol
just hits you. You don't know as much as
Jay can anyway.
That's coming up on Wednesday.
My son was diagnosed with diabetes 3
years ago.
Since then, we have lost our homes.
We've had to move out of state. We've
had cars repossessed.
We've had to choose whether we eat or if
we buy his life-saving medication.
Because of the high cost of insulin,
we're forced to share my insulin
prescription to try to keep us both
healthy. Having to choose between
keeping your child alive and paying the
bills is an absolutely heartbreaking
decision. But it's not like we have a
choice because without insulin, my
diabetic 12-year-old daughter will most
certainly die. Now, the price of insulin
is steadily rising, right? It's
increasing. Price gouging is not
illegal, but buying insulin on the black
market is. Keep that in mind. Now, there
have been protests over the skyrocketing
prices of insulin, and Washington is
starting to investigate. Just recently
they grilled pharmaceutical companies
about the high cost. And the big
question I want to know about insulin is
why is a medication that has been around
for almost a hundred years not gone down
in price. Well, you think that would
happen over after 100 years. Instead, it
seems like the opposite. The prices
actually have gone up. Marso who's been
investigating this is back. The cost of
insulin it seems like it's doubled.
That's the numbers that I've been
seeing. Doubled in five years. What's
really behind the rising cost? Yeah,
there are a few things that are going
on. So, first is that there are only
three companies in the United States
that make insulin and they can set the
price and there are no limits and
there's no regulation on what that price
is or how high it can go. The other
thing is insurance policies. We have
wildly different insurance policies in
this country. So, if you're someone with
diabetes with a very high deductible,
you have to pay out of pocket until you
reach that deductible. And even then,
the insurance company may only pay a
portion of the cost of the drug. So the
consumer is really bearing a lot of
these costs and just a couple things
here. First of all, it's a very
complicated relationship between the
different people in the healthcare
field. Maybe for a reason because it
makes it complicated for us to follow.
But in fact, according to a recent
study, insurance co-pays are higher than
the actual cost of the drug 25% of the
time. You need to ask you pay the cay
actually being more than what the actual
drug would cost on its own. And the
pharmaceutical companies are blaming the
insurance companies. So they're going
back and forth. And that lack of
transparency has allowed a lot of behind
the closed door deals. What are these?
These worry me a lot. Yeah. So, there's
essentially a negotiation that's going
on between the drug manufacturer, the
pharmacy benefit manager, and the
pharmacies about the price. But all of
that is shrouded in mystery. The
consumer is kept in the dark. They have
no idea why they're being charged what
they're being charged or how they came
up with those prices. There's a a lack
of transparency here. That's why the
show is important because if you
understand you can get upset at the
right people and once they know you're
on to them, people start reacting. So,
Dr. Lever, you have type 1 diabetes,
correct? You take care of people with
diabetes, which makes you especially
good at answering this question. What
worries you the most about the rising
the seeming rising cost of insulin?
Yeah. So, it it becomes the cost. Can
patients afford to pay for the
medication that they need to stay alive?
That's my biggest concern. The secondary
concern I have is that if people can't
afford it, they start rationing it. They
say, "Okay, which is better than not
taking it." But if you start to ration
it, that means you take half of your
appropriate dose of medication. That
leads to longer term risks,
complications of diabetes, eye disease,
kidney disease, nerve damage. You think
about every problem that someone could
have diabetes related, they're setting
theirelves up for that. So it's very
scary. So, we reached out to the
pharmaceutical research and
manufacturers of America and they
realized that there's a problem and they
aggressively dispute that the high
prices are because of them. They told us
there's a I'm quoting them robust
competition. So, they provide discounts
and rebates on insulin. But listen
carefully, those rebates are not being
passed along to the patients. They said
in part, "Unfortunately, patients
typically do not benefit from the fruits
of the competitive marketplace because
the price they pay at the pharmacy set
by their insurer is tied to the
undisounted list price." They go on to
say, "This is because middlemen are
gaining a profit by including these
medicines and health plan deductibles
that would expose patients to
undisounted prices."
Lots of things going on here, guys. if
they're pay, you know, giving little
discounts to make prices affordable for
consumers and consumers aren't getting
it and someone's pocketing the
difference. That's a real issue for me.
And the fact that you don't understand
the system is not an accident. You don't
understand for a reason because they
don't want you to understand because if
you don't understand it, you can't fix
it. So, this is a good opportunity for
us because it's not just insulin here.
It's a lot of the drugs that are
potentially saving or changing your
lives. Dr. Levy, when someone is in your
office talking to you about this stuff
and you know they cannot afford insulin,
what do you tell them? Yeah. So there
are some alternatives to offer. There's
one um foundation called Insulin for
Life and they do provide for people in
need options for insulin that's well
prepared, well stored that people c can
reach out for. The other opportunities
are alternative or older insulins, ones
that are not routinely used nowadays,
which one can still purchase in
variousarmacies for about $25 a vial.
They're not old. Yeah, they're not
ancient. They're just they were invented
a while back. Yeah, they were invented
longer ago than the current insulins
that are the most invogue and utilized
the most. So there are alternatives, but
those have to be carefully managed under
the supervision of a a physician because
they're dose differences. If you were to
switch and say, "Okay, I can't afford
this." You need someone to guide you how
to switch from insulin A to insulin B in
a safe fashion. Right? There are
companies including my trusted
sponsorship partners ShareCare that have
an app which allows you to compare
insulin prices in your area's
pharmacies. You may be able to find a
better deal. Educate yourself. Mara,
nice job going undercover. Dr. Levy Liz,
if we don't fix the problem of rising
insulin costs, we're going to have more
dangers of people buying frozen or
ineffective insulin. If you're taking
insulin, ask your doc if you can use one
of the older, cheaper types. They can be
just as effective without risking your
life buying insulin on the black market.
It is not worth it. We'll be right back.
[Music]
Up next, we investigate what's really in
beauty products you buy at the dollar
store. Is it a true beauty bargain?
Hello, Dr. Oz. It's Dr. Whitney. I'm
here in New York City. I'm actually at a
dollar store and I'm doing a little
investigation. I'm looking at different
beauty products for the skin, the hair,
the nails. I want to see which ones are
safe to get and which ones may not be
worth the bargain. We certainly don't
want to put our health at risk. So, I am
loading up my basket here and I will let
you know what I find.
Today, we're investigating dollar store
beauty products. Dermatologist Whitney
Bow is here with what she's uncovered. I
never knew there were so many beauty
products at these dollar stores. I'm How
many products can there be for hair and
skin in a dollar store? Yeah, I found a
surprisingly large variety of beauty
products at the dollar store. I found
products ranging from eye shadow to
makeup remover. There was hair dye,
shampoo, there was body lotion, shaving
cream. I even found face masks. So, how
does the dollar store actually do that?
These products are sort of expensive in
general. How can you get it to a dollar?
Is it really a dollar? As you might
suspect, first of all, some of them are
made on the cheap. You know, some of
them are made using maybe not the
highest quality ingredients, right? But
there are a few gems if you know what to
look for. And that's an excellent point.
You know, when I was looking around the
dollar store, not everything costs a
dollar. You know, some of them range all
the way up to $4,5.99.
But I think in general, the way that
these stores are able to keep the prices
so low is that they're basically
stocking up on brands that don't have
that name recognition, right? You're not
paying for that brand name and you're
not paying for the marketing campaign
behind that very well recognized brand
name, but you're also not getting the
trust, which is why I'm curious because
I thought there probably some things
that are worth getting, some that are
not. So, we look at all the dollar store
beauty products and Dr. Bo is going to
tell us if they're a pick or a pass so
you can still take advantage of these
deals. My go-to test is here to try out
the first item which is trending all
over the internet. Hello. Hello. These
are these blending sponges. I'll admit
this. I don't actually get a lot of hair
and makeup. At least I in my life I
hadn't until I started the show. Now 10
years later, I'm getting a little better
at it. But I see some artists using
these little bundle. I thought they were
the cool little toys initially and they
start putting their toys on my face. So,
have you used these before? Well, yeah.
I mean, these are all the rage when you
want to get that makeup on. Right. So,
these things can be pretty pricey in in
regular stores. Yeah. Yeah. know they
can cost up to $25 at, you know, certain
beauty stores. So, you know, looking
here, we're not telling you, Ranata,
which one is the $25 one versus which
one's the dollar one at the dollar
store, but if you're looking, I mean,
quite honestly, it's almost impossible
to tell them apart, right? They both
have very similar shapes. You want to
take that one, you can take that one.
I'll give you that one. They have very
similar shapes, you know? They're made
of very similar feel the material. very
similar material to give you that
flawless finish that you're looking for,
right? So, yeah. First, you want to get
them wet. So, you want to do it with me?
So, we'll get them wet. You want to wet
them first and then you give it a good
squeeze. So, you you want to get it damp
and then what you do is you take So,
it's got two different ends, right? Take
the the wider or broader end. You want
to dab it in the foundation there. And
then you're going to instead of using
the way that you would use your fingers
or a brush, you sort of wipe this. You
want to press the makeup into the skin.
So, is it okay if I if I demo? Okay, you
got it. Don't get too high. Now, what
you want to do is you want to use like a
a bouncing a tapping a dabbing motion to
actually press that makeup into the
skin. I I punching motion. I like that
idea. A punching motion. I didn't say
punching. She's like a sister. I don't
remember that. Let me get you. Let me
get you one. You can use that bird's
side. Ow.
She did that on purpose.
And what's the side? What's the pointed
part for? It shouldn't be dangerous. Um,
so yeah. So the pointed part gets into
those hard to reach places like the
sides of your nose or underneath your
eye. Yeah. You want to get in the
corners. Oh, sharp. Exactly. No, it's
not. I'm not hurting you. Right there.
Yeah. All right. So, both both design.
You apply them to yourself. You just
compare these two. Which one do you
think is better? Is there a difference,
first of all? Yeah. The purple and the
the green one. These are the same
company and this is one. So, which which
is which is which? So, this is the $25
and that is the dollar. Oh, I like
those.
Almost impossible. So, the beauty blend
sponge is a pick. Is that Absolutely.
Nice job. That'll save some money. $25
versus one. That's a Now, next. How
about these? The dollar store face
masks. I've been seeing these things.
They're huge trenders. You know, I was
in airport. I saw a lady walking around
the airport with one, but now they've
been in, you know, grocery stores,
planes. There's actually these are real
pictures posted about. So, Britney, what
do you think about these? What
ingredients did you find? Well, so in
the masks that I found at the dollar
store, they actually contained an
ingredient that was named allergen of
the year in 2004 because it caused so
many cases of skin inflammation and
irritation. So, the name of the
ingredient is cocamopropylane.
You say that. Say it three times. Oh, I
got it. Cocoamopropyl Betane. Oh my
gosh, she actually got that. I mean, my
name is so I have to get Whoa, that was
amazing. So, cocamopropylane is a
detergent. So, it it's what sort of
gives like body lotions or body washes
or shampoos that sort of foamy rich
bubbly lather. And unfortunately, in
this mask, cocamopropylane was listed as
the third ingredient on the ingredient
list. So, it's in there in a pretty high
concentration. So, for me, guys, that's
those are red flags, right? So this this
the dollar store face masks they're a
pass because you got to be sure that
what's in there is what you want to have
in your face. No no cocoa purple but
tank. Okay. Oh god. Gosh.
You awesome. I love showoffs. I just
fantastic. Three years of residency to
get that down. All that tuition. I
wasted four years of med school for
nothing. All right. Dollar store
foundation. Is it a pick or a pass?
We're not the thoughts on this. Would
you try a foundation that you bought at
a dollar store? No. to think that the
dollar store might have something that's
good enough to go all over this space.
Okay.
And not irritated million dollar.
Exactly. Hello. So, Dr. W, you you
examined this Dr. B. I did. I took a
look at all of these and you know, as a
dermatologist, I'm trained to sort of
look at the ingredients, you know, which
ones are going to clog pores.
Unfortunately, your instincts were
correct, RA. Even more worrisome than
that, is it possible that this bottle is
sitting in a hot warehouse somewhere,
you know, for days or weeks, and if so,
it can turn this bottle into a petri
dish and grow up a whole bunch of germs.
So, yeah, I I would Dr. Come over here.
I made a little illustration to make
sure this really sinks in for everybody.
So, I made you all a massive bottle of
foundation. There it is, your
foundation. Right. Now, in some cases,
you pointed out, it could be sitting in
a warm warehouse for we don't know how
long. Right. Right. And over time, what
happens is the combination of the warmth
plus the liquid base of the foundation
can provide a perfect breeding ground
for bacteria. And those purpley bacteria
grow in there. You can't tell, right?
Some of them might irritate you, some
you can get away with, but why take a
chance at something that Renata said,
you have million-dollar faces, don't put
a cheap foundation on there. So, the
dollar store foundation is a pass. Not a
pass. Coming up, the dollar store beauty
bargains that makeup artists and
dermatologists like I could both swear
by. Right? You love these things. They
can be spilling their secrets. Stick
around.
[Applause]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day, but when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
We are back investigating dollar store
beauty products. I asked makeup artists
and dermatologists to spill their
ultimate beauty secrets that you can buy
at the dollar store. Dermatologist
Whitney Bo is back along with my go-to
tester.
Their first dollar store beauty secret
to stock up on is shimmering eyeshadow.
Why do you like the shimmering eyeshadow
at dollar stores? I love shimmering
eyeshadow at dollar store cuz you can
easily transform it into a shimmering
body lotion. So, it's great for that
girls night out if you just want a
little extra sparkle, a little extra
glow. And if you go online or you go to
the department store, you know,
shimmering body oil, shimmering body
lotions, they can range from 20 to $50
for a small tube. So, this is such a
great way to save a couple bucks. So,
how do we make it? What do you So easy.
So, what you want to do is you want to
start with your favorite lotion. Take a
couple pumps, put that into a jar. You
know, I'm using a glass jar here. And
then, this is why you don't want to
spend a lot of money on the shimmering
eyeshadow part. You're going to take
that eye shadow. You can either use
bronze, you can use like a pearly white,
depending on if you're going for sort of
like a a bronzy glow or a little bit of
a highlight or shimmer. And what you do
is you take a fork.
A fork and make sure you got a piece of
paper underneath. I thought you're
putting it on your skin. So, wait. The
first step is you're going to collect
you're going to you're going to break
down some of those particles. kind of
collect them onto your piece of paper
and then you use that like a funnel and
you basically collect it and then you
get it into your lotion. Stir that
around. We actually premixed two
different ones for you so you can try it
out. And you basically then just apply
that to your arms, your legs. You can
put some on your cheekbone as a little
highlighter on your collar bone when you
mix in in the uh it does and it breaks
it down. It's a very subtle glow. It
gives you a subtle shimmer. No, I
wouldn't use dollar store eyeshadow on
my face every day, right? But once a
month for that special night out if you
want to have that beautiful shimmering
body. I'm shimmering. I'm shimmering.
Very subtle. What do you think?
This is awesome, right? Isn't this
great? Let me tell you why. If I want to
fake a a beach uh photo shoot, this is
what I need right here. Some body
shimmering from the dollar store instead
of spending $50.
Exactly. That's it. All right. Next tip
comes from the makeup artist who does
the glam for Beyonce and the
Kardashians. Take a look. Hey guys, I'm
here to share with you a couple of
dollar store beauty products that are a
must to stock up on. The first one is
hair conditioner. Hair conditioner is a
great alternative to shaving cream if
you're ever in a pinch. What you want to
do is pour out the conditioner, lather
on your legs, and shave like normal. It
is a great beauty bargain that will
leave your legs feeling soft and smooth.
Okay. Next, if you're looking to
moisturize and give your lips a little
bit of color, get yourself some dollar
store chapstick and make an awesome lip
tip. What I personally like to do is get
a makeup palette like so. And I've
crushed my favorite blush. And here's a
dollar store chapstick, which I mixed
both of them in the middle.
I applied with the back of my finger.
And as you can tell, I have a nice flush
of color that looks natural and it's so
inexpensive.
The next beauty bargain can give you a
fiveinut manicure. Five minutes. They're
called nail stickers. Why do you like
these more than those gel manicures I
see everyone using these days? I mean, I
know why gel manicures are so popular,
right? They're they give you that
durability, that longl lasting wear, and
they give you that incredible shine. But
my patients who do gel manicure after
gel manicure, you know, eventually your
nails are thin and they're weak and
they're brittle. So, I say, you got to
take a nail salon holiday. You got to
take a break. But most my patients don't
want to go without some kind of, you
know, bling,
some kind of polish. So, nail stickers
or little decals. So much fun. A great
alternative. Okay. Are they tattoos?
What are they? How do they work? Yeah.
So, what you do is first you want to
take you want to just take like some
scissors and you just cut around the way
that See how these are cut into little
little You don't have to worry about
getting it perfectly around there
because you're going to be putting it in
water anyway. They come with this little
plastic sort of coating on top. So, you
want to take that off. You can use some
tweezers if you want to get a little
extra fine motor control, Dr. Oz. And
then the the here. So, if you guys see
my little sticker here, what I'm going
to do is I'm going to wave this in the
water because you want to get it really
wet. So, that's the trick. And all these
these stickers work differently. Some of
them do work more like temporary
tattoos. These, the best way to do these
is you get them really, really wet. And
then you want to take your finger, do
this with me, Renata. Let's see if we
can do it. And you want to try to
actually press them and glide them off.
So, I don't know if you can see that.
Mine came right off. And then you want
to press it onto a clean, dry nail. So,
here's where your tweezers might come in
if you're not able to get. And can you
guys see that on my nail? Yes. Right.
So, then Very nice, Sakra. We're
matching. Oh, fabulous. That's easy.
Very nice. Simple. What do you think
about it? Cheers with our little nail
stickers. Amazing. I love it. I love
this cuz I'm not one to actually wear
nail polish, but to do these stickers
every now and then on my fingers without
having to, you know, get chipped because
of the nail polish along. Exactly. This
is awesome. I like these. So much fun.
Yeah,
I got to say I'm going to start wearing
these. I like these. I'm going to
impress my daughters, guys. Thank you
very much. We'll be right back.
Comedian Jay Leno pays us a house call.
Laughter is not the best medicine. In
fact, it doesn't work at all. But get
serious about his own health. High
cholesterol just hits you. You don't
know.
That's coming up on Wednesday.
We're back with three awesome medicine
cabinet hacks that you can use right
now. These are tried and tested by one
of our favorite bloggers from our bite
club. Please welcome Jay. Yay. I
understand. Do all your friends come to
you with home remedies? They do. I'm
like everybody's mama. Like I was raised
by this southern black lady and my
grandmother was awesome. I'm like Nana
Remix. Okay.
So why do you love witch hazel so much?
I love witch hazel because it's
something that everybody has. It's
something everyone knows how to use.
It's super cheap and like why not? Like
we need to use this. So show me a hack
that you've been talking about and I've
been hearing about with regard to
makeup. Yeah. So you know I'm 34 but I
need to make sure. Thank you.
But I got I have to make sure that I'm
able to maintain this face. So when I'm
using this, I always use two tablespoons
of water, two tablespoons of olive oil.
I like olive oil better just than any
other oil cuz it's natural. You use on
your skin, you use your hair. It's like,
look at this. You see this glow? I do
like the glow. Nice. Right. And then the
two tablespoons of the um the witch
hazel. So you're just going to mix it
up. So you're making a makeup remover
for me. Absolutely. This is something
that you will buy in a store and it's
actually going to be like 30 40 bucks.
These ingredients probably cost you
three bucks. It seems too good to be
true, doesn't it? To save all that kind
of money. Do you mind if I just
absolutely trust but verify here?
Please. All right. So, I'm I got a
little bit here. Who's interested in
trying this out? Here we go. Oh, I got
something here. One second. I got a I
got a victim right over here. Here.
Somebody's brave enough to take their
makeup off on national television here.
Hi. What's your name? Hi, I'm Biana. Are
you a Are you a believer in this idea?
that you think might work. Oh, I'm up to
giving it a go, so why not? Where are
you from? I'm Australia. You're from
Australia? Yes. I'm from Australia all
the way just to see you. The show airs
in it's in 100 countries, but it's in
Australia. I go there all the time. It's
so good to have you here. Next time come
visit. I will. Thanks for having me.
We're actually on our honeymoon. You're
on your honeymoon.
That is so cool. You have very good
taste in women. Congratulations. All
right. So, here I'm going to You mind?
Yeah. So, I'm going to You are brave for
allowing this to happen on television.
So, I'm just taking your makeup off. I
couldn't even tell you had any on, by
the way. You didn't Oh, yeah. It didn't
come off. Look. Look. You see? Oh, yeah.
There's a bit there. Actually, come up
over here. Both you come down.
Now, show your cheek to that camera. I I
think it's a very You It's smooth. It's
clean. And look, makeup came off with no
problems. You know, you have big plans
for your honeymoon. Well, we've been uh
been to Greece. Um, and then obviously
to New York and then we're going to
finish up with Disneyland. Well, New
York City, city I love dearly, needs to
have you touring around looking your
best. So, if it's okay with you, I'll
send you down with my glam squad so you
look elegant and attractive as always.
In fact, you can drag down your new bow
and get your hair and makeup. I'll give
it a go. Give it a go. And you know
what? After that, go to dinner on us.
We'll send you to a nice restaurant in
the area. Thank you so much.
Congratulations. So proud of you.
Oh my goodness. I love honeymoons.
I don't know about you guys.
Part of the reason I love the covenant
of of of marriage is it's the best thing
I ever did in my life. Jay is getting
married. So without question, nothing
even close. Yeah. Yeah. That's
beautiful. I'm glad to hear that. I'm
sure you're going to get you there, too.
That's part of the show. This show is a
show's a dating service, by the way.
We're trying to Oh, I need a man. So,
let me let me know. We can put that on
my blog, too. I J a man. That's right.
After I watch facial with the wish. You
got one more little hack for us. Yeah.
Which is to have to do with pimples. And
this is actually said putting aspirin on
a pimple which I know works. Yeah.
Because I've heard about it but I've not
seen it actually done. So please demo.
Yeah. So I again my grandmother she
showed me these things when I was young.
I had you know a couple little little
blemishes a little bit. Um, but I
remember I had this one fashion show and
I was so excited to be a part of it. And
she was like, she's like, "Oh, you were
going to dress you up. You're going to
wear heels, you know." D. And I'm like,
"Oh my god, Nana, I have a pimple on my
face. What am I going to do? I can't
walk in a fashion show with this huge
huge thing on my face." She was like,
"Girl, get some aspirin. It'll be fine."
I'm like, "What am I going to do with
some aspirin?" She's like, "Oh, just
crush it up. Put it in a little powder
on it." Take it like this with your
spoon. Yeah. So then we're going to put
it right between the two spoons and then
just crush it up. And it's like not even
that messy. If I can crush it. Yeah, you
that's what I do. I think goes right on
the spoon. Mess it up like that. And
then what is this here? Just water. So
yeah. So we'll put just a couple drops
of water in it. And we want to make it
into a nice little paste. So then we'll
mix it up and then literally put it
right on your skin. And you'll that's
it. And you just leave it on the spot
for at least 10 minutes. You don't want
to put it any longer than that cuz then
it'll dry out and you have a whole
another problem. Yeah. Cuz you see this
how it's a taste there. See guys,
looking carefully and the nice thing is
is it's an anti-inflammatory. So reduce
the redness around the pimple and might
help the pimple. Yeah. Yeah. I like
this. I love it. Nice job. Thank you. I
got one more surprise for everybody. We
got bonus hacks at dr.com. But before we
go to break one more hack that I really
like a lot. We have been using band-aids
wrong our entire lives. Watch this. It's
going to change yours.
[Music]
This best-selling author claims her
husband was poisoning her. I'm worth a
lot more dead than I am alive.
How she foiled his plot. People are
getting poisoned all the time. They
don't know it. All new.
That's coming up tomorrow.
Today, big news. In fact, breaking news
about your heart. Is open heart surgery
becoming a thing of the past? Well, we
all know someone who's had that kind of
invasive surgery with the the big cut in
their front. It's made with a device
like this that we use as heart surgeons
to saw open the ribs and expose the
heart. I grew up doing this. It's pretty
invasive, but a big new study shows
there may be a safer, easier way to
treat one of the most common and serious
conditions that can affect the valves of
the heart. And guess what? 2 and a half
million people in the US have this
problem right now. It's called aortic
stenosis. And here's what it looks like.
There's the heart, right? Pounded away.
And there's this big tube coming out of
it that it carries blood to the rest of
the biac, the brain, and the other
organs. Inside the heart, the blood goes
back and forth across this valve. But
this valve which is importantly
regulating the blood when you look at it
from above opens up like a MercedesBenz
sign. But if it gets stenotic, if it
gets scarred in like this and get little
piece of calcium on it, it can't work.
So it makes it harder for the heart to
push the blood out to your vital organs.
You get symptoms when this happens
because the heart's backing up. You
start to faint because no blood's going
to your brain. You have shortness of
breath. The blood backs up in your
lungs. And when it's severe, right, it
can cause life-threatening issues. So
about two decades ago, two innovative
engineers, two cardiologists had an
idea. What if we could fix this problem
with only making a small incision in the
groin and replace this valve with a
catheter instead of using that saw that
I used earlier? They asked me to help
design the device and now a new clinical
trial all these years later suggests
that this treatment now it's called TAV
or TAVR may become the best option for
everyone. And I want to introduce you to
my friend Dr. from Marty Leon.
Martin actually he helped lead the
development of the device and the tavern
trial with Michael Mack and some great
engineers both named Stan by the way the
stands. So show everyone how this works
and how much effort it took to make this
happen. So you make a little cut in the
groin and there's the catheter. The
catheter goes up. We snake the catheter
across the aorta. Then we cross the old
valve here, the diseased valve. And then
we expand the new valve. And you can see
the new valve is expanded and now it
works like a normal valve. And looking
at it from above, you'll notice I showed
earlier how it got scarred in. Now it's
working normally. And one big idea here
which actually very young doctors share
with us was you don't have to take the
old valve out. You can just actually
push the old valve to the side. It's
like mortar, right? Actually holds our
new valve in place. So give us the
summary of the results. This was front
page news everywhere around the world.
So this device, this technique was
originally going to be used only for the
patients who are very high risk for
surgery. What we did was now the fifth
randomized trial, but it's in low
surgical risk patients, which is the
majority of patients with aortic
stenosis. What we learned was that after
a year of following these patients,
there a thousand patients in this
clinical trial. You compare surgery
versus TAVER, we learned that there was
about a 50% reduction in death, stroke,
and rehospization at the end of a year
if you use the catheter system, the less
invasive system. So, it's the best of
both worlds. Exactly. Less invasive
seems to work maybe even better. And
listen, we don't have outcome past the
year really. All right. In general, you
don't have to wait 15 years to see if
these valves will last as long as the
old fashioned ones. But this is really
good news for a lot of you. So, come on
over here. Mery's joining us. She was
part of the clinical trial. And you are
brave to have done this. Let me hand
that to you. That's what your valve
looked like. Wow. So, what do you think?
It's amazing. I never saw it. It's in
there. It's This is actually Dr. The
other is the exact same one you have in
your body. What was it like being
randomized in the trial? It was
wonderful. I didn't know until three
days before that I was going to be
chosen or picked. Um and so I'm
delighted because I had a friend that
had um corona coronary disease and she
had um open heart surgery and she has
not been the same since. She's had
complications. Mine was a wonderful
experience. Well, as a surgeon, I've
always believed part of my job, coming
on over, was to put myself out of
business. And the status quo wasn't good
enough. You want mercies of the world
bragging to their friends about how well
they're doing. So, I've got all these
young people, doctors, nurses. This is
my point of my partners, by the way,
Isaac George, working together to make
these advances
a reality. And my colleagues at the
hospital, yes, you should think because
it's the young folks that are changing
medicine. Advanc is so quick, we barely
keep up with it. Marty and I with our,
you know, graying hair and years of
work, it only hand the baton off, but it
makes a huge difference because the
bodies don't change, but technologies
do. So, I want to congratulate all of
you very much with the bottom of my
heart, making this all possible. And
congratulations to you, Marty, for never
giving up, being persistent, having a
lot of grit. Congrats to you as well.
We'll see you all next time.
[Music]