[Music]
A special Mother's Day event. Kelly
Roland is here to prove just what a
survivor she is. From the joy of
becoming a mom. Moments of me actually
catching poo in my hands. So, and how
she lost the baby weight. For me, it is
not about being skinny. I just want to
feel good. Plus, Real Housewife of New
Jersey, Jacqueline Lorita fights back
against her autistic son's haters.
Coming up next on Dr. Oz.
[Applause]
[Music]
Thank you very much. Welcome to the
show. Kelly Roland is music royalty
first as part of Destiny's Child now as
a successful solo artist. But recently,
in a period of just seven months, Kelly
experienced both the joy of marriage and
motherhood and the tragic sudden death
of her beloved mother. Today, Kelly
Roland is here to prove just what a
survivor she is. Kelly, come on
[Applause]
[Music]
out. Hi. Hi.
Oh, thank you for coming. Oh, thank you
for having me. I'm so excited to be
here. Hi, everybody.
So, you recently did something that's
got a lot of people talking and raised a
very, very big question. Is there a
possibility of a Destiny's Child reunion
or just just a one-off event that you
did? You know what? It was a one-off
event. Um, Michelle had this incredible
record called Say Yes. If you don't have
it, you should definitely do it. I have
it. It's amazing. And um she asked
myself and Beyonce to get on the record.
It was just as simple as that. And there
you go. A reunion happened. It was very
easy. Well, you look at Kelly and she
has that incredible new mother glow. A
thank you. Just posed for a wonderful
cover for the Essence magazine. Uh and
these photos I'm going to show them to
you. They're unbelievable. Thank you. Is
motherhood everything you dreamed it
would be? Yes. I mean it's it's such a
beautiful thing because we have the most
beautiful moments where Titan is a cute
child. He's a cute kid. Does he have an
agent yet? You know, he doesn't. But I
have amazing moments like of course when
he's waking up, we get to smell him. He
smells so good to moments of me actually
catching poo in my hand. So, it's been
some really ups and downs and just some
messes at times, but it's fun. So, I
understand you sing him to sleep. So, if
you're a Grammy award-winning artist,
what do you sing to your child? There's
the song that I recorded called Mama's
Little Baby. And I just simply say to
him, you will always
be mommy's Little
Baby. It's really sweet. Perfect. So,
the lyrics are ideal. Yeah, it's it's
really sweet. What surprised you the
most about Mothers? You're 6 months into
the Yes. experience. Six. Let me see. I
think what surprised me is probably how
fast he's growing. I mean, literally in
the morning, he's like this size, and
when I get back, he's this size. I'm
like, what are you going to do today?
And I I think the hardest is really
trying to balance being a wife, being a
mom, and um having your your job and
your occupation at at the same time.
Like, you want to do everything and you
want to do everything great. Y'all
understand, don't you, Liz? I do. So, I
just I just I always want to do that,
right? But I always want to have my
sanity at the end of the day as well.
You know, there's an interesting
balancing act we not just between
ourselves and our children, but in our
relationships and our children. Yes.
Yes. And I have this conversation with
my wife all the time about who's more
important, the babies or the of the
spouse. Oh, y'all are I think the
relationship with with your partner is
the most important relationship. I mean,
that's how the baby got here. That's
right. So, I think I think that's the
most important relationship to have and
that's the way I've ordered mine. And so
it's my husband, my baby, my career, and
that's exactly how it goes in my
household. Yeah. And it's something we
don't talk about much, but I know that
it hurts relationships sometimes,
ironically, because you fall in, you
know, in with the baby. And of course,
baby's very demanding for time. What?
What? Huh? What? Yes. So, of all the
things you do, one of the most
impressive to me is that you maintain
such an incredible body. You just made,
you know, you're able to, you know, to
lose baby fat as you have done. You lost
70 pounds. Is that right? Almost.
Almost. I'm a work in progress. I am a
work in progress. You know what? It took
a lot of dedication. And for me, it is
not about being skinny. I just want to
feel good. If I feel like I look cute in
this dress or this great pair of pants,
then that's what I like. I I like to
feel good. I feel like it radiates all
over who we are. And um I just I just
want to feel good. What's the right
motivation? Because if you aim at that,
you actually have a goal that you can
meet, but you still have to do things to
get there. So, give me that. I mean, I
had to work out. I did a lot of cardio.
I did spinning. I practiced this 8020
rule where like 80% of the time I'm
eating foods that like, you know, really
give me nourishment and give me energy
for my workouts because I can't lie, I
will do two workouts a day. I go a
little ham and um and the other 20% I
love chocolate and I love wine. So
that's my 20 and I'm You clapped on
that. So that's how I approach it.
You're you're so serious about
motherhood. You actually became a
spokesperson for a baby fabric detergent
which I I would love if you if you can a
little footage on this. Describe what it
is to everybody. Yes. Well, I mean it's
it's the draft campaign and basically I
just love the fact that I wanted Titan
to feel really safe when he when he came
home and I remember smelling my
girlfriend's baby. I was like I want my
baby to smell good. She told me about
Drift and I started using Drift and I
love the fact that it wasn't going to
mess his skin up. It was hyperallergenic
and my pediatrician told me about it and
now we're in this cuz they have this
whole like phases and I'm on drift
active baby cuz Titan's learning his
first meals. It's so exciting already.
Yes. Of course it's 6 months. You
should. Yes. So he's having his first
meals. He's crawling around everywhere
and the drift active baby just
completely 99% of the time just gets all
those little stains out. So it's been
awesome. Let me shift gears. A lot of
happy things in your life. Yes. Titan
obviously. Yes. Uh but you lost your
mother. Yes. It was sudden. Yes. Cardiac
arrest, which means the heart just stops
beating. Yes. Uh, was it expected at
all? No. It's It's so weird. It was the
the strangest phone call because um I
was remember just putting Titan to sleep
and then him waking up maybe a couple
hours before. And then we got this phone
call and it never was on our radar
anything about her heart or cardiac
arrest, anything like that. And um next
thing I know we're rushing to Atlanta
and I literally get there and I realize
that I lost my mother. So immediately
after that I'm thinking what happened
you know what led to all these events
for this to happen and it was just a
surprise and it was a surprise to the
doctor surprise to us all. So how do how
do you make sense of that when something
so much of who you are is taken from
you? Yeah. You know what? I The first
thing I did was of of course I'm still
grieving to be completely honest. Um and
I think that every time I look at Titan,
sometimes he's looking over my head and
I'm thinking that my mother's around us
some some way or another. But also I
went to go have a physical because I
wanted to know if that is, you know,
passed down through generations. I had
no no education about it. So, I just
wanted to be knowledgeable about it.
Most of us don't know your mom. Describe
her for those of us who would love to
know more. She is a light and will
literally come in here and cook
everybody a meal and make sure that
everybody is happy and say a prayer with
you. Just the sweetest the sweetest
sweetest person. And there are moments
where I just wish she was right there
next to me. And I know she is in spirit,
but it's definitely still hits home. She
got to meet Titan. Yes, she did. Did she
Did she give you any mothering advice?
Um, I remember feeding Titan and she
just comes over my shoulder and says,
you know what you're
doing. And I was like, I took all the
classes, Mom. I think I know what I'm
doing. She's like, a
class? So, she said, that's just stuff
you just learned. But anyways, um I
remember sitting there and she watched
everything that I was doing and how I
was just, you know, with Titan and she
said, "I'm just so proud of you." And it
just meant the world to me cuz that's
all you want your parents to do is just
love you and be proud of you. It is the
goal, isn't it? Yeah.
Paying back and making
crazy as it is, her legacy, besides
maybe saving your life because she got
you to check yourself out. Yes. will be
to change the lives of lots of other
folks who now are going to think, you
know what, healthy, she was 65, 66. Yes.
Yes. A healthy young woman. Yes.
Suddenly he's gone. Yes. And is there
anything I can do to make sure it
doesn't happen to me? Absolutely. I
think it's all it's important for all of
us to know exactly what's going on with
our hearts and get physicals and just
know what's going on with our body as as
a whole. So, I really enjoyed meeting
you. You, too. God bless you. Good luck
to you. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up next, we're celebrating
mothers with a courageous mom on a
mission to fight back to protect her
innocent autistic son from cyber
bullying. Her heartfelt and moving open
letter will change how you think about
autism for good. Coming up
next, all new odds. Women who lost half
their body weight. Transformation so
amazing you have to see it to believe
it. I'm not. If you think you can't lose
weight, think again. How they did it so
you can too. Plus, rip a page from Laala
Anony's power playbook. You can be great
at more than one thing. How she went
from the bottom to the top. Lala sharing
her rules. All new Oz. That's coming up
on Monday.
[Music]
[Applause]
Today's show is all about moms and our
studio audience is filled with mothers
and daughters. Let me hear you guys.
There's one more beautiful than the
next. I I love when beautiful women
bring up other beautiful women. I'm very
proud that you are all here. So, Jacine
Lorita is a courageous mom and she's on
a mission. She's fighting back to
protect her innocent autistic son from
cyber bullying.
How far would you go to protect your
child from the pain of bullying? I love
you. Jacqueline Lorita had to face that
question head on when she came upon a
shockingly mean-spirited Facebook post
demeaning autistic children and their
parents. That post hit especially close
to home because Lorita's youngest son,
Nicholas, was diagnosed with autism when
he was 2 years old.
So cute. Now five, Nicholas has come a
long way with the love of his family and
the help of diet and therapy.
With
in today, Jacine speaks out about the
joys and challenges. Nick, it get
raising her beloved son, Nicholas. And
she confronts the cyber bully who
attacked not just her son, but all
families raising children with autism.
Bye.
I'm so sorry. things. You don't have to
be sorry. I know it's hard to have these
conversations. So, Nicholas is five.
Yes. So beautiful, so young. Boy, to
already be in a very shocking way
bullied. Yeah. I mean, anytime a parent
sees their child struggle or in hurting
over something, you're going to hurt it.
It's a ripple effect. And what people
need to understand is that children with
autism, they face many challenges every
single day. And every day they work
really hard to overcome those
challenges. So the last thing they need
is for someone to, you know, make
mean-spirited comments, you know,
because they don't understand
differences of others, you know, people
that are different from themselves.
And uh if I can, I'm going to share the
post. It's it's you know, you described
as mean and ignorant. I think it's
pretty accurate. So here's what was
said. Why do people give birth to
autistic kids? waste of society's
resources. Right. So, what went through
your mind when you saw that posted? Um,
I was angry. I mean, you're talking
about my child for one of many. Um, I
just couldn't believe someone could be
so cruel and mean-spirited. Um, really
disregarding the life or value of
another human being. So, to me, I just
was really taken aback. And then I was
sad because I realized these are there's
people out there that that feel this way
that my son's gonna have to face one day
and he's gonna have to to cope with
that. So you did something about it. A
lot of us sit there and stew and are
frustrated, but you actually wrote a
letter and this letter that Jacqueline
wrote getting a lot of attention. Would
you mind reading part of it? A part of
it. It's very beautifully done. You
don't have to read the whole thing.
Right.
Okay. So I said, "Why do people give
birth to autistic kids? Let me educate
you. There is no medical detection or
prenatal test to tell you that your
child will be born with autism. Even if
I had known about my son's autism prior
to his birth, I would still have chosen
to give him life. I went through five
miscarriages to finally give birth to
what I consider my miracle child. I
couldn't wait to hold him in my arms,
look into his eyes, and love him
forever. He is worth every resource that
will help bring out the best individual
he can be. He is worth every skill we
can teach him so that we may make his
life a little easier in the
[Applause]
future. Oh, sorry.
Protecting our children, your son, they
are emotional issues. What do you hope
people will take from your letter? Um I
you know one in 68 children are
diagnosed with autism today and that
number is rapidly growing and these
children cannot control the way their
brain functions. It's it's different but
not less
and I think that you know instead of
bullying have some compassion try to if
you don't understand something educate
yourself and try to understand it. try
to help and if you're not going to help,
at least don't
hurt. Um, so I I felt very passionately
about this as well. Our team started to
look for how this happened. The bullying
Facebook post was removed shortly after
it first appeared, as you know, but we
did some digging. We found the woman
that we believe to have posted it. Now,
we're not going to use her name because
she says her account was hacked and the
post was made by somebody else. She
tells us, and I'll quote her, "I do not
have any dislike of people with
disabilities. I'm just an ordinary
citizen trying to live my life in peace.
So either she's learned or she's
learning or maybe it wasn't her at all.
Yeah. But give us give us some hope in
this issue. What do you hope folks will
take away from this? You've been through
the bullying, many of us have
experienced it in different ways. How
can kids who are suffering from autism
and the millions of who are afflicted
because they're their families or love
them dearly, how do they react? What
should they take away from this story?
you know, when you when you see a child
um having a meltdown in public because
children on the spectrum, they become
very frustrated um because they can't
communicate
uh the way they want to. It's it's hard
for them to express their emotions and
control their emotions. And you know,
with that comes meltdowns. And sometimes
these meltdowns happen in public and
people look and they stare and they make
comments about the child or the parent.
And instead of saying something
mean-spirited, you know, and escalating
a situation that's already
uncomfortable, you know, just even a
look from somebody to say, you know, I
understand. I get it. And, you know,
don't worry about it. You know, carry
on, you know. So, I I'm so happy you
wrote the letter. I I thank you for
sticking up because it's a is a role
model for the rest of us. Thank you. All
right. And this year for me comes down
to one little boy, Nicholas, and the
millions of other kids with autism who
deserve our love, respect, and
compassion. Remember, whether you're
saying things to friends or posting
things online for the whole world to
see, your words matter. We'll be right
back. Have a health question? Ask on
dr.com and get answers directly from Dr.
Oz and his team of experts. No question
is off limits.
Coming up next, a daughter wants to give
back to her hardworking mother who
spends all of her time helping others.
Always putting herself last. This
deserving mom needs some TLC. Yeah. Come
on out. A Mother's Day surprise. Coming
up next. All new Oz. Women who lost half
their body weight. Transformation. So
amazing, you have to see it to believe
it. I'm not g. If you think you can't
lose weight, think again. How they did
it so you can too. Plus, rip a page from
Laala Anony's power playbook. You can be
great at more than one thing. How she
went from the bottom to the top. Lala
sharing her rules. All new Oz. That's
coming up on
Monday. For many of us, including me,
mothers are simply heroic. and I love
having you all here to celebrate you.
Let me give you a hand again. I love
having all the moms. It's often hard to
find the words to describe a mother's
love and then thank them for all they
do. That's why when I received this
letter from Emily about her
extraordinary mom, I wanted to help.
Take a look.
My mom, Gail, has had to endure more
than anyone should have to in their
entire lifetime. I'm a middle child and
I was born into a family with an older
sister, Julia, and a younger brother,
Christian.
Both of my siblings were born with
cystic fibrosis, a horrible
life-threatening disease, and my mom
took care of them every day. My sister
had to go through two double lung
transplants. In 2011, she succumbed to
the disease and passed
away. My little brother is only 22 and
still fighting the disease. My mom still
takes care of him every day. In addition
to this, she has worked as a nurse for
35 years to support the family. again,
spending all of her additional time
caring for others. She's got back
problems, arthritis, COPD, the physical
labor, the stress, the long hours and
shifts. It's definitely taken a toll on
her
health. I'd love to give her the
recognition she deserves and truly thank
her for giving up her life and sometimes
sanity, caring for myself and my
siblings.
Gail's daughter Emily is here. What do
you love the most about your mom? Well,
you know, my mom is so caring and she's
done so much for for my siblings
throughout the years and for myself. Um,
you know, even now she helps me she's
helped me to live out my dreams. Um, I'm
an entrepreneur and she's been such a
driving force behind me pursuing that.
Um, I know a lot of parents don't like
that. So,
she shows her love as most moms do. So,
why is it so important for you to
surprise her today? I just want to give
her a day of recognition um for her. And
what can I help you with? What's the
surprise gonna be? What do you want to
do to make her look different? I'd love
to give her a makeover. You know, she
doesn't really ever treat herself. She
shops at thrift stores. Um where's my
brother's hand-me-downs? Where's your
brother's hand? Yeah. She'd rather give
the resources, you know, to other
things. So, all right. So, since Gail
always puts herself last, we wanted to
help surprise her and give her a day
where she puts herself first. And this
is a remarkable, remarkable
transformation. Take a look.
Gail thinks she's keeping her daughter
company on a business trip in New York
City. Little does she know what we have
planned for her.
Hey guys, come on in.
I have a very special surprise for you.
A message from someone very special.
Hey Gail, Dr. Oz here. Your daughter
Emily enlisted my help to surprise you.
She told me how you're always putting
everyone else first. So today it's time
that we take care of you by giving you a
full day of pampering and beauty.
[Music]
Pretty overwhelmed. Thank you, Dr. Oz.
And the only reason I'm here is because
I've got I've got wonderful children.
Have a lovely day. Thank you. Have a
good one. Good luck. Bye, Mom. Have fun.
We'll see you. Thank you.
First stop, the spa treatment at BMV
Skin Specialist Boutique. Then, Gail
heads over to Nunio Saviano's salon for
hair and makeup. Hi, Gail. My name is
Nunio. Welcome to my salon. We're going
to make you look great. Okay, now we're
going to start with your color.
Now, we're ready for some highlights. Go
for it.
So, we're going to give you a cut that
is going to make you look great.
We're going to get started with
makeup. Gail, do you want to see how you
look? Yes, please. All right. Here we
go. You guys ready to see Gail? You
happy? A full day of pampering. You
ready to see her?
I am. Gail, come on out.
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh, I got to give you a hug. I got to
give. How are you, sir? How are you? How
are you? So, how does it feel to have
finally after doing things for everybody
else all the time to have a full day of
pampering? Well, first of all, I only
wear my brother's her brother's t-shirts
on his clothes. When I heard
that overwhelming, I don't I can't put
in words. It's just been just
overwhelming. Can't believe that all
this has happened in such a short frame
of m time. And I'm very grateful. Oh,
please God. We're grateful for you,
Emily. Really about your mom. She looks
great. And she did this. And that's
what's even more moving is that she did
this. So, thank you. Did you have any
idea any idea, Gail, that your daughter
was worrying this much about you? No. I
always said I was fine as long as I can
go out for a coffee or go to the library
or go for a walk. No, sir. I didn't. I
really didn't. Well, you know, I was
taught this by a gentleman when I was a
younger parent, and he said, "Always
remember, your kids aren't going to
treat themselves the way you treat them.
They're going to treat themselves the
way you treat yourself." So for all the
moms out there, if you want her to be as
beautiful and helping as you are, make
sure you're taking care of yourself as
well. God bless you for all you do for
your family. Thank you, sir. Now, I want
to thank all the moms out there. A big
thank you to my mom. Mom, I really am
sorry I made you tired all the time.
There is a very bad little boy. She's
always watching us in turkeys. I love
you, Mom. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Dr. Oz's newsletter delivers information
right to your fingertips. Get Oz's daily
tip, recipe, and a sneak peek of today's
show in your inbox every morning. Sign
up at
dr.com. Coming up next, have you been
trying to save up for that something
special? A new dress, a family vacation,
but you still need to make ends meet. In
honor of Mother's Day, we're revealing
mom's bestkept money-saving secrets to
put money back into your pocket. Coming
up next, all new odds. Women who lost
half their body weight. Transformation.
So amazing, you have to see it to
believe it.
If you think you can't lose weight,
think again. How they did it so you can
too. Plus, rip a page from Laala Anony's
power playbook. You can be great at more
than one thing. How she went from the
bottom to the top. Lala sharing her
rules. All new Oz. That's coming up on
Monday.
[Music]
[Applause]
We're back celebrating our moms and
today I'm sharing mom's bestkept
money-saving secrets. They're all brand
new and they only made the grade because
they've been road tested by a mom. Now,
our first secret comes from a mom who
says she tricks herself into saving
money. So, this is the basic concept.
How many of you have tossed spare change
into a jar like this? Let me see. Show
hands. All the mom satisfied. So,
Francis says she came up with something
even better. So, what is your money
saving secret? Well, growing up as a
child, we didn't have allowance. So, we
used to kind of save all our money in
the jar. But now that I'm an adult, my
husband and I, what we do is we save our
dollar bills. If there's any loose ones
around the house, we just dump them in a
box and we save them. And we keep this
box in our bedroom because we all know
that dollar bills are always safest in
the bedroom. They are safe there. Put
them in the mattress. So, when do you
look to see how much you saved at the We
typically we wait till the end of the
year. So, once you have a big
celebration, you pull it up. All right.
So, audience, let me come to you guys.
Thank you for that, Tim. I'm gonna come
back to you in a second. Let me see your
wallets. Put your wallets out. Listen,
get we get ones in there. Ones? No. No
ones. Only 20s. 20s and fives. Five.
Five. Big SP. You must have given them
away. You have ones here. I have ones.
There are a lot of ones here. Look at
that. Think about all these ones. Would
you think would you consider doing what
we're being advised taking these ones
and putting them in a box? Maybe. Maybe.
So, if we did that, Francis, in your
case, when you do this little exercise,
how much money do you end up with at the
end of a year? Well, we typically save
anywhere between $300.
300 bucks. $300. I'd do that. That's
better than the change counter over
there. I like that idea very much. Thank
you for your advice. Keep saving. Thank
you. Love what you do. All right. Next,
we want to find ways of saving money at
meal time. Don is a mother of three.
She's busy. She says there was a time
that she was spending way more than she
wanted to on food, so she came up with a
plan to cut costs. What's the secret?
The secret that I have in my family is
we do at least three meatless meals a
week. And we do here's a frittata, which
you know is easy to sneak in a little
spinach, which is a favorite. Uh also a
black bean burger, which is my husband's
favorite. And finally, for all working
moms, I work actually work on a farm.
And it's great to throw all kinds of
vegetables in here. And at the end of
the day, you work on a farm. I do. I do.
Where do you live? I live in Cranford,
New Jersey. Good for you. There's farms
in New Jersey now. Yeah. It's the last
one in New Jersey. Do the kids mind when
you make these meatless dishes? No,
actually, they love it. Especially the
eggs because eggs is a great uh way to
sneak things in. Like I said, something
like spinach and a lot of cheese in
there, too. Not too much, but enough to
make that tasty for them. So, if folks
right now move from having meat to a
meatless uh option three times a week,
yeah, they could copy you. How much
money do you roughly save? At least $30
a week. And that's not even counting the
health benefits. $30 a week. So, in a
year, that is $1,500.
Just do the math for everybody else.
What do you do with all the extra cash?
You could buy a car. I know. Well, my my
my two girls have very expensive tastes.
They love to horseback ride. And so,
it's a nice hobby to do. I do. I believe
I have the same problem. By the way,
enjoy farming. Thanks for being so much.
All right. Our next mom has three kids.
She says she's found a great way to find
extra cash. She says her money saving
secret is all about rounding. Now, most
folks are intimidated by rounding. They
heard about in math class. So, explain
it to us all. Well, I like math. So,
rounding, I like to round up when I'm
paying my bills and take the extra
money. So, if I have a cable bill, let's
say that's $85, which we know the cable
bill is a lot more than $85, but it is.
I'll round up to 90 and I'll put that $5
in savings. And then when I'm putting
deposits in the bank, I round down. So
if I have a check for $185, I'll take
$10 off the top and put that in savings
and just put the other 175 where I pay
my bills from so that I have this money
that I don't even see, but it it
accumulates over time. Yeah. So your
checking account actually purposely
underestimates how much money you have
there. Yes. Well, I actually I actually
opened a separate account that I try not
to touch. You know, it's the it's the
savings account. I have three boys at
home. we're saving for college and this
is the money that you know when we can
spare it, we put it in there and we
don't spend it. What gave you the idea
of doing this? You know, I'd like to say
it was my idea, but I had heard on the
um radio about a bank that offered a
debit card. It was like a a bank card
where they would round up the change and
do that for savings. And I thought, I
don't need a bank card to do that. I can
just do it with my own money. So, give
me an idea of how much money we're
talking about at the end of the year.
How much can you save? Um, you know
what? Probably about $100 a month. So,
it's like $1,200 a year. $1,200 a year.
Yeah. So, put this together, everybody.
If you do all these secrets, it's
roughly $3,000 a
year. You might as well enjoy it, cuz
you're saving money without realizing
it. For more money ideas, log on to
dr.com. I love surprising moms. Were you
surprised?
Do you have a favorite $1 fix that you
use in the kitchen? I never buy store
brand salad dressing. It's way too
expensive and often packed with
unnecessary ingredients and calories. I
use lemon juice and olive oil. Saves
money and tastes great. Share yours on
facebook.com/d. Next, a mother fighting
for her child. A young child fighting
for her life. The battle to get her a
lung transplant even when the law said
no. What she did to fight the system and
now she's helping other kids get
transplants too. An inspiring Mother's
Day story next. All new Oz. Women who
lost half their body weight.
Transformation so amazing you have to
see it to believe it. I'm not giving. If
you think you can't lose weight, think
again. How they did it so you can too.
Plus, rip a page from Laala Anony's
power playbook. You can be great at more
than one thing. How she went from the
bottom to the top. Lala sharing her
rules. All new Oz. That's coming up on
[Music]
Monday. Lots of moms and daughters in
the audience. Are you always fighting to
protect each other? Yeah. Yeah, you are.
Well, today I've got a story about two
fighters. A mom fighting for her child
and her daughter fighting for her life.
Janet Burnan made national headlines two
years ago when she fought for her
10-year-old daughter Sarah to have a
lung
transplant. Sarah suffers from cystic
fibrosis, a life-threatening illness
that targets the lungs. Her condition
was so severe her doctor predicted that
she had only weeks to live unless she
received a successful lung transplant.
[Music]
But federal policy prevented children
under the age of 12 from being
considered for an adult lung. Janet
launched a massive publicity campaign to
change the under2 policy and filed a
lawsuit against the federal government
claiming the system discriminated
against
children. She also took the fight to
social media. Family and friends
circulated a petition on change.org
which collected over 370,000 signatures.
The grassroots effort paid off. The
transplant network created an exception,
making Sarah eligible to receive an
adult lung
transplant. The first surgery
failed. But after 3 days in critical
condition and on life support, Sarah
received a second
transplant. This time, the high-risisk
operation was a success.
It took six long months to recover, but
Sarah was finally able to return home to
her family.
Janet and Fran Mahan and their daughter
Sarah are all joining us. I like I like
the thumbs up. How you feeling with your
new lungs? Um, it's going really well.
Um, I've been able to run around outside
and um go to the pool and I've been
learning how to ride my bike. You're
riding your bike now? Yes. That can be
dangerous.
Are you happy being able to do all these
new things you couldn't do before? Yes.
Have you seen lungs before? Um, I've
seen a picture of them, but I didn't
actually see them like in real life
before. Like maybe like the way you're
going to see them in a minute under that
towel. Yeah. You want you want to see
them under the towel? Yes, I do want to
see. You do? Come on over here. So, here
your purple gloves. Goes with your
dress, by the way. Here, mom and dad.
You take a look at these as well. Let me
show you what your lungs look like. And
just so we're all on the same page here
because this was a lifesaving
intervention mom did. Sarah didn't get
just Are you ready, Sarah? Hold on. You
ready? I got She wants me to hold on.
I'm going to hold on. Just put them on
my gloves.
The gloves a little big for you, but
they the color goes well with your eyes.
All right. So, you didn't just get one
lung, you got two lungs.
So, that's what they look like. You can
go ahead and touch them.
What do you think about
them? You playing an instrument. What
are you? They don't make any
noise. You can pick them up. See, these
they're just squishy feeling. They are
squishy feeling. Don't drop them now.
But lungs are unique and they blow up
with air and they do all kinds of
miraculous things and they're very
delicate. So when they're destroyed and
we replace them, it's a big operation.
And you can see these are adult lungs. M
they do fit in the children and we can
do things to make them fit, but it's not
always an easy match. That's important
because Sarah was only 10 years old when
she needed the transplant and she wasn't
considered first on the transplant
waiting list for adults, only for kids.
So, Fran, how did you react finding out
that your daughter would probably die
because she couldn't get listed on that
adult list? I was shocked because Sarah
has had cystic fibrosis her entire life.
So, we knew at some point it was going
to be challenging, but what really was
really shocking was the fact that that
someone else who was much healthier than
her would probably get lungs before her
just because of her age. You okay with
those lungs?
You know, it's these organs are so
sacred when we do transplants. I always
think about that as you're putting them
into people because it is truly the gift
of life. But when these lists and you
know these lists are created by good,
well-meaning people, but they sometimes
have gaps in them. So Janet, how does it
feel to know that because of your
petitioning and pushing and shoving, you
not only saved your daughter's life, but
many others now because you created an
exemption on this pediatric list? Well,
of course, it was amazing to save Sarah
and very surreal, but we always wanted
to make the change for all kids. It was
never just about Sarah for us. Um, so we
feel really, really proud. At night, we
still go in and look at her breathing.
You know, it's just an amazing thing
just to see her breathing like any other
kid. Never take that for granted again.
Parents do that a lot. Brent, who's the
bigger fighter in the family, your wife
or your daughter?
Sarah. I think Sarah most definitely. Um
she
went she I mean through the entire
process and just her entire life she's
always effortlessly fought never
complained and there was one point
actually when we were in the ICU when we
asked her you know that this is really
rough this is tough I mean at any point
this is too much for you let us know and
she looked up and gave us this look and
little sly look like she's kind of
giving out and she she said that she
never wants to give up and she never
wanted us to give up for her.
So Sarah, what's next for you besides
playing with the organs? What are you
hoping for next? Um I want to be on the
swim team um with my brother and sister
Sean and Ella. So, I'm going to do like
lots of courage to ask you so you don't
have to do anything in the fall or the
winter. Nothing's going to hold you
back, my dear. Nothing whatsoever. I'm
very proud of you and your parents as
well making this all happen. To find out
how to become an Oregon donor because we
have enough donors. We don't have any
crisis. We're getting them for the
patients. You can log on to
donatelife.net. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Whoever said a doctor's visit isn't fun
has obviously never been to the Dr. Oz
show. Is that right? Make your
appointment today. Go to
dr.com/tick and sign up for free
tickets.
All new Oz. Women who lost half their
body weight. Transformation so amazing.
You have to see it to believe it. I'm
not giving. If you think you can't lose
weight, think again. How they did it so
you can too. Plus, rip a page from Laala
Anony's power playbook. You can be great
at more than one thing. How she went
from the bottom to the top. Lala sharing
her rules. All new Oz. That's coming up
on
Monday. All new Oz. Women who lost half
their body weight. Transformation. So
amazing you have to see it to believe
it.
If you think you can't lose weight,
think again. How they did it so you can
too. Plus, rip a page from Lala Anony's
power playbook. You can be great at more
than one thing. How she went from the
bottom to the top. Lala sharing her
rules. All new Oz. That's coming up on
Monday.
[Music]
With Mother's Day just two days away,
here's a little history lesson about the
celebration. It all started with a woman
named Anna Jarvis, who wanted to honor
her mother, a Civil War peace activist
who died in 1905. Now, Jarvis pushed for
a national holiday to pay homage to all
mothers. And in 1914, President Woodrow
Wilson signed the proclamation making
the second Sunday in May the National
Mother's Day holiday that we celebrate
today. So to all the mothers out there,
especially my dear Lisa and Daphne, who
are both mothers now, happy Mother's
Day. Now it's time for you in case you
missed it. First, Mom's bestkept
money-saving secrets. Believe it or not,
you can save money at meal time by
introducing your family to vegetarian
and meatless meals a few times a week.
You can make meatless meals like this
Crock-Pot vegetarian chili, which is
super easy to make. You can save time
and it tastes out of this world. They
have a black bean burger. I'm going to
have all these recipes on dr.com. And
eggs are fantastic source of protein.
Healthy omelets can uh be made. And by
doing this, you can easily save 30 bucks
a week. $30 a week. That's about
$1,500 per year. Even better, healthy
vegetarian diets are typically low in
fat and high in fiber. Here's another
great tip that's mom approved. Instead
of putting just loose change in a jar,
you should do this, too. You know, save
that money. It makes a difference. But
take it one step further and toss the
singles from your wallet into the shoe
box each night. When you do that, those
$1 or $2 a night add up pretty quickly
to a savings of $300 a year. And that I
think is a reasonable chunk of change to
make something good in your life happen.
And another show off with Kelly Roland,
who I adore, and she speaks to the
beauty of life when this new child came
into her existence, but then she lost
her mom tragically. And for Mother's
Day, I want us all to think about the
one thing we really appreciate about our
moms, besides the fact they gave birth
to us. So, who wants to go first? Who
loves their mom? Har, what's your name?
Christine Welker. So, what's special
about mom? What's special about mom?
Well, I'd say that she taught me how to
be strong, passionate, and love
everything I do. Is that right? I hope
so. Yes, it is. How about you over here?
Um, my mom has got me through good times
and bad times, and she's my rock. Is
that your sister over there? It is. Hi.
What's your name? Melissa. Melissa. To
top your sister now. It's a competition
here. We're trying to beat each other.
She's taught me how to operate a
kitchen, how to cook. I wouldn't have
known how to turn the oven on if it
wasn't for her. So, thanks, Mom.
Head down to your college over there.
I'm definitely thankful for my mom
working so hard, sending me to a great
school. Definitely my education for my
mom. Now, is now is mom that's grandma
there? All right. So, what do you have
to say for grandma? I am so grateful my
mother gave me my sense of humor.
Is your mom funny? No, you're not that
funny. Mom,
so is that mom, grandma, you get to She
is funny. She is funny. Well, her
daughter has this. So, I was I had this
big vision in my in my home for a book I
was going to write. It was going to be a
comedy book. So, I was talking to my
wife about it and she was very drolly
acknowledging that it wasn't going to be
very good. So, I finally thought I'd go
to my daughter to get an arbitration.
So, I went to my daughter. I said,
"Honey, don't you don't you love this
idea? It's so cool. And she looked at me
very calmly and she said, "It would be a
funny book if funny people wrote
it." So, I love you all for Mother's
Day. Thank you for being here. And I got
to do my little disclaimer here. Don't
forget, please be careful of dubious
people online that make it seem like I'm
endorsing their products. I don't. To
see a full list of our trusted
sponsorship partners, you go to dr.com.
I will see you next
time. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
[Applause]