[Applause]
Honestly, I don't know. Alec Bowwin and
his beautiful wife are doing it. They've
got four kids, ranging from 5 months to
5 years old. It's a lot to handle,
right? It'll keep you going. But perhaps
Alex's biggest dad challenge. Well, it's
not how to keep his cool when his
22-year-old model Ireland sends out an
Instagram post like
this. And it goes viral. About to tell
us how he responded to Ireland's post.
Plus, he's going to tell us about the
personal health struggle his family
recently helped him through. Alec Bowen,
my friend, come on out
[Applause]
here like an
airport, right? Can I go over here? Go
this
side. You know,
oh, they love you. I always say when I
come here, I say, "This studio of yours
is like an airport terminal.
We need to have like a duty-free shop
over here and a Starbucks over here. The
biggest stage in Manhattan." It is a big
stage. They used to Now, I want to ask
you a quick question, please. Didn't all
your daughters post pictures of
themselves like half naked on a
motorcycle? Oh my goodness. Come on. I
had this. Well, this I've had adult
daughter issues, which we'll talk about
as well. But before that, how did you
react and how did you feel because
they're different when you saw that
picture? I think that the um you know,
Ireland is a model and she does a lot of
fitness modeling, so swimwear and
athletic wear. So, in that world, I
guess it's like anything goes these
days. So, as a as a father of three
grown children, I struggle as well. And
you we we want to protect our daughters,
but at the same time, they're they're
going to grow up. and Ireland now is a
model, but she's a public person and
she's out on her own making a name for
herself. So, how do you deal with that?
What's it like for you? Well, I don't
know what it was like for you, but I
mean, in this day and age where the you
know, me too, times up, sexual assault,
all these issues that have become uh
very uh front and center now. And so as
a father with with girls, uh I'm
grateful that both daughters I have from
two different marriages have very
capable mothers. Yeah. Cuz the mother is
the one who's going to teach the girl, I
think, how to get around in the world.
It's hard for us to break through. Well,
let's talk about congratulations are in
order. You know, since the last time
only a year ago you were here, your
five-month-old Romeo is with us.
Congratulations. A fourth child. Cute
little thing, right? fourth child, but
they're all under five, which keeps you
going. What's it like? What's it like
when you go home now? Um, we uh uh I
literally have a moment now. I walk in
the door and I I I literally I I'm not
kidding. I take a pause and I'm like,
"How did this
happen? What happened here? I was
single. I was divorced. I had one kid.
I'm in a I remember being in a
restaurant. I remember she was very
beautiful. I remember we talked and I
thought she was very interesting and
very colorful and smart and then boom, I
got four kids like Jiffy Pop. It was
like boom boom boom boom boom boom boom
boom boom and we have four kids and it's
um but I I must say that uh I'm at a
time in my life I'm 60 and I I'm at a
time in my life when work is just in a
different place. Yeah. I mean, I love
working and I the things I do I enjoy,
but I certainly was ready to have
something else that was more uh powerful
and more meaningful to put my energy
into. But since you're a father now,
what's it like? Well, I mean, I think
that it it's my wife works and she
enjoys working, but she also has
accepted as a lot of women do, it's a
very difficult thing for women. My wife
could go out the door and be uh your
daughter is uh uh you know in
broadcasting and she's a famous uh you
know uh host of a show and your daughter
is this absolutely gorgeous woman who
I'm madly in love with Daphne and uh
she's just I love her. She's this
fabulous woman. Although Lori and Daphne
have a podcast by the way. Yes. Which I
know takes time. They're very they're
both perfectionists at this. So it does
put some more pressure on you. And I'm
wondering cuz I've always thought of you
as sort of being hands-on. You You Not
anymore.
Well, how's that how's that different
now taking care of the kids as when you
were taking care of Ireland when she was
a child? Well, I think it's much more
complicated when you're in a house where
we had kids so quickly. You know, we had
four kids in four and a half years. So,
we're you walk in my kitchen and a
five-year-old child is the oldest child
in the room. You know, you to put that
in perspective, there's four little
kids. They're all little with their
needs and everything. So, they're kids,
so they're going to do what they do. But
my wife, what I love about her is she's
always maintaining an energy in the
house of them apologizing to each other,
saying please and thank you to each
other, not just the exchange between
adults, but that the relationship
between the children is a healthy one.
So, love that. I hear that Hillary might
want to have another baby. I'm just
curious. Who told you that? I've I've
got my
my Are you ready for another baby? Well,
my wife said, "I want to have another
baby. We want to have another girl." And
I said, "I hope you and your next
husband are very happy together
and we can all be friends. Maybe we go
all live in a compound together and have
breakfast deal. We'll all be friends and
be collaborative." And I hope he's a
nice guy. I wish you well. I hope you're
happy. And uh uh No, but she wants to
have another one. And uh maybe we will.
We'll see. We'll see. All right. You got
a job for me? You always have a job.
Coming up, Alex going to open up about
the serious surgery which he actually
had that has changed his life and how
playing Donald Trump on Saturday Night
Live is affecting his health. His
interesting answer when we come
back. We're back with the one and only
Alec Baldwin. Had serious surgery this
past winter, a hip replacement. Well, I
went along and uh uh I you know, I had
back pain and I'd hurt my back and that
was a condition that would come and go
and sometimes get worse uh uh from a
from an injury I did doing a play in New
York many years ago. And then uh the
summer of last year, like 2007, I'm
playing tennis and I felt a pain I never
felt before. And I was like, "Oh my god,
what is that?" And I go in and I get
x-rayed and they said, "You're bone on
bone." And uh I have a congenital
displacia. You're a doctor, so you know
what that is. That's when your hips are
born a little wide. That's why they put
those kids in little binders sometimes
when they're young and the the the the
the ball doesn't fit into the socket
properly and so forth. So it's your
mother's fault. Yeah. Well, believe me,
I'm happy to I called her again. Another
thing that I owe to you, you know, but
uh the um uh the I I I go and they say
to me they're going to have the surgery,
which is very very complicated because
you have to have at least a couple weeks
you can lay low and not do anything. So
I had this one done. I have to have the
other one done. But I tell people uh
when they do that, I say uh get x-rayed
when you're like in your 40s and find
out, do you have that dysplacia? I mean,
see a doctor and have them tell you. You
know, this is the the 10th year of the
show. I'm not a doctor, but No, you but
you play one on talk shows, which we'll
get to in a second. Uh but when I
started the show, uh we hip replacement,
people always thought it was a an older
person's problem. Well, I would I played
football on weekends with my friends
till I was 40 years old. I played
tennis. I'd ski. I mean even when I was
and this is critically I think
significant is even excuse me even when
I was heavy and I got really overweight
and bloated from you know uh from my
later on we'll talk about my sugar
condition and when I gained weight from
that I still felt strong and I would you
know I go chop wood and I I felt good
you know what I mean and when this hip
thing happened I did not feel good I was
in so much pain I was nauseous every day
since you didn't really have a lot of
background in this when you walked out
of the doctor's office and he said hey
you've got bone on bone you're going to
have had your hip replaced. What were
you feeling? I was so depressed. Well,
because you you you hit that age. I'm 60
and I felt good. I mean, even, like I
say, even when I was heavy, I felt like
I could do things and play and run and
do this. And when this happened, you
start to think about, well, now I'm a
car that the parts are falling off the
car. I'm a car. The car is going down
the road. It's got no hub caps and the
fenders hanging off and the car. And now
I'm thinking going, oh god, that's me.
I'm that car now. you know, and it's
very uh uh uh demoralizing when you face
something, anything we have, I mean,
you're a doctor, you know, this anything
you face that is just has a whiff of
mortality. Yes. You start to get very
emotional. So, well, you know, one of
the reasons I love your wife is posted
this beautiful picture of of holding
Alex hand in in the recovery room and,
you know, I know she took good care of
you. Do you think you were a good
patient? Uh, were you whining all the
time, moping around? I had I I had uh
hernia surgery uh years ago. I had the
little groin hernia and I I I had
surgery uh back in 2006 or I forget when
quite a while ago. And uh when I'm done,
this woman that was the head of the
recovery room was this uh you know,
middle-aged African-American woman. She
had all the credentials on her. She was
the head lady. And I wake up from the
surgery and you know they give you some
pretty space age drugs when they're
going to cut you open. You know what I
mean? And I wake up in the thing and she
says, "Mr. Baldwin, I'm Muriel so and
so. I'm the head of the ICU." And I lit
I literally literally I go,
"Muriel, I love you,
man. I love you, baby." Like I was so
happy to be alive. Yes. And when they
put you under, I think, what if I don't
wake up, you know? And when I woke up, I
was like, "Have dinner with me, Muriel."
Well, you was loving with the Ari when
you recognized her. My wife is uh I'm
very lucky. My wife is the easiest
person to love I've ever met in my life.
Oh, she's the easiest person to like.
She's the easiest person to love. She's
the easiest person to be around. And the
other day I was saying something to her.
We were arguing about something. And my
wife literally turns to me. She goes, "I
like, you know, tomorrow you're going to
wake up and say I love you and I cannot
live without you." She goes, "So why
don't we just jump to that right now?"
And I thought, "Oh my god, she's funny.
I know she's been hammering you a little
bit on your diet. I I hear this, you
know, through social channels. Well, she
holds up a mirror. She doesn't hammer.
She's Yeah, she's very laid-back, but
she does say, you know, whatever you
want to do, and we can talk about that,
you know, my whole pre-diabetic. Let's
do that. Explain to everybody because
you've learned a lot about it. Well,
you're trim and you've been trim your
whole life. Well, I So, I played
football in college and when I Where'd
you go? At Harvard. Where'd you play?
Safety. Oh my god. And I uh I was
bigger. You were bigger. Yeah, I was I
was bigger. It was mostly muscle, but I
had fat on. And then when I became a
physician, I saw a lot of people who
were heavy, not doing well. And I
thought to myself, I'd rather be a
slimmer version of myself and live
longer for the people I love, right? And
that I really I've talked to the
audience many times. If you make it easy
to do the right thing, it happens. But
diabetes sneaks up on folks not just
because of weight, for other reasons as
well. Some people are genetically
predisposed. And when you do have
diabetes or pre-diabetes, it changes a
lot. It has that that as you mentioned
that that whiff of mortality. Well, I
think the other thing is I I go and I
had Lyme disease. No, no, I had I had a
kidney stone. And I go into the doctor
and he does my blood work and he goes,
"Hey man, your sugar is insane. We did
your blood work. Your sugar is nuts."
And he goes, "I think you're diabetic or
you're pre-diabetic." And then in the
ensuing six or seven months, I was going
to do a movie. I wanted to lose weight.
And I lost 35 pounds in a six or
eightmonth period to go do this movie
Blue Jasmine for Woody Allen. Yes. And
I'm there uh uh and and the whole idea
was that uh uh you know even my doctor
said I've never seen in my professional
career in my entire medical career
someone crash their numbers their A1C
numbers everything as effectively as you
did but by losing weight. No by by
manipulating diet only. No cookies,
mints, candy, fruit, ice cream, no
dessert, no no uh uh pasta, bread, rice,
any grains. It was salad and fish and
and and and vegetables and so forth for
quite a while. I lost 35 pounds. I felt
great. But what I've learned in my life
and for everybody, I have to say this,
and I'm not just saying this because you
because you're a friend. I mean,
obviously I respect medicine and doctors
and you have to talk to your doctor and
they got to tell you what's going on.
But for me, it was like as if I could
just stop eating sugar. Yes. I stopped
eating sugar and my weight would go, my
numbers would go bang and I'd feel
great. Now again, my wife is the one
that taught me the metaphor of the
brimming cup. If you eat a little bit of
sugar and then you don't eat it for
three or four days, then you eat a
little bit of sugar, then it goes down.
But if you eat it and then eat it, then
then it spills over. The cup is full.
That's when I feel so sick. It makes me
sick. When I don't do it, I feel great.
So talk to a doctor. Talk to an
endocrinologist and make sure you're
doing but with and I'll tell you as a
doctor, let me speak to the doctor side
of this. It's a lot easier for us to
manage you if you're doing the diet
stuff on your own cuz it's hard for me
to sprinkle insulin on a cookie. It
doesn't quite work like you think it
would work. That's a great idea. That's
right. Why don't we go bake some insulin
cookies right now? Next on the dock
garage. Yeah. No, but but you're you're
very right in that the less sugar I eat,
the better I feel. All right. Up next,
more with Alec Bowwin. Stay with us.
That was a clip from the new Alec
Baldwin show. It's on ABC. It's right
across the studio uh from here. You
enjoy it? Well, I have four kids. I need
all the money I can get my hands on. I
need money. I need a big bag of money.
These kids cost me a fortune. It's
driving me nuts, you know. But no, the
show was another example of a way to
stay home and shooting things and
developing projects where I can stay
with my family. That's the priority. So,
do you enjoy the show? You enjoy talking
to folks? Well, I love doing a show. I
mean, you do a show every day, which is
a different grind. I can't even express
to you how tough it is to do a daily
show. It's really tough. Fallon and you
and Coar and everybody that's on every
day. That's a really really uh different
muscle. And for me, we shoot in bundles.
We get a stage in this building as you
know. Sometimes we've actually borrowed
your set. I'm on the phone going, "Is Oz
out of there yet? Get him out of there
now." And we come and we shoot match
game in this building and we shoot uh uh
the talk show and we do it in bundles.
So we we clear out a week or two, book
all the guests we can and we bring them
on and hopefully we book people where
it's something that the audience wants
and I'm interested in them at the same
time. Yeah. One of the biggest stages of
all is Saturday Night Live, the iconic
program that we all have grown up with
and is still dominant. And you're
playing Donald Trump again this year,
which is uh you all love him, Miss
Donald Trump. Now it's fantastic. I I I
I know it's fun or you wouldn't do it.
There's one guy in the in the in the in
the in the fuchsia colored shirt there
with the glasses. He did not clap when
they said no. I didn't know. Now he's
clapping. I hope we have I always hope
we have one Donald Trump fan in the
audience. And you can tell cuz everybody
else go, "That's so And one guy's like,
I hate that Alec
Har. He's horrible." But but there is a
lot of stress since you mentioned Donald
Trump fans. There's a lot of stress when
people come after you personally uh when
they don't like what you're doing to
imitate as talented as it is. I've
really gotten to the point where uh you
know, first of all, America right now is
a place which is a boiling pot of very
intense opinions. You know, Americans
are very on both sides are very upset
and they're very angry. people who don't
who think that Trump is someone who does
not represent what the chief executive
of a of the the
uh um commander-in-chief of the country
should be and other people who think
he's exactly what he should be and that
I've never seen people argue about that
more in my lifetime than now and I think
that in this country uh if we change the
campaign finance system in this country
that is the lynch pin of all the
problems in America today it's very
painful Would you ever run for office? I
tell you the truth, I would love to run
for office. I think I would be a great
president. We would have insulins coated
cookies in the White
House. Me Oz, Dr. Oz would come sprinkle
the insulin on the cookies for
Thanksgiving and for Halloween. Uh, and
no, I I think seriously, there is a part
of me that would love to try to bring
again what I call common sense. There's
things that you know and that you know
and that we know that the government
should be doing in education and in and
in infrastructure and so forth. There's
just things we need to get straightened
out because the United States really is
behind so many other countries in in
technology and so forth. But my wife
said she would divorce me if I ran for
office. So she did. Yeah. So in the
meantime, how long will you keep playing
portraying Donald Trump on Saturday
Night Live?
Um well that's tough to say. You know,
if if if I have a fifth child, I'm gonna
be a greeter in Vegas at a hotel to pay
my bills. We don't have no time for
Trump. I'm gonna be like, "Hey, I'm Alec
Baldwin." Remember me? I was in
Beetlejuice. I was in Bele. Well,
meanwhile, cuz the Hawks new show, the
Alec Baldwin show airs Sunday nights on
ABC. What time? Uh I here's what I
suggest. I think it's it could be 9:00.
It could be 10 o'clock. I don't
remember. But why don't you just put the
channel on ABC at like 6 o'clock in the
afternoon? Right after the football
game. Watch the football game. I'm all
for that. Then right after the football
game, go to ABC and leave it there on
Sunday nights. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good