Actor Shannon Gardy is no stranger to
the spotlight. Since she was 10 years
old, she's had a successful career on TV
and in films. But now, the actress is
starring in her own real life medical
drama as she faces a health
crisis. At age seven, Shannon Dar moved
from Memphis to Hollywood. By 10, she
was a working actress. At 11, she
captured a winning role and America's
attention as the courageous Jenny Wilder
on Little House on the Prairie. Her
stardom was solidified when legendary
producer Aaron Spelling cast her as the
boisterous Brenda Walsh on the smash hit
90210. Spelling and Shannon combined
forces again for the hit series Charmed.
Since then, Shannon has enjoyed a
charmed Hollywood life, working as an
actress, producer, and director, and
finding lasting love with husband Kirk
Israeno. Then, in 2015, the press leaked
devastating news that the actress later
confirmed. Shannon Doerty was battling
breast
cancer. Please welcome Shannon Doy.
I'm so happy you're here. Thank you. All
right. You're 44 years old.
Life's going well. Yeah. Charmed as we
were saying, right? And you hear those
fateful words, you have cancer. Yeah.
Where were you? What went through your
mind? Um, I was in a car driving on PCH
back to my house. My mom was actually
driving. I was in the passenger side.
And the doctor called me and he told me
that. And all I could think
was, how do I tell my family? you know,
how are they gonna deal with it? It was
um you know, you worry most about the
people that you love and about making
sure that they're going to be
okay. So, I'm already going to
cry. So, for me, that was the hardest
part. My husband told me, he goes, "Just
think of everybody in their
underwear." So, you're all in your
underwear right
now. K Kurt, her husband, is joining us,
by the way. He's in the audience.
I I know this is difficult. Uh we sat
down about a month ago and talked
privately and and I know how passionate
you are about your story being helpful
to women all over the country. Yeah.
Whether it's a cancer diagnosis or
anything else. And you're so insightful.
So, I'm going to have you if you walk
you, you know, our audience through
what's going on in your life. Okay. Was
there a family history of breast cancer?
Um it was on my father's side. His mom
had uh cancer, breast cancer and uh
emphyma I think. Um but nothing my my
mom's side is healthy as can be. And you
discovered the lump yourself. Yes. How
did that happen? Uh, I was in the shower
and um I felt something a little odd and
um and you know a million different
scenarios go through your head at the
time. You you know you compare yourself
to your dog and you're like oh well he
has like a fatty cyst here. I'm like
Leroy. Everything's fine. You know I
mean your head goes into into all sorts
of different places. Um, and then and
then reality comes in and you're like,
"Ah, I should probably get this checked
out." And and did you um un you know,
unfortunately I was with uh business
managers at the time. Um and they um
they as business managers do you you pay
them 5% of every single dime that you
make and they go you do nothing. You
don't even know where your bank accounts
are. you know, for the most part, they I
mean, they literally take over your
life. And so, their job is to pay your
health insurance, to pay your mortgages
on time, to pay your Verizon bill, to
make sure your AT&T bill is paid. Um, to
make sure your taxes are paid. Like, I
mean, that's their job. Um, and for 5%
you really hope that they're doing that
job because that's a lot of money. Um,
and I found out that they had not in
fact paid my health
insurance. Um, yeah. And you know,
timing wise, it was past being eligible
for other sorts of insurance. So I I I
didn't I didn't go to the doctor when
when I needed to.
So you delayed seeing the doctor? Yes.
Knowing there's a lump in there. Yes.
That is something that women all over
the country are struggling with right
now. Yeah. What's that like? The
powerlessness of that. Um, I mean it's
pretty frightening and all I can say is,
you know, go go like because you have no
idea what that extra time might have
might have afforded you and and usually
what it is is that like mine for
instance spread to a lymph node and or
two
and you know it might not have spread.
There's a really strong possibility it
wouldn't have spread. So I think
obviously as you know as a doctor the
most important thing is catching it as
early as humanly possible. So when you
finally get to the doctor's office and
they start examining you treating you
horrible.
Horrible. What did they tell you? You
know I'm actually very shy like and
modest as my husband will attest. And so
to have all these people like touching
my breast is really uncomfortable. And
um I don't know if there's any breast
cancer survivors. Actually, this whole
audience is breast cancer. Oh, I love
you
guys. Oh, it's
amazing. You're all gorgeous, by the
way. You're beautiful and and I'm dying
to hear your story at some point as
well. But it's it's horrible. You know,
you're you're in there and then it's the
waiting for the results and you're like,
"Okay." And they do the mammogram and
they're like, "This doesn't look so
good." And we think that, you know, we
think that we should do a biopsy and in
your head you're like, "God, this is
this is turning all bad and how is this
happening to me?" To me, you know,
that's what you say to yourself, right?
And I always thought that I was I'm in
the middle of writing a book about my
experience and and and in it I say that,
you know, I was Superman. Like I thought
my body was so strong. I felt like and
nothing nothing could touch me. And now
I feel like like a lemon, like a car
that's a lemon. And you're like, how can
I return it back to the dealership and
get a new one? Um, and you do you just
kind of feel like how where did I go
wrong? And how am I how did I fail? You
went one step beyond at everything you
did in your whole life, but especially
now. Right. So when you got the
diagnosis, you started looking for other
approaches, different therapies. Yes.
walk us through what was good, what was
bad, what was ugly. Well, I mean, first
off, I think doctors are phenomenal and
um I love my doctors at Cedars. I think
they're great. Um but I think that often
times what we do as patients is we just
accept what they say and we go, "Oh god,
they know everything, so we're just
going to go along with this." So they're
like, "You need to take both off." Okay,
sure. or you need to do this or you need
to do this kind of chemo. And I think
that it's it's very important to
question it. Yeah. To constantly sort of
look at them and question and say, well,
but why? And is there an alternative?
And and if I stay on medicine a little
bit longer, is that going to change
maybe the kind of surgery that I have to
have? And um you know, why do I have to
have radiation because it's so damaging
to your body? Or you know, what are the
different forms of chemo? and have we
tested me to see which chemo will work
for me? And then there's the alternative
medicine. There's vitamin C injections.
I don't know if you guys did any of
those, but um you you you did that.
Yeah. Vitamin C IVs um which are
phenomenal for you. I don't think they
cure cancer, but they're phenomenal. I
mean, it's vitamins being injected into
your body. And um and you research a lot
of stuff. If you research these clinics
in Mexico that claim to cure you. Yeah,
you guys know those. Huh? Um, did you go
there, too? No. God, no. No, no, no. I
didn't know. Uh, I drew the line at
going to Mexico. Um, but you're already
so overwhelmed with the decisions you're
having to make and with your own
research. And this sort of comes at you
and it's even more overwhelming. you
kind of what I did is I buried my head
in the sand and just sort of tuned
everybody out and kind of figured out
what felt right for me and obviously
with a lot of prayer as well. So what
did you do? Is the mass still in your
breast? Yes. So I have not had surgery
yet. um my oncologist felt that we
should give this sort of an opportunity
this medicine protocol to see if it
would shrink uh the tumor and it's also
known to it sort of cuts off all your
estrogen. So my particular tumor is is
estrogen. It's all fed by estrogen. So
the minute that they they cut it off,
it's sort of like okay, you know, pretty
sure it won't spread at this point. Um,
and then you hope that that the protocol
you're on actually shrinks the tumor so
that again you have more
options, you know, down the road for
surgery. Do you think your doctors
wanted to wait as long as you've waited?
No. Does it make does it make you
nervous that the the tumor is still in
there? No. Um because I feel like I
needed to be ready and I needed first,
second, third opinions and I I didn't
want to look back after surgery and say,
"Wow, I wish I had done this instead."
When we come back, I love you. Why
Shannon waited to have her cancer
removed? The other thing she's tried.
Stay with us. What do you remember about
shooting that episode from That was
Beverly Hills 90210 by the way. was the
first time in a teen show aimed show
that breast cancer was part of the
story. Yeah. I felt um I felt a profound
sense of responsibility.
Are you struck now by how life is in a
patriarch? I mean that's too close.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean I wish I had Brenda's
outcome as opposed to mine. But, you
know, I think that at this point, I just
hope that I can help any woman who's
going through it and make her realize
that like I'm right there with you, you
know, and we can all go through it
together.
So, my medical unit called Shannon's
oncologist who told us Shannon's
specific cancer is an estrogen positive
invasive ductal, which is a very, very
common yes, form and it feeds off
estrogen. So, in order to help, you try
to turn off estrogen because it makes
tumor lip get larger. I know that your
doctors are very nervous about you
stalling the surgery. I'm going to use
the word stall because you've gotten a
lot of opinions now. What have you been
doing in the meantime? And just walk us
through in some detail the therapies
that they're giving you. So, I get a
Lupron shot once a month and uh which is
just not pleasant because you
emotionally for the first couple hours,
days, week, uh you're a little, you
know, off I would say. Um, or shut your
ovaries down. Yes. So, I mean, I guess
that was sort of the hardest part for me
of going on this protocol is because I'm
44 and my husband and I wanted children.
So, you go on Lupron and you instantly
go into menopause. Well, 2 months later,
you're in menopause. Um, and but you
know, you have to make choices in life
sometimes. And, uh, you know, maybe that
just means that we adopt and we're
supposed to be those people that, you
know, provide a home for a child who
doesn't have one. Um,
you very good at that. Yeah, thank you.
I think so too. And then I take another
pill which I cannot pronounce. It's
okay. So, the big question. Mhm. This is
our last conversation ended without an
answer to this. Have you decided to have
a surgery? Yes. You have? Yes. Oh, God.
Yeah.
And what type of surgery are you going
to have? Have you decided that yet? Um,
I haven't. It's between two of them and
at the end of the day it'll be up to my
doctor and it could, you know, change
the last minute. Uh I'm I'm actually
going to a center
um that you know of very well and uh
just to sort of get their general
opinion. Good. Good. And then I head
back to LA and instantly sort of go in
with my doctors and they, you know, I'm
like, you guys make the final decision.
What what would you do if it was your
wife? What would you do if it was your
daughter? And ultimately that's I I you
know I whatever they're just breasts
right um I mean I love them mine mine
but you know and everybody's really
they're beautiful and but you know in
the grand scheme of things they're just
not I would rather be alive and I would
rather grow old with my
[Applause]
husband. I I get the fear uh it's
different for women I think when they
sense their breasts which are part of
who they defined by. I mentioned that
the audience is filled with women who've
already been through this because I
thought as much as you're helping them,
they might be able to help you. So, if
it's okay, I'm going to have them just
say a few words from their heart. I
haven't scripted this, but we'll hear
from them. And I I don't know who wants
to go first. Uh, everyone who has had
breast catch, please stand up in the
audience. And maybe you want to go
first. Words of wisdom. Something that
might help Shannon, something that
helped you. Hi. Hi.
Your tears, I think, have brought all of
us to tears because we've been in your
shoes recently. Um, and we all came for
you. Literally came here for you today.
[Music]
You guys are amazing.
You're killing me today. We knew about
you coming and we came here for you.
There will be women watching. Yeah. Who
will hear you and listen to your words
and be their own best advocate. And you
I promise you will have saved lives
today during this. Oh my god. Thank you.
[Music]
How are you? I'm good. How are you
doing? I'm doing well. You got Thank
you.
I wanted to talk to you today about a
mistctomy because the biggest
misconception about a mistctomy is that
you're no longer beautiful anymore and
you're no longer a real woman. But I'm
here to tell you, these women are here
to tell you that you are a real woman.
That you are beautiful after your mctomy
if that's what you choose to do. Well, I
can tell you that you're gorgeous, so I
believe every word of love. Thank you so
much. You all are. Thank you. And
there's life after a mistctomy. There's
a living life after a mistctomy.
You can tell why you guys are survivors.
God bless you for all being here today.
All right. Coming up, how breast cancer
affects Shannon's family. We're going to
meet her husband Kurt. Stay with us.
We're back with Shannon Dy and her
husband Kurt, who's now joining us in
the audience. Shannon just announced
that she's battling breast cancer. Kurt,
when someone you love is going through
something like cancer, it affects the
whole family. How's it been with for
you, how you been handling this? Um, you
know, it's that when when this kind of
thing happens that, you know, the thing
that you can't help is that it changes
you. That um you have you have no choice
in that, but the it's how it changes you
that you can kind of deal with. So, I
think with us, it's um brought us much
closer together. Um, it's one of those
times where you you you get to test your
metal as a as a married couple. He loves
you a lot.
Yeah. He's trying very hard not to cry.
So, when you go public about any health
issue, but especially in cancer, it can
affect the way people perceive you. Yes.
How's it affected your career?
um it's affected it because you do you
do change a little bit while you're on
the medicine and everything else and you
do get you know you gain weight and
there's nothing that you can do about it
and you do get puffy and I think I think
that that all affects a career like mine
that's not only based on talent but it's
so much based on sort of the superficial
shell that that is right here and so it
it it has affected it and you know I've
been lucky I like a director that adores
me and hires me for a lot of stuff and
another director like Kevin Smith, but
you know th those are few and far
between. I think that most people are
usually like, "Oh god, is she okay?" You
know, what's the stress like dealing
with not just the career issues, but the
cancer, the family? Stress is stress is
rough. Uh the stress is very hard. Um,
and and I think that stress is, you
know, one of the worst things to to to
be going through when you have cancer.
It it aggravates it all. Um, also, I
don't know if you guys felt this, but
anytime I wake up with like a weird
crick right here, I freak. I'm like, "Oh
my god." Like, it's spread. Like, now I
have like some weird neck cancer. Now I
have throat. Like you just imagine that
you're breaking down all over and your
your entire body is breaking down in you
and that's incredibly stressful. And
really all it means is you should treat
yourself and go get a massage, right?
You're a courageous woman. I admire your
determination, but the one word I put
next to your name is grace. Oh, God
bless you. And I wish you the best as
you go through this. Please keep us
posted on the surgery. I'll be
supporting you and praying for you. to
everybody else here.
Thank you for watching.
[Music]