Pick it, push it, pop it. What really
lies beneath? Dr. Pimple Popper is here
with her most frightening case yet.
They're scared to find something out
like that. And Suzanne Summers up close
and very personal. Her Instagram pick
that started a firestorm. Plus, the
filthiest humidifier in America. You
have to see to believe. I'm terrified
and repulsed at the same time. Coming up
next.
[Music]
Are you ready for season
[Applause]
11? Today you're in for a treat and a
big one. She's one of my all-time
favorite guests, has nearly 6 million
subscribers on YouTube, and has been
restoring her patients confidence while
grossing out fans for years. She took
the internet by storm when she started
posting videos popping
pimples. Now, years later, these videos
have gathered over 3.5 billion with a B
billion views worldwide. Check it out.
Oh my. Please welcome the popular pimple
popper, Dr. Sandra Lee. Come on out.
[Applause]
Hello, darling.
Nice to see you. You look wonderful.
Thank you. Thanks. Oh my goodness. Here
in person. Yes. No pimples, though. I
didn't bring any with me. Yeah. You're
not wearing any today. You know, people
cannot look away, not just from you, but
from these cases, you What is so
universally mesmerizing about your work?
Well, I think it starts with a little
fascination, you know, with what we do
as physicians, but there's something
cathartic about it. I mean, there's
something about removing something that
is not supposed to be there and putting
everything back in this place. And I
think that's really why people keep
coming back to it. A little bit of OCD
in all of us, isn't there? Yes, it Yes,
there is. It makes you feel good and
that's what's so wonderful about it. I
actually think women and men are a
little different because in my family,
the women groom all the time. Yeah. So,
if they see something on me, they I can
see my wife go like this, just staring
at my forehead. It is definitely more of
a woman thing, too. They'll chase you
around the house, pin you down, that
sort of things. Yes. All right. So,
today we're checking out some of Dr.
Lee's most frightening cases yet. I'm a
spoiler alert here. These are a lot
worse than your average pimple. You all
ready for this?
I knew I knew you would be. Take a look.
That That's jaw-dropping. Yeah. So, he
has a case of rhinopa, a very serious
case. This is a form of rosacea to all
the people who have rosacea. It does not
mean that you're going to get rhopya. It
happens more in men uh people who are
fair complexed. It happens primarily on
the nose and you get this really
thickening of the nose, the skin of the
nose. It's really oily. What causes it?
I I we don't actually know what causes
rosacea because people in my family have
it. It's that redness of the cheeks.
Similar. Yeah. Santa Claus redness.
Exactly. And I want I really want to say
that's really what's really important
about this. It's not caused by
alcoholism. A lot of people think that
and that's not fair. It it definitely
rosacea and rhopya are triggered or
worsened by alcohol. There's certain
triggering factors. Alcohol, caffeine,
stress, sunlight, all the kind of things
that you know probably make us enjoy
life, right? You know, uh but it is not
does not mean if you have rhinopa that
you're an alcoholic. But what is the
cause then? Do we believe? Uh it's just
an overgrowth of tissue. It's a form of
rhinopima that just causes this
thickening and it's not um it's not a
medical necessity to remove it, but it
is certainly obviously it is not it's
cosmetically disfiguring. I thought we
had little mites on our do we all have
I'm sorry I forgot to ask I'm fascinated
by this and I because I I see it in my
family. I've looked into it. We all have
these little mites, little bugs on us,
right? Right. This is something that
kind of freaks people out because there
are mites that live on our skin normally
like little caterpillars and they kind
like that. Yes. And we we do find that
people with rosacea and rhinopa have a
higher concentration of these mites on
our face. But we all have them. They're
all watching us. They're all on us right
now. So, you know, they're like they
when you see them under electron
microscope, they're really kind of cute.
But I'm sure people most most people
don't think they look cute, but I do.
And they live on our they live on our
face and they live along with us. But
with people with this condition, we do
find an increased amount of them. So we
have tried to target um treatment you
know at you know trying to destroy some
of these. But in the meantime how how do
you treat it? Where do you even start?
You need your nose. Yes. Yes. Well this
is an extra part of your nose. He
obviously has too much nose and it's
actually you know affecting his ability
to breathe. So you actually we use a
device. It's called a loop cottery or a
loop electro surgery. It's a lot like
what you use in surgery a boi that you
cut and cauterize at the same time. And
we use it like a hot knife through
butter. I mean, it's essentially it's so
hot that it will just make a cut through
it and it's bloodless. It's very
satisfying, but you have to be careful
because obviously if you take off too
much, you can't put it back. This is
after this. Yeah, this is another Yes,
this is another patient we I did their
rhinopma. Uh, so we see a lot of
patients with it and it's just so
satisfying to do because it's such it is
something that can transform somebody so
quickly and you know, they're so
thankful for it. It's just really a
wonderful um treatment to be able to do,
you know. I'm really proud of it. You
should be and you're back to life again.
People are staring at you. I mean, you
can't. How do you hide your nose? You
can't. You can't. Anything that you do,
people are going to look at you and look
directly at your nose. So, you can't
hide it. Now, it's easy to think that
Dr. Lee only focuses on humps and bumps
and lumps. But when you're in her line
of work, there's no telling what might
come through the door next. Take a look
at this case. Oh, Maya is terrifying.
Yeah. You know, psoriasis is really
common. We see it actually in
celebrities, too. Kim Kardashian has is
told the world. Yeah. It affects one out
of a hundred people. Um it is not
life-threatening, but it's a chronic
skin condition. It's lifelong. And so
how bad does it get from different to
have 90% of your body covered? People
can have just one little spot on their
elbow or on their scalp or they can have
90 100% of their body involved. And so
it it also um causes arthritis which is
really common. So there are a range of
treatment options really if you have
mild condition. Yeah. I was going to say
that is that you get arthritis because
the same thing on your skin is happening
in your joint. Yes. Yeah. Essentially,
we think, you know, we don't really know
exactly what it is, but we do know it
has something to do with an overactive
immune system because we do find certain
treatment options that are targeting
that help, right? So, um you know, we
use topical steroids, which is really
common because that helps to blunt the
immune system, but now we have all these
biologics which are amazing. They've
really transformed dermatology and
rheumatology and medicine. So, one shot
once a month or something. Yes. Yeah.
Once a month. Depends on the medication
that you use and it can really it
cleared this guy up essentially in about
a month or so. He recovered from that.
Yes. Yeah. It's so amazing. Amazing the
things that you can do now. It really
makes me happy to be a dermatologist
that we have these things now that can
that can really help to change people.
What was his emotional response when he
no longer had continuous pain? Well, the
emotional response is that you the pain
but also the fact that now he feels like
he can interact with his kid. I think
the big deal was that he he could go to
parties with him. he can work. You know,
before it was so painful it it was
difficult for him to work and you're
embarrassed because your your wife is
his wife had to follow after him and
clean up all this scale. You know,
imagine you have so much skin in your
house in your bathtub. You take a bath
and it's stuck in your drain. All these
sorts of thing that just affect your
daily living. God bless you for helping
him. All right, up next, one of the
strangest cases Dr. Lee has ever
encountered. We just showed you a couple
strange ones. This Yeah, there it is.
We're going to show you the surgery
required to fix this right here in
studio. Be right back.
[Music]
Coming up, the most frightening cases
Dr. Pimple Popper has ever seen,
including one like this. Yes, you won't
believe how big cases like this one can
get. Is
next. Do you need a health reboot?
Something you can stick with. We have an
easy to follow lifestyle system that can
get you back on track. 20 goals. Lose 20
pounds and reduce your risk of disease
by 20%. A plan you can stick with
because we made it easy. From the way
you eat to how well you sleep and how
you manage your stress every day. System
20 for 2020. It feels good.
We're back with Dr. Pimple Papa herself,
the adorable Dr. Sandra Lee. Now, we've
been talking about the most frightening
cases Dr. Lee has ever seen. And this
one might just take the cake. Take a
look. What is going on here? Well, that
that's a lipoma, but it is the biggest
lipoma I've ever seen. And of course,
we're doing it on this show. It is it it
is the it is bigger than a baby. It
would be a record making baby, really.
12 lbs 9 oz. That That's crazy. Yes. We
take a step back here. You all saw that,
right? Right. Whenever you walk around
with a 12 pound mass in your back like
that, I hope not. What is going Why do
people not go seek care? Why don't they
address the issues? You know, I I I try
not to blame the patients certainly
because you know what happens? You
there's money involved. They don't have
the money. They have to work. They have
to, you know, raise a family and have
have a have a life that they can't get
away from. They're scared of doctors.
insurance won't pay for it. Um, and
these are really things that's not
life-threatening. A lipoma is a benign
growth. And other doctors might see it
and say, you know what, you don't have
to remove that. It's not medically
necessary. But there is also the fear
that it's not just a lipoma. There could
be become a cancer, right? They do
become cancer sometimes. Yes, they they
can. They certainly can. But something
that grows this long under the skin for
years and hasn't threatened your life
yet, unlikely. But yeah, at any moment,
anything can turn. So, what made it so
difficult to remove? The size of it, of
course. And you know, also this
gentleman, he's so sweet and kind, but
you know, it's hard. You know what? I I
do things under local anesthesia, so I
have to manage a lot of different things
at the same time. I got to talk to the
patient, make sure they're comfortable,
make sure that I can get this out, make
sure it's not, you know, bleeding, make
sure. So, there's a lot of things going
on in my mind. All right. So, we
constructed a massive replica. Actually,
it's about the same size as the lipoma.
So, not so massive. Big, you mean a real
life replica. Walk us through the
procedure. Literally, what did you do?
Yes. So this is essentially this is his
back and we take a big blade. Oh yeah, I
got to put my gloves on for this. This
is a replica. Yes, that's right. So you
have to make an incision that's along
the lines of the skin so that it heals
correctly. So it's horizontal or
vertical. Um usually in this case it
might be a little bit diagonal even
because I want to go along skin tension
lines, resting skin tension lines to
hide it as much as I can. And I make a
smaller incision always because I'm
trying to minimize it and also pop it
out in as small a hole as possible. And
I use my hands for this. Really, not
really blades as as little as possible
because obviously um your fingers are
blunt and you'll be able to dissect this
lip palm out. So, oh my goodness. A look
at that. So, here it is. It's always a
little hard. It's It's stuffed in there.
So, I use my hands to kind of undermine
what we call undermining, right? And I
pull it out. You I know you want to
help. I want to help. Don't y'all want
to get in here? That's exactly like what
what it was like. So, um, like
delivering a big at the end, that pop at
the end is Oh. And then there's usually
connective tissue. This is like fibrous
connective tissue or scar tissue. Yes.
If you could help me out. We usually
just trim it. I make sure there's no I'm
very careful about bleeding and making
sure we we stop that because obviously
we don't want this little red
cauterized. Yep. And then Oh, and there
we go. There it is.
Place it on. How good does that feel?
Yes, it feels good. That felt good. Did
you let me close this? Did the surgical
team applaud? I applaud in my mind
actually. How when you've helped
patients and we've you've shown us a
couple today that you really have
changed our lives. What does that do to
you? How does it change you? I mean it
feels wonderful. This is the biggest
gift that this show has given me. The
fact that I can actually see, you know,
you do so many things too on a daily
basis, but I actually get to see how it
changes people. They think, you know, I
see them thank me and it just it's the
best feeling in the world. It really
makes me proud to be, you know, be proud
to be a dermatologist. Well, doctor, I'm
very proud of you. Congratulations on
all your sex. It's very welld deserved.
Thank you. Keep it up. For more
frightening cases, there are plenty
more. Tune in to Dr. Pimple Popper
Thursdays at 9:00 p.m. on TLC. It's a
fabulous show. We'll be right back.
[Music]
Coming up, the wonderful Suzanne Summers
is here revealing her new way to age.
Yep. I'm sharing what I eat and what I
use to feel younger and more vibrant
than ever. And it's really cool. There's
the evidence.
[Applause]
You may know her as Chrissy from Thre's
Company or Carol from Stepbystep, but
Suzanne Summers has made a new name for
herself as one of the most outspoken
health advocates who isn't afraid to
bear it all. Suzanne recently made
headlines after this photo created a
firestorm across the country. You see
why? At 73 years of age, actually 73
years young, Den is here to reveal the
truth behind that picture. Oh, I love
having you here. I love
looks so good, too. I know. She knows
all about aging. She's going to reveal
some of the anti-aging secrets as well.
But can I just first start? Everyone was
buzzing about that photo. What's the
backtory? The caption, by the way, was
here. I am at 73 in my birthday suit.
And that's just a tribute to you. you to
look so vital to feel so good but in
addition to have recovered from breast
cancer yet they were critics what do you
have to say to them people didn't like
the fact that you posted that I know
wonder I wonder why you know my whole
thing for for women and men and what I'm
realizing is that I'm enjoying aging and
you can't lie about your age anyway
because there's a thing called Google
yes but I just want you to know girls it
ain't
over it ain't
over and so I thought when I was 73 I'd
be old and chronologically I'm old in in
society, but I'm not old. I don't. I
have energy and I do have a a a
fractured hip right now, but um that
slows me down a little bit, but that's
just from all that sex Allen and I are
having. Allan Allen that Allan Hamilton
actually the interesting thing about
Suzanne, I may brag on you. If if you
know folks in Hollywood, you know
Suzanne's reputation there. I mean,
everybody is coming to you for secrets
on how to stay young. You're kind to
come on the show and share it with all
of America. So, as just as an example,
this is a recent photo. It's on social
media. Everyone can pull it down. This
is you and Courtney Cox, Jen Aston, Lord
Dur. I mean, there some superstars
there, right? How'd you guys become
friends, by the Well, Courtney lives
right up the street from me and um all
those girls um have been looking to me
um for aging tips because I know I know
what they're going through right now.
It's just beginning. It's the decline of
hormones. And you and I have talked
about this a lot. And I started writing
about bioidentical hormones. I don't
know, this is my 27th book, so maybe 10
or 15 books ago. was called a new a new
way to age with a spectacular again
effort to educate us. Thank you. Well,
well, there is a new way to age and when
you look at the present paradigm of
aging, it's something none of us want.
It's decrepit. It's frail. It's one of
the big three, cancer, heart disease,
Alzheimer's, with the eventual end point
being the nursing home. And so, if you
don't want that, you have to start
making the right choices now. And what
I've realized in writing all these
books, it's been such a privilege, is
that if you listen to the language of
your body, you know, I joke about
menopause, it's it's [ __ ] sleepy,
sweaty, bloated, forgetful, and all
dried up. You know, what a poem. You
know that. Oh my goodness. Right. But
that's the language. When you're itchy,
when you're sweaty, when you can't
sleep, the body's talking, saying, "I'm
missing something." And so that's when I
got into putting back through lab work
these natural hormones in exactly what
you need individualized. So that's how
you take care of that part of aging. So
let me ask you is because you're a
walking testimonial to what you're doing
so my talk. Yeah. Well, so when you are
with these superstars for example who
are going through life a generation
behind you, are they taking your advice?
Do they take biioidentical hormones? Are
they doing the things you recommend?
They they uh they're doing it. Look at
them. Don't they look good? They look
good. I mean, I don't take credit for
them, but um they were they they were
interest they Courtney and Jennifer
sought me out and I I saw them in a
restaurant one night many years ago and
and we want to talk to you and I when
women say that to me, I know what it is.
And um it allows you to stay of life
rather than out of it. It allows you to
keep your juice in the best way. And not
only for women, but for men. I mean, I
look at my husband who's 83. He he looks
so amazing, really. And um I think we
have to rethink it. I' I'd really like
to live well into my hundreds as long as
I keep my brain. One of the reasons that
age is so valued in human society is
because it brings wisdom. And as you
look back on your career, and I showed
the picture of you and Thre's company
earlier, television's changed a lot. And
so if if you reflect back with me if
perhaps share what you share with those
stars that you've been mentoring on
their health, how has the industry of
television changed? Well, if you had to
if you were in television when I was in
that was probably the best time to ever
be in television unless you find a a a
niche like you have found. You have
found something only you can do. Um but
at that time there were only three
networks and um I was on the number one
show and so if you're watching
television on Tuesday night probably
half the country or a little more than
that was watching Thre's Company. Oh my
goodness. So it was a very powerful
thing. Um and I love doing that show. I
was fired because um I I my contract was
up and I went to renegotiate and all the
men are making 10 to 15 times more than
me and I'm on the number one show. I
thought are they all 15 times better
than me? So when I went in to
renegotiate they had already decided
that they were going to u fire me so
that women would stop asking. That was
before the me too movement. If it
happened today I would own ABC. Oh gosh.
Oh my goodness. Is that right? But
here's the good thing. I think in every
you have to find the silver lining in
everything. So now I'm fired and I'm
sitting at home. I had been on top of
the world. I'm sitting at home and
thinking why why did I do why wasn't I
happy? And then I hear a voice. I hear
voices and it said why are you focused
on what you don't have? Why don't you
focus on what you do have? Now I'm
talking to the voice. I go what do I
have? You have enormous visibility.
Everybody knows your name. And it hit me
like wow. Wow. Well, what an advantage
that is. So, I said to Allan, "I'd like
to do a Las Vegas nightclub act." So, we
went, and it's a long story, but he made
a two-year deal at the MGM Grand. And in
' 87, I was named female entertainer of
the year along with Frank Sinatra. Oh
gosh. And then I had nothing to do dur
during the day. So, I started writing
books. So, I wasn't ordering room
service and and um watching soap operas.
And then the book started becoming
bestsellers. And then I started
educating myself. And um I was
introduced on one show as Autodactic.
And I had to go look up what
autodidactic was. And a lot of great
contributions have been made by
autodidactics. It's usually people like
myself who are not educated. And I
learned everything that I'm capable of
learning and continue to learn. And so
my scope is narrow. But I now lecture to
doctors. I was just asked to lecture to
7,000 doctors in S. Paulo, Brazil. and
and I don't walk out insecure because I
understand this part of of aging and I
am experiencing an incredible quality of
life. I sleep eight hours every night
without any drugs. That's a big deal.
That's a big
deal. I u I have a sex drive which
normally at my age that starts waning.
You know, when you don't have sex
hormones, estrogen, progesterone,
testosterone, we women can't feel sex.
So, it's not like we've lost interest.
We can't feel it. So, when you put back
these sex hormones, woohoo, you start
feeling stuff again. And you look at
people differently, right? I want to
share some of these secrets. When we
come back, she's going to reveal her new
plan and the secret she does every day
to stay young. And it's not what you
think. Stick around.
The microwave is the best tool. We have
10 unexpected ways to use your microwave
that will blow you away. Eggplant palm
in the microwave. Use your microwave to
cook and shuck the corn. 14 minutes and
you got this baby. And what's really the
best microwave popcorn? We investigate.
Plus, haven't started our system 20 plan
yet? There's still time. We're revealing
sleep hacks and stress busters for a
restful new you. That's coming up on
Monday.
[Music]
[Applause]
I'm back with the wonderful, the
beautiful Suzanne Summers and her new
plan that she says can help reverse the
clock to help you look and feel decades
younger. In fact, you are no longer
afraid of age at all. At all. You have
made it your mission to help people feel
younger at any age. And I want to if I
can I'm going to take you through a
couple tips everybody. These are all
Suzanne's ideas. The first one has to do
with the skin. When I look at you and
you pointed this out there, the actual
texture of the skin looks fabulous. And
your skin is is your external barometer
of what's going on inside your body,
right? How do you do it? So if you look
at skin, which you have under a
microscope, these pores look like big
holes. Now imagine you're putting There
it is. There's your pores. Okay. So now
you're putting chemical cream over those
holes. Where do you think it's going to
end up? is going to drop into your
bloodstream. Yeah. Your your skin does
matter. And to your point, what you put
on it, minimal toxins, moisturiz, let me
transition to the gut because there are
tips you provide to us about the gut
that are important because it's not just
about avoiding toxins. It's also about
feeding the bacteria the right things.
Totally. So, I've given you a couple
examples of probiotics. I got yogurt,
sauerkraut, kimchi. Are these commonly
ingested in your family? Yes. In
particular, I crave sour I crave
sauerkraut. I don't know why. I'm Irish
and didn't come from Ireland. I'm
married to a Polish guy, so maybe it's
something in there. And if I only took
one supplement every day, I think I take
a lot, but if I only took one, I would
take a probiotic because everybody's
everybody's got something wrong with
their gut, right? I in the who who here
just raise your hand. You got got
bloating, you bloat, you got things.
Yeah, look at everybody. It's
something's wrong because it's the
environment. And so the one thing you
could do for your gut that would be the
best thing you could do is take a
probiotic every day. And then to make it
work better, eat either take a prebiotic
or eat sauerkraut. I make sauerkraut.
It's fun to make. Everything's fun to do
with you. All right. I'm going to leave
it with a last tip, a surprising new way
as a health secret to slow your AC down.
I'm going to raise our glass to this
idea. What is this, Ann? Take it away.
Well, when I got mold in my GI tract, I
couldn't eat any sugar or yeast, so I
couldn't have wine. And my kids said,
"Drink tequila." I said, "I don't drink
hard liquor." Because my father was an
alcoholic. Oh, try it. I liked
it. And it's kind of um psychedelic. And
and Allan and I, we have a bar at our
house. We call it Big Al's Bar. And one
night he buzzes my office at the end of
the day. He goes, "You want a date?" And
I said, "Yeah." He said, "Let's meet at
Big Al's Bar." We went down to Big Al's
Bar. He poured me a stiff tequila. Uh we
listened to music. We talked. We ended
up dancing. And then we started dating
two, three times a week. And now we date
almost every night. Let's bring Alan
here because Breeze Company. Breeze
Company. Alan, grab your tequila. Here
you go. The best part about this is the
friendship that it means. And I love
having you here, Alan. Congratulations.
Thanks taking care of my friend.
Congratulations. Thank you. Yeah. And
top of the morning to you. Top of the
morning. You're going to hear more of
her anti-aging secrets in her 27th book,
A New Way to Age. The most cutting edge
advances in anti-aging. Everyone in the
audience, guess what? You're all going
home with a copy of the book, Not the
Tequila. We'll be right back.
You know, this is the
bestation of all.
[Music]
Today, I'm letting you in on a skin care
secret for aging skin. It's a powerful
ingredient that dermatologists swear by.
It's believed to help even out your skin
tone, reduce dark spots and wrinkles,
and now it's more affordable and
available in your skin care aisle. My
friends, I'm talking about glycolic
acid. And here to tell us what glycolic
acid can do for you is Dr. Rosio Rivera
here on behalf of my trusted sponsorship
partner, L'Oreal Paris. I love having
you here. Thank you. So, glycolic acid,
something people may have heard of, but
define it if you can. And why is it a
dermatologist go-to ingredient? Well, as
a scientist, Dr. O, it is my job to make
sure I research the best and most
effective ingredients in skin care. You
know, it's glycolic acid is one of those
and it's been one of those u superpower
ingredients used by dermatologist. They
swear by for years, but it's not always
been available to everyone, especially
in its pure form. But let me tell you
what glycolic acid does, please. You
know, it resurfaces your skin from the
inside out, which translates into fewer
dark spots, more even skin tone, and my
favorite, less wrinkles and fine lines.
But we don't always have the luxury of
time to go to the dermatologist. Right.
So, at L'Oreal Paris, we developed the
first 10% pure glycolic acid serum. That
is the highest concentration that you
can use at home, but it's gentle enough
to use on every day on your skin. So you
can get what a dermatage would have
given you in past years at home. All
right, come on over here. Dr. Rivera is
going to help all of us understand a bit
more about why experts believe glycolic
acid is so important for this skin. So
we built you skin. This what it looks
like, right? And we're just going to
pretend the surface of the skin has some
blemishes on it, some wrinkles, some
aging spots. Look at that. Right? So
when you take glycolic acid, you can be
the glycolic acid administrator. You can
be the dermatologist today. Pretend.
Right? When you put the glycolic acid on
your skin, it acts to dissolve the glue
between your dead skin cells. gets the
hyperpigmentation which in turns look at
that it reveals even skin tone from
underneath you see these dark spots it
also gets rid of them just with time but
there's something else happening right
there is the thing I like about this
though is even skin tone you do this you
dissolve some of these these linkages
you allow your skin to do what it
naturally wants to do but the key is to
fix the stuff inside the skin and on top
so if I turn this around you'll see
something very important you see those
cells as we get older they start to not
look so robust. Yes. But with glycolic
acid, what's going on with 10% pure
glycolic acid, what happens is it
activates reactivates new skin cells.
This is what we're looking at. Which in
turns reduces the wrinkles on the
surface like we just saw. And these are
the new cells from I'll share with you
my All right. So, are you all clear on
this? This is the theory of why it
works. All right. So, what do you
recommend if someone wants to achieve
the benefits that we just saw? Well, I
recommend L'Oreal's Revital Derm
Intensives glycolic acid serum. It has
10% chloric acid like we just said, but
it was formulated specifically to do
those three things we just saw, dark
spots, uneven skin tone and wrinkles.
So, ladies, be consistent because if you
do, you'll see fast and very effective
results. Can we take one second here? A
lot of viewers are going to hear the
word acid. Yes. And not surprising,
you're going to think, well, do I want
to put acid on my skin? Right. But
glycolic acid, I know, I mean, as a
heart surgeon, I know that it's one of
the foundations of dermatologic
treatment. Get folks comfortable with
what it does. Yes. So acid can be scary,
but make sure you know the glycolic acid
you're using, the purity, the
percentage, but most importantly, Dr.
Oz, is it backed by dermatologist? This
is why at Lauria Paris, we created a 10%
pure glycolic acid, the highest
concentration that you could use at
home. That's also be backed by
dermatologist. We had external panel of
dermatologist go through the entire
process and looked at our formulas and
we went farther. We wanted to make sure
everyone can use this every day. So we
added and formulated with soothing and
hydrating ingredients like aloe vera.
Therefore it's ultra gentle on the skin
yet extremely effective. So let me just
tell you something. No one has to be
scared of this glycolic acid. All right.
So the revital derm intensive pure
glycolic serum. I get it. You also
however belt and suspenders this you
believe we ought to be able to for
optimal results combine it with
something else. Yes. So let's make sure
we use glycolic acid always at night.
Three four drops a little goes a long
way. But after cleansing what happens
the next morning make sure before you go
out you put an SPF a moisturizer with
SPF. I recommend the L'Oreal Revital
Triple Power um SPF 30. And why? because
it also happens to have the top three
derm recommended ingredients. Those are
do you know? No. Educate me. Pro
retinol, vitamin C, and hyaluronic acid.
And this formula has been specifically
formulated to provide super powerful
results on aging skin. All right. So, I
actually asked power couple, huh? Power
couple. Right. So, we have a power
couple here. Two of our viewers agreed
to join us. They've been using L'Oreal's
glycolic acid serum and the SPF 30 for
10 weeks. You did it. Okay. Right. Yes.
All right. So, I have before and afters.
I think these are pretty stunning, but
we got to just So, this is before and
after Audriana's skin before the L'Oreal
product and this afterwards. So, you're
here today. What kind of difference did
you notice? Were you surprised,
impressed? I was actually trying to
prove them wrong. I'm I'm a skeptic by
nature. So, I actually went into it
thinking it's not going to work. I've
been using expensive products. I've been
trying to ward off the dark spots and
nothing worked. So, this was just, okay,
I'm going to prove them wrong. The dark
spots really Yeah, I see that. It's
remarkable. It is remarkable what it
did. But the bonus the bonus was that
the fine lines were starting to are
starting to fade and it was it's a
phenomenal product. I mean, if I could
buy stocks into your product, I would.
And so, that's why I see such a huge
difference. And within the 10 weeks, I
have gotten very um so many compliments
on what my skin looks like. I've been
going out with nothing now. Look at
that. So Leah, you did the same thing
again. I have a before and after if I
can show that. And we had you guys take
your own photos. So you know, pretty
dramatic changes in pigmentation, the
smoothness. Hyperpigmentation is
absolutely outstanding. Look at that. We
also I want to point out, let's look at
this area as well. Fantastic results. So
Leah, your thoughts and describe how
your skin actually felt before and
after. Yes, it's really amazing because
I have used other products over the
counter and through the dermatologist
before and it was very drying. I would
get a lot of redness, a lot of flaking.
I try to stick with it for a couple
weeks and then I just gave up. And this
product was amazing because they didn't
there wasn't any of that drying effect
or the redness. So I really believe that
it has done a wonderful job with the
dark spots. I have a lot of sun damage
as you can see in those pictures. It's
just remarkable. We all do. It's It's
remarkable. And then the other bonus was
the fine lines. So, so if folks want to
find the products, where do they get it?
What does it cost? Actually, because
cost could be an issue. They're less
than $24 at Walmart. Isn't that amazing?
It's amazing. I've been telling
everybody results. I tell everybody
about it. These are un retouched. So,
what do you think about the audience?
They're about to rush us here because
they're so angry that these two guests
of ours got these. What do you think?
One one one little dollop for every
audience member. No, don't be stingy.
We're going to give them both. How about
that? All right. The entire audience,
thanks to my partner L'Oreal Paris. The
entire audience is going home with
Revital 10% pure glycolic acid serum and
Revital triple power SPF 30. Enjoy it.
Look beautiful. We'll be right
back.
[Music]
From helping with your cough and
congestion to dry skin and chapped lips,
so many of you consider your humidifier
a winter weather necessity, right? But
can they be more harmful than helpful,
filling the air with excess debris and
mold, maybe bacteria. It's not only
gross, but what's lurking in your
humidifier may aggravate your asthma or
your allergies. So, my guest today says
she may have the filthiest humidifier in
America. Jessica has had this humidifier
for three years. Never cleaned it once.
Looks pretty on the outside, but is
apparently leaking some kind of a peach
colored slime. What is that? It is. And
Dr. Oz, no matter how hard I try to
clean it, I pull it apart. I go in
there, I try to scrub it, you physically
can't get into the mechanism. And when I
open it and look in there, I see this
kind of like peach slime that I just
can't scrub out. And then I don't know,
can I use a chemical on it? Is it safe
to use bleach? Because then I'm going to
heat it up and put it into the air. So,
I just don't know how to clean it
properly. I'm hoping that I do a good
job in that. Three years a long time.
What What is the problem with just
getting in there, even if it's a pain in
the neck, and cleaning the humidifier?
You physically can't. You can't reach
into some of these little crevices. You
can do an outside cleaning of it and
even on the column, but to try and get
into that water tank is nearly
impossible. So, most of us are not
cleaning it or that we don't know how to
clean it. I would assume that it's it's
impossible to clean it as well as you
think you might be doing or you want to.
Now, the compound issues, if I
understand correctly, you run it all day
long. I do. What is your biggest fear
about what might be lurking in this
beautiful humidifier that has not been
cleaned? I fear that there's something
toxic or some kind of bacteria or some
kind of creature or something that I'm
then spraying into the air in my home
without even knowing. Is there a small
animal in there? What do you think that
is? Yeah, I think it's swimming and
crawling. I see that there's some nooks
and crannies, but I know there are ways
of cleaning it, which we'll get back to
in a second. So, don't let your
imagination run too wild. When we come
back, we're going to talk a little bit
about what we actually found in here
because we did a little homework, but I
want to find out what could be lurking
inside this humidifier. All right, so
stick around. My head of my medical
unit, Dr. Michael Crooppin, has been
looking into this. First things first,
Jessica and so many others love their
humidifier. What is the deal here? Well,
cool air brings dry air and more
congestion. And when parents hear their
kids having trouble breathing because
they're congested or coughing or even
just sniffling, they want something to
do. So they bring in the humidifier,
which adds more moisture to that air,
and then that's supposed to help break
up the mucus to make it easier to
breathe, right? But so the med unit
looked into it and see if there's any
data to show that this is actually the
case. And there isn't any, but they are
recommended by pediatricians. But what
most people don't think about is that
humidifier is making all this mist,
right? And if it can send mist out that
you're supposed to breathe in, it could
also send out things that maybe you
shouldn't be breathing in. So, it's
really important to keep them clean. So,
are there some folks who definitely
should not be using humidifier? So, we
couldn't find anyone who definitely
shouldn't use a humidifier, but people
who have asthma or allergies should
probably be more careful because they
might be more sensitive to anything that
a dirty humidifier might be sending out.
There's also a thing called humidifier
lung. And this humidifier lung, that
sounds strange. This is a condition that
happens when something from the
humidifier gets into the lungs and
causes irritation and inflammation. And
this is very rare, but just another
reason why you should be cleaning your
humidifier. Well, obviously if you turn
the humidifier on, you don't feel well.
That's sort of a clue you may have one
of these conditions. Okay, tell us what
may be lurking inside the humidifier.
So, there's three things that we worry
about in a humidifier. The first thing
is debris. So, humidifiers are filled
with water, right? And water is clear,
but things can be dissolved in that
water. And when you break up the water
and turn it to mist, those things can
come out. In humidifier lingo, it's
known as white dust and it can be an
irritant. Got it. and not using your
humidifier or not cleaning it for three
years, could that make it worse? It
could. So, next thing is mold. We all
know that mold is not good for us, but
you know what mold really likes? What?
Moisture. So, humidifiers are like
beachfront property for mold. They can
grow there and they can come out again
in the mist and cause health problems.
Beachfront property. Jessica's teetering
over there. All right, the last thing is
bacteria. So, bacteria like mold also
really like warm moist environments. So,
they can grow in a humidifier. Things
like Legionella, Sudamonus are the most
concerning that could be in there. But
all kinds of bacteria could grow in
there and come out with that mist. So
Jessica, are you fearful of any of
these? Terrified. Terrified. Terrified.
All right. Well, when we come back,
we're going to reveal the truth, right?
Everyone pay attention here. What you
can do to keep your humidifier clean
will be the other lesson we teach
because you're right, it's hard, but
it's doable. Stay with us.
Coming up, the test results are in. and
find out if my next guest has the
filthiest humidifier in America. Plus,
tips on how to keep your humidifier
[Music]
clean. We swab what could be the
filthiest humidifier in America. And
we're about to reveal the lab test
results. Let's remind everybody that
Jessica's humidifier looked like this
with a little bit of slime there. Are
you nervous? Very frightened, in fact.
So, a lot of people are like you. They
have not been able to get in the nooks
and crannies. So, we checked a couple
things. Let me let me let me start off
with the bacteria. We found 14.2 million
colonies of bacteria, which is two to
three times what you have on your
arms. And I only bring that up because
that's bacteria that's being pushed into
the air that goes into your lungs. So
imagine dirty skin three times more than
your skin and you're I don't know
breathing in the bacteria that are on
it. Not ideal. That's horrible.
However, the fungus and mold stuff we
look for inconclusive. So you dodged a
bullet there. And those are actually
more of a problem oftentimes because
they'll hide in your lungs for a long
time. So what do you think?
Um, I'm I'm terrified and repulsed at
the same time knowing that even though I
did try to clean it, that my efforts
were in vain because it just didn't
work. Well, do I got to say I I was
curious about your question. These
little nooks and crannies. I think the
battle on the humidifier is not fought
in that tiny bit of tubing. It's fought
here. Oh, it's actually the big stuff.
If you can keep keep the big stuff clean
as much as you can, the small stuff
takes care of itself. Sort of like life,
right? Let me give you and everybody
else some tips. Thanks, Jessica. Here
are three tips to help everyone watching
have the healthiest humidifier in
America. First off, use distilled water.
Invest in it. It's not that big a deal.
You drink clean water. Put clean water
in your lungs. Every day, empty, rinse,
and dry the base before refilling. Every
day. Don't let the water lie in there
stagnantly because that will begin to
accumulate and that the stuff you can't
get to. And this is important. Every
week, remove the water that scaling on
the sides with vinegar and then bleach
solution to disinfect the unit. Don't
run it through the unit. Just clean off
the sides. That way when you put the
water in there, you're starting you're
rebooting the system effectively. Can
wash out whatever may be stuck in the
small tubing. All right. Remember the
power change it lies in the power used.
Spread the word. One person, one voice,
but you're speaking the truth. So it
matters. Goodbye everybody.
[Music]