A vacation should be a time to
decompress, disconnect, and relax. But
before you plan that getaway, could your
next vacation be dangerous, even deadly?
Today, we're investigating vacation
crimes. Why have so many popular
destination spots become a haven for
robbery, rape, and even murder against
unsuspecting Americans? correspondent
with Marshia Ampo has been investigating
something that I never thought we' be
talking about, but you looked a lot into
this. What surprised you the most? What
stood out? What really surprised me is
that we're seeing people become victims
of crime, not when they are going on
dangerous or risky excursions or going
to neighborhoods that perhaps they
should stay away from. It really can
happen to anyone at any time. You know,
Natalie Holloway famously disappeared on
vacation. She was on a high school
graduation trip. Much more recently, we
saw a woman in Mexico who died from
reportedly drinking tainted alcohol. Who
doesn't want a cocktail when they're on
vacation? That's part of the reason we
go on vacation, right? Is to unwind and
relax. It really can happen to anyone.
You have to be so vigilant. It seems to
me the reports of violence on vacations
have been increasing. Is that my
perception or is there an increasing
prevalence? You know, it depends on
where you're going, but it can be
shockingly high, including at popular
vacation spots. For example, in Mexico
in 2016, 75 Americans were killed while
traveling there. 75. 75. That's more
than the You guys know that? No. It's
shockingly high. That is more than the
number to give you some perspective of
American travelers killed that entire
year in every other country of the world
combined. Another popular vacation spot
is Jamaica, where in 2017, six Americans
were killed and 12 Americans sexually
assaulted or raped. And we're not even
talking about the smaller crimes, you
know, the robberies, the petty theft. It
is shockingly high. And are US citizens
being targeted especially? You know,
there are two things that are happening
here that we're seeing. For one,
sometimes people get caught in local
violence. We saw that last year a woman
was traveling from Chicago to celebrate
her wedding anniversary with her husband
in Mexico. She was hit by a stray bullet
in an upscale neighborhood. She was not
the intended target. She was an innocent
bystander, but she lost her life. And
then there are other things that are
happening. Tourists are extremely
vulnerable and valuable. So vulnerable
in the sense that think about it, you
often don't know the geography. You may
not know the language. Depending on
where you are, you may not even have
cell phone service. That makes you a
vulnerable target and valuable because
Americans are coming from a very wealthy
country, especially compared to a lot of
the poor countries that we travel to. So
think about things that you might not
normally think about. an engagement
ring, a watch. Those things can be
tremendously valuable depending on where
you're going. With all these insights,
what's the State Department saying?
What's our government doing? Yeah, the
State Department does issue travel
boardings and several popular spots are
on a list right now, including Mexico,
the Bahamas, Biz, the Dominican
Republic, hotspots, and they are
advising Americans traveling there to
exercise increased caution. Another one
that you saw on that list, Jamaica. One
travel company ranked it the third most
dangerous place in the world for female
travelers. Jeez, these are places that I
see advertisements for all the time,
places that I've gone to and I've
enjoyed. Yeah. And and you have to keep
in mind that plenty of people go there
without incident and have a great time.
And these countries thrive on the
tourist economy. So we want to be be
mindful of that. But you also have to
protect yourself. They don't want it
either. But the question is, what are we
doing about it? What can we do to be
safer? So let's get to the case of
Desiree Gibbon. She was from New York,
was found murdered in Jamaica. What do
we know about her and what happened
there? Yeah, this is really such a sad
case. She was in Montego Bay because her
family had some connections there. She
was there for a month and three days
before she was scheduled to leave, she
was found dead on the side of a remote
dirt road with her throat slashed. Oh my
goodness. So, let's get into this a
little bit. We have the autopsy report.
This was a serious attack. it. The
autopsy report shows that she had
massive bleeding and a chopping wound.
That's their word, chopping wound to her
neck. In fact, that injury severed her
corateed artery, her jugular vein, and
her trachea. You know how hard you have
to cut at someone to cut that deeply? It
went all the way down into her spine.
Now, putting it together, she had linear
wounds on her hand. So, in theory, she
they think she may have been kneeling
and the perpetrator was behind her. She
put her hand up to defend herself. So,
the knife would have cut her hand. And
in fact there were cuts on her right
hand on the palmer surface. Uh and then
the injury came along this side of her
neck and by cutting here went very deep.
So it gives you the idea that the there
was probably a man because the deep cut
was it was uh uh done by someone who was
probably left-handed based on the
injuries that we see. So these are just
highlevel insights you might gain from
looking at the op autopsy report but
you've gained a lot of additional
insights. Yeah. For one thing, and you
describe the viciousness of that attack,
that indicates that kind of attack
indicates that this may have been
personal in nature, that this may have
been someone who knew her and that this
was a personal um interaction. The other
thing is that it may not have been just
one person when you describe how brutal
this attack was. And it's worth pointing
out she was not sexually assaulted. So
that was not a motive here. So these
things tend to point to the idea that
this was somebody that she knew. So, up
next, Desiree Gibbons's mother is here.
She's speaking out about what she thinks
happened and why she believes police are
not actively looking for her daughter's
killer. Stay with us. That was Desiree
Gibbon, a 26-year-old model and actress
from United States who was found
murdered in Montego Bay, Jamaica, after
visiting the island on vacation. A year
after her death, her murder still is
unsolved. And Desire's mother, Andrea,
is here. Tell me about your daughter.
Desiree is the best person you would
have ever ever met in your life. She was
she was a wonderlust.
She enjoyed
cultures of all kind. She traveled the
world.
She was just one who wanted to travel
and just get to know people and get to
know the world. So, what was the last
time you spoke to your daughter and how
did she seem to you?
The last time I spoke to her was
probably about 9:30 p.m. on Thanksgiving
of 2017.
She was the happiest that I'd ever heard
her. She felt good things were happening
for her. She had gone on vacation there
and she wanted to spend a month. You
know, her grandparents have a bread and
breakfast in Montego Bay.
So, she went down. She said, "Mom, I'll
go for a month." So fine, she had been
there many times throughout her life.
And during her course there, she was um,
you know, going around to the, you know,
the local places where they have the
clubs and Margaritavville and things.
She says, you know, mom, maybe I'll do
bartending when I'm here because she was
an actress and a model and that's what
she did to support herself here in New
York. So she sounds good to you. This is
at 9:30 the night she disappears.
Correct. Was there anything unusual
about what was happening in her life
around then? Any out of the ordinary
events? The only thing that struck me is
odd is she deleted her Instagram.
So when I was trying to communicate with
her on Instagram, it wasn't going
through. So I asked her that day, "What
happened to your Instagram?" She's like,
"Oh, I'm taking a break. I deleted it."
So, I don't know if she had an
experience of somebody trying to contact
her through Instagram and therefore to
avoid it, she just disconnected
everything. I'm not sure. Were you
concerned about her safety at all while
she was in Jamaica? Honestly, I was not.
2020 hindsight, I didn't know, but I was
not concerned at all. All right. So,
everything seems normal with the
exception of this Instagram deletion. So
3 days before Desiree was scheduled to
fly home, the evening that she spoke to
her mom, her body was found in an
abandoned driveway. Mhm. What was like
to get that phone call? Oh god, was
horrific. I was sitting at work when her
uncle called me and told me I needed to
go home, that something happened and to
call him back on that number. And I told
him, "I'm at work. I'm in a meeting. I'm
not going home. what's the matter? So he
it was all through text message. So then
I text my husband. I said, "Your brother
just called me. What's going on? Is
Desiree okay?"
He tried to call me and because I was in
a meeting, I just hit can't talk right
now. And he sent me a message. My mother
just told me they killed my daughter.
I w was devastated. I could not move.
Sitting in the boardroom,
I didn't know what to do.
I didn't know what to do. Ultimately,
I got up and excused myself and went
into my office and called my husband.
And when I heard him screaming on the
phone, I knew.
I just knew it was true.
So, you're a nurse. Mhm. You've dealt
with pain and loss. Mhm. Now, you have
to apply that skill to dealing with your
own daughter. Yeah. A couple of days
after Desiree was killed, Mhm. you
arrived in Jamaica. Mhm. You had to
identify the body, right? What was that
like?
That was extremely difficult. And I did
not expect to see what I saw. When they
originally walked me into the area where
they were going to perform the autopsy,
I couldn't recognize her because the
body that I was looking at, and of
course they only show you the face,
um, didn't look like her. She was
decomposed.
Her skin turned completely black and she
wasn't a dark-kinned person. So, I
couldn't understand why she looked like
this. And I kept saying, "This is not
her." And my husband's saying, "It's
her." I said, "It's not her. How can you
tell?" He said, "It's her."
And it was I was devastated. I honestly
thought they walked me in there and was
taking me to some different body.
You saw probably some of the wounds.
Maybe you saw the report. I did see the
report. I saw when we were there because
I could not identify my daughter. My
husband asked to see the picture of the
crime scene where they first found her
on the uh street. That picture I could
identify her and it had very graphically
her throat slit with all the blood
crusted around her throat.
That I knew was Desiree.
I'm so sorry.
No parent should ever have to see that.
Yeah.
We have footage of your daughter. This
is exclusive video of the last time
Desiree was seen. It's from a security
camera in the hotel. I want to show it
to the audience and then if it's okay, I
want to talk to you about it. Sure.
Right. So that uh top left panel, you'll
see uh a little circle that's following
Desiree out of her room downstairs. Now
she's in the top right panel, the
hallway walking towards the lobby of the
hotel. And then we'll pick it up in the
bottom left. Uh, Desiree will appear,
walk through the lobby of the hotel. And
as you're looking at this, I want to
point something out because she's going
to walk through the lobby of the hotel
without really stopping, and then out
into the front of the hotel, which is
the bottom right panel. And notice she's
got flip-flops on, shorts, not carrying
anything that we can really tell. And
then she goes around the corner right
there, and just out of sight, apparently
was picked up in a car, it appears. So,
so as you look at that security footage,
what does that tell you about your
daughter?
she was going to meet somebody she knew.
It is somebody who called her, said,
"Come outside." Um, for whatever reason,
uh, because she came the first time she
came down, you could see her looking
through the door. She was looked like
texting on her phone talking to the
security guard, went back up to the
hotel room. The only difference when she
came down that second time is she had
put a pair of sunglasses on her head.
Clear pair of sunglasses and came back
down, said something to the security
guard and looked at her phone again and
then went through the door. And as she
made that left, that was the last time
she was ever seen. Why would she put on
a pair of sunglasses? I have no idea.
Just an accessory, I I guess. And the
security guard have any insights at all?
None. In fact, when he was questioned,
um, he had said that when Desire was
leaving, she said, "I'll be right back."
Are you satisfied with how police are
investigating this case? No,
not at all.
I'm extremely frustrated with the
authorities down there. It's very
difficult to get answers from them.
Um,
you know, from the very beginning, there
was a flip-flop they found at the crime
scene and the one of the detectives took
it back to the hotel and just threw it
in her hotel room on the floor. So, it
wasn't taken for evidence of any kind.
And
when they went to the hotel to go
through her room, um, she had a local
cell phone she bought in Jamaica. I
found it in one of her bags there as I
was packing up to bring her things home
when we were leaving.
and because they were asking about her
cell phones. And fast forward a year
later when I went down for the one-y
year anniversary, I had inquired about
that phone and if they had contacted the
people inside that phone and they looked
at me like I was crazy and they said,
"What phone?" There was never a phone. I
said, "Yeah, there was a phone." And you
know, I had taken pictures of everything
in the phone. And I said, "But what
about this person? Did you contact them?
Did you investigate this one?" "Oh, we
don't know anything about that phone."
So, one detective looks at another and
says, "Oh, we sent it to Kingston, but
it there was nothing in there. It didn't
Their their line is," it didn't prove
fruitful to our investigation. So, I
know you haven't gotten much of response
from them, right? But we did. We got a
statement from the police. When we come
back, the latest on the investigation
and what you needed to know about
staying safe and protecting yourself
while you're on vacation. Desiree Gibbon
was murdered while vacationing in
Jamaica. Her body was found just three
days before she was scheduled to fly
back home to New York. Desire's mother,
Andrea, is back and joining her is
private investigator TJ Ward, who also
investigated the Natalie Holloway
disappearance. She got some experience
in the area. We reached out to the
Montego Bay Police Department. We asked
whether they were prioritizing Desire's
case. Here's what they said in part.
This particular matter is being given
high priority, attention, and is being
treated as a significant investigation.
statement goes on to say they've pursued
and continue to pursue several leads.
They have interviewed several people and
they're analyzing a number of items for
forensic evidence. We got the full
statement on dr.com.
Andrew, I know they haven't been
forthcoming with you, but they did share
a little bit of an update with us. What
do you think about their claims, their
statement?
I think it's amazing that they would
respond in such a way where I can't even
get them to answer a message. it'll take
him sometimes a week or two weeks to get
back to me and the only statement I keep
getting is there have been no new leads.
So that's very interesting that you were
able to obtain that statement. TJ, why
did you decide to get involved? Well, I
was asked to get involved and we have
expertise that work in cases outside the
country and we want to take our
expertise and assist the Jamaica police
with things they may have missed or
followed up with. And what's it going to
take to find the killer? Well, there's
certain things that I have seen already
in the case, uh, such as the second
phone that was found, and there was a
array of numbers were in that phone that
apparently have not been identified. And
we need to identify those and identify
other witnesses in this case that may be
important to lead us to this heinous
crime. Are you going to look into her
Instagram account and why it was
discontinued? We're going to follow
every lead and work hands-on with Andrea
to try to establish who the killers are
and hope to get results from our
investigation. Andrew, what do you think
happened to your daughter? You know her
better than anybody.
I honestly have no idea. I I do know
that whoever killed her is somebody she
knew. I had heard at one point through
the underground in Jamaica that there
was um a gentleman who was interested in
Desiree and she was not interested. Uh
and I was told that when this particular
individual saw her talking to another
person, he became very jealous and he is
the one who killed her. I don't know
that to be true. That's what they're
saying in the undergrounds of Jamaica.
And people will tell you, everybody
knows what happened to her, but nobody's
willing to talk.
Well, I look forward to hearing your
investigation. We'll follow the case
with you. This crime should be solved.
Thank you again for coming. I want to go
back to our correspondent, Marciao, who
has some tips on protecting ourselves
when we're away on vacation. These are
vitally important ideas. I had never
even thought of some of these concepts,
but we can do things to stay safe while
on vacation. You spent a good part of
your life traveling the country. Yeah, I
used to live on the road the whole world
and even to conflict zones. And you want
to make sure that you do not let your
guard down. A lot of times we're on
vacation. We don't take the precautions
we would normally take because we want
to relax and let our hair down. You can
do that, but you also have to be smart.
So, for one thing, travel in groups.
Don't go places alone. And keep in mind
that these attacks can even occur at the
hotel or the resort that you're staying
in, even upscale places. Try not to
overdo it with the drinking. I know
nobody wants to hear that. The other
option is you can just have a designated
sober person in your group. One person
who's kind of looking out for everyone
else. The second thing is is your hotel
room is really important. Now, when I
was living on the road as a reporter, I
had a cameraman who used to call me
Goldilocks because my room had to be
just right. I would go back to the desk
two and three times until I got a room I
felt safe in. Don't stay on a floor
that's too low and easily accessible
from the street. You don't want to stay
in a room that's remote, that's too far
away from all the action, or that's near
a dark stairwell. Make sure you use the
deadbolt because there have been cases
where hotel employees with keys have
been the perpetrators of crime. And this
is my favorite travel gadget of all
time. It's light. It's easy to pack. So,
this is a doors stop. It's a doors stop.
You shove it under the door. You put it
under the door. It's battery operated.
So, on the back, you turn it on when
you're ready to use it. You put it under
the door and it does two things. One, if
someone tries to come in, it stops the
door. And when this is triggered, it
sets off a piercing alarm. Oh, I see.
Yes. You see this? This actually goes up
and down. So when the door, if someone
does try to push the door open, it stops
the door, but it also triggers the
alarm. Good. It's like carrying a
personal security system. And in a case
where it might be a hotel employee with
a key, you're going to throw them so off
guard because they're not expecting an
alarm in the room. This I never travel
without it. Well, there should be this
best a part of everyone's travel kit.
Well, thank you very much. We'll be
right back. Everybody, thank you for
watching.
[Music]