[Music]
A night at the movies could be scarier
than the film. What was the most
disturbing thing you found? We're
investigating the five germiest
hotspots. It was disgusting. That could
be playing at a theater near you. Number
one on our list. It is even dirtier than
your toilet. Plus, could you be buying
beef all wrong? When it's first ground
starts off looking bright red. The Dish
Crew has a buyer guide to get the best
beef for your burger.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you, Becca.
[Music]
Today, an investigation into dirty movie
theaters. That sounds like it's a scene
out of a horror movie. Ooh, scary.
There's mice invasions, bugs like
cockroaches crawling around, and mystery
germs and bacteria all over. Take a look
at what was uncovered at movie theaters
that might make you make your skin
crawl. It is, of course, the weekend,
and there's a good chance you might be
headed to the movies. Well, before you
go, you just might want to see what Lisa
Guerrero found lurking inside some
theaters. When you go to the movies, you
expect the theater to be clean, but we
found that's not always the case. That's
disgusting. All that leftover popcorn
and candy can attract some unwanted
guests. That's a mouse popping out
between the seats inside a California
AMC theater. These mice were filmed by
another movie goer at a Texas AMC this
fall. And it's not just rodents. Corey
Vgillio says he was disgusted after he
discovered these bugs crawling all over
the carpet at this AMC theater in
Ontario, California. As I'm recording,
zooming in, I'm seeing multiple what
looks like to me baby cockroaches. He
spotted them after he dropped his keys
under the seat. That's when he also
noticed all this discarded food. There's
no reason that these filthy conditions
like that should have been uh underneath
my seat. Trash. So, we decided to take
our flashlights in movie theaters in New
York and New Jersey. And what we found
after the theaters were supposedly
cleaned may disgust you. Popcorn, candy,
trash everywhere. Remember, these
theaters are supposed to be cleaned in
between showings. We found discarded
cups, wrappers, liquor and soda bottles,
lots of gum, even a tooth flosser. Yuck.
And who takes off their socks during a
movie? But look what else we found at
this popular AMC in New York City's Time
Square. Trap after trap after trap right
behind the movie screen. There's popcorn
and candy stuck all the way back there.
It looks like it's been dragged back
there by rodents. It appears that you
guys have a rodent problem. Are you
aware of that? The manager didn't want
to answer our questions. And you can't
be in here doing this. But of all the
theaters we checked, this AMC had the
grossest conditions.
It's a dead rodent in a trap. It's so
gross. And look at all those droppings
and what appear to be mouse nests. We
found something that you need to see.
This manager agreed to take a look at
what we found behind the curtain. Do you
guys have a rodent problem here in this
theater? No, not really. He told us they
have a pest control service that comes
once a week. Do you think it would be
disturbing for your patrons to know that
there are mouse traps and dead rodents
just feed away from where they're
watching films?
I guess so. But it's also a much better
solution than actually not having traps
and having the rodents make an
appearance during the movie. So gross.
AMC told us their policy is to clean the
theaters after every show and again
after business hours. They say they work
closely with pest control experts at
their locations nationwide and say the
use of traps in non-public areas is a
common and effective practice to
eliminating pests. Oh my goodness.
Joining me now from Inside Edition is
investigative reporter Lisa Guo. I am
shocked by what you shown the traps with
mice that look like they almost
decomposed in there. Trash. Endless
amounts of it. Right. It was it was
pretty shocking. You know, we we wanted
to do this story because we saw a video
that people were posting on social media
that they took with their own phones
around the theaters that they were in.
And we thought, Dr. Oz, is this just,
you know, isolated incidents around the
country or is this happening everywhere?
So, we got out our flashlights and we
went to a bunch of different theaters
and we were really disturbed when we saw
the rodents and all the droppings. What
was the most disturbing thing you found?
Uh, at one theater, two nights in a row,
we saw the same dead rodent in a trap.
Oh, it was it was disgusting. The reason
that we're just iconically scared of
rodents is that they transmit disease,
right? A variety of diseases, all kinds
of bad things because they're rooting
around and stuff. And you when you come
into contact with rodent droppings, it
can be a big-time problem for a lot of
folks. So employees are supposed to
clean up the place. Sure. What's not
being done? Well, first of all, as
moviegoers, we shouldn't be littering as
badly as we do. First of all, we have to
take some responsibility for what we're
doing. Also, these companies maybe need
to hire more than one person to clean in
between. I mean, one person can only do
so much. And if you have five minutes to
clean an entire theater that hundreds of
people have just been in, that's an
impossible task. So, maybe these
companies need to hire more people to
clean the theaters. So, just to be
clear, everybody, I love going to
movies. I suspect most of you, too. I'm
not saying to stop watching movies at
theaters. We just need to be aware of
the problem so we can ask for change. So
Lisa's reporting got us curious about
the germs in a movie theater. So we did
our own germ swabbing to find out the
top five germiest hotspots. You all
curious about this? I thought so.
Remember, anything below a 50 is
considered clean. Anything above a 50,
we're just going to say it's dirty for
the sake of this show. Let's start with
number five, the selfs serve butter
dispenser,
which had a germ score of 122.
What is going on at the buttery at the
butter dispenser next to the popcorn?
Dr. Oz, don't you love butter? Everybody
loves butter on their popcorn. So, you
get your popcorn and you press that
dispenser and what are you doing? You're
putting your hand on the same spot that
everybody else has put their hand on.
And then you take that same hand and you
put it in your popcorn and you plop it
in your mouth and you lick your fingers.
So you're getting all those germs that
everybody else has left on that butter
dispenser. Guys, this is yet another
reason to hold back on the butter and
the popcorn. I've been telling you a
bunch of other ones. I haven't thought
of this one. One more reason. There you
go. All right. The fourth geriest spot
in a movie theater. Come over. I'll show
it to you myself cuz we actually brought
some into the studio. It is the seats.
Of course, Lisa have a seat. Do they
ever clean these? How do these get
things get uh into the sanitary
condition we want them to be in? Think
about this. Think about all the people
that are sitting in these seats,
especially during the summer time. And
you got your your shorts on and you got
your tank top and you're sweating and
you're sitting against the seat and then
the next group comes in. We checked with
movie theaters across the country and
they say that 14% of these theaters
clean less than four times a year these
seats. Four times a year. Yes. But 58%
said that they cleaned it every day,
which I find pretty suspicious. Are they
really going to disinfect and shampoo
these seats every single day? No. That
seems impossible. If you detect
something on a seat, make sure to tell
the manager the theater. Yeah, they
scrape the bubble gum off, but I don't
think they're going to clean this. Is
impossible? No, it's impossible. All
right, number three on the countdown.
The floor. And it's not just the
discarded food on the floor, but the
germs that everyone is tracking in. So,
what did you find after putting a purse
on the floor? So, we swabbed the purses.
Before we put a purse on the floor, the
germ score was 140. After we put the
purse on the floor, we swabbed it again.
226.
That's how disgusting what is on the
floor is getting on your purse. And
think about this. You then take the
purse home and you put it on your
kitchen counter. So all the germs from
this nasty floor are going home with you
to your kitchen bone appetite.
Enjoy yourselves everybody. The second
germiest spot in the movie theater is
the armrest. Right, which had a germ
score of 1,371.
Why is it that the armrests are dirtier
than the seats themselves? Cuz your
hands are dirty. And so when you put
your hand on the armrest,
you're getting your germs on there and
you're picking up everybody else's germs
that have been on the armrest. So that's
why so many people are touching the
armrest and you're bringing it home with
you, right? Chances are you're touching
the armrest. Then you know what you're
doing? You're touching your face without
even thinking about it. And you watch
them moving, you're nervous, you're
clawing at yourself. We found on average
you touch your face 16 times an hour.
That's one6 times an hour. It's
frequent. You're always doing something
up here. So, it matters that you've got
a armrest. That's a problem. Up next,
you're curious about it. The dirtiest
part of the movie theater and you're not
going to believe what it is. It is even
dirtier than your toilet seat. So, stick
around. What is it?
[Applause]
[Music]
An unlicensed doctor. I went in to get
my breath smaller. Scamming patients
instead. What did he do to your body?
Botching surgery. that went from a
double D to an N and how he took
advantage with sex and drugs. Plus, an
ex-husband turns up dead soon after the
divorce. A person approaches the car and
shoots Dan at point blank range. And who
the police zero in on, no one expected.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
You're seeing it all. We are back
investigating dirty movie theaters and
counting down the top five germ hot
spots. Now, we just went through the top
four, the butter dispenser, the seat,
the floor around you when you sit in the
movie theater, and of course, the
armrest because you're touching the
armrest and you're touching your face 16
times an hour. So now it's time to find
out the germiest spot in the theater.
Number one on our list. It is even
dirtier than your toilet. Inside edition
investigative reporter Lisa Guerrero is
back. The number one hot spot for germs
in your movie theater is drum roll
please. The cup holder. The cup holder.
We swapped the toilet. This is what the
numbers are. We swapped the toilet. Had
a germ score of 219.
That's not so clean but not that bad.
when we swabbed the cup holder. This cup
holder one like this had a germ score of
3,416.
So, how does this get so dirty, Lisa?
Well, think about it. First of all, the
cup holder has nooks and crannies, so
it's hard for their employees to get in
and to clean around the actual cup
holder. So, what I recommend, Dr. Oz, is
when you're drinking, only hold the top
of the cup and then put it down. never
touched the bottom of the cup that's
been in this nasty cup holder. So, now
that you become a world expert on dirty
movie theaters, what are you doing
differently? You've changed your whole
approach, I gather. I have. So, now I
get to the theaters early, about 15
minutes early, and I take my cell phone,
and you know how they have the
flashlight on it? So, I turn on my
little flashlight and I check underneath
the seat I'm going to be sitting in. Got
front, behind, all over the place cuz I
don't want to see any nasty. Most people
get there early anyway, right? To get
better seats. So, don't just sit there
and watch the commercials. do some work,
right? So, look around. Look around and
if you see something nasty, tell
management. They want to know and they
want it to be clean for you. Now, we
revealed a couple things that are really
problematic, like the dirt, the
dirtiness of the floor around you. So,
people have purses, right? What do you
do with it? Okay, so if you have a
purse, do what I do. Take a little
plastic bag with you, wad it up, stick
it in your purse. When you get there,
simply unfold it, throw your purse
inside, and then knot it up, stick it on
the floor while you watch the the movie,
and then when you're done, take it out
of the bag and throw it away on your way
out. And that way, this never actually
touches the floor. Or you can do what I
do.
Smart. Just wear a cross body bag. Never
let your bag touch the floor. The only
thing that should touch the floor,
bottom of your feet. Yeah. Keep your
shoes on and your socks. Yeah, exactly.
So, thank you very much. Very nicely
done. Appreciate the investment. We'll
be right back, everybody.
You think you might have the next big
invention or idea on your hands? Well,
stick around because Shark Tanks Lori
Gir is here to tell you what you can do
today to make your entrepreneurship
dreams a reality. I'm here to inspire
you to live your best life. You don't
want to miss this. Listen to her.
[Music]
She's one of the most successful
inventors in the hit show Shark Tank.
Lori Grineer has created over 700
products, holds 120 patents all around
the world, including the Scrub Daddy,
right? Perhaps my favorite, the Squatty
Potty, cuz it really works.
Banttom bagels. We'll get to these in a
second because you don't know they taste
good. And it all started with this
little jewelry organizer that she
invented. It's pretty cool. But now Lori
Grineer has a brand new venture that's
not about selling you a product. It's
about inspiring you to sell yourself and
make your dreams come true. And she's
here today to reveal it. Please welcome
Shark Tanks Lori Grineer.
[Applause]
Thank you for coming on. Thank you.
Oh my goodness, you look good. Oh, you
look good. So, the thing about your
career is it has always reminded us that
there's a role for women in the
entrepreneurial world and I'm curious
since you're on the inside, do you feel
like it's changing? Are we equalizing
the playing field for for women where
was once very inhospitable? Well,
listen, I think being an entrepreneur
and deciding to take your own life into
your own hands already levels the
playing field, right? And I think,
right,
and women are amazing. They're
multitaskers. They're brilliant. They
can tackle and handle anything. And then
the one big piece of advice, don't think
of yourself as a woman out there. Think
of yourself as a person and the best
damn one there is. Yeah, a little.
So, I know all your fellow sharks and
I'm always curious what they're like
behind the scenes. So, share a little a
little dirt. Give us a scoop of what
what happens when the cameras are off on
Shark Tank. Well, uh, music starts in
between the entrepreneurs. We get about
five minute break and Mark Cuban is
always screaming at the top of his
lungs, singing with it. And then Damon
is an extremely funny guy and he knows I
crack up from his little um he tells
like little grade school jokes which I
find hilarious. I don't know why. Um so
he'll tell me those and usually try to
make us all laugh. We have a crafty
table where there's lots of food and
we're always starving and then we go up.
Crafty table means that they have like
um I don't know pizza and different
tamales and stuff that we can go get in
between the breaks and it's usually
empty by the time we get there cuz the
whole crew has eaten everything. So who
who has the unhealthiest diet among the
sharks? Oh wow. Um probably Cuban. I
think Cuban. Yeah. How'd you know that?
Cuz I played against him in the
celebrity basketball game. Yeah. Cuban.
Cuban.
He'll he'll vacasillate from being
really healthy to being atrociously
horrible. All right, let's talk about
this magazine. It's fantastic. It's
called Living Inspired. It's a
wonderfully crafted exercise like
everything you do. But what sets it
apart in your opinion from a lot of the
other magazines on the stance? Well,
listen, Living Inspired was truly a
labor of love. Every single page is by
me. I there's not one page in there that
was not truly done and touched by me.
Um, it has everything in it. I feel like
in a time of sometimes people not
feeling very positive, I wanted to put
out a magazine because I'm a big
believer in positivity, inspiration,
giving back, having fun, feeling
empowered. And so I wanted to put that
all in the magazine. And the magazine
truly is just pick it up for a minute.
It truly is all about, it's called
Living Inspired. So from the title
inside it is advice on work and at home
and it's these are from me. It's truly
advice at work and at home but there's
also like great places to travel,
wonderful things to eat at different
levels, all budgets. There's um how to
sleep better. There's advice on deep
discounts, great products that I love.
I've heard from people say that have
read it thus far that when they open it
up, maybe they weren't in the best mood
or, you know, they weren't even in a
good mood, but when they were done, they
felt happier, they felt inspired, they
felt like they could tackle anything.
They felt like you could do this and um
that their life was better. So, that's
what the intention was. And I'm really
glad to hear that's how it's working.
Well, will you share some of your wisdom
with some of our audience members?
Absolutely. Entrepreneurs, come on over.
some amazing tips to attract everyone to
greatness. So Lor's gonna give some
advice to some entrepreneurs looking for
a little inspiration that many of you
out there for example says she has a
vision but has a hard time taking a
first step and making it happen. You
brought your vision with some products
to demonstrate. Yes, my name is Tasia
and I'm the creator of Body Party which
is an allnatural skin care line. Uh so I
have butters, scrubs, glow oils which is
an illuminating body oil. I'm working on
cuticle oil, eyelash serum, and body
wax. So, what's your advice? So, my
advice would be first thing, most
important, what is the key thing that
makes your products stand out versus any
other body butters or scrubs? So, I try
to also create custom uh butters and
products for anybody's personal skin
care and skinincare issues. Uh so, I
create a questionnaire and that's why I
have here what is my skin type? A lot of
people don't know what their skin type
is. So for all my customers, I ask them,
"What is your skin type? What are you
battling with?" And then I try to create
the product based on their issue. Well,
my advice would be because this is so
customized and specialized, I think you
should stay online as a business because
otherwise um you know, you'd need an
army of people to be out in retail
asking people those questions. But you
can easily fill out a questionnaire. I
would try to get out there um and get
this out there in a social buzz way. I
think Instagram ads are fabulous. I
don't know about anybody else.
They are fabulous. They work. Yes. And I
think grow slowly. Grow slowly and keep
learning from your customers. Priceless
advice. Yeah. Be sure to check out Lor's
new magazine. It's called Living
Inspired. It's on stage right now. Thank
you for being my hero. Appreciate it.
All right, guys. Be right back.
[Applause]
It's the biggest burger bash ever. Stay
tuned for a chef's secret to upgrading
your everyday burgers and turning them
into an ooey gooey cheesy delight. Just
be warned, you're about to get very
hungry.
What if you could see what the future
you looks like? Would you see wrinkles
and lines? Dry, crepey skin from years
of not moisturizing?
Maybe sunspots from not wearing
sunscreen religiously?
Could changing something about your skin
care routine today make a difference
down the road? Well, with the help of my
trusted sponsorship partner, Olay, we're
taking a look into the future of your
skin to help you visualize the impact of
your current skincare routine. And to do
this, Olay principal scientist Dr. The
broken Noisa is joining us. Bro, thanks
for being here as always.
I love how you break your stuff down,
keep it straight up. The biggest mistake
that we're all making with our skin that
will affect the future of our skin is
not wearing sunscreen every day. You
know, we do a lot of things to take care
of ourselves, our minds, our bodies.
But, you know, too often we don't think
of our skin and our sunare as a form of
self-care. You know, sure, most of us,
you know, moisturize our skin to offset
some of the effects of aging, but you
cannot stop there. Did you know that one
week of incidental everyday UV exposure
equals one day at the beach? It does.
So, wearing sunscreen on a daily basis
is one of the most important self-care,
wellness actions we can take for
ourselves. So, you always bring hard
science, new ideas. Yeah.
So, how are we going to get people to
value the importance of their skin care,
especially against sun, right? So, the
scientists at Ole created a technology
um to show you what your skin will look
like in the future. It's called Future
You and it's an advanced simulation
algorithm that is based in a huge
database of thousands of facial images
from women of all ages, all skin types,
all ethnicities. What you were seeing
there was one example, one small extract
of that database, a Caucasian average
face aging from 10 to 80 years old and
back. And we can use this technology to
predict what your face and skin are
going to look like in the future. So
what do we do? What's the goal once
you've generated this information
besides scaring the heck out of us?
Well, so first of all, it's really for
so that women better understand their
skin and how it changes over time. so
ultimately that they can better select
and tailor their skinincare regimens to
their personal needs and circumstances
so they can have the best skin they can
for as long as possible. Right. So, you
brought some examples to us. What do
they do to come up with to change
people's attitudes because you're very
concrete and very specifically it's
focused on sunscreen waking people up to
some of the numbers you've given us.
Yes. Well, so what we can actually do
with the future U technology, we can
model different behaviors. We can model
great skincare habits such as wearing an
SPF every day. And once people accept,
okay, I should be wearing a sunscreen
every day. We need to provide great
products that don't feel like the
typical sunscreen. So, not too greasy,
not too heavy, or else women are not
going to use them. We know that.
So, we came up with Olay Regenerous Web
SPF 25. It's a moisturizer with built-in
UV protection. Doesn't feel like a
sunscreen. Leaves your skin with a
breathable, very light finish. Or if
you're looking for even more UV
protection, how about you try the new
Olay Sun Shine Control with SPF 35. It's
a a light oil-free facial sunscreen
lotion specifically designed to
flawlessly blend into your skin and
leave it shine free with a matte smooth
finish. Right. So, we're going to do a
little experiment together. Beauty
director at Shape and Parents magazine,
Kate Sandival Box is here. She's also
here on behalf of Olay and she's tried
the future simulation. You are very
brave to share your data with us. We're
and you're all going to see it in a
second, but this is the point to wake
you up to the mistakes you may be making
so you don't make them. So, walk us
through like Dr. what we're looking at.
Right. So, what we did obviously earlier
this morning before the show before um
Kate went into hair and makeup, we took
a picture of her. Obviously, wanted to
keep it as realistic as possible. So,
this is her picture and then we um took
it through the simulation. So, I'm going
to show you. I can use this little
slider here. Do you want me to deage you
first? So, this is you today. I can
actually make you look a little younger.
So now we're 5, six, seven, eight, nine,
10 years older. And what I want to what
I want you to look at is what is
actually changing with age. It's three
things. Most people think wrinkles and
texture, but that's just one aspect. And
you're probably actually too young for a
lot of that. Face shape changes as we
age as well. But the third thing, what
what we're really seeing here with you
is hyperpigmentation, skin tone. So you
see that pigmentation coming through and
we know exactly what the main cause of
that is. It's unprotected UV exposure,
right? So, it is largely preventable.
And actually, let me show you something.
Okay, I'm gonna go to next. So, this is
the final stage of future U actually
shows you this is your skin's future in
10 years time. If you follow the average
aging curve, average I mean for your
age, for your skin type and ethnicity,
right? Thousands of women. However, how
about this alternate future? You could
also look like this, Kate. And the key
difference is great skincare habits
including using SPF every day which will
prevent a large amount of the UV damage
that leads to hyperpigmentation. So
Kate, how do the stimulation change your
attitude towards sunscreen? I think it's
really a wakeup call for a lot of
people. I hear from readers all the time
about sunscreen and they say that they
know they should be wearing it, but they
still aren't applying it consistently.
And FutureU is showing you the effects
of those skincare habits or lack
thereof. In fact, at Shape, we just
named it one of the coolest new skinare
technologies of 2019 because of its
potential to be so Congratulations.
So, you recently started using your
sunscreen uh control product, which I I
must point out, you mentioned it very
briefly, but it's sort of a matte
finish. It doesn't make you look like
you're reflective, which my wife was
always complaining to me about. Right.
Exactly. So, has it has it affected you
in ways that are positive? How's it
how's it worked? Absolutely. I started
using it. Immediately when I put it on,
I noticed that I didn't feel anything on
my skin. And heavy, greasy sunscreen is
what everybody complains about,
including me. This left no residue. I
could put makeup on right away. It
doesn't have that telltale sunscreen
smell either. So, bottom line, no
excuses anymore. Don't skip the
sunscreen. So if if you already have a
regimen for taking care of your skin,
moisturizer, yes, retinols, whatever
you're doing, how does the sunscreen
work into that? Yeah. So clearly, I
mean, when you take care of your skin,
it's, you know, moisturization and SPF
protection are the two big important
things. Um, and so no matter whether
you're using the uh Olay Regenerous uh
whip SPF 25, which is moisturizer and
sunscreen in one product, or whether you
use the Olay Sunshine Control, which is
a separate sunscreen that you could just
use on top of your regular moisturizer.
Whichever way you go, this should be the
last step of your morning skincare
routine.
We love the audience so much. There must
be a way of incentivizing them to pay
attention to the sunscreen stuff. All
right. So, if you go to olay.com
and you do the future you experience
yourself, you can enjoy a special 25%
off the Olay sunscreen product.
Everybody, no matter where you are, you
take the you future you test. You'll
learn for yourself. Olay.com is there
for you. And how about the audience
here? Well, guess what? We care about
you so much that Olay is sending you
home with Olay Regenerous Whips SPF 25
and Olay Sunshine Control. Enjoy them.
We'll be right back.
[Applause]
If there's one thing that brings us all
together, it's food. So, we're calling
everyone to the table to dish on
everything. From the latest food hacks
and trends to everyday recipes you can
make for dinner tonight. Singing is my
first love, but my other passion is
baking.
I'm an iron chef, but mostly the
executive chef of Butter Restaurant and
mother to an 11year-old. This is the
first recipe I ever made in a
professional kitchen. They were
terrible. My cooking is like me. A mix
of Caribbean heat meet southern sweet.
This is like my girlfriend in the
kitchen. I am as a chef first and
foremost about flavor. It's simple. It's
celebratory. And most of all, it's about
having a great time in the kitchen. What
is going I'm trying to help. Let's dish.
[Applause]
Welcome to the dish on Oz. Oh my
goodness. Lots to talk about, Daffy.
What's on the menu today? So many
delicious things like always. What is
more delicious, you guys, than sinking
your to teeth, one tooth, and many teeth
into a big juicy burger.
Oh, it's so good. Today, we are
celebrating our love of burgers with our
very own burger bash that you do not
want to miss. First up, could you be
buying beef all wrong? We We want to
teach you some good things on this show,
too. You might not even know it. We are
going to give you our buyer's guide to
cutting through all the label confusion
to help you get the best beef for your
buck.
Plus, the no mess slider hack that has
been breaking the internet. We're going
to show you how to get that under
control. And then, Alex is revealing her
secret to making your burger chefworthy
with a delicious cheese sauce. Okay. And
because that's not enough, we want to
finish it off with a sweet burger makeup
makeover that you have to see and taste
to believe. It's kind of wild. I'm
excited for you guys to see that.
Jamaica, you say sliders are the perfect
crowd-pleaser. I have to agree with you.
Um and and it's a great way to get the
party started, get everyone welcome and
happy, and you are turning the flavor up
with this ultimate hack for a burger
snack. What do you have in store for us?
Well, this is going to change the way
that you make burgers at home. You guys
check this out. Okay, we are doing
muffin tin sliders. All right. Yes. Get
excited about that. So, you just season
your beef. Preheat your oven to 450 and
just do a little salt and pepper on the
outside there. Make sure you always
season your burger. That's the key to
make having good flavored burger. Then
you'll place the patty inside the muffin
tins. And you just cook for 5 minutes.
And of course, you got to add a little
cheddar cheese to it. And then load up
all your toppings. Onions, pickles, you
have it. You name it. Put it on that
burger, baby. Okay. Do we not love that?
Those cute little sliders. You corrupted
the muffin taste and then you enjoyed
guys. Now, we all know that all burgers
aren't created equally and there is one
rivalry that has left our country
divided. Yes. Which coast makes better
burgers, east coast or west coast? So
today, West Coast. Already we have
opinions. East Coast.
Well, well, yeah. Boo. Exactly. So today
we're squashing this aid old beef once
and for all with a burger bash debate.
Here to represent the east coast,
Jamaica.
East Coast. Yes. Yes. East Coast in the
house. Yes. Now you're going to argue
why you think Shake Shack has the best
burger. And representing the West Coast,
Daphne.
Come on, guys. There's no Westies out
here. This is ridiculous. That applause
was really life, but choice and burger
was not. You mean you're you're you're
on team In-N-Out Burger. I am. And
you're going to rep and you're going to
tell us why you think that's the best.
Each of you has 20 seconds to make your
case for who has the best burger. Okay.
I'm going to start with you, Jamaica. 20
seconds on the clock. Let's go. Watch.
All right. I am a Shake Shack girl
because they use potato rolls and they
toast and butter their rolls before they
make them. The beef comes from a
proprietary blend of beef from a
legendary butcher and they grill it in a
cast iron skillet. And do not get me
started on that special sauce. I mean,
come on now.
Shake shack in the house. Yes. Hold it.
That fighting words. She crushed it with
3 seconds remaining and she crushed it.
Is there a real clock? All right, Duffy.
There is an actual clock on you right
now. So, we got You ready? Dig your
heels in. You ready? I'm ready. All
right. West Coast baby 20 seconds. All
right, you guys. Here's my In-N-Out
Burger. It reigns supreme forever and
ever. Familyowned since the beginning of
time. A proprietary blend of their own
meat made the same way. I'm about a
classic with a twist. I have two words
for you. Animal style. We are talking
about caramelized onions, rich brown
sauce, American cheese sauce, special
sauce on a sesame seed bun. You can't go
wrong from that. Perfect onions, perfect
fries. All right, that's it. Perfect.
All right. So, if you guys agree with
Jamaica that East Coast burgers are the
best, give us a round of applause. Okay.
Yes.
Yes. Thank you.
Oh, no. All right. What about Daphne
with the West Coast argument?
All right. No soup for you. All right. I
hate to beat the pregnant lady, but I
think I won this one. I'm so sorry. I
love how you decided you won. All right.
Jimmy, you got it. It was pretty
obvious. No matter where you live,
finding the best ground beef for your
burger can be a pretty daunting task.
So, today, we're helping you through all
the confusion. So, first you got to
figure out the right cut. You want to
look for the chuck. Please demonstrate
the chuck, Alex, if you don't mind. The
chuck is right here. Right there. See?
Elegantly located. More bang for your
buck. This is a great allaround purpose
for ground beef since it's not too fatty
and not too lean. It's got tons of
flavor, which is what I care about.
Actually, when I have meat, I want it to
taste good. Daffy, come over here for
one second. Yes. Talk about color here.
This is something that a lot of folks
mess up. This is this is really cool.
Again, this is like when you're in the
grocery store and you're looking for the
right thing to buy because there are a
lot of ground beef options in the in the
butcher pack and also in your sort of
fresh pack and takeaway areas. Beef when
it's first ground starts off looking
bright red like well more like this. Um,
and as it oxidizes over time is when it
starts to get a little bit lighter in
color and then into this more brown and
then eventually into gray category,
which is how you know it's been let sit
outside for a bit. But if you're looking
for something already ground, get it as
bright, nice, fresh, and red as you
possibly can. Right. So then the
question is, do you make it yourself?
You get patties. Alex, honest here.
Yeah, honestly. Takes a little while to
make these. Yeah. Honesty. I have to say
if you buy your meat from the same place
and you trust it. I would go for ground.
I really would. And there's no no shame
in buying the ground meat, the
pre-formed patties. I like to mix them
up a little bit. Even if they're
preformed. I think it's nice when
there's a little bit of that uneven
touch, but no shame in ground meat. Do
you raise it up high like this or you
squish it down? It depends on how long I
have to cook and how how hungry I am.
Okay. Two thin patties like that is
gonna cook quickly. Yeah. If I have
time, if I'm basting, if I'm putting a
cast iron skillet on the stove and then
in the oven, I'll go thicker. But you
know what? All in all, you want an even
patty, not too thick. And you don't want
the portion to get out of control. You
know what I mean?
Now she's talking about not like 80
burgers like you see there. Okay. All
this burger talk is making me hungry.
you stick around because Alex has a
burger and cheese sauce recipe you do
not want to miss. Stick around. Pass
those sliders here. Pass those sliders.
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
[Applause]
[Music]
We're back with a dish on Oz and today
is all about burgers. Alex is the queen
of crafting the best burger and her
secret weapon. She swears it's bathing
the beef in a silky cheese sauce for
some more fun between the buns. Oh yeah,
she said that. All right, Alex, why do
you think cheese can either make or
break the perfect burger? You know, I I
people that say to me, "I just want a
hamburger. I just want ketchup, no bun,
and a pickle. They're not to be trusted.
These are not friends. That's the future
enemy at hand. You need some cheese with
your burger. You just do. It's It's
balancing. You know, it's a balancing
act in life. You know what I mean? So,
what makes the perfect cheese sauce? All
right. So, I was thinking, you know, I
love two slices of American cheese
crisscross over melty. I love that.
Sometimes you want something different.
A simple cheese sauce. You can make this
ahead. I love this sizzling. I hear
that. It's like hard to talk. Okay, so
this is just a simple cheese sauce. You
could make it with a rue. I went
simpler. Just some cream simmering with
some grainy mustard for thickness. He's
like, "Please pay attention to me. I
love it. Look at you." So just cream in
here so far. Yeah, cream. A little
grainy mustard, a little paprika. You're
going to put a dash of hot sauce and a
dash of woristure. Not enough that you
really feel salt and heat. Oh my god, I
love it. Give the pregnant woman the hot
sauce and look what happens.
And a little worshir sauce. I love
worashir sauce. And then just simmer
that cream a little bit and then just
start whisking in all that cheese.
That's actually what gives it the body.
And then when you build your burger,
then you just pour the cheese sauce like
a cascading waterfall over your burger.
Oh my. Right. Are you going into
surgery? What are those? I am scrubbing
in, doc. Okay. I am scrubbing into the
waiting room of my world, which is
ground beef. Um, you know, the thing
about making a burger is that meat can
get overworked the way cake batter can,
the way flour can. When you overwork
cake batter or bread dough, the flour
gets tough and chewy. So does meat. It
does not want to be taken to the gym a
thousand times with you. So just gently
spread it. Notice how I've pushed it up
around the sides. That way I can season
more surface area and just season it
once and the seasoning really gets in
there, right? Just gently mix it
together. Don't overwork it. I mean, you
really don't want to let these the meat
and the salt sit together. When you
brine meat, right, brine a turkey or a
chicken. I love how he gets involved.
She's a good griller. Yeah, this is my
specialty. I'm I'm rescuing these
burgers. Thank you. When you brine a
chicken, right, it gets it changes the
texture. You don't want salt to sit on
beef. Thank you, Doc. I'm glad you
scrubbed in with us. All right. So once
you form your burgers, right, then you
want to put a little dimple in the
center. That flattens the burger out as
it cooks so it sears more evenly. And we
like that. All right. So now you got
your burgers there. Dimpled as they are.
Dimpled as they are. They're dimpling
away. They're cooking. And now we're
going to stuff. And now I mean it's time
really to Is it time to eat? I think
it's time. We have your prepared buns
over there. So over here. Now what
happens? Let's build this burger. Get
some cheese sauce on there. How about
Yes. Okay. So here's the question.
cheese sauce on the bun.
I I like to char the bun, right? I'm
going to say let's put the burger on
there. That's why I wore gloves, you
know? I didn't I don't want to burger. I
feel some onions on the other side.
Okay. Right. These are just charred with
a little bit of vinegar. Need a little
acidity. And not too heavy, doc. Right.
Not breaded or anything. There's no
There's no onion rings or anything, so
that's good. Let me pour it. Let me pour
it. Let me pour it. Let me pour it. Let
me pour it. You can. You can get go
right over the meat. Go, go, go. Pour it
slow. Pour it slow.
Yes. Oh,
I have some y'all. X-rated dish today.
All right, we're going to taste when we
come back. You kept working. I'm going
to get Well, you know what? You have
that burger. Thank you. Up next, we're
going to put Alex's burger to the test.
Plus, a sweet makeover for a burger you
have to see and taste to believe. Stick
with us. What is this, though? I want
the burger.
The burger. Look at that. So beautiful.
An unlicensed doctor. I went in to get
my breath smaller. Scamming patients
instead. What did he do to your body?
Botching surgery. I went from a double D
to an N.
And how he took advantage with sex and
drugs.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
[Applause]
It is our burger bash. Alex just crafted
this perfectly cheesy burger that looks
like a dream come true. Are we Is
everyone ready to give this a taste? You
didn't wait for me. You went right into
it. All right. And Alex, these are your
onion rings that we've got. What is the
secret to getting these crispy
delightful onion? We'll take a bite and
then we'll just eating them. This thing
is really, really delicious. It fills
your whole mouth. Cheesy. Yes, it tastes
cheesy. And mustard. You got a little
bit of mustard. You took the hamburger
out of my mouth. All right. I do have
one request. I need more cheese sauce on
the side so I can dip my onion rings in
there next time. Agree. Noted. I agree.
Yeah. Both signs. Noted. So now, what if
I told you people are actually eating
burgers? Not just like we are the right
way, but for dessert. It's not exactly
what you're thinking. Okay, take a look
at this sweet burger makeover that's
popping up all over your Instagram feed.
Hey, hey, hey.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
All
[Music]
right, guys. They look delicious. I
would never have expected it. But just
in case in case you want it, we're going
to put the burger cupcake recipe along
with all the other recipes from today's
show on dr.com/theish.
And the dish crew is back next Wednesday
serving up tasty recipes and food hacks
that your friends and family will love.
We will see you all next time.
Thank you.
[Applause]
[Music]