[Applause]
It's almost the halfway mark, so today
I've got the tricks to surviving the
weekend without falling off the total 10
rapid weight loss plan. Ty is here now.
She's been on the planet and has lost a
total of 15 pounds.
Now, like so many of the viewers, uh you
wrote in saying you're really worried
about the weekends. You think you're
going to gain weight with us? You know,
I would gain weight because my husband
and my daughter are foodies. They eat
burgers, pizza, anything you can name.
They eat it. And I don't want to be
tempted to go off my little weight loss
plan. Can we have an honest
conversation? Yes. This is not a time to
go out there partying it up. This is the
weekend I want you to sort of hunker
down. I'm going to make it fun, okay?
But you can't go out there and blow
everything. We're going to reevaluate
what you expect to do on a weekend,
right? Let's get through it. These are
two weeks going to make a huge
difference in your life. So, we're going
to recreate your weekend to make it easy
to do the right thing. Next 48 hours,
you will win and lose this battle. We're
going to do it together. Okay. The first
thing we're going to do, and it's a huge
obstacle for anyone on the weekend
trying to lose weight, is happy hour.
Yes. Friday nights, happy hour. They go
hand in hand. What's a typical Friday
night happy hour like for you? Oh,
gracious. I want to actually sit down,
just have a few drinks with my husband,
and just relax. Relax out of the stress
week that I just had. Well, first of
all, I'm glad you're not going out, but
I'm going to make one little additional
improvement on it. I'm going to analyze
what it is you see, for example, in a
glass of wine. What do you like about
it? You like the act of holding it, the
ritual of massaging it, right? Do I have
it right? Yes, I do. Right. That's what
we like doing, right? And it keeps us
addicted to the process. So, you want
the soothing element of it, but I can't
afford to give you the sugar water,
right? With the alcohol that's in there.
So, this doesn't have to be painful, but
we're going to make a little
modification. Take that same type of
wine glass. Make it a big one. Okay.
You're going to put some lemon juice.
Just go ahead and squeeze that in there.
Lemon juice. Okay. And then you're going
to add some sparkling water. All right.
I got a little in there already, but add
a little sparkling water. And then put a
little garnish on there. Strawberry just
to jazz it up a tiny bit. Got And I'm
not asking you to compare this to wine,
right? I'm saying to me, there's no
comparison. No, there's no comparison.
But but it's this I is enough to get you
through Friday night. You're going to
reward yourself in a week by looking so
good when you program. That's what I'm
That's the goal. All right, come on
over. The other thing I want you to do
is think differently about how you
reward yourself. We always use food to
reward ourselves for a long week of
work. You want to enjoy the weekends,
you want to enjoy it with food. Doesn't
have to be that way. This plan calls for
you to detox yourself. The detoxing
isn't just what you put inside your
body. It's what you put around your
body. Definitely. So, I made you a
little bath here. You don't have to get
in, but this bath is going to help you
rid yourself of toxins and it's going to
deal with cravings that you have because
it's a cravings killer. Yes. And so, you
have a hot water tub, I gather.
Definitely. Yes. So you fill it up with
warm water and then when it's warm, just
the warmth by itself will allow you to
start sweating. It gets rid of some of
the toxins. You start to circulate the
lymph in the body, which is how the body
gets rid of garbage in the body, right?
So it likes that. Then you're going to
add some Epsom salts. Go ahead and add
that in there. Two cups. Sprinkle it in
there. Be dramatic about it. Just thrust
it in there. Yes. Right. It has
magnesium sulfate. Your body absorbs the
magnesium. You're going to use it all.
And then look like this.
Okay. And then if you messes up, your
husband will clean up. So the magnesium
gets absorbed and so it actually relaxes
your muscles and it relaxes you for that
reason. It's fantastic for sleep. Then
you're going to add a cup of baking soda
because you actually want to look your
best and this will help with the skin.
It'll soften your skin. It definitely
does. Oh, you tried. I've tried it.
Perfect. And if you've got dry skin,
it'll also help with that as well. I
want you to soak in that tub for 30
minutes. You're giving yourself a gift
without giving yourself any calories or
even temptation of calories. Okay. All
right. So that's Friday night. Now let's
go to Saturday. All right. Saturday is
all about And that's a whole day. Yeah,
it's a whole day. It's the first full
day of the weekend. So what's your
favorite thing? What you would do
typically do on a Saturday? Casinos. I
don't know. Casinos. Casinos, movies, or
just chilling out. So uh first of all,
I'm I'm I'm happy you're having fun.
Yes. Uh for this weekend, we may not go
to the casinos because there a lot of
temptation there. I want to give you
three things to do on a Saturday. They
are not going to put any calories into
your body and you're still going to
enjoy them. Great. So I want you to do
things that make you feel good, right?
So, for example, you could stay at home
and just get a facial. Do it yourself.
Okay. Now, I'm gonna have my husband do
it. Yeah. Let him do it. Even better.
It's the least he could do. Absolutely.
Exactly. Okay. Or if you want to get out
a little bit without going to the
casino, you can get a manicure, a
pedicure, something just to sort of get
you relaxed and feeling good about life.
Pamper yourself a tiny bit. But I think
one of the best things you might want to
do is to organize your life. So, for
example, reevaluate your closet. Yes.
And not just any way you can reevaluate
it, you're going to do with a very clear
purpose. You're going to pick an outfit
that you actually want to get rid of
when you lose the weight. Okay. On the
rapid weight loss plan. And you want to
pick an outfit you're going to be able
to get back into again when you lose the
weight. Yes. Yes. I have that already. I
have my skinny jeans. And every woman
has a pair of skinny jeans. So Oh, there
they are. Look at them. Yes. Oh, no.
Those are my fat clothes. Oh, the fat
clothes. Those are the fat clothes. I'm
burning those as soon as I lose the rest
of my weight. Burning those. Torching
them.
And then you have you already picked out
those skinny jeans you like. Yes. Yes, I
have the skinny jeans. I bought them
already. They're folded up nicely. I see
them every single morning. I can tell
you're excited. Very. Okay. All right.
And Saturday night before you go to bed,
we have all these recipes on the Total
10 Plan. Pick the ones you haven't
played with yet. It's, you know, it's
time to do a little bit of evaluation.
Find some things, some foods you that
you've never tried before. Play with
them a little bit. Explore options that
you may be able to use during the week
when you're, you know, crazy busy and
can't think about it. We got a
cauliflower dish. We've got a zucchini
that this, you know, that's a that
actually mimics pasta. It's a copycat.
So, those are nice little ideas for you
to have. So, takes the opportunity on
Saturday night when you have a little
time. All right. Plus, you won't gain
any weight that way. Okay. The next
obstacle of the weekend is Sunday. This
weekend's a big weekend, you know. Yes.
You got the football playoffs. Got the
Golden Globes. You're all watching.
Football fan. Huge. Now, the best part
about football is probably the food.
Yes. Right. The whole room smells like
it. The house smells like it. Now, the
game plan here, cuz you need one for the
football game, is to actually make a big
bowl of chili. Okay? So, you're going to
do it with a slow cooker. That way, it
makes the whole house smell nicely.
Okay? And and and you want that comfort
smell around the house, but you're not
going to put the usual comforts in
there. You're going to put the foods
that are part of our total 10 rapid
weight loss plan. So, in this case, I
got some tomatoes, some beans, ground
turkey, whatever protein you like. This
is optional. You don't have to use this.
I love the ground turkey, so I'll keep
it. Perfect. But you can make a
vegetarian version as well. Then we have
the onions, the peppers, the celery, and
then all these wonderful spices. Garlic,
cumin, paprika, chili powders, uh, you
know, a little olive oil. And you put
that all together, salt and pepper to
taste, okay? And you're going to have
this, which not only does it taste
fantastic, but it will smell fantastic
for the entire house. And you can enjoy
it as you wish. You're not going to gain
weight cuz it's pretty much all the
foods you can eat unlimited amounts of
in the program. Right. Okay. Now, that's
my warmup. But this is the piesta
resistance. This is what you're going to
like. Okay. You're going to make buffalo
cauliflower wings. All right. So, you're
going to marinate cauliflower. You're
going to break it up in little pieces
like this. You're going to marinate it
in hot sauce, lemon, the paprika, and
salt and pepper to desire. And then, of
course, you got to have the blue cheese
saw, right? You got to have that. That's
where the spice is, right? So, you're
going to replace your normal blue
cheese, which is going to put a ton of
weight in your thighs. It never leaves.
Instead, you're going to take Now, to
get those skinny jeans on, you're going
to get your yogurt. You're gonna add a
little stevia to it, some paprika, some
lemon zest, and a little bit of hot
sauce to taste so it's not too hot for
you. Okay? And then that becomes this.
And please taste that if you like. And I
got to even have the celery there. Take
away the hotness if it's a little too
much for you. Okay. You got to get the
hot sauce. I worked hard on this. Okay.
Okay. Okay. This is your Sunday special.
As the game is ending, you put the last
one in your mouth and you think to
yourself, "Ah, it feels so good. I can
do this. You can do that. That wine that
I had earlier, this the wine sun wine.
wine with no wine in it. Like, use the
glass. Be the party girl. Enjoy
yourself. And you're gonna be so darn
skinny. You'll be in those skinny jeans
in no time. That's the plan. That's the
plan. Love having you. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good