We're back talking about the skin
ingredient retinol and how it can
transform your face. Now retinol comes
with lots of questions like how much
retinol do you need, right? Or when
should you use it? How much is too much?
Right? Should your face be red? I got
that question. We're back with Linda who
doesn't want to give up on retinol.
Right? She has some other questions. For
example, how do you pick the right one?
To help answer all these questions, Dr.
Froo is joining us to arm you with all
the information that will come in handy.
So, not all retinols are the same. We've
established that. Why is this a range of
retinol products on the market? Well, so
here's the deal. So, retinol as an
ingredient is actually incredibly
difficult to formulate. So, to start off
with, retinols are not very stable. What
does it mean? They don't like heat. They
don't like UV. They don't like oxygen
because it makes them start to degrade
and be less potent. So how you formulate
your product, how you produce it, even
how you get it properly into your jar
and there's a lot of products in the
market that are not very stable which is
why you might not be getting the results
that you were hoping and you know
expecting. Part of the reason I wanted
to hear is you actually formulate
retinol in your lab. So explain to us
how you think about the process when you
actually make the stuff that you that
you give to your customers. What do you
look for? Okay. Okay. Back to the
basics, right? retinol vitamin A. It's
an oil soluble vitamin. So if we are
creating once we're creating a product,
we really need first we need some sort
of oil or lipid to dissolve and disperse
our retinol in so that it's evenly in
the whole product. Um and you know and
to keep it really stable. So I brought
two very different oils here with me.
Let's see what happens when I try to put
my retinol blend into these oils. Please
do. So this is the retinol blend that uh
we use in our Olay retinol 24
formulations. Just a few droplets in
here. And then uh of course what we
would do, we would mix this together.
And what we're really expecting to see
is one even solution. All the retinol is
dissolved in my oil. But that's not
really what's happening. A lava lamp. I
mean, look at this. Yeah, it's that's
like oil oil and water literally looking
like that. But it's both oils. It's just
not the right oil that I've chosen here.
So, what should it look like when you
add retinol to the right kind of fat for
the right time? Let's maybe look at this
second oil blend we have here. That's
the one that we use in retinol 24.
Again, let's do the same thing. Let's
just add a couple of drops here into the
oil. And
again, let's shake it up. Let's see what
happens.
Ah, much better. That's what you want to
see a clear solution. The retinol is
completely dissolved. You all see the
difference between those two in the oil.
You want this mixed in nicely. This one
is not dissolving at all. So, what makes
the O retinol 24 different from other
retinols on the market. All right. So,
we already talked about finding that
optimum oil blend which might be you
know screening hundreds of different
oils but then what you do with it. So we
are trying to basically think about it
as we're trying to hide the retinol on
the inside of the product so that it is
stable and protected. So once we have
the oil, what we're going to do is
create what we call an oil and water
emulsion with lots and lots of little
oil droplets on the inside of the
formula surrounded by the water face and
other protective ingredients.
So we gave you the Olay retinol 24. You
tried it for a couple days. Thoughts on
it? So much better. So much better. So
no big blotchy rash. No. Um, my skin was
really smooth and bright every morning.
I was so excited to wake up in the
morning. I didn't have any like
sensitivity, no redness. It was just
really, really nice. And plus, I felt um
really moisturized. It was really
pretty. So, what do you make of her
results? Expected? Yes. Not surprising.
Really not surprising. You know, with
with this product, you know, you get
24-hour hydration, but you also get
24-hour potency. Um, you wake up with
that smoother, brighter skin. And that's
very much what we heard from women in
our clinical studies and our research.
The vast majority did not experience any
irritation. They can use it every day
which means they're going to start
seeing the results. So you say there's a
bunch of ways we can do it. So las
microscoping cream can also play a role
in this just to be clear. So who uses
this, right? And what are the other
options if you don't want to have it all
mixed together for us? The convenience
is great, right? I mean, this is, you
know, if you're a kind of a one-step
nighttime regimen person, you just want
to moisturize but have all the benefits
of retinol. This is it. A one-step
process. Great. But you could also use
the serum and then maybe on top a
different moisturizer like my favorite,
the Olay Regenerous Microscoping Cream
for flexibility. Take it. Up to you.
We're we're not we're not telling you
what we what you have to do. We're just
creating fabulous products and how you
use them is really down to your product.
So no matter which you choose, how do
you apply retinol correctly? Yeah. So
there's a couple of things. So a, you
know, we heard that retinols can be, you
know, sensitive to UV. So that's why
it's usually best to use them at night.
And then the other thing is, I mean, you
have to stick with that for a little
while, right? I mean, results like 28
days is a really good period, you know,
four weeks, which is not super long. And
that's when you really start seeing more
and more benefits. You feel safe now?
Yes. All right. Up next, thank you,
Rocka. The most delicate area of skin
that may be giving away your real age.
Find out what it is when we come
back. Not all skin is created equal,
which is why the delicate skin around
your eyes may need a little bit extra
TLC. It's thinner with fewer oil glands,
more sensitives, prone to issues like
puffiness, discoloration, wrinkles. Here
are some pictures of my audience
members. Their eyes are looking right at
us. Whose eyes are these? Because you
get to be my guest of the day. Who is
it? Oh. Oh, I got the victim right here.
How are you? What's your name? How are
you? I'm Erica. You do have very pretty
eyes, Erica. Oh, thank you. Thank you.
So, what do you think about your eyes?
What can you are they just the way you
want them? Well, I have on concealer
right now, but in the morning, I'm like
really dark around the eyes. So, um you
know, just due to stress and just do to
just life. So, I just put like a little
something on. So, I'm trying to get rid
of that. Do you like taking tests? Yes.
You all like taking tests? Yeah. This
test Julia, come on down here. Give you
a little quiz everybody. We've created
with our partner Olay to help determine
your skin care product for the eyes.
It's got to be customized. Olay
scientist Shannon Whites is here to walk
us through it. Everyone follow along.
Keep track of your answers. Super
simple. Three questions and then
Shannon's going to explain what it
means. Okay, you got this, Shannon. Got
it. Question number one, which best
describes the way your eyes look? Think
about this in your mind now. All right.
So, A, crepey and dry. B, not sure. Need
all kinds of help. My eyes look older
than my face.
C. Dark circles. I haven't slept in
days. Yeah, you. One of those letters
applies to me, but we'll get to that
later. Question two. What do you tend to
do to combat your under eye concerns?
Your eye concerns in general. So, A,
cucumbers and cold spoons. B, eye mask
makeup the works. C, try and get more
sleep. You keeping track here? Yes. All
right, last question. What kind of
benefit do you think you want from an
eye product? So, A is one that is
moisturizing and cooling. B, one that
does double duty, so it conceals and
corrects. C, one that makes me look wide
awake and fades my dark circles. All
right, Eric, you tied up your answers?
Yes. Let's walk down here. So, no matter
what you all answered, there's a
solution for you. That's the real
essence of today's segment to get you to
appreciate that if you're wise about
what your problems are, you can
customize the perfect solution for it.
So, who out there answered mostly A's?
Hands up. Mostly A's. All right. So for
A's, they have dry skin under their
eyes. So if you said A, mostly A's, what
do you what do you have for us? Yeah. So
if you answered A, you're looking for a
deep hydrating eye gel. So where about
A's again? I got solutions for you. Oh,
where where's Oh, there's an A right
here. So close. More A's. Gez. Olay's
deep hydrating eye gel is actually a
hyaluronic acid formula that's going to
hydrate that dry skin around the eyes
for a more refreshed look. Right. How
many B's are there? Put your hands up
for your bees. Oh, there are a lot of
bees. More bees. Okay. All right. So for
bees, they have puffy and wrinkly eyes.
Here, you do this. Now you walk around
Bob. Very good. Now keep Erica busy. All
right. So if you were bees, you're going
to look for a threein one. So I really
like the Olay Ultimate Eye Perfecting
Cream. So it actually has some titanium
dioxide in there to give it kind of a
touch of concealer, but it won't bleed
or smear, and it blends with every skin
tone, which is huge. The other thing
that it has is amopeptides. So, those
are going to help build your skin from
the inside so that way you can see
visibly firmer skin on the outside. All
right. And finally, C's, which I've been
told, yes, you feel like a C. I feel
like a C. All right. Every day. But the
C's, they seem to have dark circles.
What causes the dark circles? So, it is
mostly genetics, but they can be
exacerbated by your lifestyle. And what
do you have for us as a solution? All
right. So, you want something that has
vitamin C and caffeine that's going to
really improve and brighten that eye. I
personally like the um Olay brightening
eye cream for dark circles. But what's
what's actually in the cream that let it
work the way it's supposed to? This is
the fun part. So, we're going to come
over here. So, what I have here is a
little bit of a deconstruction of the
product. Some of the key components of
the the Olay eye brightening cream. So,
what you'll notice is that uh you can
see how the ingredients here worked
together to kind of reflect the light
away from the eyes. We've really worked
to kind of enhance and make this a very
unique blend so that it reflects light
for everyone for any skin tone and
really works to really brighten that eye
area. How do you actually apply it here?
That'll be all right. Let's work on
that. So, what you want to do is you can
use uh this product in the morning and
the evening on cleansed skin. And you
want to take um a little bit of the
product and you want to make sure you're
dabbing it all around the eye. So you
want to use it under the eye, the outer
corners of the eye, and the eyelid. Um
and then you'll want to then kind of
really make sure it's it's worked into
the skin and fully absorbed. How long
until Erica sees the results? So what
you're going to actually notice an
improvement in the skin feel right away.
So, after the first use, and what's even
more amazing is after four weeks, you're
going to see that physical reduction in
the dark circles. That's what we're all
looking for. Grab it out of her hand
quickly. Take it from her before she
changes her mind. All right, the
transformation you have to see to
believe with the product picks you can
afford. Take a look at what's taking
place backstage right now. We'll be
right back with more.
[Music]
[Applause]
That was a sneak peek at what's been
going on backstage. Now, if you're tired
and stressed out like so many of us are,
you got the 10-minute transformations
you have to see to believe. Take a look
and see if these hardworking women sound
like you. Hi, my name is Karen
Tapalleski. I've been a nurse for 10
years. I work in the surgical ICU and
most importantly, I work night shift.
night shift is just a whole different
environment. I pretty much live off of
coffee, caffeine, tea, just sheer
adrenaline some days trying to get
through. She's always there for all of
the other staff members on night shift
and she's always doing it with a
positive attitude and a smile.
Last October, my mom found her breast
cancer had come back. We had her home
and I helped my dad take care of my mom
handle her medications, doctor's visits,
just pretty much nursed 24 hours a day.
if it wasn't, you know, at work, it was
at home. It was a very, very emotional
struggle year to try and separate home
and work and still, you know, make a
living and provide for my family. It's
worth it. Even my worst days, I I love
what I do. I get to take care of
patients and just use my knowledge, my
experience, you know, to really try to
help them. Hi, I'm Lori. I'm a nurse.
I've been a nurse for about 11 years
now. I'm a single parent to four
children. So, my time is spread very
thin. On the days when I work, I get up
between 4:30 and 5:00 in the morning. My
feet hit the floor. I'm running trying
to get the kids ready, get them out the
door, get them to daycare, and make it
to my shift on time. And then it's 12,
13, 14 hours before I get home again.
This past year, I started in school.
I've been studying to become a family
nurse practitioner. That has made our
schedule even more difficult. um
juggling trying to make sure that my
children all make their appointments.
So, it's just a challenge. Consequently,
um I'm the last on the list. I take care
of my children. I make sure that I do my
work. I get to school on time, but I
would like to take care of myself a
little bit better.
After the surgery, I know firsthand the
integral role Cin and Lorie play in our
healthcare system. I know they deserve
to be rewarded. So, beauty consultant
Danielle Gay gave Corin and Lori
backstage makeovers just minutes before
they are coming out here. You're going
to see it right now. We are dying. I'm
dying. I'm dying. I would have seen it,
but there you were there. I want to see
it again. All right, Corin, you're up
first.
Oh, the makeup got her
smiling. And now, Lori, it's your turn.
Very
polished. Very elegant.
So Cody, what's been the most surprising
thing about this makeover? I saw you
before. By the way, thank you both for
all your work in the hospital. It be,
you know, there there's no medical
system without the nurses. What's the
most surprising thing for you? Really,
just how quick she transformed me from
looking tired and exhausted and to
looking like this. You have lives to
save. And Roy, why is the makeover so
important for you? Well, having a
routine that I can do in the morning
that's just for me will help me to have
the confidence to keep going and doing
what I'm doing. So, can we show the rest
of the country exactly how Danielle did
this? Come on over. Danielle did all
your magic backstage. So, you got to
walk us through the process of what you
did so everyone at home can take
advantage of your wisdom. Yes. So, of
course, your makeup routine starts with
your skinare routine. We prepped the
ladies with the Olay Regenerous
Microsculpting Cream. One of my
favorites. It's a great dewy finish
moisturizer. Then you move on to
foundation. So, foundations come in a
variety of undertones. So, a quick and
easy trick is with your jewelry. If you
look best in gold, you're warm. If you
look best in silver, you're cool. And if
you look good in both, you're neutral.
Perfect. It's It's easy cheat. All
right. So, if you want to add a
dimension to your face, quick trick.
Give us some hacks. Super quick trick is
to lift underneath the eye area. So,
you're going to do that with concealer.
Now, a lot of times you see concealer
where it's just dotted underneath the
eyes, and that's not really, you know,
really getting that surface area. So,
better way to do it, an upside down
triangle. So that upside down triangle,
that's going to get the areas where
there's dark circles, any other
discoloration. And then you definitely
want to make sure that you blend that
out. Dr. Eyes, you're truly concealing.
Yes. Yeah. I like I like I leave mine
like little red patches. I can play a
football game. Yeah. Going to battle.
Right. And then blend it out. Then you
want a quick finish with mascara. Yes.
So a lot of thing a lot of times with
mascara, what you want to look for is a
thinner brush because a thinner brush is
really going to get those inner corners
and really give you a lot of volume and
a lot of lift. And you're going to go
from the root and wiggle out to the to
the tips. Gives you a nice fanned out
lash. Can I see your smiles? You guys
deserve. That's that's what I want.
Happy nurses. Yes. Daniel, very nice.
We're going to put more Daniel's
transformation tips online. Thanks for
being here, Cory and Lori. I want both
of you to know that that the medical
community is finds nursing invaluable,
but more importantly, America sees it as
the number one most respected
profession. So, congratulations. Thank
you. Representing. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good