Dental scams. Six cavities when I was
told I had none. You just don't know who
to trust. Oz undercover. We were shocked
at people being overcharged. I was in
the chair for less than 10 minutes when
she started finding problems. The total
cost $3,500.
Plus an Oz medical mystery. The boy who
was slowly turning to stone. He's going
to be in tuned within himself. Coming up
next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you guys.
Today, an undercover investigation that
might make you angry. In a group
brainstorm, it came up that several
members of my staff felt they had been
scammed at the dentist. So, we looked
online at Yelp reviews, which you I know
many of you use to pick a doctor, and we
were shocked at the claims of people
being overcharged or that something
shocked me even more was that they were
being overdiagnosed.
So we went undercover to see are
negative reviews a good indicator of a
bad doctor. When we asked correspondent
Maras Gavakmpo to investigate, she had a
story of her own in a story that sort of
stunned me. So I want you to hear that
and we'll get into the investigation. So
what happened to you? You hadn't been to
a dentist in two years. Yeah, I'm not
the biggest fan of the dentist. What
happened two years ago? Uh well, I went
to the dentist. It was for a regular
dental checkup. Nothing was bothering
me. Um and the dentist said that I had a
crack in a filling that needed to be
repaired. So, I took their word for it.
I made a follow-up appointment. I went
back. I got the work done. I remember
the needle for numbing was incredibly
painful. Um, but I got that procedure
done. So, you were so entranced by this
idea that not everyone was being as
professional as they could be that you
agreed to help us infiltrate behind
lines. Yeah. To figure out what's really
happening. And you look at these online
reviews. Yes. So, how'd you organize it?
How did you begin to set it up? Well,
the first thing we did was get a
baseline because remember I hadn't been
to the dentist in two years. So, we went
to a dentist, Dr. Rashbomb, and he gave
me a thorough exam to let me know the
current condition of my teeth. In the
meantime, our team was combing Yelp
reviews, looking for people who were
complaining about their dentist, and we
were shocked to find how many people had
complaints. So, we actually followed up
with some people. We did our due
diligence, and then we made appointments
at some of the places that seemed like
the worst offenders. Let's take a look
at how the investigation unfolded.
Dentists. Are some taking an unnecessary
bite out of your wallet? To find out,
we're going to go undercover visiting
several dentists with these glasses and
a hidden camera.
Yeah.
I told the same story to each dentist,
and it's true. So, I just wanted a a
general checkup to see if there was
anything pressing that needs to be
addressed. Um, because I haven't been to
the dentist in a few years. I was
shocked by their
findings because just one week before
I'd gotten a baseline checkup from New
York City dentist Dr. Justin Rashbound
and he told me, "Overall, your teeth
look like they're in great shape."
That's right, great. No cavities. Dr.
Rashbound did a thorough tooth and
perodontal exam and took a complete set
of X-rays to determine the health of my
teeth. What are some things that you saw
that might need to be addressed? What
are some things that you might expect
another dentist to say you should
address this now? Well, I think one of
the I think uh another dentist will
probably see or should see uh that you
have a filling that needs to be replaced
uh on your bottom left. So, just to be
clear, you think I need the filling
addressed and I need a teeth cleaning.
That's it. Nothing else. That's it.
Armed with this assessment from a
trusted dentist, I was ready to go
undercover. After being rigged with a
hidden camera, I headed out to three New
York City dentists with some bad online
reviews to see if any would prescribe
unnecessary work and try to overcharge
me.
And everyone watching, this is not about
bashing dentists. Most are honest and
reputable. So, I've invited a team of
dentists here to weigh in on what you're
about to see. Dr. Justin Rashbam, that's
who met before the uh the investigation.
She wanted to get a baseline. My
personal dentist joins us, Dr. David
Jyn. and Dr. Adah Cooper, a practicing
dentist and spokesperson for the
American Dental Association. And they're
here to help you pick the best dentist
to make sure you get the best treatment.
All right, so now Mara had a good idea
of the condition of her teeth. But to be
sure of the diagnosis, we had her x-rays
examined by an additional dentist for
confirmation. So up next, our
investigation continues. You will not
believe what happened undercover at
various dentists with bad reviews across
New York City. Stay with us.
All new. For years, we've been told to
eat less carbs and more protein. New
research shows that those steaks,
burgers, the bacon could be the secret
culprit behind your biggest health
issue. Meat belly dilemma. When you eat
this kind of diet, bad bacteria can
overpop populate. Plus, shocking
information that you never knew about
seafood. 90% of our seafood is
important, and the FDA only takes a look
at 3% or less. All new OS that's coming
up on
[Music]
Monday. I'm back with Marcompo who went
undercover to dentists with negative
online reviews to see if they'd really
overcharge or even overdiagnose issues
with her teeth. My panel dentist is also
back. We're going to check with them in
a little bit. But before going
undercover, Mara got a complete dental
checkup, a baseline for comparison. So
before we see the the results of your
investigation, this really got me. How
did you figure out which dentist to see
and how many did you have in mind to go
visit? Yeah. So we based this on Yelp
reviews and we picked seven of what we
thought were probably the worst
offenders based on the reviews. We only
made it through three of them because we
were so shocked by we found by what we
found with the first three. And for
those three consultations, we spent
$450. But we didn't even have to go to
all seven just for the visits. 450
bucks. Yeah. Just for the visits. No
cleanings, no anything else. So remember
what these dentists were told when the
appointments were made. They were told
that Mer had not seen a dentist in two
years just wanted an assessment would
pay out of pocket. Those are the
baselines. So what happens next in our
investigation? Well, it surprised us
all. Take a look. The first dentist I
visited undercover really surprised me.
The only cavities I see are are the top
wisdom teeth. In the middle of the
teeth, you have these little cavities. I
have cavities in my wisdom teeth. Yeah.
Look, I I can show you what they look
like. Okay. I I'm going to trust your
judgment, but you fairly certain that
that's the case. Very certain. Okay.
With uh with 100% certainty? Yeah. And
the cost to fill those two cavities
along with a mouth guard he recommended.
So, your total for the full guard
fillings comes out to $1,150.
$1,150. Just getting out of that visit
and I am shocked. Two cavities. Let's
see what the next dentist will find.
There are three things that are going
on. Um, one thing, two that had a root
canal that would need a crown to protect
it so it doesn't break on this side.
Yeah. Then on the other side, there's a
filling from DK going on underneath that
filling. And then there's one more
filling, which is a regular filling on
the top here that needs to be replaced.
The total cost $3,500.
So, apparently I need two replacement
fillings and one new crown. But hey, at
least no cavities. Let's see what the
next one says. I was in the chair for
less than 10 minutes when she started
finding problems. She has a MO on 30 and
an acclusal on 32. You also do have some
cavities on your wisdom teeth. The teeth
all the way in the back. On the top or
the bottom? On all four of them. I have
four cavities. Mhm. Actually, five.
Actually, it wasn't five. It ended up
being six cavities. The total cost to
repair them,
$1,930. I'm just shocked. I mean, six
cavities when I was told I had none. You
just don't know who to trust.
Yeah. Looking at the audience, they're
shaking their heads. More importantly to
me, the dentists, colleagues, the panel
are shaking their heads. So, let's take
let's go to you guys from zero cavities.
Dr. Rash, that was your professional
opinion. What's your reaction to the
dentist finding things that you didn't
see or were they not there? I'm not here
to say that my exam was the right one
and everyone else's was incorrect. But
it's not only necessarily uh if a
filling needs to be treated, but also
when a filling needs to be treated.
There are certain fillings that Mara had
that were not the most beautiful looking
restorations I've ever seen. So, simply
just replacing fillings. Just because
something doesn't look aesthetically
perfect doesn't necessarily mean that's
the correct treatment. And I tend to be
a little bit more conservative and in in
that instance I recommend to just that
one. I think everything else will hold
up for quite a long time. So Dr. J, this
is a judgment issue. I go to you. I
trust you because you are conservative.
Thank you. And I value that. You know,
you're thoughtful. You point stuff out,
but you do the least you can. So how do
you go if you're a consumer from being
told you need maybe one filling or no
actual real bad cavities to maybe having
six things having to be addressed? Well,
you really got to get to know your
patient first. You can't just on day one
say you need A, B, C, D, and E. Our our
job is to promote longevity of tooth,
not to just drill and fill them. Dr.
Cooper, you represent the American
Dental Association, which of course is
robustly full of wonderful ethical
people. Absolutely. But the profession
must get concerned when you see this
kind of variability as well. again from
zero to six or a big number difference
between one exam that we trust and
another exam that we just heard. Yeah.
Let me say first of all that you're
right. Most dentists are really
hardworking, impeccably honest, and have
devoted years and years of training to
making sure that they're doing what's
absolutely best in your best interest.
In making that
determination, you're both right. There
is a range within which most dentists
work to determine what the best
treatment is based on you and your needs
and your history. Okay? So for example,
at one end of the range are dentists who
tend to be more conservative in their
treatment. There are other dentists who
are a little bit more proactive. Okay?
So, make sure that if one dentist has
told you something and another has told
you something else that you don't just
assume that both of them are being
dishonest with you. It may just be that
they're practicing along that spectrum
of different philosophies. But, you
know, the heartbreaking thing to me, the
most heartbreaking thing to me about
watching that video is the look of utter
confusion on your face. No dentist wants
a patient to be that confused. Most
dentists really want you to understand
what's going on. Really want you to
understand what we're saying to you. And
so if you're feeling confused because
you've gotten different opinions because
you're not understanding what the
dentist is saying, ask the questions
because it puts the power back in your
lab to make good decisions for you. Ask
to see X-rays. Ask to see pictures. Ask
if there are any alternative treatments.
You can ask for priorities. When
patients come into my office, I always
give a list of priorities. This is what
you can do to make your teeth stronger.
And these are optional things to make
your teeth prettier. If you ask for that
list of priorities, if you ask the
questions that you have nine times out
of 10, because dentists really do care
about you and your oral health, you'll
leave without the confusion. All right.
So, what about the 10th time? What if
you're not satisfied by what by what
you've learned? Then leave and find a
dentist that you trust. So, up next, how
to pick the best doctor and avoid
getting treatment you don't need. Stay
with us.
[Music]
For 32 years, this 12-year-old's death
has remained a mystery until now. Using
genealogy and cuttingedge DNA technology
to create her suspected killer's face.
That's coming up on Tuesday.
I'm back with correspondent Mars
Gavakmpa who went undercover to dentists
with bad online reviews to see if she'd
been overcharged or overdiagnosed. And
what we found, well, it shocked us both.
We're joined by a panel of dentists who
want to make sure you get the best care,
including the dentists who did Mara's
initial assessment, Dr. Justin Rushbomb.
So, I got my personal dentist, Dr. David
Jyn, is here and Dr. Adah Cooper, a
practicing dentist and spokesperson for
the American Dental Association. All
right. So, let's look again at the
diagnosis from the second dentist,
Marasaw.
There are three things that are going
on. Um, one thing, two, that had a root
canal that would need a crown to protect
it so it doesn't break on this side.
Yeah. Then on the other side, there's a
filling on decay going on underneath
that. And then there's one more filling,
which is a regular filling on the top
here that needs to be replaced.
[Music]
$3,500 worth of work and four visits.
So, Dr. Jin, how do you explain the
different diagnosis and the different
costs that were brought in in these
different dentists? Well, the exact fee
structure that each dentist charges, it
it really depends on them. Like for
instance, if you have a medical
condition, when you go from one hospital
to the next, the fees uh varies greatly.
On the other hand, in terms of
diagnosis, it's our job to actually
explain to you what is arrested, what is
what is active, what is urgent, what is
not. So many folks watching now are
going to be confused because they see a
whole slew of options and it's not
always that clear, I think, which ones
are important. You certainly didn't have
that belief. It wasn't clear to me. No.
So, let's just take this one by one.
First of all, we don't have a lot of
transparency in medicine or in dentistry
on costs, which is a big big problem in
this country. But there's one place you
can look in healthcare. It's called the
blue book, right? The healthcare blue
book will give you an estimate of the
costs in your area. And I'm going to put
a link to it on my website. So, at least
start with that so you have a a way of
beginning to enter the discussion of
what things are cost. How do you
actually know if you're being taken
advantage of? And I'll open it up to all
of you because there's no way that every
single dentist is perfect. And just
looking at these Yelp reviews, there are
plenty of great Yelp reviews or dentists
in New York City. I don't know why
people would go to these dentists with
bad Yelp reviews, but they are at
practices. They're busy. So, how do you
know if you've walked into a problem?
So, maybe I can grab this question. So,
the first thing is my best patients at
my office are referrals for my existing
patients. The second thing, if a doctor
tells you you have a cavity and needs a
filling, need a filling, ask them to see
the photograph, ask them to see an
X-ray. The last thing I would say is to
avoid um deals online um through any of
those online advertising uh avenues. So
when you do those, I can tell you right
now the dentists that are advertising
for free bleaching, free consultations,
they are not making any money from your
initial visit. They are there in the
hopes or of finding things to do, things
to work on. And that's potentially a
major issue. So I would avoid any type
of online deals. Uh that's that's a big
thing. Well, the office that that said I
had six cavities actually offered a free
cleaning uh free whitening with your
visit. So, that speaks to your point.
Well, follow on to uh what he said.
Really, it's really important for you to
create a trust. The bottom line is like
in my office, it's all about family.
Everybody come to me as as part of my
family. Um Dr. Oz is like a brother to
me you know and somebody might be a
mother to me and somebody might be a son
to me and they are part member of the
family and that's how we create trust
and you have to understand and and
develop your own treatment plan based on
that and say hey if this is my loved one
would I do that to that person that's
the key question to ask would you do it
for your family Dr. Cooper, this is a
big issue for you at the American Dental
Association is is having a dental home.
It's tremendously important to have a
dent dental home. One thing that I
noticed about your experience is that
you were going to dentist to dentist to
dentist and you really didn't know
anything about any of them and they
really didn't know that much about you.
They didn't know your dental history.
They didn't know your home care regimen.
They didn't know whether you had any
what we call parapunctional habits like
tooth grinding and other things that may
make fillings and crowns more needed
than others. you really didn't have a
relationship with each other. So, what
you really could have done perhaps to
avoid misunderstanding is to try to
establish a dental home, a relationship
with a dentist that's long-term because
that way when things come up in your
mouth, you can talk to your dentist
about it. You can decide when to do it.
He will base his recommendations on how
likely it
is that the situation will progress. And
so with the relationship with your
dentist that's long-term, your dentist
knows you and can make a better
prognosis of what the outcome of various
treatment methods are so that you'll get
the best result for you. All right, let
me go back to the consumer perspective
here. What are your thoughts now about
these online rating services since you
did use them with some success in
predicting a bad experience? Yeah, for
better or for worse, people consult
these online reviews. They are very
popular and that is how we identified
the offenders so to speak that we found
um for this investigation. So you
absolutely can consult online reviews.
Also if you have a bad experience, speak
up about it, make it known. Post your
experience online so that other people
can consult it. It's one way to try to
get a sense of what's going on. We
should note that Dr. Rashbomb five out
of five stars. So he's doing quite well
when it comes to the online reviews. All
right, let me offer some final thoughts.
In both medicine and dentistry, we don't
have good resources to find the best.
Like when you go shopping for a car or
an appliance, you have all kinds of
rating systems that are pretty
objective. So, we've got to rely on the
tools that we have, like these online
reviews, which I think can be valuable.
And you got to get advice from people
you trust, like your friends and family.
Frankly, that's what I do, and I'm a
doctor. But most importantly, you have
to have the confidence to ask questions
if you're confused, because a confused
patient is not going to be a happy one.
For more tips on how to get the best
dental care, go to our website. I'll be
right back.
[Music]
Up next, we're unraveling a medical
mystery. How can a 12-year-old boy
turned to stone? We have exclusive
interviews with his family, his doctor,
and the boy himself. Stay with
[Music]
us. Today, we're investigating a medical
mystery. How can a 12year-old boy turn
to stone? Jaden Rogers was only six when
his parents noticed his skin was
developing a stone-like texture. And no
matter what they did, they kept
spreading and getting worse. Jane's mom,
Natalie, is here. Jaden is backstage
with his dad, Tim. We're going to meet
them both in a little bit. Thank you for
being here. Thank you.
You said that little piece that your son
used to run around. Yes, he did. What
was his like? Tell me more about that
life that he had before this all
started. Um he was really energetic and
used to run and play and get into
everything he could get
into. Um he was just your typical boy
that like to play boy things.
How was Jaden handling this emotionally?
Emotionally, it's pretty hard on him.
He's pretty quiet. um doesn't talk a lot
about things and
um
sometimes he cries and other days he's
just tries to be a happy child. Um it
depends on the day and how he's feeling.
when he has the pain,
he's usually wakes up in the middle of
the night screaming um that he's in pain
and he's holding his legs
and needs more pain medicine and we're
getting to be where we're using more and
more pain medicine every day.
You're wonderful parents. Thank you.
Tell the love you have with your son is
unbounded. But there must be moments of
sadness in all this. But what's your
biggest fear?
My biggest fear is pretty much that he's
going to be in tuned within himself and
um not being able to move without pain.
Uh
that the stiff skin is going to compress
on organs. Um, there's just not enough
known about it
to know what is gonna happen with Jaden.
You use that word in tomb. Literally put
it his coffin is his skin. Mhm. Yes.
Burying himself in his own skin. Yes.
Well, we're going to meet Jaden and his
doctors here as well to help explain
this medical mystery. How can a
12-year-old boy turn to stone? And what
is the best hope for his future? Stay
with us.
[Music]
For 32 years, this 12-year-old's death
has remained a mystery until now. Using
genealogy and cutting edge DNA
technology to create her suspected
killer's face. That's coming up on
[Music]
Tuesday. We're back investigating the
medical mystery of a 12-year-old boy
whose skin is turning to stone. Jaden
Rogers symptoms started developing six
years ago and his parents have stopped
at nothing for a cure. What could be
happening inside Jaden's body? And
what's his best hope for the future?
Clinical geneticist Dr. Margarita
Science from Children's Hospital in
Colorado joins me now. She's been
working with Jaden and his family to try
to find a cure. Thank you for all the
great work you do at the Children's
Hospital. So, what was your first course
of action when you met Jaden? When you
first heard the story, right? So, as a
physician who cares for children with
exceedingly rare conditions, we prepare
for our visits by researching the
condition, but specifically for Jaden,
taking into account, this is a young boy
with a chronic medical condition. What
was his diagnosis? And and are any
doubts about whether this is what you
think it is? So he has a condition
called stiff skin syndrome and there is
no question that this is the right
diagnosis as it was confirmed on biopsy.
I want you all to understand how rare
stiff skin syndrome really is. 54 cases
have ever been reported including Jaden.
Correct. For most folks it's just it's
isolated to one part of the body. It's
just the leg or just the arm. But Jaden
has a progressive form. It is consuming
his entire body. And this worries me
because it can restrict his lung
function. You know, you can't breathe.
Everyone put their hands on their chest
right now. And push on your chest as
hard as you can. Then try to take a deep
breath in. You notice you can't quite
get everything in. That's what he's
living with every single day. And I want
to show you what's actually happening
inside Jaden's body. Because it's not
just about this condition, but it's
representative of other conditions
because your body is made up of genes.
All little parts of your DNA. They can
like these yellow dots that make the
proteins that govern our body, right?
And sometimes you don't have enough of
them. They turn off. Sometimes they turn
on like these red ones. They make too
much. You don't have a lot of control
over this. You're born with this. The
gene in Jaden's skin u is that's turning
it to the stone-like texture is making
too many of these proteins, right? Like
collagen and other ones you've never
heard of, right? things like micro fibro
which you know I hadn't even heard of
mucin uh you know and that forces the
skin to stay in one place like you know
how you have scaffolding to do some
construction imagine if you had too much
scaffolding you need these things in the
right amount but too much because these
genes are overactive put you in this
rigid case and as mom was saying it
embalms you rather intombs you right the
the entire layer of the of the skin is
involved in this and it keeps
progressing and it begins to look like
these. These are images. Dr. Science, if
you can walk us through this. So, this
is his thigh, which he says is one of
the areas that's hurting him the most.
Correct. And so, as you can see
demonstrated here, there's extra hair
that's developing and growing in this
particular area. And although the
surface of the skin itself looks normal,
we know the epidermis is normal in this
particular condition, but it's that
layer underneath the dermis that's
becoming abnormal and hardened. So
what's the best hope for Jaden? So I
think the best hope for Jaden would be
is if we could slow the progression of
this condition. So what we're doing is
additional genetic diagnostic testing to
identify the specific gene or genes
involved with this process. And if you
don't find a solution, you know, as
clinicians, we know the urgency
associated with a progressive disorder.
Um that's what we're concerned about is
cardiopulmonary function, overall
restriction of movement. His mom is very
worried about that appropriately. Thank
you, Dr. Stein. So, we wanted Jaden to
be comfortable, so he stayed backstage
in the dressing room and I went down
there to meet him and to examine him.
Hey, how are you? Good. How are you?
Nice to meet you. Hey, Jaden. How are
you?
Tired? Yes. What's your favorite class?
I think my favorite class is recess.
That was my son's favorite class. Now
he's smiling. He's
How much pain are you having from this
condition?
A lot.
Does it keep you up at
night? Would it be okay if I examined
you a little bit? Can you hold my hands?
Give me your other hand, too. And can
you squeeze my
fingers? You're strong. Oh my goodness.
So it doesn't make you weak at all.
You're still strong.
All right.
What What part of your body do you have
most of the thickening in the tightness?
Um here. May I touch that area? You can
touch this part. That's just starting.
Oh, yes. Does it hurt when I press? No.
Is that how your thigh started also?
Yeah. Yeah. It's very hard here. All
through here. And this area is still
soft over here, though. And it goes
around to your back more. Do you feel
that? Are you able to stand here? Hold
my hold my hands. Just stand up. You
don't have to Oh, you're strong. Okay. I
can I'm just going to touch your back. I
just want to see how far that goes
around. And none none of this hurts you.
Just uh just a little bit. All right.
Well, don't do whatever it hurts you.
And And how's your balance? If I were to
let go of you, can you stand? Mhm. Yeah.
You want to try? Yeah. You can stand.
Oh, yeah. You stand pretty well. Oh,
that's
good. It's been a real pleasure meeting
beating you. Take care of you, Jaden.
All
right. I got to say, Jaden is about as
13 as a 13-year-old can be. He gave me a
hard time the entire time. He's quick.
He's sharp. And when his mind is as
intact as it is, and he can witness
what's happening to his body, it's that
much more urgent for us to get involved.
So, if you want to support Jaden's
treatment, please donate to his GoFundMe
page, Treatment for Jaden. Special
thanks to our friends at People magazine
for their amazing footage. Visit
peoplev.com if you want to watch the
full story. We'll be right
back. New research shows that those
steaks, burgers, the bacon could be the
secret culprit behind your biggest
health issue. When you eat this kind of
diet, bad bacteria can overpop populate.
All new OS. That's coming up on
Monday. Most of us have a skin care
routine that we stick to out of habit.
It's all about a repetition of steps day
in and day out. But are you using the
right products the right way in the
right order? Today I want to clear up
the confusion with the help of
dermatologist Dr. Whitney Bow who's here
on behalf of my trusted sponsorship
partner number seven. Thanks for being
here. You have a very busy practice.
Everyone wants to go see you. What is
the biggest mistake you see? And you're
dealing with a lot of fairly
sophisticated people. So, believe it or
not, overcleansing is the number one
mistake that people make when it comes
to their skin. Now, it's okay to scrub
and sanitize your kitchen counter, but
you don't want to take that approach
when it comes to your face. You know, if
you overcleanse the skin, you can
actually not only strip the skin of its
natural oils, but you also disrupt the
delicate balance of bacteria on the
skin. Our skin is covered in trillions
of microscopic bacteria and they exist
in this very delicate balance this very
delicate equilibrium and if we mess with
that balance we can actually trigger
inflammation in the skin. See I thought
you were going to point out
moisturizers. Ah cuz that's a big
challenge I think a lot of folks have. A
lot of people think that all they need
is a moisturizer but that's another very
common mistake. Right. So you want to
keep your skin care regimen simple but
you also want to make sure that your
skin is getting you know the vitamins,
the nutrients, the attention that it
needs. So as our skin matures, yes, we
lose moisture. So having a moisturizer
as part of your skinincare regimen, it's
absolutely crucial for trapping back
that moisture, hydrating the skin, but
Dr. Oz, you can't rely on a moisturizer
alone to really drive those anti-aging
results. I always tell my patients, you
have to make sure that you're also
including a serum in your skincare
regimen because it's the serum that
really helps you with your aging
concerns, things like wrinkles and loss
of firmness and uneven tone. You know,
it's the serum plus the moisturizer.
It's that combination that gives you
even better results. And that's why I
like to recommend a skin care system or
a skincare regimen that actually has
agedefying ingredients in both. So,
number seven's Restore and Renew Face
and Neck Multi-Action Serum, followed by
their day cream that has an SPF 30 in it
really gives you that onetwo punch. And
just as some of the biggest mistakes
we're making, come on. I'm going to show
you why dermatologists like you argue
that we need a serum and a moisturizer
both. So, we built you a very high-tech
complex bottle here. This is soil,
basically dirt, okay? And the soil
represents your skin because that's what
your body initially gives you. And then
you have serum which is fertilizer right
and then you have moisture which is
actually in this case we'll just use
water but moisturizer does that it
hydrates your skin if you want your skin
all this stuff this raw material that's
so fertile to be healthy and rich like
this grass you have to actually address
it these issues unfortunately too often
our skin gets dry uneven it gets crackly
like this you don't want that so instead
you want to add the right serum like Dr.
Bo was saying, right? And as you add the
right serum and of course you rub it in
a little bit and then you combine that.
Remember the good serum will have things
like calcium in it, amino acids,
camides, all the things that we know
from years of research help the skin.
And then when you add the moisturizer,
go ahead and add that. Yep. Lots of
moisturizer. Then all of a sudden you
have this rich fertile soil which is
very different from the crackly stuff
that we started with. So compare these
two. Which which do you want your face
to look like? right? Dry and crackly and
therefore wrinkly, right? Or the
healthier looking youthful state
represented if you actually have
moisturizer with the right kinds of
serum added to it. If you had it all
together, you'll end up with this nice
beautiful result. In fact, you'll be
able to grow beautiful
flowers in that skin of yours if you so
desire. Thank you. So, a regimen like
this one by beauty brand number seven
can really help restore the skin by
delivering five clinically proven
results for the face and the neck. So,
when it comes to the face, it's been
shown to actually visibly reduce the
appearance of wrinkles thanks to a
powerful peptide blend in vitamin A. It
can also help firm up the skin thanks to
hibiscus extract and hyaluronic acid.
And it helps even out skin tone thanks
to a combination of vitamin C and Indian
gooseberry. When it comes to the neck,
it's also been shown to not only make
the neck skin feel firmer, but it
appears visibly smoother, and it just
helps reduce some of that crepey texture
that we all hate, thanks to an added
complex of calcium amino acids and skin
camides. So, you add the serum first,
then immediately afterwards, you can add
the day cream. It's all about the order,
right? You want to think thinner to
thicker, and that's one of the secrets
to really getting the most out of your
skin care products in your regimen. You
always want to start by applying the
thinner, more lightweight products and
then you follow that with the thicker,
richer, creamier ones. If you apply the
heavier, thicker products first, they
basically act like a barrier. They stop
the lightweight products from
penetrating and doing their job. So for
example using number seven system you
would start with the serum then you
apply the eye cream and then last as
your final step you apply the day cream
or the night cream because that's the
thickest layer you can do yeah you could
do them right after the other you don't
have to wait a period of time a good
serum will absorb very quickly so one
after the other you're perfectly fine so
it can time management issues come up
yeah it takes a few minutes all right so
you brought some real examples of a
volunteer skin these are actually number
seven's restore and renew serum treated
skin examples. And please, if you don't
mind, show us what you've got here cuz
this is remarkable to me. So, what
you're seeing here is you're seeing the
before photo, right? So, you know, you
can imagine why this woman might be a
little self-conscious of the skin on her
neck. It's a little deflated. It's a
little dehydrated. You can really
appreciate that crepey texture. That's
exactly what you sort of see when you
look at this image. But, let's back over
here because now this woman has used the
serum for about 12 months in this
picture. Okay? Every single day for 12
months. And you can see that the skin
looks visibly firmer. There's less of
that crepey texture. You know, even this
deep wrinkle. It was deeper on that
side. Look at how much more shallow or
tighter, more firm it looks here. And
then if you take a step back and just
look at the tone, you know, which we're
talking about there, like the brown
spots, the uneven pigmentation. It's
just a more even skin tone throughout.
Audience, don't you love the fact that
you could feed your skin the nutrients
it needs? I love that you can do it on
your own because it signals that your
skin is a living, breathing organ. I
wanted to see how well number seven is
restore and renew face and neck serum
and the day cream works. So, we gave it
to one of our viewers and you tried it
out for a few weeks. Mara, how are you?
Oh, great. How are you? So, let's go
back before we gave you the products.
Describe what you thought about your
skin. Describe it to us. Um, I I drink a
lot of water and I wore sunblock, but I
only wore sunblock with the tinted
moisturizer and I just felt that my skin
wasn't it was losing elasticity and I
felt like no matter how much water I
drank, my skin was still kind of dry.
And I put on the uh serum and I felt
like it just feels firmer. And I was
getting the crepey and the the little
drippy kind of the turkey neck, but it's
really I see a big difference. It feels
a lot firmer and I just felt that the
cream was amazing because it really it
just my makeup the base makeup. It
layers very very well. You put the serum
on, the cream on and your makeup on and
it's not like things are sliding off
your face. It's actually penetrating
into your skin and doing the job it's
supposed to. Now you made the whole
audience jealous of
you. H how do we find it? Where is it?
What does it cost? So, you can get the
serum and the day cream at Target or
target.com for $60 around $60 for
actually both of those products
together. It's pretty good. But the
thing is, these guys at Number Seven are
very kind. They're trusted sponsorship
partners of the show. What do you think
about the audience? I don't know. You
guys want to try this baby? All right.
Well, thanks to Number Seven. You're all
going home with their Restore new face
and neck multi-action full system. Enjoy
it. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
We're celebrating our 10th season and
we're not turning back. We're looking
forward to our next 10 and yours. All
year long, we're challenging you to
discover your health and life goals for
your next 10. 10 days, 10 weeks, 10
years. What's on your bucket list? Where
do you want your life to go? What dreams
do you want to make a reality? Share
your goals with me at #myx10 and you can
win prizes or even end up right here on
my show.
[Applause]
[Music]
I'm here with crime correspondent
Melissa Moore, who has an incredible new
podcast exploring her relationship with
her father, Keith Jesperson, better
known as the Happy Face serial killer.
Did he pass along genetic traits to
Melissa? Does she have the brain of a
psychopath? We teamed up with the
podcast masters at How Stuff Works to
co-produce this chilling new podcast
called Happy Face. and it drops
today. I'm so impressed, so riveted by
what you've created. Tell everyone about
it. Yeah, I had a lot of questions
about what my father did. And I did go
to see him in prison one time and he
said, "Do you want to know why I
committed these murders?" And I said no.
At the time, I didn't have the courage
to walk down that path. And I finally
had the courage to go on this journey.
And I met with people, not with my
father, but I met with other people that
could give me the true insight and the
answers that I was seeking. And along
the way, I found secrets. I found family
secrets out. I discovered shocking new
truths about my father. And ultimately,
I walked away with the knowledge that I
was seeking. We all have questions in
our lives. I think yours are a little
bigger. The stakes are a little higher.
Right? Take a look. I was a young girl.
I was 11 years old. and my parents had
just divorced. And this was my first
summer vacation with my dad where I
stayed at a different home than my my
childhood home. And the moment I walked
in that house, I felt like I wasn't
alone, that there was energy there, that
there were spirits there in every room.
My first night, I fall asleep a little
bit, but then I'm awakened by being
touched. My hair is touched. So, I leap
and I'm going to go run into my dad's
room, but I
froze. I wasn't going to be safe in my
dad's room. And I didn't feel safe with
my
dad. And so, I laid on the in the
hallway floor, curled up in a ball,
hoping that the night would just go away
fast. In the morning, my dad stepped
over me and he said, "Why did you fall
asleep in the hallway?" And I said, "I
was being touched, Dad." and he said,
"Oh, don't pay any attention to them.
They bother me all the time at night."
Melissa, who is your dad and what is he
known as?
My father is Keith Hunter
Jasperson. He's known as the Happyface
serial killer.
That's intense. Is the journey of
discovery as is as intense as it seems?
Even more so. It was incredibly intense.
and to revisit all of those old memories
in the past, but to walk away with the
revelations that I did was definitely
worth it. I'm proud of you. I wish you
best of success. Keep doing it. Keep
chugging along. Thank you. You can find
Melissa's podcast, Happy Face, available
today on iTunes or wherever you like to
find your podcast. Check it out. Thanks
for watching. We'll see you next time.
[Applause]
[Music]