Fast food pizza, a quick go-to meal, but
are some chains cutting corners where it
counts? Sort of like a biotech cheese
business here. And cold pizza. We love
it, but is it safe to eat? What the USDA
says is a 2-hour rule for any
potentially hazardous food. Plus chicken
flavorings. They recreated a simulated
version.
>> A simulated version. How do they do it?
Now, that tastes like chicken. That's
amazing to me. Coming up next.
Y'all ready for season 10?
>> Yeah.
[Music]
>> I love you, Da.
[Applause]
[Music]
every single second. An average of 350
pizza slices are sold in this country.
Even champion pizza toggers like Nino
Caniglio. Oh my goodness. And then he
couldn't keep up. It's why the
modern-day giants of American pizza keep
finding ways to make this stuff faster,
cheaper, and cheesier. But are they
taking shortcuts? Right? They're cutting
corners that are putting our health in
jeopardy. And how are they able to sell
pizza so cheap anyway? Right? They're
less than five bucks a pie. Well, today
I'll be right back. We are investigating
fast food pizza from America's biggest
pizza chains. Scott Weiner is a
professional pizza enthusiast and he's
not only the foremost expert in pizza,
but he's also the Guinness World Record
holder for owning the most number of
pizza boxes.
Why would you even do that? Is that your
living room? Where is that?
>> Listen, I don't want to talk about the
collection is personal thing for me.
>> Personal thing. All right. So pizza uh
chains have dropped their prices so much
you start to wonder instead of cutting
triangles are they cutting corners?
>> You know, it's a good question because
the independent pizzeras can't compete
on price. They compete on quality. But
the big chains have to figure out how to
get people. So they they do it by buying
tons and tons of cheese, tons of flour,
and tons of sauce. So this way they can
charge way lower prices.
>> Let's investigate some of these
shortcuts. We'll start with the cheese.
Is that okay? That's a great place to
start because 40% of a pizza's food cost
is the cheese. So if you're going to
save money, that's how you do it.
>> So how would it used to be done in New
York? It's the mozzarella town.
>> Absolutely. Mozzarella is the absolute
number one pizza cheese in America, but
there are two different types of
mozzarella. This is kind of confusing.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, cuz you know, like the
normal standard pizza you get is covered
in cheese.
>> Yes, it is.
>> But a pizza margarita has these clumps
of brighter white cheese. That's fresh
mozzarella. And fresh mozzarella is when
you take curd from cow's milk or from
buffalo milk. You cook it down and you
stretch it, but it's a really high
hydration. There's a lot of water in it.
>> So that means that it shelf life is
pretty short.
>> So about 100 years ago, the dairy
industry started working on the shelf
life thing. And that's how we got this
low moisture mozzarella has lower than
52% water content. So that it means that
this cheese will last a lot longer
because it's just got less water in it.
But the issue is when you're using this
type of cheese in a big commercial
setting, you got to take this block of
cheese and you got to shred it down. So,
I mean, try shredding this cheese right
now. This is crazy labor intensive. It
takes forever. Certain stand mixers
started adding in cheese.
>> That's all I got for all that.
>> I honestly expect a little more from
you, doc, but I guess you're not a pizza
doctor. But listen, this type of thing,
we kind of got around this because
rather than shredding it yourself, the
pizza industry, or rather the cheese
industry, started working on
pre-shredded versions of it, which is
good cuz it saves on labor cost, but
it's not so great because if you leave
this stuff to itself, it starts to clump
up. So, they added in all these kind of
anti-caking agents like potato starch,
uh, calcium silicate, all this other
stuff, which prevents the cheese from
clumping up, and that results in more of
a greasy shine on top of your slice. See
all that shiny puddle of oil on top? You
know, this is this is fat from the
cheese. It's not all bad, but yeah, if
you do the blot test, I mean, a lot of
people eat their pizza like this.
>> Oh, no. And this is I thought this was
just fat coming out, but it's because
they have these different products in
there.
>> Some of it's fat coming out, but also
some of it is the residual from all
these anti-caking agents.
>> Look at that, guys.
>> And now your pizza tastes like a napkin.
>> Yes, your pizza tastes like a napkin.
>> I don't want to do that.
>> All right, so that's the first thing
cheeses. I understand now that the
industry got involved in this. All
right, second big issue. the cheesy
chain pizzas. They've got breads. You
often, you know, you get bread, right?
Bread with cheese when it comes with the
pizza. So, it's more bread and cheese
with the bread and cheese that's already
in the pizza.
>> Absolutely. I mean, and cheese is a
great part of a pizza. And it's
definitely the most exciting thing, you
know, like in the commercials, you
always see the chain pizza commercials
with that slice getting and you get the
cheese pull
>> breaking apart like this.
>> And it probably saved the dairy
industry. I bet
>> that it probably did because, you know,
about a year ago since the dairy
industry had this crazy issue with
overpopulation of dairy cheese. Uh the
US government started asking chain
pizzeras and other chain food companies
to start using more cheese. So one of
the big chains increased one of their
products cheese by 25%.
So this means that the dairy industry
might be saved a little bit by this, but
it also means that you're eating all
this extra cheese that you might not
need cuz I don't know about you, but I
think a good pizza is a balanced pizza,
not cheese. It just blows my mind to
think that there first of all that
cheese industry is being bolstered by
the pizza industry, but they would add
25% more. It does take the balance away.
>> It totally takes it away, but you know
what? It makes it look real good. And
cheese has a high perceived value. So
less cheese makes you think it's a
cheaper pizza.
>> All right, the next shortcut, it's a big
one, is the dough.
>> Yeah. I mean, look, dough is probably
the most significant part of a pizza
because all pizzas might not have
cheese, might not have sauce, but they
all have dough. And you only need four
ingredients for dough. water, flour,
yeast, and salt. And some of the
independents don't even use commercial
yeast if they're doing natural
fermentation. So the other end of the
spectrum with the big chains, some of
them are using all these kind of
oxidizers and strengtheners for dough.
And some of them are even not great for
you. Like there's one ingredient that's
in this pile over here, potassium
bromine, and that's an oxidizer. So it's
going to help the dough ferment faster
and trap more gas. But that's actually
on America's list of potential
carcinogens. and most other
>> on America's list.
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. It's a type category 2B
carcinogen. And we're still allowed to
use it, but if you have too much of it
or if you underbake the pizza that has
it, it could be dangerous to you.
>> Do other countries have the same problem
with it?
>> Other countries have a huge problem.
It's not illegal in China. It's not
legal in Canada. It's It's illegal in
most places. It's not banned in the US
yet.
>> Oh my goodness. But there is some good
news. I understand because that chemical
you just mentioned earlier,
>> other changes are happening.
>> Yeah. At least one of the chains is
using a flower that doesn't have any
potassium bromate and their flour is
unbleached. So that's great.
>> Well, so the industry listens. If you
guys if you guys tell people what you
want, they'll actually come along with
it. All right. No one knows this better
than than Jino Kigla, who you saw
earlier spinning around the pizza dough.
10 time world pizza maker. He's a world
champion pizza maker from the Brooklyn
Pizza Crew. So what are the markers of a
good crust? Educate us. A great dough
is, you know, all about the
fermentation. So, you want to have, like
Scott was saying, a long fermentation.
Uh, the best is using like a poolish, a
bea, or wild starter culture. And it's
just going to make for a healthier bread
product. I think a lot of the problem
with the industry is is, you know,
they're not fermenting right, which is
making like stuff that's it's it's going
to fill you up. It's going to, you know
what I mean? Not break down, not digest
easily.
>> It smells so good already. You haven't
even cooked it yet.
>> Yeah, it's amazing. And it's, you know,
chalk full of uh probiotics, great
tomato sauce. Pizza simple. That's why
Italian food's so popular. It's just
simple stuff.
Go.
>> And the secret to making a world class
is is just a couple ingredients done
right or is anything else special.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's it. Like as long as
the most important thing is fermenting
the dough uh properly and using that
because that's what's going to give you
a healthy really healthy pizza. I mean,
>> is this arugula? This is basil. Get that
basil on there.
>> Oh, I like that.
>> You're going I like green stuff. I like
the green stuff.
>> So,
>> all right. Now, we actually cooked this
one ahead of time. Go ahead and pull it
out. Who wants to taste a little pizza?
World class pizza.
>> All right. Let's just cut it up. Cut it
small. They believe me. They'll cut
they'll they'll eat your fingers off.
>> You You'll lose a couple here. We need
you to make more. How many pizzas you
make a day?
>> Uh about like two 300 a day.
>> Two 300. All right.
As we feed the audience up the next cold
pizza. Yeah. You like cold pizza,
everybody?
>> What is What gives? How's that possible?
Everyone loves cold pizza. Is it a
health gamble or is it good to go? If
you've ever eaten leftover pie for
breakfast, you will not want to miss
this. I hope you like it. You're going
to find out. Stick around.
Good.
>> The Atlanta child murders.
>> Most of the people did not believe that
Wayne was the killer. A victim's brother
reveals
>> I got this big secret. You know
>> what some won't believe.
>> I was there. I saw this guy. I looked
him in his eyes.
>> Plus, actor singer Donnie Wahlberg talks
true crime and shares chilling details
about Charles Manson.
>> He almost got a record deal. He didn't.
And that's one of the things that set
him off on his murder spree.
>> All new Oas. That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
Ew. What are you doing?
>> Oh,
why are you filming me? Sometimes my
cheat dinner turns into my cheat
breakfast.
It's good. Pizza's good. I love pizza.
What are you doing?
What are you doing? Who eats pizza this
early in the morning?
>> Yo, who cares? My body. I do what I
want.
>> So unhealthy, bro.
So,
>> I can eat it whenever I want. Night
time, daytime, I don't care.
>> Nah, bro.
>> So gross.
>> Your own thing.
>> I love it. What are you doing? I get
that from my kids. So, some call it the
breakfast of champions and others call
it a ripe harvesting ground for
bacteria. So, what's the deal with cold
pizza? Is it safe to eat? And what's the
real reason it tastes so good to some
people, especially the next day?
Professional pizza enthusiast Scott
Weiner is back and he looked into the
science behind why the taste of pizza
can improve as it gets cold. So, what's
the deal? Why are people so obsessed
with cold pizza? Well, there's a couple
reasons. First of all, you know, you
have all these active aromatics like
garlic and onions and herbs and all
that. And you know how it is when you
make something fresh and something still
warm, those flavors all stand out pretty
independent from each other. But if you
give them time to meld, you know, like
day old lasagna tastes really good. So
good,
>> right? That's because those flavors tend
to mellow out and then they combine so
you get a little bit of a more mellowed
and mesh of a flavor. It's a little bit
more rich. But then we can't ignore the
fact that of course fat is flavor.
>> Yes.
>> And fat and water separate. So the oil,
the fat from this pizza all rises to the
top as it cools off. So when you take a
bite, you're actually going to get the
fat right on the roof of your mouth. So
you get that flavor first.
>> All right. So this explains why the cold
pizza tastes so good. But is it safe to
eat? My medical staff went inside our
pizza lab testing and experimenting with
how to store leftover pizza. They
chilled one pie in the fridge overnight
and the other one, well, we left it on
the counter, right? That happens
sometimes at home, too. Now, you can't
see them with the naked eye, but these
could be harboring some harmful
bacteria. To find out, I asked German
specialist Peter Deluchia to join us.
So, let's start off with the pizza we
put in the fridge last night. Last
night, pizza in the fridge last night
like it's supposed to be theoretically.
Is it safe to eat cold today? I love
cold pizza, so I'm not going to ruin it
for anybody. It is good to eat today. If
it's in the refrigerator, 40 degrees,
it's good for four days. So, here's the
reality, though. So many of us, we leave
the pizza on the counter overnight.
Doesn't make its way to the fridge,
right? Does that make sense if it's been
on the counter to eat? Well, you know,
you forget about it. You leave it out
there overnight. What the USDA says is a
2-hour rule for any potentially
hazardous food, and pizza is one of
them. Has to be put under refrigeration
at 40 degrees within two hours.
>> No one does that.
>> Well, I'll give you the big butt on this
one. So, I'm going to say, you know, but
in this case, first of all, health
department, we're not getting big pizza
complaints. We're not getting big pizza
outbreaks. It's not happening. We're not
getting those calls. Maybe we'll get a
call that someone finds a hair or
something else in their pizza that they
don't want, but it's not happening. So,
what I'm going to say is that it's, you
know, it's a it's a safe it's it's,
let's say, a semisafe thing to do. And
this is why. It's because of water
activity. Water activity is the big
issue. What do germs need to grow? They
need a good pH and water activity. And
when you're looking at baked bread,
baked cheese, add the acidity of a sauce
on there. It's really not the
environment where germs want to grow.
So, it makes that regular plain pie. I'm
going to say, you know what? Roll the
dice. Eat it in the morning. Odds are
you're going to be fine.
>> I was going to do it anyway, but so is
the entire audience. But let let's let's
you know let's go on to the next thing
is let's have toppings. People like to
have all these exotic pizzas and
toppings. You start adding chicken and
broccoli and fresh tomatoes and all
these different things. Now you're
making a much more potentially hazardous
pie. Don't forget to put that one in the
refrigerator or if you leave it out
overnight, you know, I say when in
doubt, throw it out.
>> So generally good news from the health
department.
>> Generally I try I don't want to make I
don't want I want to keep pizza good. I
love pizza.
>> All right. Here's the challenge though.
Does it still taste good? What's the
best way to store leftover pizza if you
can put it in the fridge? World champion
pizza maker Neo Kadigio is back in our
pizza lab to test two methods. Two
methods, everybody. Science meets
savory. So, do you like cold pizza, by
the way?
>> Yeah, cold pizza's all right once in a
while. I prefer the room temperature to
be honest with you.
>> Room temperature is okay.
>> Yeah, room temperature is nice. Out of
the oven, a little cool down. You know
what I'm saying?
>> All right, so we're going to explain how
you and my medical unit tested storage
methods. This is the stack and rack
technique or the other version, but
there they are very diligently doing it.
I just take a darn box, put the pizzas
inside of it, right? Throw it in the
fridge. This is what a lot of folks do.
Yeah, I would once again I wouldn't
recommend this. The oxygen's going to
get there. Your uh product's going to
become very hard. All right. It's not
going to be enjoyable the next day, but
you know, sometimes uh we don't feel
like wrapping stuff. So, we're all
guilty of it. But the stacking wrap is
definitely the way to go.
>> You think? Well, I'm going to put it to
the test cuz I've got our our bike club
here. They're tasting me coming over
here. you know, reheated the pizza that
we stored straight in the box and he
heated the pizza that was wrapped,
stacked and wrapped rather. Right. We're
gonna see if you guys can taste the
difference. So, Menel, you want to go
first?
>> Yeah. Okay. So, I definitely want to say
that this one was a little bit drier
than this one. I could definitely tell a
little bit of a difference. Not a huge,
but definitely the cheese in this one
just tasted richer and it just tasted
like if it was fresh instead of just
microwaved right away.
>> Were you happy with the red plate? Very
happy with this one. I'd rather choose
this one than that one.
>> Amanda.
>> Yeah, I agree. This one was definitely
more crumbly. This one tasted a lot
fresher, more It was moistister.
>> So, you're a red plate person, too.
>> Yeah.
>> And guess what? The red plate was the
wrap, the sacked wrap. It actually seems
to pay off. But here's the thing. I
didn't know till just before this show.
>> How do you actually reheat pizza? How
many of you microwave your pizza? Oh,
>> bad, bad mistake.
>> Real bad.
>> Real bad. Right. What's the way to do
it? Is it putting it in the oven?
>> Putting it in the oven is a good way to
do it, but what we really prefer, what
most pizza guys prefer to do is to get
it in a hot pan. All right. I like to
put a top over it and just fry it up a
little bit. It takes about like one or
two minutes.
>> All the pizza guys are doing that. And
you know, no one ever told us. The
secret is out. Guys, thanks for joining.
Be right back.
[Music]
>> Love your chips and dip? We have a guac
shock. If you're buying pre-made from
the store, how do the companies get away
with that? You may be getting more in
your supermarket salsa than you think.
All new Oas. That's coming up on
Wednesday.
[Music]
[Applause]
We've been investigating some of your
favorite weekn night meals. Now, the
crowd-pleasing side dishes that know you
all love because they save you time,
money, and they taste so darn good. Rice
and couscous and pasta with, of course,
chicken flavor. But did you ever stop
and wonder, is there any real chicken in
there at all? And what exactly does
chicken flavor really mean? Well, Mark
Shasker wrote a book called The Dorito
Effect, which remains one of the most
surprising windows into how the food
industry develops flavors in a lab that
keeps us wanting more. So, how what do
we know about how they actually make
these fake copies taste even better than
the real thing?
>> Yeah. So, when I was researching the
Dorito effect, I contacted a flavor
company and they told me the whole
story. They had just released a new line
of chicken flavors. And the way they
made this is they got a whole bunch of
super high-end chefs in Europe to get
the best pastured chickens they could
find and make the most wonderful chicken
broth they could find. And then they
took those broths and they chemically
analyzed them. They figured out what are
the flavor compounds in that broth. Then
they recreated a simulated version. So
here's what happened. Mark hit the road
to get some answers. He visited a
chicken farm and he asked, "Why doesn't
chicken taste like it used to?" Isn't
that your all your question? What
happened to our chicken? Take a look.
Chicken these days doesn't taste the way
it used to. Question is why? What
happened to chicken? Why does it taste
so bland?
>> To find out, I headed to a 200 acre farm
in Indiana run by my friend Pete
Echelman.
>> How you doing?
>> Good to see you.
>> Yeah, great.
>> Okay, Pete, tell me, why doesn't chicken
taste the way it used to? When I buy
chicken, it is the blandest meat. It
tastes like wet paper towel. What What's
going on?
>> Simply chickens are not raised like
this. They're out uh all natural on
grass eating bugs. They're harvested
around 14 16 weeks versus 6 weeks.
That's the difference.
>> So you're you're saying the fact that
these chickens live outside on pasture
eating this stuff and they grow more
slowly that makes them taste better.
>> Absolutely.
>> So if most chickens today don't live on
farms like Pete's where do they live? I
set off to find a modern-day chicken
farm. There's one, but it looks more
like a factory than it does a farm. And
something tells me it's not open for
tours. Inside, there may be as many as
25,000 birds. And they spend their
entire lives not doing much of anything
other than eating. But just what are
they eating? To find out, I'm going to
check out this local feed store. Tell
me, what's in modern-day chicken feed?
Basically, you add corn for your
calories here, soybean meal for protein,
and then the vitamins and trace mineral
mix.
>> So, would you say then that this food is
designed to make chickens grow big and
fast?
>> Basically, the the diet is always
designed, I would say, for chickens to
grow faster.
>> You've heard the expression, you are
what you eat. What about chickens? Well,
there's some debate on this, but certain
scientific studies show that the flavor
of chicken is influenced by what
chickens eat. And if chickens grow up
never eating bugs or grass and only ever
eating bland feed made from corn and
soybeans, that's how the chickens taste.
Bland.
I had one more stop to make to find out
why chicken these days tastes so boring.
>> Greg.
>> Hi, Mark.
>> Greg Gunthorp runs a chicken processing
plant that supplies some of Chicago's
best chefs.
>> So, Greg, if I think chicken tastes like
tap water, it's not my imagination.
>> It's not your imagination at all. Most
commercial chicken is soaked in bleach
water for about 90 minutes in a large
automated chiller.
>> And how does that affect the flavor?
>> Washes out a lot of the flavor. To
maintain flavor, Greg avoids water.
Instead, he air chills his chickens
inside this refrigerator.
>> These chickens when they cool like this
in a fridge, they taste better. They
taste less watery, I'm guessing.
>> Yeah. They're, you know, the you can
wash some of the flavor out by chilling
them in water. It would be like taking a
ham sandwich and dunking it in water.
>> Right. Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> All this talk of bland chicken was
making me hungry for the real thing. So,
I decided to go back to Pete's Farm to
see what a slow growing, pasture-raised,
air chilled chicken actually tastes
like.
>> This is the moment of truth to try my
chicken.
[Music]
Oh my god, it actually tastes like
chicken.
>> Here's what I take away from that.
Instead of using real chickens to give
us chicken flavor, the food industry has
turned to science. So, here's how
chicken flavor is often made. I just
take what Mark taught me and put it in
some pictures for you. First off, they
don't start with chickens. So, get rid
of the chickens. There's no chickens in
this thing. Instead, they start with
boiling soybean meal. Soybean meal,
right? They do this in large vats of
hydrochloric acid and they leave it in
there for about six hours. It's
basically a chemistry lab that that
wrenches apart the protein molecules and
turns them into amino acids, things that
Mark was talking about. Corn syrup can
then be added to the mix for an even
more intense browning flavor. Then the
solution is neutralized with sodium
hydroxide. Why am I telling you all
that? Because sodium hydroxide, sodium
salt, right? It leaves the product with
an abundance of salt and then it tastes
like chicken when they're done. Go
figure. But it's never ever had a
feather and it definitely never lived on
Old McDonald's farm. I just want you to
be clear on that. But now first, I mean
a bunch of questions come to mind, Mark,
but first, how did anyone ever discover
this? Who who have put the pieces
together and thought they could make
something chemical that tasted like
chicken?
>> Well, like I said, you know, they've got
very sophisticated equipment. They can
analyze the the chem the flavor
chemicals in actual chicken. They don't
bother with the nutrition. It's not
about the protein. It's not about the
vitamins. It's just about the flavor.
And they recreate that.
>> Are you worried about these flavorings?
Do you think they're dangerous at all?
>> So, a lot of people ask me, are these
toxic? Are they going to give me cancer?
That's always the big worry. Is it going
to give me cancer? I don't think that's
a danger here. What is the danger is
that this is the stuff that makes food
delicious and it keeps us going back and
back and back. And let's face it, our
big problem when it comes to food is
eating too much. I would say if you're
looking for flavor, go to nature. Use
herbs, use spices, use parmesan cheese.
Nature does not have a flavor problem.
The processed food industry does. On
that note, if you want savory,
mouthwatering tastes of boxes without
all the added chemicals, got good news
for you. Up next, it's the three tricks
to naturally flavor your favorite
grains. And guess what? You have them
all in your fridge this very second.
Stay with us.
[Music]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever you
get your podcast.
[Applause]
Are you obsessed with the taste of box
side dishes but don't want all the added
chemicals and the salt? Well, there's
good news today cuz Chef Dicky Dinky is
breaking all the flavor rules down to
revealing three all naturatural tricks
for tastier side dishes that are going
to blow your mind. All right, so we're
going to put Nikki's new side dish
solutions to the test. To do that, we
assembled a team of crack tasters who
are obsessed with the box stuff. They're
going to give us their honest opinions
on how naturally flavored sides stack
up. Are you ready to do that?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Here goes. First up, we're
going to add salsa to your water. And
then you're going to boil the food in
there.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I'm going to boil my
rice in a mixture of half salsa, half
water. And what this is going to do Oh,
feel free. Um, what this is going to do
is it's going to put that salsa flavor
directly into our rice and give it great
color. So, if you're making rice for say
a big Mexican feast, you've got some
tacos, this is a great side dish.
>> All right, Kayan, you've been tasting
this whole time. Please compare this to
the usual box product you eat.
>> Wow. This is fresh and flavorful. It's
definitely not as overpowering and salty
like the box stuff.
>> It's really great.
>> That's a winner.
>> It's great. We love salsa. Put that in
our buns. I didn't think you could boil
the sauce. I thought you'd mess it up.
>> No. People are so afraid of messing
things up. Sometimes we don't take
chances. And that's one that you want to
take.
>> All right. Next up, we're going to
replace the butter or your oil with
schmaltz cubes.
>> Yeah,
>> schmaltz. It's a word. I looked it up.
What does schmaltz mean?
>> So schmaltz is just chicken fat. So
anytime that I cook up, say chicken
thighs or skin on chicken breast, that
fat that renders into the pan, I save it
just like you see here. And then I just
scoop it into an ice cube tray. And you
can see it's got all that great gelatin.
And what this does is it adds intense
chicken flavor to your dish. And it's
one of those things that you would have
otherwise thrown away. So it's free and
we're going to have it on hand because
we're freezing it.
>> I think it's brilliant. I used to always
get upset throwing this away. No more.
So
>> once you freeze it, it looks like this.
>> You pop it open.
>> Yeah.
>> Like that. And you take these little
babies.
>> Put it right in your finished couscous
or whatever kind of grain you have
instead of say a pad of butter. And that
chicken flavor will perfume the dish and
it just adds this lusciousness, this
richness. You can smell it. It's great.
>> She perfumes it. I love it.
>> Perfumes it. Who doesn't want chicken
perfume?
>> I want So Maria, would you perfume with
schmaltz your couscous?
>> Absolutely. Well, Dr. Oz, admittedly, I
am a horrible cook. And when I use
anything, it's very bland and it's very
dry, but this was very flavorful. It was
very rich and creamy. So, I certainly do
have an appreciation.
>> It's mana from heaven. Yeah,
>> I like it.
>> Finally, we're going to cook your grains
in orange juice. Now, the first two I
sort of got. I This thing seemed crazy.
>> Uh, it's a little crazy, but crazy in a
great way. So, we are simply replacing
your boiling water with orange juice. In
this case, we did some uh quinoa. It's
got a little sesame oil, a little
scallions. Not many ingredients here,
but because the grain is so flavorful,
the whole dish just sings. Not many
greens, but the name, think about this,
orange juice infused quinoa with some
sesame oil.
>> Some adjectives, please. Princess,
>> it was definitely tangy, very tasteful,
savory. I really enjoyed it.
>> I like the ginger. It's my favorite.
>> Yeah, a little bit of spice.
>> All right, I want to thank Chef Nikki
Dinky. Her book is called The Meat.
Actually, just meat on the side.
>> Just meat on the side. You can all at
dr.com. I'll be right back.
[Applause]
Love your chips and dip. We have a guac
shock. If you're buying pre-made from
the store, how do companies get away
with selling guacamole doesn't have real
avocados in it?
>> And you may be getting more in your
supermarket salsa than you think.
>> Sugar, sugar, sugar. Oh gosh.
>> All new OS. That's coming up on
Wednesday.
[Music]
[Applause]
For those of you in pain, I get it.
You're desperate for fast relief to an
aching back or sore muscles.
Over-the-counter pain relieving creams
and lotions may seem like a safer choice
than taking a pill. But can those
numbing ointments that you're using be
addicting? Today we investigate pain
relief cream confessions. Can you be
overusing these over-the-counter
solutions or worse overdose on pain
relieving creams?
I keep my pain relief cream with me
every day all day. I keep one in my
purse. I keep one in my car. I even keep
one at my desk at work. It's essential
that I have my pain relief cream with me
every day for my chronic back pain. I
need my pain relief cream. I use it so
much even my husband tries to hide it
from me. I rely on pain relief cream.
It's my security blanket to get through
the day.
>> I love my pain relief cream. I use it
every day, even more than normal lotion.
[Music]
Pain specialist and anesthesiologist Dr.
Gupta is here to help investigate pain
cream addiction. What kinds of pain
relief creams are people using,
overusing, maybe even getting addicted
to?
>> Dr. Oz, there are so many pain creams at
the pharmacy right now. And this is the
issue. People find them very easily.
There are tubes, there's gels, and there
patches, and people want to take them
right now. They don't want to take
pills. Um, they're fast, they're easy,
and you can get them without a
prescription. And they think they're
safe. And that's why we're here today to
talk about them.
>> All right. So, let's talk about what's
specifically in them that might be
addictive.
>> That's right. That's right. So, there's
many ingredients. Menthol is one of the
most common that you'll hear about and
that gives you the cool sensation that
you when you apply on you feel good
about that. Also, camper oil, very
traditional type of medication that
you'll find in many countries. Uh, it's
an essential oil. Eucalyptus from a
tree. Uh, and also menthol salicellate.
Now, that is one that we have to be
concerned about. When you use a lot of
it, that's when we can run into trouble
and it can actually be toxic,
>> right? So, what's the amount that you're
supposed to use? How do you know when
you're using it more often than you're
supposed to? Give me some of the the
rational guidelines from from an expert.
>> And that's and that's what we really
need to be worried about. Um, you know,
look, as a doctor, a pain doctor, we
really have to be concerned here. Three
to four times a day, no more than seven
days.
>> Right. So I I'm interested. You say
three to four times a day for a week and
after that you got to talk to somebody.
>> That's right.
>> Let's go talk to Kimberly. She's going
to be one of our audience member. She
uses a cream five times a day.
>> Hello.
>> Thanks for being here. And five times a
day, which is I didn't think was an
unusual amount. And when I hurt myself,
that's probably what I would probably
do. Explain how you first learned about
these creams and how you've built up to
five times a day.
>> About seven years ago, I ran my first
half marathon. Um I noticed my knee
started hurting during the race, so I
stopped at the medical tent. It was the
first time um they lthered me up and I
continued the race and after that it
just became
every day I started using it so I could
run and and I got into CrossFit and
that's
>> this is exactly what I often hear. It
starts with once or twice you get
introduced to it and it does sound like
other types of addictions. You slowly
building up more and more and more. So
Dr. Gupta, what's actually happening?
>> Look what she's experienc Kimberly's
experience is the common thing that I
hear in my office. The most important
thing here is that we have to remember
drugs are drugs. You have to remember
that if you use too much of it, you're
going to run into trouble and harm can
happen. And we're going to talk about
that.
>> More is not better. Even though this is
America, there's a rational amount.
Here's a picture of a burn that could
happen after using too much of these
creams. That's actually what happened to
this patient.
>> And there was one case, Dr. of an
overdose in a teen who used too much of
a pain relieving cream. Mhm.
>> I I don't know how much they were using,
but they had a pretty benign problem,
but it ended up becoming
>> a lethal complication.
>> Right.
>> Let's come on over, Elizabeth. Have a
seat in that chair because I've got a
surprise for you in a second. Dr. going
to show you why that the heating pad is
such an issue here. I never thought
heating pads and creams would ever
interact with each other. Never crossed
my mind. I thought you're supposed to
use them together.
>> That's right.
>> Your skin, this is what it represents,
right? Has little pores in there. And
when you add a pain relieving cream, in
theory, these little pellets of pain
relief go through the hole and you're
good to go. When you put a heating pad
on your skin, what happens to the pores?
>> So, the pores get bigger. And this is
the problem.
>> So, as the pores get bigger, now let's
both add a handful of cream, right? And
as we do that, you'll notice mine don't
all go in. They're sort of sitting on
the surface, whereas yours are falling
in there pretty readily. In fact, hers
is so big, I could probably just pour
this straight in there, right? And if
you look at the amount that's actually
getting into the skin, it's dramatically
different. You're you're absorbing the
active ingredient at a different rate.
And that can result in symptoms which
lead to confusion, vomiting, headache,
you know, nausea, complications that you
never could think could be associated
with a pain relief cream.
>> That's right.
>> So instead of using a heating pad plus a
cream or but if you are going to do
this, this is not irrational. How often
would you do it?
>> Look, you have to be careful. uh heating
pads have the risks that we just talked
about, but very cautiously and talk to
your doctor. I mean, I would tell my
patients to avoid combining these type
of treatments together and people still
do it, but talk to your doctor if you're
going to do all these things together at
once.
>> All right, let's talk about something
simple like knee pain. Let's say you
have knee pain because you're trying to
do the right thing for your body.
>> That's right. That's right.
>> Kimberly wants to put the cream on
there, but since you're a pain
specialist, teach us what else might be
causing the pain. Let's deal with the
root issue, not cover up, paint over the
cracks in the foundation of our health.
There are things that you can do at
home. So, one thing you can do is have
an upright back in a chair, cross your
legs over your knee. Um, what I can do,
take your leg, and what I'm going to
have you do is place this knee actually
right here and this. And I'm going to
have you straighten this leg and then
lean forward. And then I'm going to have
you put your hands over this knee right
here. Both hands like this. And now I
want you to lean towards this hand. Lean
and actually cross your back. And do you
feel that stretch in your back?
>> Very much. And so you're going to feel
it in your back and in your hamstring
and in something called a purformis. And
this muscle, if you do alternating
repetitions, actually can actually
stretch most multiple muscles, not only
your back, but your hamstrings and your
knee. And this is an exercise that I'll
recommend to my patients very frequently
just in the office, whether you're an
athlete, whether you're someone that has
back pain or knee pain, very effective.
>> It's a much more holistic approach. I
hope that's helpful to you. Keep
running. Absolutely. All right, we'll be
right back.
The Atlanta child murders.
>> Most of the people did not believe that
Wayne was the killer.
>> A victim's brother reveals what some
won't believe.
>> I was there. I saw this guy.
>> Plus, actor singer Donnie Wahlberg
shares chilling details about Charles
Manson.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
One thing I loved about visiting China
with my trusted sponsorship partner,
USANA Health Sciences, was the ability
to explore how traditional Chinese
medicine and conventional western
medicine work together. They each have
so much to offer. But how do you decide
when to incorporate an ancient practice
into your life today? We'll take a look.
Beijing is fast-paced and fast growing.
A city that radiates hope and
prosperity.
The best part, the people. Wherever we
went, we were greeted with tremendous
enthusiasm.
Another joy of this journey, the food. I
sampled exotic snacks by day, and on my
first night, an extraordinary classic,
Peeking Duck.
The next day, a stiff neck I developed
during the flight was getting worse. But
I was in China, where the approach to
medicine often blends the latest and
high-tech without casting off what's
worked over time. I was game to give the
age-old methods a try. At the Dau
Traditional Chinese Medicine Clinic,
some of the practices date back
thousands of years, but are they still
relevant?
>> Chinese medical doctors are very
important in China. Currently, we are
confronting a lot of challenges such as
drugresistant viruses and chronic
diseases. Therefore, we value
traditional Chinese medicine even more.
>> How does traditional Chinese medicine
differ from Western medicine?
>> The biggest difference between
traditional Chinese medicine and Western
medicine is their different worldviews.
One way to look at it is that
traditional Chinese medicine takes a
holistic approach to health centering on
balance and energy flow orqi while
western medicine focuses on curing
disease. And if you have a patient, how
do how do you decide if they should get
traditional Chinese medicine or if they
should get western medicine?
>> The difference between them is that
western medicine is more suitable for
certain diseases.
>> For example, pneumonia.
Administering antibiotics can result in
a speedy recovery.
>> Other complicated chronic diseases may
require treatment using traditional
Chinese medicine.
One of the most fascinating aspects of
traditional Chinese medicine is the use
of herbs. I watched what is essentially
a traditional Chinese medicine
pharmacist prepare a prescription.
I mean, look at this. There's so many
herbs here. They're all so different.
How many herbs are there in traditional
Chinese medicine?
>> There are more than 10,000 of them.
There are about 450 that are commonly
used. And what's the most common
solution? What problem do you solve?
>> Some of the common ones are used to
treat colds.
>> It was time for me to be the patient.
So, I'm with Dr. Pong. He's helping me
with this neck pain I've had since
flying to China.
>> Dr. Pong will use moxabustion where an
herb is burned over certain areas of the
body to facilitate healing.
>> It's warmer than a heating pad would be
and more intense. Dr. Can you explain
what you're doing?
>> Well, in traditional Chinese medicine,
the pain point is called ashra.
Through the stimulation of that point,
we can promote the relaxation of the
muscles and the pain will dissipate.
has a powerful smell. Oo,
it's like a an incense. What What does
it smell from? Oh my goodness. You're
getting it.
>> This is mugwart leaf.
>> The session lasted about 11 minutes.
>> Does it still hurt?
>> It's amazing. I mean, it has been
non-stop aching for 3 days. I mean, it
doesn't hurt at all.
That's remarkable.
Who would have thought?
[Music]
I have witnessed in China a unique blend
of ancient and modern and a people open
to both who do their homework and hold
on to what works, learning from the past
to help shape the future. I know that
USANA Health Sciences Chief Science
Officer Dr. Robert Senate also shares in
this belief. What kinds of ideas has
USANA adopted from past eastern
philosophies?
>> Well, we've adopted a very holistic uh
approach towards health which comes from
Eastern medicine. But holistic means
that we pay attention to the body, the
spirit, the whole the whole person
rather than just organs and cells within
their body.
>> We're not just a bunch of molecules.
We're actually connected in ways that
are special, unique.
>> Exactly. In ways we don't even
understand yet. So scientists often
infuse eastern knowledge into modern
supplements that are being created
today. It's happening all over the
place, but it's especially evident when
we try to take care of ourselves. So Dr.
Sen, walk us through some of the the
traditional ingredients that you that
you're seeing out there, especially the
ones that USANA is starting to use in
his supplements.
>> Okay, so we actually share quite a few
ingredients in common with traditional
Chinese medicine. We use certain
mushrooms such as rayi and shiakei. uh
they've got polysaccharides that
stimulate the immune system and help
your body uh fight against um things
that are invaders. We also use a form of
baker's yeast called beta glucan. So
it's the cell walls from the baker's
yeast that stimulates the immune system
and keeps it modulated. And then we also
use the mineral zinc quite a bit because
zinc is a micronutrient that your body
needs actually increased amounts when
you're under stress and when you're
exposed to things that you shouldn't be
exposed to. It's remarkable to me that
traditional Chinese medicine figured a
lot of this stuff out thousand plus
years ago. I mean, imagine walking
through the forest and seeing this.
Look, it looks like a piece of art.
>> Yeah.
>> You just come in close on these. Look
how pretty those are. Then understanding
exactly how these might work. I'm
stunned. For example, the baker's yeast.
It makes sense, right? If you showed me
the wall of a bacteria that could have
been invading me, of course, I'm going
to think it's a bad thing that I want to
knock out. So since there's no bacteria
there, I just get my my tentacles go up
to watch out for problems, but I don't
actually overreact.
>> Exactly. You got it exactly right.
>> So how did you kind of take all these
ingredients and put them package them
into one product?
>> Well, the prlucamune is really a
compilation of all those particular
ingredients from traditional Chinese
medicine. So we've got the the rayi, the
shiakei, the beta glucan, and then we've
also got zinc in there. So it's all
formulated together at the appropriate
effective amounts. It's been clinically
studied. We've shown that it not only uh
improves the immune system function but
also uh improves a measure called
protectiveqi which is uh it's a TCM
measure of protective immunity. Well,
thanks to my trust sponsorship partner
Esana Health Sciences. You can go to
dr.com right now to enter for a chance
to win one of a thousand bottles of
USANA's PU commune. And for the entire
studio audience, you're all winners too.
You're not taking individual marshals.
You're going to get home USA commune.
Enjoy it. We'll be right back. Stay
healthy everyone.
[Music]
[Applause]
Doctors are notoriously known for having
bad handwriting. So, I wanted to look a
little deeper into this theory and to
see if there's really a science behind
how we write and what it could possibly
mean about our personality. So, I asked
handwriting expert Michael Hernandez to
analyze my handwriting to see what it
says about me and what it says about
doctors. How are you?
>> It's pleasure to meet you. Doing well,
thank you. But
>> just before I get started, why do
doctors seem to have bad handwriting?
>> Well, quite frankly, uh doctors have a
lot of things on their minds. They
process information very quickly and as
a motor skill, their hands just can't
keep up with how quick their brains are
functioning. So, it's a great thing.
>> Maybe it's a good excuse.
>> Used to bother me before I became a
doctor. Now, I can't read my own
handwriting. All right. So, what should
I write here?
>> You can write uh whatever you had for
breakfast this morning. Yeah. Uh, so
I'll say for breakfast
I had
yogurt and
berries.
>> Okay.
>> Excellent.
>> Now, first and foremost, from looking at
your handwriting, I'm going to say that
you're a very good listener. You're
actually you not only like to talk, but
you're a very good listener. And more
importantly, you are very good at
keeping secrets. But more importantly,
what we do find with with you also is
that you process information very
quickly, which is a great trait. Uh what
I would probably say, you know, is
you're not someone who beats around the
bush. You're very direct. You're to the
point, and more importantly, uh I would
say that you're very open-minded as
well, and you're very ambidextrous.
You're dexterity.
>> I'm going to take you home with me.
>> All right, good enough.
>> And you know about ambidextrous,
surgeons have to be ambidextrous because
you have to be able to operate from both
sides of the body,
>> right? This is remarkable just from
handwriting.
>> Well, I'm not telling you anything that
anyone who doesn't know you well
wouldn't tell you.
>> All right, we're going to put more on
dr.com. Together, change is happening.
Our journey is just beginning.
[Music]