Warning signs that can go unnoticed. I
was undiagnosed for 22 years. Symptoms
that can mimic other illnesses. Had
severe neck pain in the back of my neck.
How do you know if you are at risk for
thyroid cancer? It sneaks up on you,
which is one of the reasons we miss it.
Plus, Shark Tanks Damon John reveals his
own battle with the disease. The fact
that to save one life, isn't that what
I've been given this public stage for?
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you back.
[Music]
[Applause]
If you're feeling tired, you have
trouble losing weight, or you spot hair
in the drain like looks like this in the
shower, right? That could be an issue
with your thyroid. But is it a sluggish
thyroid or could it be thyroid cancer?
It's an important question since thyroid
cancer rates have tripled over the last
three decades and three out of four
cases are found in women. So today, we
are arming you with the red flags to
look for so you can tell the difference.
Joining us now, a man who turned his
survival story into a mission to save
lives. Please welcome my dear friend,
the shark with the biggest bite. Damon
[Applause]
John, my man, my
favorite having you here. How you doing?
Well, before we get too far into this,
you obviously David's going to talk a
little bit about his thyroid cancer,
stage two thyroid cancer. How you
feeling now? I am feeling great. I am uh
um cancer free. I'm in remission. Yeah.
Um I but but you know, it's a process. I
I still have to check on it and I still
have to stay on top of it and make sure
that it doesn't come back. I've been in
one year in remission, but you know,
it's a it's a I got to keep educating
myself on how to improve. Do you ever
wake up in the middle of the night,
stare at the ceiling, and think, "What
if I hadn't figured it out? What if it
wasn't caught in time? Yeah, I have. I
have thought about that. I I I you know,
at one point we felt that it may have
been moving up to my lymph nodes. Um and
I think about all the work that I've
done all my life. You know, as an
entrepreneur, I never took care of
myself, right? We took care of everybody
else, right? Family and the employees
and everything else. And why didn't I
take care of myself? Uh I just didn't
know that you could be ahead of the game
and try to get early detection. I always
thought let me stick my head in the sand
and hopefully that invisible bust
doesn't hit me like it has hit such
people like our dear friend uh big an
yes big an good example. Yeah. So so you
just using investment technology because
you know you're a businessman. Yeah. You
argue that the biggest investment we
need to make is to invest in ourselves
in our health. Absolutely. Yeah. You
know first of all from uh you know from
one standpoint if you're healthy then
you can be more productive. All right.
And then you know uh mentally also think
about that you know the the old saying
is a person with their health has a
thousand dreams a person without only
has one. And when you see us on Shark
Tank we don't talk about health. We
don't talk about uh you know we'll go
out and learn everything how to increase
sales and reduce cost and what's new
technology but we won't say something
doesn't feel right. How do I check into
it? And maybe a doctor or somebody is
not you know one point they can't
diagnose it immediately. We go oh that's
okay. I don't say that in my business.
You tell me it can't work, I don't go,
that's okay. So why don't we do the same
thing with our health? You know, I I
never heard actually that a person with
their health has a thousand dreams and a
person without their health only has
one. Yeah. I think that's true for any
of us who've been ill, right? The day
you get sick, you got one thing that you
got to aim for. Everything else falls
away. Absolutely. And that's what we're
doing today. We're going to help you all
invest in your health because I got the
best investor out there to make it
happen because knowing what to look for
can make all the difference. So I want
you to meet two more thyroid cancer
survivors. Come on over here. Everyone
is in remission. Dope. Congratulations.
I'll high five on that. Congratulations.
How you doing? Could you start with you?
By the way, I can't help notice. Is this
Is that a tattoo? It's real. Yes, it is.
It's a beautiful butterfly. It's a
beautiful butter. Why a butterfly? Well,
having a hidden c cancer for so many
years. Um, it represents the shape of
the thyroid gland. And so, we butterfly
warriors have the thyroid ribbon color
of aqua, pink, and purple. And I
designed it after a Peruvian butterfly.
And it flattened the koid while covering
the scar. Yes. So there's multiple
benefits. That's correct. Plus
emblematic of your survival. That's
true. Now Nicole here is a big time
Shark Tank fan. All right. So I know
that you got a little message here for
Damon as well. Oh, I do. I'm glad to
meet well both of you in person but um I
appreciate that you are open about not
only you know before you were diagnosed
um not maybe putting your health as a
priority. It's great that you're
bringing awareness to you know that this
is sort of a lifelong thing once we have
you know once we're in remission we're
still monitoring ourselves and it's sort
of the dayto-day um battle to thrive you
know. Come on, give me a hug.
Feel good to hear that? It does. It
does. You know, because I didn't know if
I wanted to go public with it, but I
figured if I could just save one life,
you know, isn't that what I'm what what
I've been given this public stage for?
So, of course, you got a big voice for
us. Yeah. Coming over here. Well, most
people with thyroid cancer don't have
symptoms. If they do have symptoms,
there are four essential red flags,
right? And each of these flags is
important for you to keep in mind. So,
I've got three survivors who walk us
through it. They've been start us off.
The first red flag for folks to pay
attention to is trouble breathing. Did
you have that problem at all? I did not
actually have that problem of trouble
breathing. I really didn't. Uh and I
didn't feel many many of the the the the
symptoms until after I said, "Wait a
minute, maybe there was an issue and I
didn't notice it." Now that you
mentioned it, that's the point right
now. We're going to actually mention it
so you think about it before it happen.
And and none of these are all that
common because most people with thyroid
cancer don't have any symptoms, but
these are the ones that do sort of wake
you up to them. Okay, Janet, go ahead.
You get the next red flag. And I'm
wondering if you had any of these
problems, constant cough being yours.
Horse and constant smoker's cough every
night for more than two years and never
touched a cigarette. Whoa. So constant
cough number three. Take it away,
Nicole. The third red flag is all about
neck pain and what kind of pain it is.
or the ejection. Did you have any pain
at all? I did. I did not realize it had
to do with my thyroid, but I had severe
neck pain in the back of my neck. I
couldn't sleep. Um, you know, and I
thought, "Oh, boy, I need a massage."
But after my surgery, it resolved. So,
yeah, it's chameleon, you know, it
sneaks up on you, which is one of the
reasons we miss it. And the fourth red
flag is trouble swallowing which happens
because as the as the thyroid starts to
get in the way of other basic functions
right on top of the throat you'll have
issues with breathing. You'll have
issues with swallowing sometimes because
it begins to invade in the tissues
around it or just because it gets bigger
and you can get that even if you have a
a goer which is an evident cancer. So
there that this is in a critical
location in your body. So it's trying to
whisper to you that it's there. When we
come back the at home thyroid test that
we're going to be calling the Damon John
neck check. All right. Like that idea,
the Monica. Absolutely. I love it. All
right. You can do it right now in your
own home. We're going to show you
exactly how. So stick around.
[Applause]
[Music]
He's accused of a lot of questionable
behavior. He asked me to undress me. He
watched me while I did so. He was very
creepy and unprofessional. He conducted
the exam without any gloves. It was very
uncomfortable. I didn't understand. The
university gynecologist accused by over
300 women of the most unspeakable
crimes. These young women were violated.
All new Oz. That's coming up
[Music]
tomorrow. We are back with Shark Tank Mo
Damon John who survived thyroid cancer
is on a mission to save lives. Now,
we're about to show you a super easy
atome thyroid test you can do right now.
But first, take a quick look at the
thyroid and what it does. So, your
thyroid is this itty bitty
butterflyshaped gland. It's hidden
beneath the Adam's apple, which is out
there, right under here. And it affects
your body in a really big way. Most
people know that it regulates your
body's metabolism, but it can affect
your heart rate. It can affect how your
lungs squeeze, even your body
temperature. So, a lot of things begin
to get affected. If your thyroid is
making too much of a hormone, all these
hormones going up, then guess what? The
heart goes faster, lungs go faster, your
temperature goes high. that makes too
little of a hormone that's called
hypothyroidism. A lot of you have that,
right? That can signify an autoimmune
problem that can increase your risk of
thyroid cancer as well as making you
feel sluggish and, you know, slowing
everything down too much. Now, the good
news is is when this thyroid gets large,
you know, most of the time it's not a
big deal, right? Only a small percentage
of people end up getting cancer. So,
I've got a little test to figure out if
your thyroid is healthy or if it's
enlarged. You need to go out and get
someone to look at it. We're gonna call
it the Damon John neck check. All right,
you audience, you all do this? Okay, put
your hands together like a butterfly.
Like you're gonna swim or fly like that.
Okay, you all ready to do this? Okay,
now we're all going to do it together.
We're we're floating like a butterfly.
Put that on top of your Adam's apple.
Got the Adam's apple, right? Okay, now
those fingers that were just dancing,
push that a little bit. You feel the
little ribs there, the little notches?
That's the trachea. Okay. Now, al
together you're going to
swallow. As you swallow, if you need a
little water, you can drink, get a glass
of water and get the water in your
mouth, then swallow. Then, if you feel
something jump up and down, like a piece
of tissue, like a small finger jumping
up and down beneath your fingers, right?
That means you've got a thyroid that's
bigger than it's supposed to be. If it
feels lumpy, if it's sore, don't panic.
You go see a doctor. All right? So,
everyone
swallow, right? What are you feeling now
that you're doing it right?
It's okay. No problems. Nothing. You
feel anything? No, I don't feel
anything. Good. You're not supposed to
feel anything. Oh, that's a good thing.
If you don't feel anything, of course,
the coughing is allowed also, right?
You're pretty good. Did you Did you feel
something when you were having the
thyroid when I did? Yeah. When I went
into the and the surgeon told me to feel
there, I did. Yeah. And you notice, by
the way, he's got his fingers under his
tie. It's sort of low. It's not up here.
Don't feel under your chin, right?
You're not trying to That's the Napoleon
dynamite thing. Yeah,
that dynamite test, right? Let's get it
down low. So, listen, not all lumps and
cancer, but it's always worth a trip to
the doctor's office for some peace of
mind. This whole audience is help is
happy now. You should do it as well.
Teach your friends. We'll put a quick
little one sheet on dr.com to help you
remember how to do the Damon John neck
check. I'm not letting him go yet
because he's going to share some of his
business advice when we come back. We're
converting this set into a shark tank
with a nurse entrepreneur and nurse
prneur challenge. I can't wait.
[Applause]
Calling all nursing students. The Dr. Oz
Show wants to celebrate you. If you're
currently enrolled in nursing school,
you could have a chance to win $10,000
and be on my show. Go to dr.com to enter
by November 15th.
[Applause]
We are here with Damon John who had
stage two thyroid cancer and credits the
amazing medical professionals around him
with saving his life. Now he's given
back lending his Shark Tank business
smarts to two nurse prneurs who are
competing for the first ever coveted
golden
stethoscope.
Oo, it's a nurse prneur Shark Tank
today. That is really a pretty prize.
Are you guys ready? They're ready to go.
All right. What do you look for when you
get pitched an idea? Uh, you know, can
it solve a a problem? Uh, and of course,
I look for the entrepreneur. Do they
really have a passion behind it? And are
they really do they really believe in
it? All right, let's meet our first
competitor. We narrowed it down to two
nurses who have briefly pitched their
product. And Damon's going to pick his
favorite. Up first in the tank is
Sarah. There she is, Sarah. Come on out.
She's a nurse. She practices in
Delaware, actually. And she has a
solution to a big problem. Damon, take
it away. Hello, Dr. Oz Damon. My name is
Sarah and I developed the Qualclipip
stethoscope holder because I find
wearing my stethoscope on my neck very
uncomfortable. It was giving me
headaches and neck pain at the end of my
shift. I didn't like the way it swung
into my patients when I leaned over to
provide care to them. And also for nurse
safety to prevent an agitated patient
from gaining control by using the
stethoscope as a strangulation device.
Never thought of that. Happens all the
time. Oh my goodness. Very very scary.
Never thought of that angle. All right.
So what's the solution? So instead of
wearing my stethoscope around my neck,
I wear my stethoscope in my koala clip.
Koala clip. Koala clip because it
reminds me of a koala. The way a koala
grabs onto a tree. Yes. Well, you put it
like that. Oh, yes. So, it's al it's
spring, so you can really wear it
anywhere that you'd like. Um, I like it
on my pocket. A lot of my customers like
the like it on their waistband. You can
at the end of your shift, you can put it
on your tote bag on the outside so you
don't have to put your um stethoscope
and curl it up and put it in your bag.
Uses a hair clip, all kinds of very
cool. Sure. Sure. And and there's
nothing there's nothing out there that
uh you know previously to to hold
stethoscopes. Well, there is something
out there um to hold stethoscopes. It's
a different design than mine. I have a
design patent. All right. And uh it
didn't work and that's why I developed
this product because I had really bad
neck pain. Thank you very very much. Do
you have any specific advice for Sarah?
uh you know honestly this is a very uh
simple product that is needed in the
market and this is not one of those
things where you need a big deal. You
can start off by making a dozen or a
hundred and or you know whatever the
case is and it could actually grow into
a very very big business. So
congratulations. Thank you. All right.
Now let's see who your competitor is.
Amy is here. Come on out Amy. Let's see
what she Oh my goodness. She's bringing
a patient with her. A patient and a
nurse and an orderly.
This looks uh a serious deal here.
All right, Amy, briefly, what is the
product? Yes, my name is Amy
Copperweight. I am the CEO of Avkin. I'm
also a clinical nurse specialist and
faculty at the University of Delaware.
What we've really done is taken these
large plastic mannequins that students
are normally taught on and rettaught on
and taken that lifeless form and
actually taken the technology into bits
and pieces so that they actually could
be used on a live person. So they can
really develop not just the competence
but also the compassion that's needed in
healthcare today. So is it is it the
chest piece? What is the actual device?
So yes, the the actual device Damon
actually has one right over here. If you
take a look, this is the first of three
of our patented products. Um it actually
has lung sounds and you can instill
mucus into it because we know patients
with tracheiotomies often have a lot of
mucus. So it's just that realism, that
authenticity, but you actually have a
real person there. So you're interacting
with a real person as they're learning
the care.
So you actually suction it in. Yeah.
Come on up. Come on up. We're going to
do this together. Oh my goodness. Inside
here, you go. That's uh that's beyond my
pay grade, man. I want to see how you
do. You can see it on this side. Um so
essentially this thing is is it's a
piece of technology, wearable technology
that actually has sensors inside. So if
I suction too deeply and hit her corina
or the where her lungs bifurcate, she
actually will get a vibration and know
how to react and respond the way a real
patient would. So, it's really giving
that authenticity to real true bedside
care. So, Dr. Oz, you have a pair of
gloves over here. We're going to do this
non-sterily even though it's for TV.
Just for time. Go ahead. Go ahead. Put
some gloves on. I'm going to turn the
suction
on. Megan, take a couple deep breaths
for me. Do you feel like you're having a
hard time breathing? Okay. So, I'm going
to be a bad nurse and I'm going to go
down and hit her corina, but we'll see
if Dr. Oz can do a better job after I'm
done. So, I'm going to go down. Well,
that wasn't done right. No, that's not
good. All right. Sorry. Okay. So, I'm
simulating what the nursing students
would have done. Taken too long, been
uncomfortable. And now we're going to
see if Dr. Oz can do a better job here.
I'm I don't I'm not usually better than
a nurse at this, but we'll give it a
shot. Yeah. Well, maybe if you don't go
down quite so far. We go.
Go ahead and do the suction on the
All right, that's enough
time. That is realistic. Yeah, it's
really meant to create that authenticity
and realism. And then at the end of the
simulation experience or the learning
experience, they actually get to hear
from the patients perspective how that
was. Here, turn, turn that off so I can
hear you better. Sure. Damon, advice,
brain, what what do you think? I have no
idea what just happened. Um, and I'm
just I'm just so thankful for medical
professionals because I I'm I'm just so
thankful for medical professionals. I I
I have no idea what just happened.
David, don't you want competent and
compassionate health? No, absolutely.
And thank God you can think of this and
keep improving science to make us
healthier. I I make t-shirts. So, all
right. You tell us who is the winner.
Now, you got two wonderful nurse
entrepreneurs. The winner is
Oh, they're both saving lives. Both. I
can't do it, Doc. I can't do it. All
right. Both. Both. Two winners. All
right. We have two coveted winners.
There we have it.
I didn't want that on you.
How many put it on wrong? Two winners.
Congratulations. You both did a
wonderful job. You know what? Because
you're nurses and because you guys are
the ones who really make the healthare
system work. God bless you. Thank you
very, very much. Absolutely. All right.
Now, I got a special announcement with
Damon for a second. Before we go, you
teamed up with Johnson Johnson for the
lab coat of the future quickfire
challenge. It sounds cool. What is it?
You know, the lab coat has been the same
way for so many years. And you look at
technology today where we can probably
make uh some technology on it where if
you're having some products on it and uh
you know it's dangerous for the lab code
professional or the professional using
or people outside we can know more about
it. The lab code has been the exact
same. So Johnson and Johnson and I
teamed up. We awarded $50,000 to someone
who came up with a new design for that
and now you can be part of it all. You
can all be champions of science. Today,
Johnson and Johnson Innovation launched
a donation campaign that will be open
through the end of October. As a part of
their commitment to advocate for
science, Johnson and Johnson will donate
$5 to Biotech Institute up to
$25,000 for every social media post
using the hashtag champions of science.
That's all you need to do to pro to to
protect all these great professionals
who are saving our lives. Everyone at
home, you take out your phones, be a
champion of science, tweet with the
hashtag champions of science. # to fuel
the next generation of innovators. God
bless you. Thank you and John.
Congratulations, nurses. We'll be right
back.
Fall in love with fall. And Reay is here
with a guide to her favorite soups for
this time of year, which includes a
whole new green. And it's not kale.
[Music]
[Applause]
Rachel Ray has changed the way we
approach the daily meal, teaching many
of us that cooking can be simple and
fun. And her practical downto-earth
methods can morph anyone into a
full-blown foodie. Now, this culinary
mogul is here with a brand new make
ahead food prep guide to fall soups that
will fill your freezer with healthy
dinners for this season. Please welcome
my good friend Rachel Ray.
[Applause]
Are we dancing?
I love having you here. I love having
you here, too.
So, I I got to say,
I you all love her as much as I do, but
I have a special affinity for you. And
one thing I know is I know it's the fall
because the racial ratio's 13th season.
It's back. Yeah.
Can still afford groceries. I got a job.
Yay. Well, that's one of the things that
makes you so special. Thank you. Thank
you. The fall, besides having to go back
and make the show, which is I know is a
joy for all of us. Fall is my favorite
season. Um, and soups are probably my
favorite type of of food. They they
really are very nourishing in in so many
ways, like for your soul, not just your
body, but And they're great cuz they can
take whatever you got in the summer.
That's right. And and you make it
because fall creeps up on you and
repurpose it. Yeah. late late summer,
early fall, I I do tons and tons of make
ahead meals, and they're all soups and
stews and sauces, translating the
vegetables into a freezer. This Yes.
This is what Rachel is really good at.
Now, this is this is really
smart. When you make your soups and
stews for the fall, don't put them into
those plastic storage containers. They
take up too much room. cool them down to
room temperature and put them in these
flat freezer bags and you can stack up
dozens of them in the freezer. And it's
a great way when broccoli's on sale,
make some broccoli soup. The last corn
of the season, make some corn soup or
corn chowder or corn and seafood soup.
It's as easy as a box of stock. If you
don't have time to make stock from
scratch and any vegetable combination,
throw it in the freezer, make your own
uh takeout food and frozen foods and
canned foods. It's so much cheaper and
better for you. Let's talk about soup in
general. I I've heard you say that if
you really want to make Italian food
healthy, Yes. make it into a soup. You
know, Italian food, uh, if you're not of
Italian descent, if your family isn't
Italian, some people think of Italian
American food that's very delicious but
super high in calories, like chicken
parm, you know, fried chicken with
cheese and lots of uh giant sides of
pasta with with tons and tons of cheese.
But if you're trying to trim down,
Italian food and soups are actually a
great way to do it. Lots of vegetable
laden soups are very filling and full of
great nutrition and you can have a
little bit of pasta in it or beans, but
you're not eating a ton of calories.
You're just getting a a ton of great
nutrition. So, you three examples of how
we take these healthy ingredients. Three
of my favorites. Two of my favorites.
And you're bringing him to life for us.
Everybody loves tomato soup, right?
Yes,
a lot of people enjoy a creamy tomato
soup. So, finishing with heavy cream.
This is an Italian traditional method of
making tomato soup. You take your root
vegetables. I like fennel, carrot,
celery, onion or your usual suspects. I
put garlic in everything. You add stock,
uh, San Marzano, canned tomatoes. And
you thicken the soup in a very clever
way. Not with heavy cream, but with a
little palenta, a little corn, a little
cornmeal in it. It makes it sweeter and
more delicious. And then I love these
little immersion blenders. It's so much
easier than taking the soup and trying
to throw it into a blender. Screaming
hot boiling soup. Don't do that. When do
you add the tomatoes? You can add them
here. It doesn't matter. You soften the
veggies just so they're going to go
through the blender a little easier. And
then you just break this down and let
the tomatoes cook out and you thicken it
with a little bit of palenta. Those are
done. If you want to try a little bit.
Oh, you made it already. Oh, she's so
prepared. Those are some dundons.
It's truly delicious. It's slightly
sweet, but it's savory. Isn't that It's
full, isn't it? And this is such great
nutrition. And it's And what else is
great about soup is it stretches a
dollar. You know, it's the way you
stretch a book. Why do more people not
use palenta as a thickening age? Is it
brilliant? It's just it's an it's an
Italian thing. It's a cultural thing.
Like we just you know people in America
don't use cornmeal. If you come from the
south totally use cornmeal grits. Hello.
So there's probably a lot of great chefs
down south that would thicken up
anything with a little bit of cornmeal.
This is today's hero. Today's hero for
delicious and super sweet. It's our
hero. All right. Now this is a little
special. This is you know this is the
minestron with chicken riata meatball.
But can I say one thing? Yeah. People
don't eat escoral. This is esciral.
You'd say in Italian scroll. When you're
a kid, um the first meal you're
introduced to is a chini de pepe. Little
bits of pasta in broth with a bit of
greens. You know, most people know this
soup from like it's a derivative of
wedding soup. They call it little
meatball soup. But this one, I hope
everybody downloads this. It's so
delicious. If you want your kids to
embrace escodol or kale, put it in with
little baby meatballs and pasta and they
will love it. But I talk about kale all
the time and I've actually gotten a lot
of folks to eat it. But this isn't kale.
This is a green we never really talked
about. This is a great sturdy green that
you can cook with and it is a superfood
as they say. But scuttle or escarol is
milder once you cook it out. It's only
slightly bitter. You can eat it raw in
salads. This is again your usual
suspects. Carrot, celery, onion, garlic,
stock, vegetable or chicken. And you I
always drop in when I make soups. This
is a great tip. The rind of parmyo
reaniano. The whole soup tastes like
parm cheese. My wife does that. You get
so much flavor. It's it delicious. I
always buy a piece of cheese with the
rind on it and I keep them in my
freezer. It looks like um Remy the rat
tattooy rats in my house cuz I got so
many cheese rind in the freezer. little
fresh music, but it's so good in your
sauces, and your soups. Throw that
together. And you just wilt the greens
in here. And now this, you cook the
meatballs not in oil. So healthy. You
cook them like dumplings directly,
dropping the chicken and the ricotta
into the soup. So try it. Try it. This
is good. Okay. The beans you add when?
The bean. The beans and the pasta you
cook off at the same time as the baby
meatballs.
It's great nutrition and children love
these little meatballs. They're soft,
they're sweet, and it's just ground
white meat chicken and a little ricotta
cheese. And this all has the right
texture. It's got a nice and all the
bitterness is out of it. No, it's
delicious. Honestly, the kids will love
this. And you're giving them great
nutrition. And this is why people get
married to these soups. I think it's a
good reason for it. All right.
Delicious. Finally, roasted cauliflower
soup with a parsley salad bruschetta.
Both again, this is classy. classy way
of thinking something so good for us and
making it taste unbelievable. Everybody
loves cream soups, but again, cream
soups are not great for your figure,
right? Then they're not great for your
arteries. So, this one we just take
cauliflower and put a little bit of
olive oil spray on it or a little
drizzle and toss and then a little
nutmeg, salt and pepper or white pepper.
We roast up whole heads of garlic so
it's sweet and delicious and not sharp
and bitter at all. We roast this and
paste it. And then we take the roasted
cauliflower and you just puree it with
stock vegetable or chicken. I'm going to
serve up a here. I'm going to serve up a
warm one. This one's staying nice and
hot. And then I put a little bit of
extra roasted cauliflower on top. It
tastes creamy and delicious. And all
this is is eating a giant bowl of
cauliflower and stock and roasted
garlic. It's so good for
you and cruciferous vegetables, right?
They are so good for you nutritionally.
The best way to detox your liver. But
look at how you're doing it. I And you
can't mess it up. It's basically the
simple stuff. It's so like rich and
heavy and hearty and it's just
vegetables. I can taste the fresh herbs.
It's got this little brightness to it
from the lemon. Yeah. I always finish
soups with a little bit of acid. And
this all these soups you added a little
lemon or lime to. All of the soups have
a little bit of acidity. In Italian
cooking, it's very important to finish
with a little lemon juice or to add some
white wine. Acidity is the balance to
the salt and the the earthiness of our
dishes. The leftover white wine. What
you haven't what you haven't finished.
Yeah, there like there's ever leftover
wine in my house.
And then the first word was veno.
There's no leftover wine in my house. We
have bottles, not glasses. Sorry. So, on
that note, the October issue of Rachel's
magazine is in Oh, it's all Italian.
Yeah, it's our Italian issue. You guys
got to check it out. And it's so good,
right? And it features Rachel's tomato
soup and palenta we started with. Check
it out for more delicious recipes. Open
up all these recipes, right? They're all
going to be on dr.com. Check them out.
They she going to be all over my
Facebook page. You're doing the take
over the Facebook page. Nice. Six
million people. Share with your friends.
We come back. Why Rachel team me up and
listen carefully. Giata Delorentes, Alex
Guenelli, and some of the biggest names
in food send a powerful message to young
women everywhere. This is important
stuff. Stay with us.
[Music]
[Applause]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day, but when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
[Music]
We're back with Rachel Ray. Advice for
young women who want to be chefs, young
women who want to be like you. Well, you
know, I think uh my best advice for
anyone is to value work itself. You
know, my mom taught me from the time I
was very young that work is a privilege
and if you work very hard and you're
grateful for every job you have in life,
I really believe especially in this
country, you will go forward. So you be
successful at whatever you want to do. I
also believe
whether whether you want to be a chef or
not. I also believe very deeply that
when I was a kid and you went to public
school, everybody got home. Everybody
got shop class. You learned how to fix a
car, sew a button, make your own food.
Basic trades. Yeah. Everyone should
learn the basics of cooking good
nutritious food. It helps your
pocketbook. It certainly improves the
quality of your life and the length of
your life. It is an essential skill for
everyone, not just people that want to
cook for a living in in my opinion. I
the issue of the of the role of women in
this process is critical to you and I
think it's something I want to spend a
second on. Now the culinary world is
dominated by male chefs which is always
surprising to me. So what can women do
to become those chefs? I think that you
know as in any profession the person
best qualified for the job deserves that
job but there is a a big discrepancy in
the number of women. You know at our
magazine we try and celebrate women with
a cover that we do called like a boss
right so last year we did uh a big issue
about it and and I had all these great
female chefs on our show. This year we
wanted to go back and represent women of
color that are boss chefs. It's hard to
find. You know what I mean? That we have
to really nurture our young people and
if they're into it, give them the same
the same respect across the board for a
man and a woman in the kitchen or any
place else. But I really I really think
that that's changing and the tide is
turning and I think that just having the
conversation about it like at this
year's um food and wine festival here in
New York, we're doing a supper is served
event. It's all female mixologists and
chefs and Giata Darentes and Alex
Garnerelli. Um myself, everybody all
Martina McBride is performing. It's a
real celebration of what women are doing
and how innovative they are in the
kitchen. Let me high five you on that
because high 10. I talk to Daphne about
this all the time and I see as a young
woman who's trying to become like you,
right? It's it is challenging in ways I
never anticipated. And like you, I want
the best person to do the best job,
right? But but I want everyone to be
able to play on to have the same
advantage is is is all we're asking. Get
everyone on the field and then let the
best player win. Respect, right? And to
just get the same respect. I love
everything you stand for. Love you
person as well. It's our 13th. Lucky 13.
10th double digits right here. You can
check out the New York City Wine and
Foods Festival. Oh, I think the audience
Yeah, the audience is going to get some.
No, no, no. That was You're stealing my
thunder, Rachel. Darn it. No, look, she
didn't mean that. It's It's October 11th
through 14th and we're going to be
giving away some tickets to my Facebook
followers. Look for that today. And
there's one last thing. Okay. You want
to say it? No, you go ahead. Oh, we can
both say it. Okay. One more surprise.
Let's do it together. Everybody in the
studio audience is going home with
tickets today.
Enjoy. Spread it around in the wisdom as
well. Make the food. We'll be right
back.
[Applause]
[Music]
We're celebrating our 10th season and
we're not turning back. We're looking
forward to our next 10 and yours. All
year long, we're challenging you to
discover your health and life goals for
your next 10. 10 days, 10 weeks, 10
years. Share your goals at #myx10 and
you can win prizes or even end up right
here on my show. It happens to all of
us. You walk through the door after a
tough day and it's chaos. Dinner isn't
cooked. Laundry isn't done. You kick off
your shoes and step on something. Ow.
And you're ready to blow a gasket.
Instead, pause for a moment and take
five deep
breaths.
[Music]
Ah, everyone do it together. So nice. No
matter where the stress in your life is
coming from, today I have the self-care
regimen to help you go from manic to
mindful in just minutes. And I've
enlisted the help of Dr. Taz Batia,
integrated physician and health and
wellness expert who's here on behalf of
our trusted sponsorship partner, Dr.
Teals. Thank you for being here very
much. As you all know, right,
mindfulness is what we all try to
achieve, but it's hard to do that
because the stress gets in the way
crazily. So, why is it so important to
helping us cope? You know, Dr. Oz,
mindfulness is a mental state that's
achieved when we focus our awareness on
the present moment, calmly acknowledging
our thoughts and our feelings. It is not
easy to be mindful today between
technology, being on 24/7, juggling kids
and work and family. It is so important
to slow down that frenetic pace and
really take a moment to relax, rest, and
kind of recharge the mind. We know that
that's so critical and nowadays
mindfulness is a necessity. It's not a
luxury because we have to be the most
productive versions of ourselves. And
what I see in practice is that all of
this really affects women the most
because they are juggling everything,
everyone else's needs and often
neglecting their own health. The whole
audience is going like this. But how to
do it? That's the challenge. You have a
hack for us. I do. So mindfulness,
remember, is achieved when we're in the
present moment. And there are so many
different ways to do this. You can do
yoga, you can meditate, getting
exercise, getting proper sleep. Those
are all ways to be mindful. But the key
is creating a space for mindfulness,
creating that zen. I like to do it by
finding a pre-sleep routine. And Dr.
Teal's Epsom salts is an easy solution.
Now, again, we can all run to yoga, try
to find time to meditate, but what's
easier than soaking in Dr. Teal's Epsom
salts a couple times a week. For me,
everybody, an Epsom salt bath really,
it's like yoga for the brain. Yes. It
just puts you in this place. First of
all, you're not going to be doing
technology. And I think this is a hack
that works because your body unwinds and
as it begins to let go, your mind can
also. It's probably the single biggest
adult tool that I use to get myself into
the right frame of mind. So, first off,
let's talk about Epsom salts. Most
people don't know what they are. They've
seen them on the Dr. Teal's bag, but
what does that actually mean? Yeah. So,
Epsom salts are a compound of magnesium
sulfate. They are a great natural
alternative to over-the-counter
medications and prescription drugs. Most
people maybe already know about Epsom
salts because they relieve those achy
muscles, that body soreness that you
might feel from time to time, but at the
same time, Epsom salts are delivering
that same magnesium to the entire body.
They also offer a triple threat,
especially Dr. Teal's Epsom salts, they
offer a triple threat of benefits when
we're trying to achieve mindfulness
because in addition, we have the benefit
of the essential oils like lavender that
promote sleep, promote rest, and what's
more relaxing finally than taking a
bath. So, show me how to make them.
Here's the thing about the smell. You
since you touched on it and the
lavender, it bypasses your thinking. It
goes right to the middle of your brain,
the reptilian part of our brain. That's
why smells affect us so much. And I
think that's important tool we don't use
enough to get ourselves in the right
mental set. Okay. Show us how you make
the So, the first rule of thumb when
we're making this is to make sure the
water is warm, not hot. So, we want warm
water. We want two generous cups of the
Dr. Teal's Epsom salt. We're going to
pour that directly into the water. And
then you want to soak maybe twice a week
for about 20 minutes. And what's
happening here is it takes about 5 to 10
minutes for that relaxation response to
really set in and for that stress to
melt away. And use that time as an
opportunity maybe use that time to
breathe and really try to visualize the
person that you want to be. And also a
lot of folks get so darn busy, right?
They don't have time to do this. So we
made it easy. We sent a bunch of our
viewers home with Dr. Teal's Epsom salt
and we asked them to take a bath with it
at least twice a week. So come on over
here. We've got the five folks who
volunteered to come in the studio and
talk about this with us. Thank you for
being here. Right now, wellness for
everybody at home. Wellness may start in
your head, but I think I'm going to
applaud you for taking a little load off
your feet and enjoying because this is
not a bad way of getting there either.
Just getting your feet to relax. So,
Dip, we're going to start with you.
Before we started this program with you,
how are you dealing with stress? Well,
you know, I have three kids. One of
them's very young. By the end of the
day, I I'm on sensory overload. I've got
diaper sense. I've got people who've
been hanging all over my ever since. I
love this. That's right. And you know,
just I've just had I've had enough. I
don't want anyone touching me. My poor
husband comes home at the end of the day
and wants a hug. And I'm just like, "No,
just nobody touch me anymore. I'm done.
I need these kids in bed and I just want
my body back to myself." So, how's Dr.
Teal's Epsom salt baths helped you?
How's it helped you cope? So, when I
finally got them to leave me alone for
the 20 minutes so I could soak in the
bath, um, you know, I I really I felt
like I I felt that sensory overload
really just kind of leaving me into the
water and just having that alone time to
breathe in the scent. It's worth the
invest. Congrats on the kids. Thank you,
Caroline. How has it changed your life
to be epaltting batting your way through
life? Yeah, I think it just kind of
helped with being more mindful like you
said. You know, I was sitting there. I
had nothing to do. I chose not to listen
to music. I chose not to read. I have a
really nice bathroom. So, I just sat in
it and just soaked. And then I felt
actually I was quite tired afterwards,
funny enough, and I just fell asleep.
Probably got a good night's sleep. I
did. Yes. And to me, what would you say
to folks who are struggling to find time
just to get into an Epsom salt bath and
let this happen? I would tell them is
definitely worth the time. Take the 20
minutes because it's worth it. the days
that I didn't use it, I said, "Man, I
wish if I would have just taken that 20
minutes, the rest of my day would have
been better." So, I don't think if I'm
taking I don't have enough time. I'm
thinking this will give me more time
because I'll be more relaxed. I'll be
able to get through my day. So, it's
definitely worth it making that time.
So, you think everyone here ought to be
spending a little more time sitting
sitting in a Dr. Teal's Epsom salt bath?
Yes, absolutely. Are you guys interested
in this at all? Yes. Well, I'm glad you
are cuz guess what? This fantastic news
is Dr. Teal's lavender pure Epsom salt
soak is going to be yours. That's thanks
to the company that's sending you home
with a bag of it. So enjoy
yourselves and thanks to Dr. Taz Bati
and our trusted sponsor Dr. Kes for all
that. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
He was very creepy. He asked me to
undress and he watched me while I did
so. The university gynecologist accused
by over 300 women of the most
unspeakable crimes. These young women
were violated. All new
Oz. That's coming up
[Music]
tomorrow. What if I told you that you
could have your cake and eat it too?
That you can make a delicious chocolate
cake without butter or oil? Believe me?
Yeah. What? Instead, you can use this
eggplant. Yes. You're thinking eggplant.
not bubb. When my team saw that eggplant
chocolate cake recipes were taking over
the internet, I needed to know if they
would work. So, I listed two of my go-to
testers, Bianca and Nephe, and they
agreed very
bravely try it out. So, one of you made
a regular cake and one of you made the
cake with the eggplant where you swap
out the butter and the oil. Is that
correct? Yes. All right. So, I'm not
supposed to know which one is which. I'm
just going to put them right here so the
audience can look at this with me. So,
as I look at these, this is a little
drier looking. So, normally you think
that might not have all the butter and
the oil that you want, but I don't know.
But Bianca, you go first. You know, let
me just taste it first. You're messing
me
up. That's so
thick. Good mouth feel. Fills everything
up.
Clearly a worthy thing to eat. And this
is also good. I'll tell you, this is a
little better from my perspective, but I
could see why you love them both. So,
come clean now. Who made the eggplant? I
did. This is the eggplant one. Yes. Can
you believe it? It's actually better
than the regular cake. That's what I
think, too. Bianca, taste that. See what
you think about. I want an honest
opinion. Would you do it again? Would
you? I would. Why not? I'm a foodie and
it's a healthy version of something I
love. Why not? All right. So, Nephi's
eggplant version has onethird of the
calories less. That's worth the
investment. Eggplants, great way to add
more fiber to your diet as well. We're
going to have Nephy's eggplant recipe as
eggplant chocolate cake recipe on
dr.com. Your friends will be so jealous.
They'll be like Bianca over here. Just
won't want to admit it even though they
they like it. Exactly. Together, change
is happening, everybody. And our journey
is just beginning. See you next time.
Thanks. Thank you.
[Music]