This man was a wellrespected university
professor who bought a used car
dealership in a SD area of town. He was
also a dedicated father of six until he
was found murdered in his office. Why
was he killed? Was it a random robbery
or something more sinister? Today, when
science meets crime, how a photographic
memory helped find his killer. Take a
look at the investigation into the
murder of Dr. Gul Telawir. Dr. can tell
where's his daughter Lisa is here. I'm
sorry for the loss of your dad.
>> Thank you.
>> What was your relationship with your
like?
>> My father and I were very close. Um, you
know, he was a good family man, Dr. Oz.
My dad wasn't the kind of guy that went
away on the weekend to go fishing with
his buddies or went down to the local
bar to watch the game. If he had free
time, it was spent with his children.
So, we were very close.
>> He's a university professor. Yes. A
doctor.
>> Taught economics, right? Had a
doctorate. Did you find it odd that he
would buy a used car lot? That doesn't
seem to jive with that profession.
>> My father saw 24 hours in a day and he
was going to use them to his advantage.
So coming from a third world country, he
was such a patriot. He loved America.
Used to tell us children, I've done my
job. You're all US citizens. You can
have, do, be, whatever you want. So it
was a purely economic decision. You
know, he would teach until about 3:00 in
the afternoon and then go to the car lot
until the early evening and on
Saturdays. So the used car business can
have it can be seedy, right? He was in
Sidi part of town, but the business
itself has sort of a dark underworld
flavor to it. Did you do you think your
dad understood the true risks of being
in that business?
>> I don't I don't think so, Dr. Oz. I
don't think he saw it that way. You
know, my father,
having grown up in Afghanistan, it's it
was a very violent country. He had a lot
of difficulties there.
>> He saw especially Nashville, Tennessee
as the promised land. He never felt
afraid. He never felt threatened.
>> Yep. He saw America as a place that
would always be safe. So while that
business does have that aspect to it, I
don't think my father ever saw it that
way.
>> Take me back to the day you learned he
had been killed.
>> What happened?
>> So it was March 17th. It was a beautiful
day. It was the first warm day we had.
So I had all the windows open in my
house. I was outside and I was um
actually seating my lawn. I had a bow
rake. I had grass seed. And the phone
kept ringing and I could hear it ringing
and you know, but I was working and so
finally I got tired of hearing it
ringing. I went inside and I answered
the phone and it was my brother and I
could tell immediately by the tone of
his voice that something was very wrong.
So he said to me, he said, "Listen,
something really bad happened today." He
said, "Daddy was at his car lot and
someone came to the lot and they shot
him."
>> Oh. And I remember asking him, "Shot him
with what?" Like it the information just
wouldn't go in. So my poor brother had
to tell me the story again. He said,
"Lisa,
daddy was shot today." And then he said
to me, you know, daddy's dead.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> And I don't know where I went. Excuse
me. So I don't know where I went, but I
went somewhere else because when I came
back, I was on my knees in my bedroom
and I was craling the phone and I was
just crying. I mean, I was just wailing.
And I heard this voice in my head that
said, "You have to get up. You have to
get up and you have to get up right
now." So I remember standing up and
asking because I knew what I needed in
that moment. and I needed to be in the
same place where my brother was. So, I
asked him where he was. He told me and
then I just got up, walked out of the
house and and drove to where he was.
>> What did you think had happened to your
father? Why would anyone shoot him?
>> You know, that that was the part that
was so disconcerting. We had no idea. We
couldn't imagine anyone that held daddy
with such animosity that they would
murder him. You know, we thought maybe
maybe it was a robbery, but he had money
on him. His watch was still on him. It
it just it defied logic to us because he
wasn't that type of man that would have,
you know, that kind of hate directed at
him, that kind of violence, that kind of
brutality.
>> So, up next, what happened the morning
Dr. Telworth died? The detective solves
the case using his exceptional memory.
That's detective Pat Posigleion. He's
investigated the death of Dr. Gil
Telawir, who owned a used car dealership
until he was found brutally murdered in
his office. Now, there were several
clues that pointed in different
directions, but Detective Postigleion
used what some call his photographic
memory to solve the case. Detective Pat
Postle is here today, as well as Dr.
Telware's daughter, Lisa. When you first
met Detective Pigleon, what was your
impression of him?
>> You know, it was such a difficult moment
for our family and we were so broken. We
were griefstricken. And the thing that
struck me about Detective Postigleon is
his otherworldly calm. He was absolutely
calm. And then he started to ask us
questions and his questions were so
thoughtful.
My sense of it was he wanted to
understand who my father was, not just
the forensic
information. He was genuinely interested
in who my father was.
>> Detective, can you describe what you
remember about a crime scene? Take this
one specifically when you arrived.
>> Well, I recall I got called out. It
happened to be my daughter's birthday.
Uh I got called out there and uh the
victim was lying, her dad was lying on
his right shoulder. His arm was
extended. His eyeglasses were in his
hand. His finger was pointed toward the
window. Um, there was a blood pattern
there that told me where the victim was
shot and where the victim ended up. It
looked like he had actually been in a
running position when he had fallen to
the ground. I clearly recall that.
>> So, a fair amount of detail. Now,
detective particular says he remembers
practically everything about a homicide
case, including the crime scene itself,
people, interviews, weapons, you know,
everything. doesn't even take written
notes because he retains it all right
here. It's the main tool he says he has
used to solve hundreds of cases. I'm
curious because I think all of us might
be able to harvest that power that you
seem to have
>> in just dealing with everyday issues. If
you can solve crimes, we should we
should be able to find our keys.
>> So, can you describe how your memory
works in a crime scene? When you first
encounter it, how do you begin to
process it?
>> Well, when I when I go into a crime
scene, first of all, I got to get the
permission and blessing from the crime
scene investigators. And once I'm
allowed to get inside the crime scene, I
make it my business to spend many hours
inside the scene. The longer I stay
inside the scene, the more sense the
scene begins to make to me. And I make
it a point because we don't know what's
relevant. We don't know what's
irrelevant. So, we look at everything as
potential evidence. And then what we do
is when we're finished with all that and
I leave, I understand everything that
I've looked at and I recall everything
that I looked at. And if it turns out to
be irrelevant, we didn't lose a thing.
So I recall every single thing because
down the road something that may be
initially irrelevant may end up being
relevant.
>> So do you think your memor is actually
better than an actual photograph of the
scene?
>> I would say that my me I could recall a
scene and then I could compare it to a
photograph of that same scene with my
memory and typically it's exactly the
same.
>> So in Dr. Telawar's case, Detective
Posigleion zeroed in on two suspects who
were at the scene of the crime. Ronnie
Aller and Terry Blandford, right? Dr.
Telawir had hired both of these men to
work at his car dealership. Lisa, did
you know either of these two men had did
you see them around the dealership?
>> One of the things I would do is I would
go and visit my father for lunch either
at his offices at the university or at
the car dealership. And I do remember
seeing them there, you know, daddy
giving them instructions, go do this
with this vehicle or that vehicle, but
just only in passing. I never had any
face tof face or one-on-one interaction
with them. So what frustrated
authorities, as both of you know, but
you should all know in the audience, is
that these two suspects, they were
pointing the finger at each other,
saying the other guy was the actual
shooter.
>> So I want Detective Pat to show us how
his memory come on up. Determined who
actually pulled the trigger, who was the
actual perpetrator. Remember both guys,
potential culprits. This is the crime
scene, the outside of the office and
inside of which Dr. Teller was shot and
killed. So, detective, as I look at this
picture and audience, let's just do this
all together. When you look at this
picture, can you tell which of these two
men killed Dr. Telwir?
>> Because I'm looking at this and I'm not
quite sure what to focus on.
>> So, you know, help us. Is it using your
your photographic memory and your
detective skills? What do you see here?
>> Well, when I look at the backside here,
the first thing I notice is the size of
the windows.
>> The size of the windows,
>> right?
>> All right. Let's zoom in on them. How
what are the sizes? The size of the
window is 24 in by 26 in this way.
>> You memorized that. You
>> I did. Yes.
>> All right. So, what about that size?
Where is
>> Well, the size of the window. We knew
there was a break in the window and we
knew that the person that entered, we
knew there was no forced entry. We knew
that the suspect came in through the
window and killed Goelwa. We knew this.
>> All right.
>> Based on the evidence. So, because the
window was 26 in high, 24 in wide, we
knew that
>> not anyone could fit in that window. So,
we had to make the deduction as to the
size of the person that went into that
window. And how big were these two men?
>> Well, Ronnie Allah, for example, was was
350 pounds.
>> That's him, Ronnie.
>> So, I'm here to tell you that Ronnie
Allah didn't fit in that window. Um,
Terry Blandford is 146 pounds. And as
soon as I saw Terry Blandford and I
looked at him face to face, I knew right
then that he was a shooter of Mr.
Telwire.
>> So, this is the killer.
>> That's the killer.
>> Pulled the trigger. Anyway,
>> he's a shooter. Yes, sir.
>> You got that all from the memory of
having walked around the crime site,
>> right? I did. I I I mean I spend a lot
of time inside the scene with the
victim. That's typically what I do.
That's what most homicide detectives do.
You spend a lot of time inside the crime
scene. The longer you spend in time this
inside the scene, the more sense the
scene makes to you.
>> And what happened to these person? Did
they both went to jail? One of them went
to jail. What happened?
>> Uh one pled and got life plus 20 years.
One went to trial and got convicted and
he also got life. So they're both in
prison right now.
>> Oh, so they were working together but
only one guy killed him,
>> right? One guy went in, the other one
was driving around. waiting for him to
come out.
>> And what what were they trying to do?
What were they trying to get?
>> It was a a robbery situation. Um but
apparently they were determined to kill
the victim and that's precisely what
they did. So
>> Oh my goodness. Yeah.
>> I'm so sorry you had to hear that here
again, but I'm sure you've witnessed it
at the court.
>> No, no. We're so grateful that we were
that we had a successful investigation
and a successful prosecution. So it's
it's not a problem to hear about it
again.
>> It brought some closure to your family.
>> It gave us our father back. Dr. Oz,
because for us, you know, if we hadn't
had that, and I don't know how families
deal with it that don't get that kind of
closure because all I would have ever
thought about when I thought about my
father was how he died. That's what I
would have been left with.
>> So, we were very, very fortunate to have
Detective Pigleó and his team do what
they did for us because the last 29
years, I've been able to enjoy the
memories of my father without that hurt,
without that pain of not having a
successful investigation. And detective
put let me pry a little into your
photographic memory. A lot of the crime
scenes that you must be investigating,
hundreds of them, they're brutal, right?
You get so much into them, you
essentially are reliving them because
they're in your mind like pictures.
>> Is that a heavy burden at times? I
>> I mean it it's kind of like a blessing
and a curse scenario where the blessing
part of it is because of my memory, it's
helped me solve uh some homicides over
the years. Uh and and that's a good
thing. Uh the other side is the curse
part is the fact that these cases bubble
up from time to time and and I actually
it's almost like I'm right there again.
But that's okay. I mean I accept that. I
understand that and and I'll take the
blessings over the curse and I think the
blessings do outweigh the curse.
>> Well, thank you for both being here and
for sharing the story.
>> Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good