A cancer mystery that the medical
community needs our help to
solve. We have clues. You've all been
exposed to something, but no answers. At
some point, you're starting to think,
what's happening to us? How friends from
one university all found themselves
battling the same life-threatening
disease? Is this just a coincidence or
is there something more going on here?
Plus, Savannah Guthri's pressing health
question for me. Coming up next.
[Music]
season 10 starts
now. Today, a mystery baffling the
medical community and a call to action
for all of you watching to help solve
it. Now, pay attention because we're
about to lay out for you the clues to
help explain why these friends from one
university all found themselves battling
the same life-threatening disease. Take
a
look. Julie, Allison, and Ashley met at
Auburn University in 1989. They lived in
the same dormatory. After graduation,
they stayed in touch. Then, something
mysterious happened. One by one, they
were all diagnosed with a rare form of
eye cancer. When I was 27 years old, I
started seeing these flashes of light
and a year later, I was diagnosed with
ocular melanoma. Then in 2001, Allison
was stricken. I was seeing about mild
flashes of light for about 7 to 10 days
and then after about 10 days realized I
had lost a little vision in my right
eye. And finally, Ashley. I was standing
in my doctor's office and um when I was
diagnosed and I told him I said you know
this is so unusual because I know two
people who I went to Auburn with who had
this cancer and had their eye removed
and he said that's almost impossible
this is so rare and that's when I knew
that this was this was probably a very
unique and unusual thing.
Ashley, Julie and Allison are here today
to talk about this medical phenomenon
that has shaken the lives of these best
friends. So Ashley, if I can start with
you, you mentioned that you felt
something weird at the diagnosis, but
how weird is it to be sitting with your
college friends, dormates, Yeah. who all
have the exact same disease, the same
problem? You know what's interesting is
this is such a rare cancer. Um, six out
of a million people have it. And so when
I was diagnosed, six out of a million.
Six out of a million. What are the odds
of three in the same school? Exactly.
And our ages and being there at the same
time. And I was actually diagnosed I
lived in Memphis, Tennessee at the time.
And I just remember after talking with
my doctor at the shock of it, you know,
but at the same time I stood there, I
said, you know what's crazy is I I know
two of the girls that I went to school
with and and I remember him saying
that's impossible. Like it's just too
rare. I said, "No, they both had their
eye removed and I was able to come home
right after diagnosis. I called both of
them, you know, found their numbers in
Birmingham because I again I lived in
Memphis and they were wonderful. So I
just feel very blessed to be surrounded
by them because they're sweet friends.
We talk to each other all the time,
almost daily. we text or or call. Sure.
This brings you together. It forges you
together. It does. You notice. Yeah.
Please. And I mean, a big part of this
story is obviously supporting each
other, but part of it is also why all
three of you, and we're going to learn
later even more interesting parts of the
story come to the forefront. But Joel,
you noticed that you had a a a spark of
light, right? A little a flash, I think
you called it. That's right. What was
that like? And how did it come on? Well,
at the time I was 27 years old and um I
just started seeing in my peripheral
vision just a flash of light almost like
you get up too fast um in my peripheral
vision. So I went to the doctor and they
just they assured me that it was more
called Moors lightning flashes and that
it would last four to six weeks and
should be gone after that. Um but it
continued and and seemed to be more
persistent and happened more frequently
and then I I became pregnant and then
once I got further in my pregnancy they
said oh it's pregnancy related and so
after you have this baby I'm sure that
these symptoms will go away but when my
baby was 6 weeks old I went back to the
doctor and because they had not gone
away in fact I had some blurred vision
you know that um that occurred as well
and that's when I was diagnosed with an
with a tumor with an ocular melanoma
with a sixe old. A six week old. Okay.
That's right. And with a significant
delay because no one would have expected
it. That's right. And also, you had
those same flashes. I did. So, did you
did you call your friends? What? How did
you It was about a year and a half after
Julie was diagnosed and we we had been
praying for her for a year and a half.
So, I immediately called her when I got
in the car after they diagnosed me. I
had had flashes of light for 7 to 10
days and towards the end of the 10 days,
lost partial vision in my right eye. Oh
my goodness. So went thinking it was a
retinal detachment to have my retina
repaired. And as they looked in they
said, "Well, there's a 10 millimeter
tumor sitting on your retina." So let me
just show these are the medical charts
for all three of you for the audience to
look at actually more with you because
you know your stories, right? And I put
them all up there because I want you to
see the symptoms and the treatments and
there's some similarities including the
fact that you all had your eyes removed
which is often done for this. So, let's
talk a little bit about this because you
first of all, I'm really happy you stuck
together because it's going to allow us
to get to the next part of the story,
but I want to do something else. You
know, there are hundreds of people
around the country, hundreds of people
who apparently are supporting you right
now and a lot of them actually flew in
today. Yes. Put your hands up. Put your
hands up if you have ocular melanoma.
There's a lot of folks and I got to say
it is it's very rewarding to me as a
physician to understand that if I do
what I'm trained to do which is try to
diagnose and treat you'll have social
support around you to lift you up and do
what I sometimes can't do which is give
you confidence and and make sure you see
the opportunities out there in your life
and Alison I know this has been
difficult for you because your tumor
spread to if I understand correctly 17
parts of your body. Yes. So, how do you
stay so upbeat when I I know you're
struggling with that reality? Well, it's
totally the Lord for sure. The prayer
that has carried us through. Well, those
stories that faith comes us in many ways
and I think you're sitting next to a
couple people who represent that. So,
let me get us all on the story because
this is a mystery in to me still. And
over the course of this show today, I'm
going to ask you to look for patterns to
be part of this because you're maybe
living in a similar pattern yourself.
Just like these women and doctors have
been struggling to find out what's going
on. I'm going to recount. We've got
three women. You just met them, right?
They're all living, all these three
women in the same dorm on the campus of
Auburn University in the late 80s. So,
what happened when these women started
to tell people what was going on,
especially using social media? Stay
tuned as this medical mystery unfolds.
Is chicken the new brain food?
We know omega-3s can be found in fish,
but chicken you feel smarter now. Yeah.
All new
Oas. That's coming up on Monday. This is
Julie, Ashley, and Allison. They all
went to the same
university, lived in the same dorm
around the same time of each
other, and now they've mysteriously all
ended up getting this rare form of eye
cancer. Wow. I'm trying to figure out
how this happened and could there
possibly be more people.
My producers and medical unit have been
hard at work trying to unravel this
medical mystery. a group of college
friends all ending up with the same
cancer. Were there more or is this just
a coincidence? Well, Ashley posted on
Facebook and people who went to the same
university started coming out of the
woodwork. 30 people in total. 30 all
diagnosed with ocular
melanoma. So, I want to introduce one of
those people to you. Lori also attended
Auburn University in the late 80s. She
saw Ashley's Facebook post and it I
guess you got a chill down your spine if
I understand correctly. Lori, it was
awakening. You know, you um I had a
friend of mine who actually saw her post
and then she sent me the link. She said,
you know, you you need to check into
this. Um unlike them, I did not have
this camaraderie of knowing anybody. So,
I was navigating all of this on my own.
So, what did Auburn University say when
you informed them that there were 30
graduates who are all suffering from the
same kind of eye cancer, ocular
melanoma? Um, the university got
involved and they appointed an
incredible man that we're all thrilled
with. His name is Dr. Fred Cam. He has a
medical clinic on campus and basically
Dr. Cam went to the university and they
said, "We we need to be a part of this.
We need to help fund some of this
research. We need to see what's going
on." So, we actually reached out to
Auburn. wanted to hear what they had to
say. They offered the statement to us.
OPER will continue to participate,
support the Alabama Department of Public
Health and melanoma experts as they
determine what next steps should be
taken in the best interests of the
patients. Good for them. So, in cases
like this, medical professionals
collaborate with health officials. It's
not easy, right? Because you're you got
doctors know about eye tumors and you've
got health officials know about the
epidemiology, the environment that we're
all living in. Dr. Dr. Marina Olaf is an
oncologist who has treated some of these
women and is actively working with
health officials to solve this medical
mystery. So explain what a cancer
cluster is. What what what has to happen
for you to be able to call it a cancer
cluster? Yeah. So a cancer cluster has a
very strict definition. If you want to
look at the number of observed cases, so
how many people are actually diagnosed
versus what the expected number of cases
is for a very specific uh location. Um,
and unfortunately we haven't really been
able to apply those statistics to these
scenarios because not everyone was
living in the specific location of
concern at the time of their diagnosis.
So we think there's probably about a 10
to 15 year lag time between potentially
a mutual exposure if there was one and
the development of the cancer. But the
way you traditionally look at cancer
clusters does not take that into
consideration. So we've had to develop
our own uh unique way of of looking at
this. So here's why I'm concerned. These
are factors and you you might be exposed
to one of these or not like nuclear
waste, radioactive material, even RF
waves, radio frequency, water to water
could be a problem, other toxins, the
environment, power lines and power
plants come up all the time as do cell
towers these days, landfills, even
things like as specialists which we know
are correlated. So as an expert and you
look at these things, how does a viewer
know if all their friends are getting
sick because you've all been exposed to
something that you might be prone to
also? Yeah. So that's when we've really
put a big team together. So it's not
just myself, it's not just the medical
oncologists um you know both in
Philadelphia, we worked with our
colleagues down in North Carolina at
Duke and now our colleagues in Alabama
to really put together a thorough
investigation and looking at these
things. So the first thing you need to
do is put everybody at the same place at
the same time. So that's part of the
geospatial analysis and once you can do
that and that goes through interviews.
So it's well where did you live? Well,
how much time did you spend there? Well,
where were you working? Where you know
did you play a sport? What fields were
you playing on? Um, and then you can
actually overly any concerns that there
may be in any of these environmental
concerns. And so then when you put that
all of that together and there's any red
flags, then we can actually go delve
deeper down um to see if there's any
potential cause. So let me give everyone
a little bit of advice on this. If you
suspect a cancer cluster in your
community, talk to your doctor first.
Let them know because they'll talk to
the other doctors. And more importantly,
become your own detective. Start your
own investigation. You just saw the
power of social media and it can help
you too. What I what I'm talking about,
right? And and that's a perfect example
of something happened at my office as we
began researching this show. Literally
take a look what happened when one of my
directors read the script. Just saw the
script for this show.
I read your script this morning and I
immediately went on Facebook and tagged
everybody I know from my college breast
cancer. Me and so far I found five other
people who went to my school, either
lived in my dorm or another dorm. And
I'm investigating to see who else. I've
tagged everybody I know to see if I
could find more people. Can a brain scan
reveal if you're a psychopath? The
daughter of a serial killer faces her
darkest fears. All new Oz. That's coming
up on
[Music]
Tuesday. When you get a scary medical
diagnosis, one of the first thoughts
that leaps to your mind is, "How did
this happen? How'd this happen to me?"
Well, when these four college friends
found out they were among 30 people from
their former university that had come
down with the exact same kind of eye
cancer, they got together. They made the
medical mystery their mission. They're
here today with an important message for
you. I'm going to start with Dr. John
Mason who's an opthalmologist who's also
on the task force looking for clues to
understand how 30 people from Auburn
University all got diagnosed with ocular
melanoma kind of eye cancer. So, let's
look for more clues. Help us with this.
So as you look at this, who's more
likely to get eye cancer taking
everybody into account? Yeah, we know
that about 2,000 cases in our country
occur per year. 7,000 worldwide is
typically patients that are light
complexed, fair complexed, patients that
are typically between the ages of 50 and
65. Can be younger, can be older. I've
treated teenagers with this. All these
women were younger. Absolutely. So
that's not unusual. Often blue-eyed,
greeneyed rather than browneyed. Yeah.
So again, light complexion, blue eyes.
And what about the issue of exposure to
the sun? That's debatable. That is
debatable. Half the studies have shown
that UV exposure is related. Half the
studies have shown that UV exposure is
not related to ocular melanoma despite
the light colored eyes. That's true. All
right. And what about hazardous
chemicals which is something that comes
up always when you worry about these
cancer occurrences that are more
frequent than you expect. Yeah. The
unique thing about ocular melanoma is we
have never identified an environmental
trigger. We do not know what in the
environment causes ocular melanoma.
That's the purpose of the study. That's
why we want to do the study. Then
perhaps we can find an answer. It's
going to be one of four answers. So it
either be environmental, genetics, a
combination of both or coincidental. But
we need the study. These ladies deserve
the study. A lot of folks aren't going
to get symptoms. Yeah. This is going to
save lives. That's why we're doing the
show today. It's not It's a mystery that
actually leads to lives being saved. If
you're sitting at home right now and
you're worried you've got a problem with
your eye, even a tumor, what do you do?
What do you recommend? I think uh every
single patient in our country needs an
annual eye exam, a dilated eye exam. We
need we can see diabetes in the eye,
hypertension in the eye, glaucoma,
melanoma, a host of diseases. The eye is
a window to the world. All right. So get
an eye exam with the drop so it dilates
it. Absolutely. Thank you very much. All
right. There's going to be someone
watching today that may have gone to the
same school with friends who developed a
similar cancer. Maybe they went to
Auburn and have ocular melanoma. So may
actually let me finish with you since
you posted this out here and we're going
to put the m melanoma patient from
Auburn on our dr.com site. So folks are
out there. There's the page right now.
You know, let us know. Let's help solve
this mystery. Let's give the doctors
some tools to figure out what's causing
this. What is your biggest hope actually
going forward? So we have a a website.
It's called
ipatchchallenge.org. And and people are
familiar with the ice bucket challenge.
We have something called the eye patch
challenge. And we actually want to
challenge you today. Oh. So we have
something for you. Lori wants to give
you ice. We have an eye patch and our um
Yes. So, the premise behind the eye
patch challenge is that we want to
encourage people to to raise awareness
and to raise funds for the research
we're doing at Auburn. What do you
think? I like it. I like it. And they
try to
do I look diabolical? Very much so. Very
much so. So, um, the idea is that we are
going to challenge you to do something
with the eye patch on to help raise
awareness and then to also challenge
someone else, you know, nominate someone
else to do this. Um, you can go on
patchchallenge.org and make a donation
for the research that we're being that's
being done at Auburn, which we
appreciate. I'm going to go do something
sportive with my kids, leaving the odds
out. Thank you for what you've done. I'm
very proud of you for getting together,
for being brave, for supporting each
other, but also finding the cure. This
is how we're going to change health in
America. It's stories like this. God
bless you. For all the melanoma patients
in the back, God bless you. We're going
to share resources on how and when to
get your eyes checked on dr.com. I'll be
right back with my
[Music]
patch. Up next, today's show anchor
Savannah Guthrie is here with a big
health question that all of you are
asking, and it is, why can't I stay
asleep? Stick around.
I recently heard one of my friends who
you all love, today's show anchor
Savannah Guthrie, had a big question
about sleep for me. Now, we all know she
wakes up extra early to bring you the
biggest news of the day, and recently
she's been having a little sleep
struggle that you can all relate to.
Come on out, Savannah
Guthrie. I know.
Hi. I'm so happy you are here. I know.
Hi. They've been waiting for you with Hi
everybody. Nice to see you. So happy you
are here. I'm so happy to be here. This
is my first time on your show. You've
been on the first time. I know you've
been on the Today's Show. We have you
every week. But well, we have lots of
good excuses to talk to you today. That
look like a rough rough night of sleep.
Is that typical? Yes, it is. I mean,
that could have been last night. the
snoring husband. Sorry, sweetie. The the
crying baby and then the early wakeup
call. And I It happens. I mean, I I
mean, I think every person who works on
these kind of morning shifts probably
doesn't get enough sleep, but I I just
have a hard time falling back asleep
once I anything wakes up. I'm like, my
mind starts working. And the thing is,
we all watch you at 7 a.m. promptly on
the day show. You look so chipper, so
awake. You get up at 4 in the morning.
How do you do that? Well, coffee. You
know, coffee is big. Um, you know, I
trudge in with my hair wet and in my
sweats and they like perform a miracle
in the hair and makeup department. I
don't know what they do, but they make
me look presentable. And I also think
there's just there's a natural energy
and excitement that you just kind of you
get up for it. So, before you became a
mom? Yeah. Were you able to sleep
better? Yes. I mean, yes, I think I did.
I mean, even when I worked in news and
I'd have these early morning gigs, I
wouldn't sleep that much, but I could
sleep well. And once I fell asleep, I
was dead to the world. Now, I mean, I
was just thinking about it. I My kids
wake up pretty much every night. You get
two kids, like the chances of both
sleeping are almost like impossible. So,
when they wake up, they go back to sleep
again. But waking up in the middle of
the night is so common among our
viewers. Yeah. Well, there first of all,
anybody who works on a morning show is
obsessed with sleep. It's like all you
talk about. You think about when am I
going to sleep? Am I going to get a
chance to have a nap? Like, I'm the most
boring person in the world. I only want
to talk about sleep. But I have a few
tricks. I have earplugs that I use. And
then I do have like a few little tricks
to calm myself. First of all, never ever
check your phone. Like what I did in
that video is the absolute worst thing
to do. Yeah, that bright light turns off
any little bit of melatonin you might be
making. Yes. And then you see the time
and there's probably a text message that
comes up or a news alert and it just
gets the wheels turning. So I try really
hard. I actually put an alarm clock next
to my bed so that I could just look at a
regular clock to see the time and not
have to tap the phone. So, uh, I do that
and then I have I have I actually have a
Bible verse I memorized when I was 12
years old. Goodness. Psalm 23 and I say
it to myself and I almost always I'm
kind of falling to sleep by the end by
the time I've said it times. Oh, the
whole thing. No, just a little bit. Oh,
you know, the Lord is my shepherd. I
shall not want. He makes me lay down in
green pastures. He leads me beside the
still waters. He restores my soul. It's
a very pastoral and calming song. But I
think if you know I happen to learn that
as a 12-year-old kid, but anything that
you memorized, there's something about
reciting it to yourself in your mind
that calms you. It works for me every
time. Yeah, it's meditative. Come on
over here. You actually allowed us to
pry into the to your brain a little bit
and look into your sleep score. So, if
you stand right over here, I'm going to
put the sleep score up here. Okay.
Again, it's just it's a simple little
way of a cool app. Yeah, I know. I like
it, too. So, you actually did really
well. I was shocked at this. I think I
had a terrible night's sleep last night
and I got a 79. You did? But I'll tell
you why I got a 79. It was interesting.
Yeah. C++. Ju just to break it down.
C++. Right. Just to break it down, a
couple things. First of your body score
was only a 52. What does that mean? So
it if you look at how you sleep, not all
parts of sleep help you the same amount.
The part of sleep that's most important
for your brain is the REM sleep, your
dream sleep. And you just knock the
further these lines are over, the better
off you did. So look how well you did
with your REM, which is just fantastic.
your deep sleep, which is important for
your body, wasn't so good. So, you got a
52 in your body score, but you had 97 in
your mind. So, that's a pretty good
number. Okay. So, net net, the only
thing I'd work on is deep sleep. And the
only way to get more deep sleep for you
probably is to sleep longer, to be in
bed longer, which I know is hard. I
would like to do that. I'm for that.
What if we started the Today Show at
9:00 a.m. That's be so much easier if
you want to watch.
The other thing that happens with sleep
issues, especially if your body is not
sleeping well, is you'll feel tired. you
feel and actually we were talking uh
socially at a separate uh gathering and
you mentioned you were on the on the
paleo diet keto diet. The keto diet.
Yes. I I did a little summer experiment.
I saw you at a party and you were like
you're on the keto diet. I said yeah I
don't know if I'm in ketosis. Can I tell
everybody what you said? Yes. I it was
so embarrassing. He goes, "Well, breathe
on me." And I'm like, "I don't want to
breathe on you. I'm at a party. That's
so rude." He's like, "Breathe on me."
And then he said, "You're not in keto."
Because one of the things is supposedly
have bad breath when you're in keto. You
smell like acetone. You'll be I didn't
have bad breath, right? No, you dealt
very well with it. No, my breath was
like tequila. That's why. That's why.
Exactly. Did you Did you like being on
the keto diet? You know what? I liked
it. I I you know, I mean, I'm not really
trying to like lose weight or anything,
but you know, we might overeat and
you're like, I like to lose two, three
pounds, 5 lbs. So, I did it and I did
like it. Um, and I'm still kind of doing
it. It's, you know, it's a lot of meat
and cheese and like it's like meat
salad, you know? It's like salad and
some grilled chicken, but you can get
more fat, which is kind of fun. So, in
some ways that you have to deprive
yourself. no carbs whatsoever and that's
really restrictive, but it's opened up
some things that I would never let
myself eat a lot of such as like cheese
and bacon. So, I like that. Do you feel
energized on it? You know, I don't I
feel less energy in the sense of like I
don't want to work out anymore. I don't
feel any I think I need those carbs to
want to go on a run or do aerobics or do
whatever I might do. But Hodis says she
thinks it's making me my mind sharper.
Like I was remembering things that were
kind of sh like she's like, "How do you
even know that?" I'd be like, "Oh, that
was on page 252 of that book." She's
like, "Where's this coming from? This
keto diet's insane." So, I do feel like
it made me a little sharper. Well,
that's part of the process, I think, is
you know, you experiment with these
diets, not just to lose weight, is to be
able to match it up with the rest of
your lifestyle. This being a good
example of why you're sharp, that might
be an additional one. However, if I want
to improve deep sleep and I want you to
access your body score better, since I
can't get you to lie in bed more, I'm
going to try some food hacks. Okay.
You're up for it. I of course. All
right. When we come back, we investigate
what are the best foods to eat for
sleep. And I think I found out the truth
about Savannah's secret obsession. Stay
tuned.
[Applause]
We know omega-3s can be found in fish,
but chicken, you feel smarter now. Yeah.
All new Oz. That's coming up on
[Music]
Monday. We are back on today's show.
anchor Savannah Guthrie and we're
investigating what foods you can eat to
get you a more restful night. But first,
I want to show something that Savannah
posted on Instagram that I loved and my
wife especially appreciated.
When is it okay to ask women if she is
pregnant? Oh my god. And notice the
answers. For the first seven months,
it's no. And after that, it's also no.
Why? Why' you post this? I would add
like if you're in the hospital actually
giving birth, it's still no. Don't ask
are you pregnant? Not until you hear the
baby cry. No. What? Not until the
child's an adult. Exactly. You know what
I mean? I I posted it because from time
to time people might on Twitter or
something say like, "Oh, are you
expecting again?" Which no, I'm not. And
you know, but I did have two babies and
I'm 46 years old, so you know, I don't
have like a washboard abs or anything.
Um, but I wore this polkadotted dress
one day and suddenly I guess it wasn't
the most flattering dress ever because
the whole internet was like, "Savannah's
pregnant. Are you hiding? Your bun in
the oven?" Blah blah blah. Which of
course I thought the dress looked good.
I had to go then burn it. And um, that's
when I posted it up. I was like, "Yeah,
no." So, I think it's just a good rule
of thumb. No matter what a woman looks
like, let them tell you she's pregnant.
You don't need to ask. You all agree
with that, right? Yeah. All right. Let's
talk about sleeps and quick fixes. First
off, what time do you normally have
dinner? You got to be in bed by 10:00.
So, bed by 10? I go to bed by 8. Oh, you
do? Yes, I have to. Oh, no wonder you
did so well on your sleep score. I was
surprised. Oh, yeah. Well, I get in bed
by 8. I might not be able to fall asleep
till 9 or so, but my kids go to bed at
7:00, so we all eat dinner around 6:00.
Um 600 6:30. So 2 hours before bedtime.
Yeah. By 700 I should I'm not eating.
Yeah. All right. Come on over. Let's
talk about some specific foods. I'm
basically on a toddler schedule. That's
right. So Snoozy salmon. The first
recommendation. We talk about salmon for
almost everything having to do with the
heart, the brain, everything else. It
turns out that it has B vitamins in it,
which is how your brain makes serotonin,
which is of course a tryptophan, which
is of course the key ingredient that
turkey has in it that makes you tired.
Okay. So if I have salmon for dinner,
it'll help. It will help. And you want
to get it at least three hours before if
you can only because you have time to
digest it and get it to your brain. At
least three I should stop eating two
hours before. Okay? But give your brain
at least three hours to absorb whatever
nutrients you want to give it. That's
general rule of thumb. Even if you take
melatonin, you got to take it early
enough that it can get into your brain.
Oh. So when people take it at two in the
morning, it's not going to work at 2:15.
I'm always like, "That doesn't work for
me." No. Okay. Now I know. All right.
That was good. Should I try it? No, you
don't have to. How do you cook your
salmon? Um, well, I'm not a big chef, as
you may know, Dr. eyes from watching the
Today Show, but I usually would grill
it. My favorite, too. All right, next
up. This is my favorite favorite
favorite thing. Tart cherry juice.
Really? Because I mentioned melatonin
earlier. This is the best food source
for it. And my father grew up on a tart
cherry farm in the central Turkey,
Anatolia. You're kidding. And that's
where I learned to drink and fall in
love with this beverage. One cup a
night. Okay. Really? You a whole cup?
You don't have to drink the whole cup,
but ideally the studies have shown that
when you drink a cup worth of it, you'll
get better quality sleep during the
evening. Now, is that real sugary?
Should I be worried about pecking on the
pounds? Which is why it should be your
alternative drink for the day if you're
going to make it. However, I what I
generally do just do a shot of it. But I
take it like this if you'll join me. Is
that a shot ski? This is a shotski.
Okay. I knew See, it's Dr. Oz after
dark. Are you ready doing it? Okay.
Ready?
It's very good. Andy Cohen, eat your
heart out. Seriously, he's going to be
so jealous of us. I bet we got you put a
little tequila in there, too. No, that's
a a woman after my heart. I know, right?
Woman after my heart. That was good.
Now, that's my favorite, but this will
surprise you the most. Okay. Kiwi. Yeah.
I don't know what your thoughts are on
it, but kiwi has actually been studied
and it helps the quality and the
quantity of sleep. Both, which is most
things haven't been proven to do both.
This does that. Kiwi, if you're going to
really do it the right way, the way they
do it in New Zealand, you have to eat
the skin, though. Isn't the skin hairy?
Well, I want you to try. This is a
special kind of golden kiwi. Okay,
that's uh a little thinner skinned.
Okay, and you get all the folate if you
do this, by the way. More fiber, 50%.
Not bad. Not bad. Like I might do it
again or never again will I try never
again. This is my first and last kiwi.
No, it's good. It's kind of It's tart,
but I The skin is not pleasant. Well, I
always think about eating fruit the way
people eat it where they actually grow
it. If they're eating the skin in New
Zealand, that's what Okay, good. It's
like eating the skin of an apple. Now,
but I'll leave this for you. I bring up
key reason part because I know that you
were infatuated by pineapples, all kinds
of fruit, by pineapples in particular.
And I finally know why. It's because
there's this person, Princess Penelopey
Pineapple. Yes, she is the star of all
Savannah's books. And not only is she
named after the fruit, but she's got all
kinds of cool things around her,
including other princesses like Princess
Strawberry, Princess Blueberry. Yes. And
I love the adventure so much that I sent
the book to my daughter Daphne. And
Daphne actually read it to my kids, my
grandkids. Take a look. Okay, we are.
We're going to read it right now.
Princesses save the world. Princesses
save the world. Your name is Princess
Save the World. Penny encouraged the
princesses to look for anything fragrant
that might work as a hook. Out of their
bags, they pulled all things smelly.
Perfume, peppermints, peanut butter, and
jelly.
It's the greatest book ever. It's our
favorite.
[Applause]
They gave it two thumbs up. The greatest
book ever. I've never gotten anything
like that out of Felo. She's the
toughest critic. Well, thank you, Felo.
What a little doll. Well, you write
about like heart disease and stuff. Yes,
this is more gripping. It's so cute.
Thank you, Daffhne. Beautifully
illustrated. Well done. But there's a
deeper meaning to the book which I think
is why Daphne liked reading it to the
kids over and over again. Would you
share that with the audience? Yeah. You
know, it's funny. So, this all came out,
my friend and I that wrote it together.
We both have daughters and our daughters
were into princesses and we're like,
where does this come from? You know, and
what does it all mean? We are not anti-
princess. We're all about the glitter
and the fun. In fact, this cover is full
of glitter. Um, but the idea was like,
how can we make a princess who's a girl
of substance? You know, when you think
about what a princess is, it's a young
lady in a leadership role. And so, we
kind of came up with this idea. Princess
Penelopey Pineapple. And in the first
book, which is called Princesses Wear
Pants, it's all about she's a girly
girl. She has her tears and her gowns,
but she's got things to do. And when she
has things to do, she wears her pants.
And in Princesses Save the World, we
meet some of her fellow princesses from
the other fruit kingdoms. Princess
Strawberry, Princess Apple, Princess
Plum. They all get together and solve a
problem, a big problem, a world-saving
problem. But here's the part that I like
the most. You actually pay tribute to
the sweetest member of the ecosystem,
bees. That's right. And I actually have
beehives. I beekeeper. Yes. There I am
with my son Oliver. Yep. And we just
harvested
our newest honey. Oh my gosh. The
private stash from my Oh my goodness.
This is so exciting.
Dr. Oz honey. I'm so Do I get to keep
this? It's yours. It's not pasteurized.
It's a medicine. Honey was the oldest
medicine known by doctors. You know
what's funny? my little boy's sick and
my doctor told me last night, give him a
little spoonful of honey before bed and
now I have really special honey to do
that with. I love you. Thank you,
Savannah. Thank you so much. Be sure to
check out Savannah's new children's
book, Princesses Save the World is in
stores today and very well done. Thank
you very much, my dear. Be right back.
Pleasure.
Can a brain scan reveal if you're a
psychopath? The daughter of a serial
killer faces her darkest fears. All new
Oz.
That's coming up on
[Music]
[Applause]
Tuesday. Roughly 26 million Americans
suffer from asthma. But not everyone's
asthma is the same. There's a severe
kind of asthma. It's called eocinophilic
asthma or e asthma for short. And today
I want to help you understand if your
asthma could be severe easthma and what
you can do about it. Here to help
explain is Dr. Amina Ramirez who's here
on behalf of my trusted sponsorship
partner Astroenica. Thanks for being
here. Good morning. Good morning. All
right. So explain what easthma is. Easma
or eosinaphilic asthma is a is a kind of
severe asthma. Uh and there are many
different kinds of asthma. The
eosinaphil is a type of white blood cell
that's a normal part of our immune
system. But for some people with severe
asthma, eosinaphils can cause
inflammation in the airways. Yeah. So,
the question is, could that be you? To
help determine if your asthma could be e
asthma, Dr. Ramirez is going to walk us
through a four question quiz. Everyone
at home, please follow along with this.
This is an area that's rapidly changing,
so we want to try to keep up with it.
So, walk us through the questions.
Number one, do you often use your rescue
inhaler to control your asthma symptoms?
Yes or no? It's pretty simple. There
only four questions. Question number
two, do your asthma symptoms wake you up
in the middle of the night?
Question number three,
have you ever taken oral steroids for
your asthma? That's an important one.
Again, think carefully about yourself,
but also people who are dear to you. And
question number four, have your asthma
attacks ever led to an urgent care or
emergency room visit. Okay. Now, if you
answered yes to one or more of these
questions, your asthma may be
uncontrolled and you might have severe
eosinophilic asthma or easthma. So, I
didn't know that much about this when I
first started to study this, but I've
learned quite a bit. So, please explain
to everybody how common this really is.
Well, up to about 50% of people with
severe asthma have elevated eosinaphils
in their airways. Half of the people.
So, let me explain to you all what this
really means with animation that I want
you to meet somebody. So, this is what
might happen to your body if you have
come join me over here. Yes. So, let's
just say you take a deep breath in,
right? And a healthy airway goes the air
goes through your mouth, through your
nose, through the the trachea, goes into
the lungs, right? But in asthma, you can
have triggers like for pollen, for
example, enter the airway and it causes
swelling and a mucous buildup. See this
green mucus buildup, right? And that can
limit air flow and lead to an asthma
attack where you're gasping for air. But
when you have easthma, you may have
abundance of these little things, these
purple eosinophils, that's what they're
called. They're a special type of white
blood cell that enters the lungs and can
cause inflammation, right? And that's
why sometimes we again we don't know why
some people are more likely to get e
asthma. But these cells can be activated
after exposure to the triggers you know
about things like pollen and dander and
dust and mold viruses hot and cold
weather which is why you can sometimes
get attacks and understand what's going
on. So how can you find out if your
asthma is of this eocinophilic type the
the e asthma? Well, getting a simple
blood test that can be done by your
doctor is a very good start. And
depending upon the results, you'd see an
allergist or pulmonologist who would
make the official diagnosis of
eosinophilic asthma based on your
specific medical history, examination,
and lab test and then be able to
prescribe the appropriate course of
action. Great. So, I want you to meet
someone now because no one knows more
about how this blood test can help with
the right diagnosis than Kosh who's here
on behalf of Astroenica. So you took
some steps to regain your health and one
of those steps is really important was
to understand that she actually had this
type of of e asthma. So what were the
symptoms that you were experiencing? Uh
Dr. Oz uh my asthma was impacting my
day-to-day life. I was struggling to go
upstairs to my second floor for 8 years.
I did not have energy at all. and we
would go on vacations and people would
go on hikes and they would uh be um on
top of the uh hike and I would be the
very last person taking inhalers and I
found myself taking inhalers uh rescue
inhalers and uh use several uh allergy
pills but nothing seems to be helping
and my asthma was not well controlled. I
was having asthma attacks and having
trouble breathing. So how has your life
changed now that you realize you have e
asthma and are trying a different
treatment approach? Dr. Oz, now my life
has changed for better. I have uh e
asthma is well controlled. I did not
know that uh that people have e asthma
and I didn't know either and a lot of
people don't. So when I learned that my
asthma uh was e asthma and my
eosinaphils were high uh I was excited
to talk about my treatment option with
my doctor and because I was so miserable
with my uh asthma and my current
treatment plan was not working. So
knowing the root cause of my asthma and
being able to find the uh right
medication that worked for me best made
me feel powerful and I was uh more
controlled. Um my asthma was well
controlled. I can breathe better. I made
it a point to use my stairs bathroom for
showers. I enjoy going on walks. I uh
take stairs as much as I can and I just
uh it's been amazing. You feel like
you're your old self again. I feel like
my old self again. I can go back doing
things that I used to. I'm very happy
for you. Thank you very much so much.
Thank you. Great. Thank you very much.
If you think your asthma could be e
asthma, take the quiz and bring the
results to your doctor. You can head to
dr.com for lots more information. I'll
be right back.
This segment was brought to you by
Astroenica. Is chicken the new brain
food? We know omega-3s can be found in
fish, but chicken you feel smarter now.
Yeah. All new Oz. That's coming up on
Monday.
[Music]
I love this video. Baby Shark has gone
viral with nearly 2 billion views on
that video alone. And kids, adults
across the world are singing and
dancing. The Baby Shark and post on
their Baby Shark challenge videos all
over social media. I want to show you my
grandkids, Felo and John John, just this
past weekend. This is how I heard about
the song.
Daddy
shark. Daddy
shark. Daddy shark. So you can see Fo
dances to our own drummer. John's very
organized though. And all kids are
different. It's sort of cool. But as a
result of this Baby Shark Mania, many of
you can't get that song out of your
head, can you? And tell you what, it's
going to be stuck there the rest of the
day. So, that got me thinking about the
science of Baby Shark and what it might
be doing to your brain. So, I thought
I'd help you with this. When a song gets
stuck in your head, that's all happened.
Right. Right. It's called an earworm.
Fast songs with simple remedies like
Baby Shark are the biggest offenders.
But here's a question. What's the best
way to get rid of it? It's to lean in
and let it run its course. So, I have a
big announcement today. There have been
almost 40 Oz babies born since I started
this show. 10 years ago and I brought
some of those Oz kids here to lead the
audience in your very own Baby Shark
challenge. So, come on out. My executive
producer Amy's daughter Harper and my
supervising producer Christine's
daughter Andy Mila and Hadley. Oh. Oh,
they're so cute. They're so beautiful,
aren't they? All right. Are you guys
ready to sing with me? Do Baby Shark. Is
that what you want to do? Mhm. You like
Baby Shark? Yes. Is this the Baby Shark
one? The first one? No, this one. Oh,
this one's Baby Shark. Okay. And And
what's mommy's shark? Mommy shark is
like this. And what's daddy's shark?
Daddy shark like this. Okay. And And
what's grandma shark? Okay. And most
importantly, what's grandpa shark? Yes.
Notice grandpa shark has no teeth.
There's no teeth on grandpa shark. Are
y'all ready to do this? Yeah. All right.
Put it on,
Scott. Baby
Shark. Baby Shark. Doo doo doo doo. Baby
Shark. Doo doo doo doo doo doo. Baby
Shark. Mommy Shark. Doo doo doo doo doo
doo. Mommy Shark. Doo doo doo doo doo
doo. Mommy Shark. The whole audience is
doing Shark. Doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Daddy Shark. Doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Daddy Shark. Grandma Shark. Doo doo doo
doo doo doo. Grandma Shark. Doo doo doo
doo doo doo. Look at the audience.
They're all doing the shark. They're a
big one. Grandpa shark. Doo doo doo doo
doo. Grandpa shark. Doo doo doo doo doo.
D shark. Doo doo doo doo doo doo. Doctor
shark. Are you ready to go hunting?
Let's go hunting. Let's go hunting.
Let's go hunting.
Let's go hunting. The
[Music]
audience. Run away. Run away. Run away.
It's a shark. Run away. Run away. Run
away. Run away. Run away. Run away. Back
down again. Back down again. They're all
safe at
last. Safe at
last. Safe at last. Oh, they were
wonderful. They're gone. What kids do?
They leave me. All right. Thank you very
much. I'll see you next time.
[Music]
[Applause]