Pork, tender, and misunderstood.
Most people have no appreciation of how
valuable this could be in their diet.
We have Oz approved cuts of pork.
They had a cleanness to it that I enjoy.
And the ultimate bacon buyer guide.
I didn't know about this. Is
unbelievable.
Plus, her memory would erase in less
than 10 minutes.
She's living the real life version of
51st dates.
All I've got to focus on is right now.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10?
Yeah.
[Music]
I love you guys.
[Applause]
We all love the taste and smell of pork
and bacon. You see it there, right? You
see how excited the audience is over
this? The crispiness, the juiciness, the
Oh, well, we can't forget about that
delicious flavor. It's all there bundled
up. But could there actually be a
conspiracy going on to get you and your
family to eat more bacon? And what are
the healthy cuts of pork you should be
buying for your family? Today, our
biggest bacon and pork investigation
ever. And I mean ever. We're going to
start with Jen from my audience. She
says she is enjoying the bacon boom. How
serious is your love of bacon and pork
and all things piggly?
Well, I think it all started because
recently I started a low carb, highfat
diet.
So, of course, everybody loves bacon and
I can get it anywhere everywhere I go in
the store. I I swear I keep waiting for
them to make a vending machine with
bacon in it, right?
And literally I breakfast, lunch,
dinner, I'm always craving it. I think
I'm I'm literally might turn into a pig.
I've been eating it so much.
All right. So, you speak for so many of
the audience. We get some answers for
you because I have some concerns as well
as some good things about pork and
bacon. So, I invited food investigator
and author of the Dorito Effect, Mark
Shasker, an investigative reporter
Marakmpo to help get to the meat of the
matter. But first, some have noticed
that fast food companies are adding more
bacon to the menus. Have you all noticed
that?
Right. As Jen was pointing out, you can
have vending machines practically at
this point. Why do you think bacon is
being pushed so hard, Mara?
Well, you know, pork prices are the
lowest they've been in decades. And so,
these fast food companies have
definitely taken notice. They are
loading their menus with bacon items and
we're literally eating it up. There's
also these reports of this partnership
between the pork industry and fast food
companies where the restaurants will add
bacon to their menus to help offset
sales slumps. So, this bacon boom may be
a little more orchestrated than people
are aware of.
And for that to work, you'd have to
assume that pork is cheaper. And in
fact, it has become cheaper. I just
don't understand why, Mark.
So, there's a a perfect storm of events
happening to keep pork prices low. For
starters, corn and soybeans, which are
the main constituents of pig feed, well,
that those prices are low. That means
the pork is cheap. The American pork
industry is massively scaled. The farms
are huge. We feed pigs antibiotics. That
makes them grow faster, brings the price
down. And to top it all off, there's a
trade war with China. Now, China
historically is an enormous customer for
US pork. They buy it in the hundreds of
thousands of tons. Well, with China
buying less pork, that means there's a
lot more of it around here for us to
eat.
So, the prices may not be a problem. You
mentioned one thing with antibiotic.
Well, a lot of people think if they go
to a fancy butcher shop or if the
packaging looks nice, that means there
won't be any of that antibiotics. That
is not the way to do it. The truth is, I
would say if you don't see otherwise on
the packaging, assume the pigs have been
fed antibiotics. Now, a lot of people
say to me, why is that? Why are farmers
out to just dump all these antibiotics?
What's going on? Well, here's the thing.
When you feed pigs antibiotics, they
grow faster. you can put more pigs in
the barn. That brings the price down.
Farmers get paid by the pound. So the
farmers that aren't using antibiotics,
they might actually lose money. So the
logic of the market dictates that if
it's allowed, they pretty much have to
do it.
All right. So Mara says the color is
critical.
Yeah, you want to look for meat that is
light red to cherry red. You also want
to look for your fat. You want to make
sure that the meat is never like this,
never white or pale. You want to save
the white for the fat. You want to make
sure that that fat is nice and white and
creamy with no dark spots. Really tasty
pork is going to have that fat
interspersed and marbled in with that
lean meat.
This is not often what it looks like.
So, get picky now that you know what
you're supposed to look for. All right,
next issue. Mark, labels. And there are
lots of labels and some of them are
pretty commonly found. So, walk us
through the most common ones and then
you got a little surprise for us, I
understand.
Okay, so this is one we know certified
organic. This comes from pigs that have
never eaten feed that's been treated
with synthetic fertilizers or synthetic
pesticides. And if you see that
certified organic, it means no
antibiotics. So, you can trust that.
Now, most people think, oh, and that one
too, natural pork, right? You pigs are
outside, the sun is shining, the birds
are singing. That word, when it comes to
pork, that word natural, it tells you
nothing about how the pigs were raised.
It only tells you there's nothing added
to the pork after they were processed.
So, no preservatives or anything like
that. So natural is not telling a whole
lot. But here's the thing. If you do
like that idea of pigs outside, the
birds sing, the sunshining. What you are
interested in then is pastured pork.
This is the rarest, I would say. Really
hard to find. Go look for it at your
farmers market. But if you're into
flavor, that will blow you away. That is
my number one pork.
And you have one last little surprise
over there, which I didn't even know
existed.
Yeah. So there's a label you might see
called no rattopamine. And people say,
"What does that mean?" Well, ratopamine
is a drug. It's fed to turkeys, beef,
cattle, and pigs. And what it does is it
promotes lean muscle growth, limits fat
deposition. Basically, you get more meat
for a lower price. There are
consequences. However, the animals that
are treated with ratopamine can be quite
agitated and it can make the meat tough.
So, if you don't want pork treated with
ratopamine, look for this label or look
for the certified organic label that
those pigs also will not be treated with
ratopamine.
All right. So, we want to learn more
about this. He spoke to the pork gal. So
he said in part, "More than 300 studies
have affirmed ratopamine as safe and
there's been no confirmed human health
issues to eating the meat from animals
that were fed rattopamine." That's their
response and I understand that there's
probably some validity to that. But I
share your thoughts. If you don't want
to get that, your options here reward
people who are purposely avoiding the
antibiotics, avoiding back dopamine if
you think that's important. Now that we
know what to look for when shopping for
pork and bacon products, Mark and and
Mara scoured the supermarkets and talked
with butchers, actual butchers, about
the best cuts to buy. I didn't know any
of this stuff. I don't think you do
either. Stay with us. It's up next.
It's been 30 years since Ted Bundy's
execution, but his bloodline lives on.
He and his wife were able to have a
daughter while Ted was on death row.
Who is Ted Bundy's daughter?
Imagine knowing that you're carrying
these genes that you could potentially
become a psychopath yourself.
And where is she now? She changed her
name.
He's trying to pretend never happened.
Plus, she survived Ted Bundy.
I remember him asking me how I'd like to
die. And he put his hands on my throat
and started squeezing.
That's coming up tomorrow.
We were talking about the bacon and pork
boom, telling you what to look for when
buying the other white meat. And now I
have a guide to tell you exactly what
cuts to buy for your family. Mark and
Mar are back. Let's start with the most
important factor for many of you. Taste.
Mark, you're the flavor guy. What is the
tastiest cut of pork?
The tastiest cut is the pork butt.
The pork butt.
The pork butt. Now, it's not what you
think. It's not the butt. It is the
butt. It comes from the upper shoulder.
It is marbled. It is fatty. You can't
cook it like a pork chop. You got to
cook it low and slow. But it is
succulent and delicious.
Why would you call it the pork butt if
it's not from the butt?
To make it the butt of jokes, perhaps.
Did you all see that? Wait. So, it's
called the It's above the shoulder.
It's above the shoulder. Yes.
Crazy naming. Okay. Chef Alli Rosa
didn't question the name, but she sent
us this clip to show us how easy and
delicious it is to make pork butt.
The first thing I actually like to do is
cut up the pork butt because then you
have more surface for browning. Now,
we're going to start cooking.
[Music]
Now, we're going to salt the pork butt.
You want to make sure that every side
has a little bit of salt because you do
not want to be missing out on the flavor
here. Once your onions have softened a
little bit, now is the time to add the
pork butt. So now you're going to let
your pork butt brown, maybe for about 5
minutes, turning it over halfway
through. But the goal here is to really
get that brown color on the bottom and
on the sides of the pork butt. Once the
pork butt is seared, it's time to add
the rest of your ingredients.
And we're going to add two cups of
chopped herbs. I've used oregano,
parsley, cilantro, some chives, but
really this is a great excuse to use
whatever is in your crisper drawer. Then
we're going to mix everything in
together. Now, we're going to put the
top on.
All right, so we have some pork butt
right here. We all have a taste. Mara's
been tasting it and and actually Mark
Sher's mouth is so full he can't speak
for a while. So, describe the flavor,
Mara.
This is really, really tender. It has
just enough fat, so it's nice and juicy.
And the beautiful thing is it's going to
take on the flavor of whatever you're
cooking and marinating it with. It's
just delicious. I bet I could even get
my kids to eat this.
Yeah. You know, I tell you, I didn't
actually think it was pork when I first
started eating it. I wouldn't have get I
wouldn't have quite known it could have
been lamb. It but it had a a cleanness
to it that I enjoyed a lot. Mark,
it's just so soft and tender and juicy.
I I love it.
Right. So, we know what what flavor what
part of the pig dean. Okay. Come on over
here. Next to our buyer's guide is this
whole issue of price. Now, listen, folks
have to be careful about money. You're
an amazing reporter, but you're a mom
also.
And as and you know to be mom, do it the
right way. You got to pay attention to
money. Absolutely. So the two worlds
collide when it comes to being gourmand
having the the pig butt over there and
getting the best cut. What did you find
work?
Yeah, we all got to watch our family
budget, right? The pork shoulder is a
really affordable cut. You can buy bone
in or boneless. It's really rich in fat
and connective tissue. This is really
flavor on a budget because it's going to
be pretty much just as tasty as that
pork butt that we just had, but for much
less price,
right? So, it's very close. You see the
picture, everybody. Uh, but it's below
it. And because of that, it tends to be
a very good price. The pork butts a lot
more expensive than this. I checked into
it. These are all pretty affordable
prices for most folks. But if it's
important to you, Scholers Way to go.
Okay, last up, the overall healthiest
cut of pork, which I know you two don't
talk about very much, but I care about
this. So, Mark, ran the numbers. Your
thoughts. The healthiest selexia cut is.
Well, if you're looking for leanness, it
is the pork tenderloin. A 3oz serving
has 3 g of fat. It has 120 calories.
This is as lean as boneless, skinless
breast of chicken. But unlike boneless,
skinless breast of chicken, it actually
has flavor. That's why I love this.
That's right. That is the problem with
with boneless skinless chicken. It
doesn't have any. It's like tofu,
which you normally I'd like if you put
something tasty around it, but by itself
doesn't have anything. Just to put a
head-to-head comparison, here's that
generally speaking bland piece of
poultry. And and here's our tenderloin
pig. Three grams of fat, 120 calories in
the 3 oz serving. I think this is a home
run. Most people have no appreciation of
how valuable this could be in their
diet.
Am I am I saying it right?
I was shocked to see these numbers that
it's the same nutritionally
and kids actually like this cuz I fed it
to our kids. All right. When we come
back, Barthrite, three bacon cooking
methods and is reporting back on which
resulted in the tastiest, crispiest type
of pork. Talking about bacon.
Wake up with an Oz approved waffle and
pancake.
This is one of the best foods we have
ever discovered on the show.
And Steman Grim reveals lessons on
leadership and life with Oprah. All new
Oz. That's coming up on Wednesday.
Investigator Mars Compo is back with our
bacon lovers cooking guide to get the
crispiest, tastiest bacon ever. I know
how much you love bacon. Oh, yes. This
is, you know, she's been asking about
this assignment forever. So, I wanted to
challenge Mara to take this challenge to
make the best taking tasting bacon,
trying different cooking methods. No
matter what you like, you have to try
something different. Did you have fun?
Yeah, I had a ton of fun. I make bacon
for my family all the time. I wanted to
test some new ways to make it.
Look at her smile. Look at this. She's
so happy about this design. Come over. I
had to have a little competition. You
know, it keeps the blood flowing. I've
got three audience members who are very
harsh critics and they're going to judge
the bacon preparations that you made.
Before we get to that, my judges, why do
you love bacon so much?
The taste, nothing like it. It's
delicious.
So, Jen is a taste person.
Actually, you Jessica, they're they're
drooling the words out. Jessica,
the flavor, the crispness, it's just
it's amazing. I mean, you can't go wrong
with bacon.
And Jaton, what do you think?
I like the fat. I like the flavor. I
really like the fat.
They all likes bacon for the same
reason. Because it tastes good. Mhm.
Little crispy, a little fat, got the
right amount of everything. Okay, come
on. You're in luck. As Mara documented
her bacon cooking testing on Instagram.
You're going to taste while we watch.
First up, bacon made on a stove top in
cast iron skillet.
This is what I know. This is my tried
andrue. It's bacon in the good
oldfashioned cast iron. And I actually
add a touch of bacon grease to my bacon.
Bacon on bacon.
I love it. Look at that bacon grease
pop.
So,
how did the cast iron skilled bacon turn
out?
You know, this is what I know, so I'm a
little bit biased. It does have its
downsides. There's the splatter, which
gets everywhere. You do have to watch
it. You have to flip it. The pan gets
hot spots. It might not cook evenly. But
this is the tried and true.
It's bacon at its best. It
is bacon at it best. What does the
audience think? Bacon testers, your
verdict on the cast iron cooked bacon.
Jess, Jen, you go first.
Cast iron. I love the cast iron because
I feel like it sears in the flavor and
almost gives it around the edge like
caramelized a little bit.
All right.
Delicious.
Jessica,
it's fatty. I love it. It's There's
nothing like it.
You're just like fat. If I said fat over
there in a bucket, you'd be eating it.
Tom, what do you think?
It It gave it a sweet taste to it. I I
liked it. It had a very light sweet
taste to it. It caramelizes a little bit
in the in the ski. It actually does make
a little bit like well well stated. All
right. Next up, bacon cooked in the
oven.
All right. So, I'm just going to set
this
to 375
and then I'm going to do three pieces of
bacon. So, this cooked much faster than
I expected it to. And look at these
pieces. They look perfect.
It looks so easy.
This was surprisingly easy. I put it in
the oven and I just forgot about it. I
didn't have to flip it. I didn't have to
turn it. And if you put foil down, you
don't even have to clean up afterwards.
This was a winner.
I don't know. I didn't know about this.
Is unbelievable. Well, actually, I I
want to comment on the the taste yet.
Jen, take it away.
I believe with the in the oven baked,
it's a little bit lighter, more crispy,
and it has a more smoked flavor to it,
which I think is really good. Let let me
guess, Jessica, you like the fat.
I like No, no, you're wrong. It's
candied and it's it's just, you know,
it's sweet. It's got that like crunch to
it and I love it.
And Jat, how does it compare to the iron
skillet? The cast iron skillet.
It has more of a fatty flavor to it. I I
I enjoy it. She took my my words as far
as the smoky. I have to use that again.
Sweet and smoky. It's a sweet and smoky.
I was a little surprised. You know, it
it's not as crispy, but it has a crispy
taste to it. Texture does delicious.
All right, last option. You ever think
you'd make Actually, I I never thought
I'd ever make it in bacon. After this,
I'm thinking about it, but let me get to
the last option. This is a method of
cooking bacon in water on a stove top. I
never thought this is possible. I've
heard about it from expert chefs. Take a
look.
I have the bacon on high heat and I'm
going to cover it with water.
Now that all the water has cooked out,
I'm going to try to crisp them up. It's
pretty much cooking like regular bacon.
So, honest opinion, you didn't seem so
excited about this method.
You know, I was a little bit skeptical.
I tried to approach it with an open
mind, but it turns out I was right to be
skeptical. This took way longer. I
didn't think the bacon came out that
great, and it was harder to clean the
pan afterwards.
Yeah. Look at the disaster on that
video. All right. Yeah, Jaton, you go
first. What do you think?
It tastes rubbery.
Rubbery?
Yeah. I don't care.
I love you. Honest.
Rubbery.
I know my bacon. Okay. Don't put on my
bacon. Okay.
Don't fool me.
It tastes rubbery. Yeah. I didn't care
for it.
All right, Jess.
It stole. I don't like it. I don't like
it at all. It's just
not like the other two.
Jen, do you agree with the panel?
No, I'm a little surprised because I
really like the cast iron and the oven
baked, but this it's not as crispy, but
it really brings out the pork flavor.
So, it tastes different than the other
two. Mara, which one would you what's
your conclusion of this experiment?
I got to tell you, this converted me. I
was a cast iron girl all the way, but
cooking in the oven was so easy and fast
and it tastes good.
The oven wins. We'll be right back,
everybody. Rethink oven. Rethink your
bacon.
Coming up in Oz exclusive, a sit down
interview with a young woman whose brain
resets every night and wipes out her
memories. Find out how she and her
family are coping with their new
reality. You won't want to miss this.
Our
[Music]
brains consist of a 100 billion cells
that help us retain and create memories.
The happy times, the sad ones, the
monumental moments that we can all think
back and remember. Now, it's a complex,
beautiful part of our biology. But what
if you woke up every day to a blank
slate with no recollection of what
happened months, weeks, or even the day
before? Kind of like that movie 50 First
Dates. That's what the headlines call
the case of 16-year-old Caitlyn Little,
whose brain resets every night when she
goes to sleep. But this isn't a movie
for Caitlyn and her family. This is real
life. Take a look.
It all started with a freak accident.
14-year-old Caitlyn Little was at cross
country practice. Some other kids were
goofing around and heads collided.
Later, when her mom came to pick her up,
Caitlyn went to the car and asked her
mom how to open the door. They knew then
that this was serious. The date, October
12th, 2017. That was a year and a half
ago. But to Caitlyn, it was just
yesterday, literally.
Every morning, Caitlyn's father wakes
her up, telling her the date and basic
facts. Today is April 10th, 2019. You
got hit in the head while you're doing
cross country practice at Southeast.
And then the next day, he has to do it
again and again and again. That's
because Caitlyn has a condition that
causes her brain to reset every night,
wiping out all her memories after the
day of the accident and leaving her with
severe memory impairment.
So to cope, Kayn and her family put
Post-it notes all over the house. In the
refrigerator, telling her what foods to
eat. In the bathroom, reminding her how
to brush her teeth. In her bedroom,
reminding her not to wear her sister's
clothes.
Cuz it gets on her nerves.
But after 18 months and little
improvement, Caitlyn's parents have
turned to some experimental therapies
like this hyperaric oxygen chamber
that feeds oxygen through there. It has
a little mask just like a nebulizer.
Some researchers believe it increases
oxygen to the brain to promote healing.
And just a few months ago, they brought
Caitlyn to a specialized chiropractor.
He is doing upper neck adjustments,
hoping to get her brain to function the
way it used to.
While doctors can't yet pinpoint the
exact mechanism causing Caitlyn's memory
loss in a way we can verify, we wanted
her and her family to share their story
as they're experiencing it in their own
words. Now, Caitlyn bravely made the
trip to New York. She is backstage.
There she is. And we're going to meet
her in just a minute. But first, I want
to talk to Caitlyn's parents, Jennifer
and Chris, who are joining us now on the
sofa. Thank you for being here and for
sharing your family story.
Thank you. Chris Chris, what's it like
for you every day, every morning to have
to reexplain the accident to your
daughter Kayn?
I've uh been the one to wake up all the
children every day. Uh while my wife
does practically everything else to get
him ready for school. So, uh each
morning I go in there to wake her up and
try to give her just the information she
needs to get started. I let her know
roughly what the temperature is going to
be, what the weather's going to be, and
then I let her know she has a journal on
her desk or um table next door. And then
she has note post-it notes that tell her
how to find that journal. Um, I tell her
that she should read her journal to get
caught up and if she has any questions,
come up and see me about 15 20 minutes
and I'll give her more details that she
needs. I try not to overwhelm her with
too much.
Jennifer, this has been a real journey
for you and the family.
Yes.
Take me back to the first moment that
you thought there might be a problem.
The first inkling there was an issue.
That's why I got kind of emotional
watching her run. Um, when we picked her
up, I picked her up, they said, "Hey,
Caitlyn had a head injury." Caitlyn has
had many injuries, as kids do when
they're athletic, and never ever has
said, "I'm in pain." I picked her up,
and we always do a rating scale of 1 to
10 for our pain. And she's like, "Mom,
this is a nine, maybe a 10."
Okay, Caitlyn doesn't complain. So, I
knew right away we were in trouble, but
I didn't know how much trouble at that
point. I was just like, "Well, gosh, you
know, you got hit in the head. camp. We
walked to the car and she just stared at
it and she's like, "What do I do?" I
said, "Well, we're going to go on home."
She's like, "No, how do I open the car
door? I don't remember how to do that."
And at that point, I sort of got her in
the car and trying to be real calm,
Chris. We have a real issue. When I get
home, you know, be ready. We need to
talk. Um, we did followed the school
protocol. We did all the things they
suggested we do for a normal concussion.
And in those first two weeks, her memory
would erase in less than 10 minutes. She
was resetting every 10 minutes of uh
that was all she could hold. And all the
doctors were like, "Oh, it's just it's
just a simple case of a concussion. It
will heal itself." And we started then
the journey of of waiting for it to
heal.
What's the most painful part for you as
a mom? I I I mean, you were remained
very emotional even watching the tape.
The tape was hard to watch because that
I guess in 18 months you kind of set
aside
all your feelings. I'd forgotten that
girl you guys saw running. I'd forgotten
the um personality you could see on that
face. And um we're worried. We're scared
that her milestones have stopped, that
we are just stuck on 24 hours and that's
going to be the rest of our lives is
just 24 hours. What's happened to her
school to her friends?
School has been um amazing. Her her
principal, her guidance counselor, her
teachers, and her intelligence is
intact. And that's what's hard for
people to believe. She is still very
smart and wants to accomplish. She wants
to live the rest of her life and and set
goals and achieve them. So, her teachers
are helping her do that.
Human body has an unbelievable ability
to recover.
Yeah.
In ways we can't even imagine.
And we get better at helping it do that
every single day.
Yes.
So, I'm going to share with the audience
something you already know about what's
going on with your daughter. Yes.
Right. Because so far, doctors have not
been able to figure out why Caitlyn
can't retain new memories. But, I want
to do something. I want to show you all
a little bit about how memory works in
the brain because memories in the brain
are stored almost everywhere. It's not
just in one spot, but there's some place
that play a bigger role. And you know,
it might be a burger you happen to love
or maybe a baby that you remember uh
your graduation big moments in your
life. Sometimes just a mundane seemingly
mundane issues about being at work or
doing your homework or or having fun,
right? These are all different memories.
And what we think of as a single memory
is actually a collection of pieces of
memory stored in different parts of the
brain. And memory problems like amnesia
can be caused by an injury or
malfunction. You bang your head, right?
And all of a sudden that really complex
process where you can remember things no
longer is there. You get amnesia. Now an
antgrade amnesia and antrogate amnesia
is about the fact that you cannot form
new memories as well as as you normally
could. They they sort of a little
misformed, right? They're not quite what
they should be. And so you can remember
the information immediately sort of, but
you have problems storing those memories
long term. Interrogate amnesia is what
Caitlyn has. The memories before the
injury might be spared, but events since
the injury may be lost because they were
never stored. So, Caitlyn was diagnosed
with traumatic brain injury
postconussion, and this amnesia she has
believe is related to that. And her
family has met numerous doctors and
specialists to help to get her memory
back. Now, unfortunately, Caitlyn has
not recovered as adequately as you just
have witnessed talking to her parents.
But I want to check in with neurologist
Dr. Aisha Sherzai who's on the cutting
edge of brain science for some insights
and she's joining us now via Zoom. Dr.
Sherzai, how common is Caitlyn's
diagnosis and what's your advice for the
family?
Hi Dr. Ross. Um this case is very very
unique and extremely rare. I mean you
don't get to see interrogate amnesia
lasting this long. And just listening to
the parents and Caitlyn sorry my heart
goes out for them. I know how difficult
it is. you know, our memories are
ourselves. It's the stories of our self.
And when that is affected, uh, you feel
very destabilized. And it seems like she
has seen a lot of great doctors who have
done the normal, the standard
diagnostic, uh, procedures to find out
what was going on. And moving forward, I
think the parents have to be very
careful and discerning who they contact
and who they come across with because
there are a lot of people with promises
of potential cures that may cost a lot
of money and may not be in her best
interest. So, they need to be very
careful about that. And you know, the
most important thing is uh for the mom
and dad to know that they are the ones
who know her best. They are her best
advocates and they have to make sure
that they support her and love her and
like you said, you know, the brain is a
very susceptible organ, but it's also
very forgiving.
Dr. Shai, thank you very very much. So
guys, one thing's clear to me for sure.
You're a family. You're closely knit.
You're bonded. You've got four children.
Caitlin is number two, I think, right in
the list. So you guys can do almost
everything together, which means you can
support each other no matter what
ailments we're suffering from. That's
almost historically pulled up together.
Siblings are all backstage, right?
They're hanging out with Kaitlin. There
they are supporting her. And even if she
takes their clothes, she can now claim
she doesn't remember doing it. Most
families don't have that excuse. It is a
beautiful thing to see a family come
together, even if it's around a tragic
event. And as I look to what you guys
will be doing in the future, that ends
up becoming the foundation of it. So
when we come back, I'd like to meet
Caitlyn if that's okay.
Okay.
Okay. And you all will as well. We're
going to hear her message that we can
all learn from. That's next.
[Music]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Rod podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
Good morning, sweetheart. It's March
20th, 2019.
You got hit in the head while you're
doing cross country practice at
Southeast.
You haven't been school for a little
while. Okay. You've got a journal over
on your desk that helps explain things.
For more than 18 months, nearly 600
consecutive days. That is the message
Chris Little has used to wake up his
daughter Caitlyn every morning. The
incident he just told her about left her
with a rare form of amnesia that resets
her brain while she sleeps. Caitlyn is
joining us now with her parents,
Jennifer and Chris. Thanks for being
here. Help us all understand what it's
like to wake up every morning with that
same message from your father that
you've had a head injury and you
probably don't remember what happened
yesterday.
As with most anyone I could imagine,
it's disbelief. You say, "No way. You're
joking.
Stop pulling my leg. There's no way it
could be over a year and a half since
October. I mean, it hadn't even been
Halloween yet. But then I look around,
I'm like, things things are a lot
different. I mean, a lot has changed.
And you get a weird feeling inside
yourself saying something's something's
not right.
What's changed the most that you've
noticed?
My family has changed a lot. Not just
physically, but I can see it
emotionally, too.
My sister has become a lot more
confident through this all, as well as
my brother. He's grown a lot taller,
but he's also become more
um
what's the word?
Confident.
Mature.
Mature. Yes. Mature.
When you woke up this morning in your
New York City hotel room.
Yes.
What What did you think you were doing
today?
What did I think I was doing? Did you
remember that you were coming here?
No. No, sir. I did not. I had no idea
when I woke up that I was in New York or
where I really was. I did not know I was
in a hotel room,
which was a big shock.
So, you're living your life with these
Post-it notes, and this is your journal.
And I just note, it says, "Read me. I am
your journal." And this says, you know,
flip me up and read me. So that you even
have notes to remind you to read it. But
what what is it what is it like to have
to use these notes to remind yourself of
the activities of of everyday living?
It's a lot like reading a book. I mean,
since I don't really remember,
I can't
pull that memory and say, "Oh, yeah. I
remember what the clouds look like or I
remember looking at that dog when we
were sitting at the restaurant. So, I
can kind of
picture of what it would be like, but
it's it's not the same as actually
remembering anything.
So, when you had your injury and all all
of us sitting here listening to you do
start to think it's sort of like that
movie that I thought was Make believe 50
First Dates.
Mhm.
Does it bother you to be compared to the
the woman in that movie?
It doesn't bother me to be compared to
her. I think it helps people understand
more
because yeah, she could remember, but
she could also
point out things that I might not be
able to that are hard to do.
Chris, what do you as you watch your
daughter now?
She seems like she's obviously very
understanding what's going on.
She's very very smart and she has a very
good grasp on things and she's handled
it way better than probably the rest of
us would have. She has a very good
attitude.
It's been hard in the parents.
Yes.
Much as your daughter.
She tells me that quite often that we um
she has it easy that she sees that we're
the ones that are much more emotional
because as she says she's going to wake
up and start over tomorrow that the
emotions don't build for her like they
do for us.
Is that right, Caitlyn?
Mhm.
I mean I really just take it
right here, right now. I can't really
look forward to what am I gonna do
tomorrow night for dinner. I don't know.
Maybe I'll want chicken. Maybe maybe
tacos sound good. All I've got to focus
on is right now.
This is where we are.
So, here's what I like to do. I can't
promise a solution or an answer. This is
an incredibly complicated process.
You're going through it. Uh what I do
want you to have is hope. So we're
reaching out to some doctors who have
done research in this area just to be
able to collect more
to help you and we'll connect you
directly to them.
That's okay. We'll start with that.
You'll certainly be the world experts on
this when you're done and hopefully
you'll find some paths as well to at
least get you to continue to improve
more than you have already.
Absolutely.
Sure. We appreciate it.
And and I want to say it's all to
everybody else. You know, I you have a
gift in a way, Kaylin. What you just
said right now is very profound. You are
forced to live in the moment. Many of us
have never lived until we've lost it
all. And at least you're day in and day
out, even if it's for that one day doing
what all of us should be doing, which is
living that day. There's I wish you the
best of luck in carrying that out. Don't
lose that hope. We'll continue to follow
Caitlyn's journey and find out how you
can donate if you wish to to the
GoFundMe page by coming to dr.com. We'll
be right back.
[Music]
And up next is the eye-catching
zerocalorie iced tea you want to be
sipping all summer long. We're sharing
the best twist to the hibiscus tea
trend.
[Applause]
It's the red hot health trend everyone's
going to be drinking this summer.
Hibiscus tea. This colorful tropical tea
is getting a lot of attention all over
the internet and today we're breaking it
down. What do you need to know about
hibiscus tea? Is it worth it? Here to
help figure out this health trend is an
expert who helps the party in my plants
podcast, Talia Pollock. How are you,
Talia?
Great.
You're you're dressed in hibiscus
colors.
What a coincidence.
Oh my goodness. Completely match
coordinated. So this tea is showing up
in coffee shops all over grocery stores.
Obviously people talking about it
Instagram. What's What's it about? Why
is it so popular? Why now? I mean,
clearly it's eye-catching and so it's
super fun and everyone's looking for
great ways to stay hydrated. And so,
here's one that has no calories, is
super nutritious, and tastes so
refreshing iced.
So, there's lots of things, lots of
reported health benefits for this little
tea. Give that a taste. Let's see what
you think. Everyone likes the taste, but
doesn't really help you physically.
Doesn't really taste like anything.
Doesn't taste like anything. Thanks for
that. Thanks for the help. No, you you
hold on to that. I don't want it
anymore. All right. First, I have ways
to make it taste like something. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
First, it can help lower blood pressure.
One small tea, rather one small study on
this tea, hibiscus tea, showed that it
actually lowered blood pressure in
people who are at risk or had high blood
pressure. So, that's pretty cool if it
can help us with the number one killer
of all of us. Next up, it can lower
inflammation. The bright red color of
this tea comes from anthocyanins and it
has anti-inflammatory properties, those
anthocyanins. So, that's why it has a
benefit. Not to mention, it also has
antioxidants by itself. And finally,
it's got zero calories, right? No matter
what it tastes like, hibiscus tea is
free on calories. Now, I think it has
lots of flavor, but it's light on the
waistline. And there's no caffeine
either, so you can drink it all day
long. So, let's bring Talia back in.
What is the best way to brew this tea to
get it to become that refreshing iced
tea that so many people are bragging
about?
Yeah. So, you can do it with the tea
bags or you can do it with the loose
dried tea petals, which I think is so
much more fun and hands-on and like
earthy. So, you're going to add half a
cup of the loose into four cups of
water.
Let's do it. Let's just actually do it.
I'm sorry.
So sloppy, Talia.
Oh my goodness.
Okay.
We got a health expert.
Hands I said hands on, you know, all
hands on deck. So you're going to put
that in your fridge.
All right.
And you're cold brewing it. So you let
it sit there overnight and then in the
morning you strain it out.
It looks like this.
Voila.
Let's see if it actually tastes
questionable like our guest was.
I think it's great.
What are you talking about? It's fine.
Oh my goodness. A lady in red. You're
even dressed in hibiscus colors.
It's kind of like cranberry.
Little cranberry. Little little less
tart though. So you don't have to put
stuff in the color. I love cranberry
juice, but do people do find that tart?
So sometimes they have to add sugar.
This you wouldn't have to add that too.
It's got a calm soothing totally
sensual taste to it. All right. Now Ty's
got a couple of habiscus tea twists to
share with everybody. How are you?
This is Karen. She likes a little
sweeter tea.
So do you like Arnold Palmer's?
Yes, I do.
Have you had them? Yes.
You know what they are?
Yes. It's a delicious blend of uh
lemonade and iced tea.
Exactly. We could make our version
hibiscus Palmer. Take it away, Talia.
Yeah. I mean, everyone knows that the
legendary golfer Arnold Palmer loved
mixing lemonade and iced tea. Why not do
iced habiscus tea instead? You still get
half the calories of regular lemonade
with the added benefits of the hibiscus
tea.
So, when you pour them, they don't
separate. Even though we have pictures
that show that they really should look
this color.
Yes.
And then it gives you a little bit more
sweetness here. Let's try this out.
Take that to that discontented audience
member over there.
Maybe we could convince her that she
actually do better with this habiscus
palmer. You give it a taste. See what
you think.
Thank you.
Don't ask too many details, Talia. She
tends to she's sort of communely over
there. Just a thumb up. Better better.
All right.
Better get a bucket.
Fine. What do you think?
That is delicious.
It's great.
Oh, it's fantastic.
It actually lighten. It's already light,
but it elevates that lightness so you
have a little bit of a fuller mouth.
It's great.
It's really pretty, too.
Very refreshing. I usually plant
hibiscus. Now, I'm going to start
drinking.
It is literally those those leaves dried
out, right?
So, it's pretty simple. I can imagine
like a regular tea. All right. Another
super cool idea is a habiscus tea
cocktail. This is really what you should
be waiting for. you kick it up a notch.
You can make us look, if you're going to
make the hibiscus tea all day long, you
can make this hibiscus drink all night
long. So, share it with us.
I love to party with this honey habiscus
lime spritzer. So, all you do is you're
going to brew it hot this time because
you're going to add honey to it when
it's hot and the honey will dissolve in
the hot tea and but then you want to
cool it. Once it's chill, you just add
lime juice, tequila, seltzer, pour it
over ice and cheers and party all night
long.
Let's just see here.
It's really good.
You know what? This is really something
special. This is a great idea. We're
going to put all these recipes on dr.com
so you can take your summer drinks to
next level. This I'm going to take you
back with this lady again. See if I can
little tequila might get her happier.
We'll be right back. In the meantime,
you want a little alcohol in yours?
It's been 30 years since Ted Bundy's
execution, but his bloodline lives on.
He and his wife were able to have a
daughter while Ted was on death Who is
Ted Bundy's daughter?
Imagine knowing that you're carrying
these genes that you could potentially
become a psychopath yourself.
And where is she now?
She changed her name.
You tried to pretend it never happened.
Plus, she survived Ted Bundy.
I remember him asking me how I'd like to
die. And he put his hands on my throat
and started squeezing.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Applause]
The search for the next big health idea
is on. I love working on new technology
and tools to keep us all healthy. In
fact, this past year I had the honor of
working on two major developments in
heart valves and one device is called
the taver device. Those all the
headlines and this device really cool.
It goes up from the groin, right? Turns
heart surgery into procedure of the past
potentially. So instead of cracking open
the chest, that little catheter goes in.
So you expand it right there. That valve
stuck in from the groin through a
puncture. It up the the aortic valve
that was stuck. And now you got a new
valve placed over a catheter without
having to open the chest without having
to stop the heart.
So, and now interestingly, I got another
idea that just to highlight it for you.
It's called a mitra clip, right? It
looks like this. Opens up like that.
Puts it across the mitro valve. It snaps
shut like that and fixes the mitro valve
that might be leaking. Reduces your
chance of heart failure by a lot. These
are huge advances. Now, both these
inventions relied on teams of people
working together for a long, long time.
even if they don't have the same
background or live in the same place.
For example, with this clip that I just
showed you, right? I work with a surgeon
from a different part of the world and
came up with an idea in the back of an
envelope. Right? So, I want to help find
the next big health idea. All kinds of
ideas are out there. We're open to all
of them. Remedies that you've been using
in your family for generations or new
uses for old ideas or what about
disruptive solutions that use technology
that could change the world around you?
We have the power, each and every one of
us. So, I'm excited to share an
incredible opportunity for healthcare
innovators and startups. This year, I'm
going to be hosting the first ever
publicist health media disruption garage
at the Health Front in New York City.
It's an event exploring the latest in
healthcare innovation. Now, as part of
the disruption garage, we are looking
for the most disrupting future ideas in
health. Four people will have
opportunity pitch their ideas the
world's leading innovators for a chance
to win services that will help take your
idea or business to the next level. So,
if you think you have an idea that will
change the future of health, go to
phmdisruption.com.
Just spell that out.com. All right? And
then submit yourself. I hope to see you
there. Remember everybody, together
change is happening. Our journey is just
beginning.
[Music]
[Applause]