An ER doctor goes from saving lives.
Immediately, I felt drugged to
destroying one. I felt him groping me.
And you won't believe the defense he
used. Isn't it the perfect cover
[Music]
up? Season 10 starts now.
That TED talk with more than 18 million
views was hosted by a prominent doctor
with a seemingly perfect life. Was
picture perfect. Dr. David Newman was a
top emergency room physician and an
accomplished author who preached about
rebuilding the trust between doctors and
patients. But underneath the surface,
things were far from what they seemed.
Newman was charged with sex abuse,
targeting, drugging, and assaulting
young women in the emergency room. Now,
this isn't the first time we've heard
about a case like this. Today, in our
Dirty Doctor's investigation, could a
doctor perfect be praying on you.
Joining me now is Aza. She's one of four
women who fell victim to Dr. Newman's
secret abuse. Thank you very much for
joining me. Thank you, Das. I know this
is difficult to recount. I appreciate
you coming on the show. When you first
met Dr. Newman. What was the setting? I
met him after attending the emergency
room uh close to where I lived. And what
had brought you to the emergency room?
Oh, I was actually having crucial pain.
I thought that I was having a heart
attack. Thank god I wasn't. But And
where was the pain? Um it was like a
sharp pain. It kind of started from
midback all the way down. Mostly the
shoulder and the arms. Okay. So you're
in there. Your first impression of Dr.
Newman? Um he was nice. He was friendly.
is brief. Pretty much your usual
experience in the emergency room. I just
figured he was a doctor's here help.
Pretty nice. And as it started, did he
do anything in his examinations or
anything else that made you a little bit
leerary that something wasn't quite
right? Actually, yes. He um as I was
telling you just now, you know, I had
pain on my right side. Um one of the red
flags that I kind of go back in my head
was he did a breast exam. He kind of
touched the wrong breast. He was like on
this side but you know once again it's
like you know this is a doctor this a
person that you immediately trust. So it
was just like you know wrong side you
know not that wasn't the side I kind of
just directed his attention back over
here. So you give him a pass on that
right now the nurse had already given
you a little bit of medication for the
pain you were suffering from. Right. And
I understand something else happened
that Dr. Newman did that made you more
concerned. Exactly. And the other thing
that he did was uh he also gave me
another shot of what I believe then was
morphine but later turned out to be
propall propall right
propall is a is a powerful sedative you
may actually remember the drug because
it was what Michael Jackson used to get
asleep at nights it's not usually used
as a treatment for pain and more
importantly Michael Jackson we believe
died from that propall so it's sort of a
dangerous thing to give in a an
unmonitored setting well so so you're
you're given been narcotics, you get
another shot of something at the time
you thought it was narcotics. Did that
strike you as strange? Were you feeling
enough pain to warrant more treatment?
Yeah, absolutely. Actually, that is
exactly what strike me, you know, um
immediately I felt drugged with the
second dose. Yes. And then what
happened? Uh that things got creepy
after that. I immediately, like I said,
I felt like I was drugged. Um I went out
of consciousness. Um, I was fighting it.
It was a heavy feeling. Made me feel
like I was falling asleep, but at the
same time, like, you know, you have to
stay up. Wait a minute. Hold on. What's
going on?
Um, I had moments where I felt like I
was trying to speak and I couldn't
speak. Uh my bed was I felt my bed moved
while you know during my pass out state
I felt my bed move from against the wall
and um I felt him groping me
and you know I felt I heard the sound of
skin rubbing you know like someone is
jack um
masturbating and
[Music]
um yeah that went on for a few minutes
and my bed moved back against the wall.
I heard the doors
open. Like I said, you know, during this
time, I'm in and out of consciousness.
I'm trying to get up, trying to fight
like, you know, this heavy seditive that
I'm feeling, and I couldn't quite do it.
Um, when I did come to, I felt
like you're never prepared for that. You
you you wonder if you're imagining that,
you're like, did that just happen? You
know, um, what just happened? Uh, I went
to the restroom and I noticed I had
semen in between my
breasts. So, that was like, yeah, this
happened. It happened. And I had a
decision to make, you know,
[Music]
um, are you going to go out there and
yell and scream at someone and say, hey,
did you do this to me? Because, of
course, I didn't think that would go
well. So, I questioned myself like, what
do you do next? What are you going to
do? you know, you are you can die in
here because I'm also, you know, still
fighting off this drug. I'm feeling and
then like, you know, I'm completely
tired in and out of consciousness even
what my, you know, getting up and
pretending that I'm fine. Did the nurses
realize that you were overdrugged? A
nurse did come in and out the room. Um,
actually a few people didn't. She was
immediately concerned. She was like,
"Why is she like this?" Um, like I said,
you know, during that time I was in and
out of consciousness. I heard this. I
heard a lot of people coming in and out
the room, you know, responded to my name
is Aza. Are you okay? Are you okay? But
I couldn't really get up. I couldn't say
anything. So So now you got a big
decision to make. You you realize this
is real. This nightmare actually
happened, right? What' you decide to do?
I decided to tell one of the hospital
staff at first. Um the PA I wind up
getting up the courage to tell him, you
know, he came in the room, he's like,
"Oh, you're awake?" And I'm like,
"Yeah."
Um the doctor that was, you know,
examining me, he actually masturbated
and did this to me. And his response
was nonchalant. Just very It's like,
"Okay, so you want me to call the cops
or something?
And I was so taken back. I was like,
"Wow, are you serious? Like, did you
hear what I said to you?" And he's like,
"Yeah, you what do you want to do?" And
I'm like, "Go get your supervisor."
Because at this point, I want to scream.
I'm upset. You know, I'm raped. Of
course you are. Yeah. And I'm like, "Go
get your supervisor." And he's like,
"I'm confused." I'm like, "What are you
confused about?" He's like, "That was
my, you know, the person you're accusing
of doing this is is my supervisor."
Oh my goodness. Dr. Newman was in charge
of the ER. Yes. So, at that point in
time, I'm like, you know what? Give me
my discharge papers. I want to go. My
shoulder doesn't hurt that much, right?
Let me get out of here. Because I'm
afraid at this point, you know, what
what if what if I fall asleep and I
don't make it out of here? Who's going
to believe what I had to say at that
moment? you know, I don't have any proof
of this, which is why I decided when I
was leaving, you know, take sheets, do
anything I can to, you know, defend
myself because I was still feeling the
sedatives really heavy at this point in
time and I'm
like, I'm not going to make it out of
here, but damn it, I'm going to try. So,
you do make it out of there. I do of you
to to fight this whole thing. And what
do you do? And I call the cops. Soon as
I get away and I get home, I call the
cops and my sister, you know, um, and I
let everybody know what happened and
they come and they take me to the
hospital. Well, another hospital, not
the same
hospital. And, um, we call authorities
and everything else from there. So, they
took the sample Yes. of the rape kit.
The rape kid. Mhm. And then what
happened to the Dr. Newman? uh he was
arrested once um he was arrested before
that and um at some point in time the
DNA came back and matched you know his
how has this impacted you every single
day since
then you never get over something like
this you know you never get over it but
um it's definitely made me realize that
you always have to trust yourself you
have to speak up and you have to be
responsible, you know, no matter what.
Um, it's sad to say that you look at
people in emergency rooms different, but
I do.
Well, Dr. Newman plead guilty to four
counts of sexual abuse. In court, his
defense says that he was going through a
hypomomanic episode from bipolar
disorder. So, coming up, what our true
crime panel has to say about this
defense. Did an illness turn a perfect
doctor into a sex fiend that drugged and
abused a woman? Stay with
us. We are back investigating Dr.
Perfects. Seemingly perfect doctors who
are hiding secret sex abuse, drugging
women and taking advantage of them. It
claimed emergency room physician David
Newman was arrested and convicted of
drugging and sexually assaulting his
patients. At a hearing, his defense said
that Newman was suffering from a
hypomomanic episode from bipolar
disorder. So, here's the question. Did
an illness really turn a perfect doctor
into a sex fiend? Joining our true crime
panel today is trial attorney Heather
Hansen from Law and Crime and
psychiatrist Dr. Judith Joseph. So
Heather, we just heard from one of uh
Dr. Newman's victims. It's pretty
graphic what he did. He gave her
propathol which could have risked her
life. He then took advantage of her.
What do you make out of this bipolar
disorder defense? It's a difficult
defense to make. Dr. O. He already
pleaded. So he did his time. He did his
two years. Now, the reason for this
defense is he doesn't want to have to
register for as long as he might have
to. He has a sex offender. A sex
offender. Exactly. He has to register
for sure. But if it's level one, it's
only 20 years. And if it's level two or
three, it's the rest of his life. And
registering might impact his ability to
practice medicine, but not necessarily,
which is really unfortunate. Sometimes
registered sex offenders can actually
practice. Dr. Joseph, I'm stunned by
that. Isn't it? I mean, you think people
are really vulnerable to their doctors.
Yes. As a psychiatrist, you have
insights into bipolar disorder, what
motivates them. Could a perfect doctor,
seemingly perfect anyway, turn into a
sex fiend because of a psychiatric
ailment like bipolar disorder? So, man,
mania and hypomomania are all hallmarks
of bipolar disorder. And when I've
treated severe bipolar episodes, there
are other symptoms besides
hypersexuality. You see someone with
racing thoughts, they're pacing, they're
highly distractable. There's no way that
they can function in a highpowered
hospital like this. Something is very
inconsistent with this story. Just to be
clear, mania is the high part of a
bipolar. So, you start to think you can
do everything and hypersexuality is a
part of that. But to your point, you
shouldn't be able to do any of the other
things you need to do to work in an ER,
especially something as complicated as
allegedly dosing such a powerful
anesthetic. It's does not add up. Right.
So, the guy worked at a prominent New
York City hospital. I mean, reputable
place. He seemed to have it all. Yes.
How do you hide this perfect persona?
How did he fool everybody? Isn't it the
perfect cover up? Yes. The mask of
sociopathy. And so, yeah, sociopaths can
be white collared. They can be
professionals. They can be college
students. And so, when you take
advantage of a position of power over
the powerless, you are exercising your
sociopathic capabilities.
Unbelievable. Thank you very much for
both your advice. Let me bring back in
Aza, who has came forward about the
abuse she suffered while sedated under
Dr. Newman's care. Her lawyer, Katherine
Smith, joins us now. So, Ara, when you
heard this hypomomanic defense, this
argument that he had a psychiatric
problem, what did you think? I thought
it was a joke. Um, it's, you know, it's
very frustrating. It's kind of sad that
people get to hide behind this kind of
facade
and I don't believe it personally, but
he wrote a book about bringing patients
and physicians closer together. I It's
ironic, right? that the definition of
trust is to make sure that your bond,
your covenant with your patient is
close, right? How do you reconcile that
with the man who assaulted you? You
don't you sit there and you kind of feel
like this individual is calculated and
it, you know, it's scary. It's scary. It
brings a different fear to you
awareness,
but I don't buy it personally. Dr.
Newman. Where is he now? Do you know?
Oh, he's free. I guess he's living his
life. He's released.
Is he working? I'm not sure. I'm glad
you put your hand up. You could have
gotten shot, but you saved others. So,
thank you for doing that. We reached out
to Dr. Newman's attorney for a
statement. Did not hear back in time for
the taping. Katherine, what can a woman
like Aza do if she's in an emergency
room? She's completely vulnerable at
that point and she's got an emergency
situation and there's a doctor that
she's uncomfortable with. Well, that's
what's tough because obviously there's
nothing you can do 100% to word against
this and it's certainly not the victim's
fault, but there are certain precautions
that we can take such as if you ever
feel uncomfortable in any way, asking
for a chaperone to come into the room is
a completely reasonable request. Um,
speaking up immediately and making a
complaint, as Aza did, in most hospital
environments, that is enough to warrant
a full investigation. Um, and also just
knowing while of course seeking out the
medical care that you need, also knowing
that just because someone wears a white
coat and they have charisma does not
mean that they're immune from doing bad
things. Well said. Thank you for coming
forward. I wish you the best. Thank you
for watching. Don't forget to subscribe
and turn on notifications so you never
miss out on new videos to live the good