[Applause]
He's one of the most famous voices of
all time. Host of the nation's top
morning shows. He's heard coast to
coast. And he counts top musical
performers like Katy Perry and Lady Gaga
as his friends. Elvis Duran not only
wakes up millions of you with his iconic
syndicated radio show Elvis Duran in the
morning show, but he's also gone through
some very public changes. Today, Elvis
like you've never heard him before on
life, weight loss, and living out and
proud as a new husband. Get in touch
with us now. Go to elvdan.com. Popular
DJ Elvis Duran has always been very
candid with his audience. For years, he
shared his struggle with his weight. And
when I was at his radio show, we took
his blood pressure. That was the day
that would change his life forever.
Elvis, your real blood pressure, it was
165 over 110. So catastrophically high
that you have a chance of having a
stroke today.
Elvis underwent gastric sleeve surgery
in 2014.
I'll never forget the moment he walked
out on stage looking slim and trip,
smiling bigger than I've ever seen him
smile before. And ever since he's turned
things around, he's been paying it
forward and helping others. What advice
do you have for all of us trying to find
our happy place? It's literally just
figuring out what makes you happy. Two
years ago, Elvis took an important step
on his own road to happiness when he
came out of the closet with millions of
listeners. And now Elvis has taken the
ultimate step. This time down the aisle.
Just a few weeks ago, I was so proud to
watch as Elvis and the love of his life,
Alex Carr, tied the knot. The wedding
ceremony was about two people becoming
one. That actually that's faulty math.
The correct math is a magical math. It's
1 + 1 equals everything.
Please welcome radio host newlywed and
my good friend Elvis Durant.
No. Take it in. They love you. Thank
you.
Thank you. So happy you're here. Which
one? Hold on. You can say whatever you
want. All right. Oh my goodness. Are
these real? Can I eat these? Yes, please
do. Chew on them. Eat some flowers.
They're good for you. Kale flowers.
They're brand new. Oh god. Everything's
edible in the couch.
It's good to be back. It's wonderful to
have you. I tell you, I watched you as a
close friend, but also admirer. Uh, and
when you got married this this past
weekend, it was very special because I
saw that culminate all the things you've
been doing for the last decade. But I
want to go back a 10-year period. Let's
just start for at a time where you were
in a very different place in your
personal life, very physically very
different, career-wise, in a different
spot. How did you get to where you are
now, where you're completely on top of
the world, and what catalyzed that
change? You know what? I think
the best moment of my life you just saw
on that piece before I came out is when
you you saved my life. You you saved my
life. And uh
I promise not to cry because tears have
salt and he tells us salt's very bad for
us.
You know, I I think you know what? For
the past 10 years, I've been getting to
know myself and uh and it's making a
huge difference. And now I have clarity.
Now I can see where I want to go for the
next however many millions of years I
have left. When I witch watched you walk
down the aisle, I I thought back to a
few years ago when it was not publicly
known that that you were gay, right? We
all your friends knew, but you weren't
talking about what what catalyzed your
decision to be truthful for to the
millions who adore you and listen to you
and trust the wisdom you share with
them. It was them. It was my audience.
You know, I I was doing a show every
day. And so, I wanted to better connect
with my audience. And there's no better
way to do that than to be honest and
say, "Hey, I'm a single gay guy living
in New York. I'm striking out, man. No
one wants to date me. The dating life
sucks. It's relatable. It's connecting."
And then I would have people write back
to me or text back and say, "I'm going
through the same thing." What's the
advice you would give to someone
watching right now who's where you were
10 years ago? Tons of potential, right?
but just not showing up in some of the
ways that are really important. Be aware
of the important things and try to brush
off the things that just don't matter.
So, by the way, you have me so nervous
right now. Can I just tell you guys it
was a week and a half ago he stood up at
my wedding and gave the best advice to
Alex and me and everyone in the audience
in the uh ceremony and I can't thank you
enough. Well, you kind of say how much
fun did we have? Did Did you see this
guy dancing? Did you show video of him
dancing at my wedding? Destroyed that.
My wife destroyed all the evidence. I've
never seen anyone cut the road. I'll
tell you, we we I actually posted with
seven steps, seven hacks for a happy
marriage. They weren't my ideas. I went
around and talked to a lot of friends
just to see what people who had been
together in relationship for a long
times had figured out. If I run into an
80-year-old couple who's been married 60
years and they're in a blissful
relationship, teach me how you did it. I
want to understand that. And what I
think you do so beautifully is you make
us comfortable. And Elvis writes about
in his book, by the absolutely
fantastic, and we'll be talking about a
little bit more. You have the ability to
to let people open. How how did you
develop that? That's actually what makes
your show to me most iconic. Well, it's
what you do every day and you watch them
every day. You're a master at making
people comfortable. I mean, if you make
your guest comfortable in your home,
they're going to have a good time. If I
make my guest comfortable on my show,
they're going to have a good time and
open up. You know, let me just want to
throw more salacious question. Okay, get
salacious. You want to get dirty? I want
to get this to it. What celeb interview?
What's Lebanon interview went off the
rails for you? I mean, just Okay, I
don't want to say the Madonna interview
was off the rails. I've done I've done
three or maybe four interviews with
Madonna. I never felt like I connected
with Madonna. I never felt like we had a
conversation about anything real. And I,
as it turns out, I've seen other Madonna
interviews and she doesn't really like
to give you a lot from the heart. So, I
want to redo I want to redo with
Madonna. I want to interview her until I
finally get to her heart and soul. I
mean, otherwise I'm I'm failing. I'm I'm
not connected. So, Madonna, if you're
watching, here's a rose for you. It's
two for you. I want you to speak to
Elvis again. Allow him to open your
heart so we can all see it better. Is
that a deal? Deal. I'm sure she's
watching. I'm sure she is. When we come
back, Elvis's weight loss journey, which
is an important one. How we went from
this to this, and he kept off every
pound, which is what's most incredible.
The secret to keeping Well, you look
good to me. The secret to keeping the
weight off. What's next? We're back with
Elder Duran discussing his new book,
Where Do I Begin? Stories he got before
I could get There it is. Guess me up,
Dr. Oz. I sort of remember, he says,
from a life lived out loud, which
described how we navigated 20 plus years
in radio. Sell us a book. Send me some
books. Send us a book. It is actually
superbly done book. And I'm going to get
some details on it. You were one of the
first to read it. Was I? It's weird if
you write a book and then someone says,
"I read your book." You're thinking, "Oh
Lord, here we go." What' you think? You
actually said you liked it. I love the
book. You know, in the break, you put
the flowers on that he was taking out of
my uh my my plant grouping here. You
thought they were fake, didn't you? I
did. I make those. But they're real. So,
are we going to make a shake out of
those or something? It's going to be
something similar to that. You shared a
lot with your audience uh about this
gastric sleeve surgery that you had.
Yes. It was a very brave move. There are
many people that we both you and I know
and all of you know who've had that
operation and haven't told anybody about
it. Why? Why would you not share this
miracle with people? I mean, it saved my
life without a doubt. Explain how that
happened. I I agree with you. I think it
did save your life. It's not easy. Some
of our listeners said, "Well, this is
the easy way out to lose weight." No,
it's Where's the camera? No, no, no,
it's not. You know, you just when you
first have this this done, you can't eat
solid food at all. How did your
relationship with food change? Because
as good as an operation as it is,
there's a good number of people who
fail. I still love food. And when I'm
I'm sure someone can relate when when
I'm a little nervous or I'm anxious.
Food, right? Anyone else? Am I the only
one there? Food. Everybody. All of us.
Yeah.
The difference is is now my stomach is
this small versus this small. And so I
just can't fit as much in. But three
years into it, three and a half years
into it now, the stomach is is it's
expanding. So my relationship with food
is now changing. I now need to be
careful, more careful about what I put
in there. So, I know that you're
thoughtful from the moment you get up to
when you go to bed at night, but you're
so busy in the morning, talking to tens
of millions of us, that you got the
shake habit going. Yes. Which is sort of
good when you have a gastric sleeve,
right? Well, the shakes are already
done. It's in a bottle. It's in the
refrigerator. You open it and it's gone.
You know, I've got something new for
you. Come over here. Oh, not one of
these shakes. Dr. Don't forget the book.
Come on. Oh my gosh. This is my my Berry
Elvis morning shake. Berry berry Elvis
morning shake. This is what I'm going to
have you do. This is this is what it
looks like when it's finished. I like
everything that's in the shake but not
in the same shake. Like you got salad,
you got fruit. What makes it special is
you get your fistfuls of leafy greens.
No one knows they're in there. The
berries overwhelming the taste. And I
think if it tastes good, this could be
what you do in the mornings to remember
me. You get up and think, I feel very
very Elvisy today. Okay. But if I don't
like it, I can be honest. Yeah. Be our
friends. Be honest. All right.
Oh, so good. That's awesome. You agree?
You agree? That's good. Okay. How much
weight have you lost? Uh, right around
120. A little over 120 lbs.
So, 120 lbs. Got me thinking. I have a
little surprise. I could calculate 120
lbs. Please. Why is he always leaving
me? Okay, I'll lead him along with me.
So 120 lbs is in the radio language 171
microphones, which is a lot of guests we
have on the show. It is 6,857
earbuds. Since you're listening to music
all the time, you know that's how much
they weigh. That's what they weigh. But
most importantly, cuz I'm so proud of
you, it's 122 copies of your new book.
All right.
because it you'll need at least that
many to feed everybody in this audience
and everyone out there because I'm so
proud of you at so many levels and I
applaud you for putting it in on paper
so we can all experience what you've
gone through, gain from your wisdom and
be better for it. God bless you. I love
you, Dr. Ross. I love you, my friend.
All right, so pick up the book. It's
fantastic. Where do I begin? Stories
that I sort of remember from a life
lived out loud. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good