Exclusive shocking new details in the
case of a doomsday cult mom whose
children Tylie and JJ haven't been seen
since September. After fleeing Idaho,
Lori and her new husband Chad Del were
found 3,000 miles away at a Hawaiian
resort, but incredibly still won't
reveal where Tyl and JJ are. Today,
we're taking you inside the storage unit
Lori abandoned back in Idaho. Will what
authorities discovered there finally
cracked the case? And does the man seen
on this surveillance video hold the
answer to what happened to Tylie and JJ?
Two days before Thanksgiving,
authorities in Rexburg, Idaho, executed
a welfare check after family members
reported 17-year-old Patty Ryan and her
seven-year-old special needs brother
Joshua JJ Valow hadn't been heard from
in two months. Their mother, Lorie
Valow, and her new husband, Chad Del,
the Doomsday author, reportedly
excommunicated from the Mormon church,
claimed that JJ was visiting a friend in
Arizona. Authorities determined this to
be false and returned to the Debbell
home, only to discover the couple had
fled. Some members of Lor's family have
said they fear she's part of a cult
focused on preparing for the end of
time. Shockingly, Lorie married fifth
husband Chad just weeks after his wife
Tammy died, reportedly of natural
causes. But now Chad is a person of
interest in her death. Tammy's body was
exumed in December, and autopsy results
are still pending. The couple has been
associated with at least two other
mysterious deaths, including Lor's
aranged fourth husband and her brother.
But more pressingly, Tyler and JJ's
family is desperately focused on finding
them alive. Especially JJ's
grandparents. JJ, please call Papa. You
know how to do it. I'm waiting for you.
Please, little man. Call me.
>> Meanwhile, authorities track down Lori
and Chad in Hawaii. But still, there's
no sign of the children.
After Lori ignored a court order to
present Tylie and JJ to authorities in
Rexburg, the Idaho Department of Health
and Welfare was ordered to conduct
formal investigations into the child to
the to the safety of these kids. Now,
that report was due to a judge
yesterday, but as of this taping, their
findings have not yet been made public.
I'm joined now by East Idaho News.com
news director Nate Eaton, who tracked
down Lori and Chad in Hawaii. So, Nate,
where are they now? Well, last report,
they are still in Hawaii. In fact,
several members of the local church
there say that they came to church on
Sunday. They went to meet with the local
leaders there and they said, "We don't
want to cause any disturbances. What you
have heard on television is lies. It's
one-sided." And they seem to just be
living their lives as if nothing is
going on, as if everything's normal.
>> Well, Nate was in Hawaii investigating
this case when authorities seized Lori
and Chad Del's rental car. After that,
he attempted to interview them.
>> Where are your kids?
>> No comment.
>> No comment. They've been missing for 4
months. You have nothing to say.
>> Listen, just tell people what's
happening. There's people around the
country praying for your children,
praying for you guys. Why don't you give
us answers?
>> That's great.
>> That's great. That's great that they're
praying for you, praying for your kids.
What?
You have nothing to say.
>> You have nothing to say. I mean, how
surprised you were you by by Lori and
Chad Dable's demeanor?
>> You know, they were pretty cold. I spoke
to them for three minutes. I asked them
29 times. 20 questions. 29 questions.
Where are your kids? It's an easy
question, Dr. Oz. You know, I could ask
you, where are your kids right now? I
can tell you where my kids are. It's not
a hard-hitting question. They ignored
question after question after question.
They did not want to answer anything.
>> Can I go to this storage unit issue a
little bit because there might be some
clues in there. You actually were just
inside the storage unit. You brought
some footage back to us. What did you
discover in that storage unit in Idaho?
>> So, two days ago, we got into the
storage unit that Lorie Del went and
rented on October 1st. You can see here
some of the items, mainly children's
items. There's a jersey with the last
name of Colby, Lorie's oldest son.
There's ice skates. And then shocking
these blankets that have photos of JJ
and photos of Ty just folded up, stuffed
in a tote, and left in this cold storage
bin along with bikes and scooters and
photo albums, baby books. I mean, there
were pictures of of photos of these kids
when they were just children, just tiny
little babies.
>> Yeah. Who who who puts all their kids
paraphernalia in a storage unit? So the
the kids were last seen in September
when they were pulled out of school.
That's right. You know when Lori started
renting the storage unit?
>> She went to the storage facility,
according to surveillance images, on
October the 1st. And then she and a man
or sometimes two men visited the
facility 10 times between October 1st
and November 24th.
>> So the surveillance footage they
referring to uncovered that Lori and a
man who appears to be her brother, Alex
Cox, visiting the unit together and then
removing some heavy stuff, a tote with
something hanging over the end. You'll
see it there. And then there's also it
looks like there's a tire or something.
Alex's truck uh was with him u or if it
was really in fact him and they were
spotted several times at the unit in
October. So when was Lori last seen at
the unit?
>> Well, they went nine times in October
and then nothing until November 24th.
Lori and and a man went back to the
storage unit. 2 days later, police went
to her home to do a welfare check on JJ
after his grandparents became concerned.
JJ was not there. The next day, they
went back with a search warrant. They
searched the house and then they went
back to that storage unit and that's
when they they searched this unit and
they took photos and and documented it
all.
>> Just to get you all on the same page
here, a surprising number of people
connected to Lori and Chad Del have
passed away. Back in July, Lor's fourth
husband, Charles, was killed by Lor's
brother, Alex, who I just told you was
the person who might have been in that
storage unit, suspiciously bringing
things out. Certainly, his truck was in
the storage unit area. Then Chad's wife,
Tammy Debel, died suddenly in October.
She was only 49 years of age, so it's a
little bit strange. And then most
recently, Lor's brother, Alex, the one
who shot her her fourth husband and and
killed him, who the one who was
potentially at the storage unit, um,
mysteriously died in December. Do
authorities think that Alex might have
known where the kids are? Do they think
that was him carrying that tote with
something hanging out of it outside of
the storage unit?
>> Well, it definitely was his truck and
then he mysteriously died a few, you
know, months later after this. So, one
would assume that he might know
something that the authorities are being
very tight-lipped about what he may or
may not have known.
>> There's a part of the story that starts
to make me very concerned. After Lor's
husband died that Charles, they there
was a service dog that JJ had.
>> Yeah. And apparently that dog was
initially offered on to be sold and then
subsequently because you can't sell
service dogs was given back to the to
the group that could you know recommend
him.
>> Yeah. The dog's name is Bailey, a
Labradoodle and JJ has autism. So it was
his best friend. You know Ba Bailey and
JJ were together all the time. Charles
dies and within two or three weeks we're
told that she tried to sell this dog for
a couple thousand dollars online. That
makes you wonder why was she trying to
sell her son's best friend? And luckily,
the organization that trained this dog
found out about this and said, "Listen,
you can't sell this animal. We need it
back." And fortunately, the dog's been
placed with another child, we're told,
who has special needs, but why would she
try to sell her son's service dog?
>> Nate, help me understand what's
happening in Lor's mind because the this
story just is not coming together for
why was she doing this? What does she
think is happening? Well, her husband
who was shot and killed was so concerned
about a year ago that he went to a court
and asked for custody of the children
because she was saying that she the
second coming of Jesus Christ would be
coming in July 2020, the world would
end. and that um she had been
reincarnated several times and she had
actually said if if you get in my way
you may die and Charles told friends
told family members if anything happens
to me look to Lori. So there were
concerns a year or more ago that she was
becoming involved in you know religious
delusions and things like that enough
that her ex-husband raised these
concerns.
>> What do the folks in Idaho think? I
mean, this is a state that people join
know each other pretty well. What do
they think is going on with any of these
weird things? Tyl and JJ's
disappearance. Are they putting the
pieces together?
>> There are so many questions. This is
probably the most bizarre case eastern
Idaho has seen, I don't know if you
could say ever. I mean, there's so many
complicated pieces. The big question
that everybody has and and could be
answered, where are the children? You
answer that question and this big chunk
is solved. whether you know they're
they're still here and heaven forbid
they're not here. Just answer that
question and the parents could do that.
>> They could do it easily. But they
ignored your questions 29 times.
>> Yeah,
>> that would be quite a bit more, I'm
sure. You can follow all of Nate's
wonderful reporting on this disturbing
case at east idaho.com. Congratulations
and keep pursuing them.
>> Thank you, Dr. Os.
>> Shed light. Coming up, missing
seven-year-old JJ's grandparents are
here with shocking new details on the
search for JJ and his big sister, Tally.
why they say this previously loving mom
has turned into a monster.
>> Listen, just tell people what's
happening. There's people around the
country praying for your children,
praying for you guys. Why don't you give
us answers?
>> That's great.
>> That's great. That's great that they're
praying for you, praying for your kids.
What?
You have nothing to say.
That's footage of one of the only times
Tori Valow and her new husband Chad Del
have been spotted publicly since news
broke that Lor's daughter Tylie and son
JJ are missing. JJ's grandparents Kay
and Larry are back with us today. H how
shocked were you both to learn that Lori
was in a resort, a very expensive
multi-million dollar gated community in
Hawaii while the rest of the world is
looking for her children.
You know, it's one thing to rub it in
the public's face and to rub it in law
enforcement's face,
but to rub it into the to the extent she
has, as you say, the million-doll
community laying on the beach,
that's the mind of a very sick person.
And I want to feel sorry for her because
we knew the other side of Lori.
>> So K, you've gone from believing Lori
was a loving mom to thinking she's a
monster that ought to be in jail. What
happened to her? She I it's like uh I
don't know exactly when she and Chad
met, but they're leading a path of
destruction everywhere around them that
they've been all the way from Arizona to
Idaho to Hawaii. I mean, and all of us
back in Louisiana,
I mean, there there's a lot of people
that have been hurt by this. And we had
spoken to um a couple of people that a
couple and the husband had been involved
in that for a little while and it
>> been in the involved in the cult.
>> Yes. And this is probably 50 families
that have been affected by this in in a
very bad way.
>> In a in a very small town,
>> right?
>> There's one person that I wish I could
stand here and talk to and he would look
me in the eyes.
Chad, let's you and I sit down. Let's
get a cup of coffee.
>> Chad D.
>> Chad Chad, the doomsday author.
>> Absolutely.
>> And Lor's husband.
>> And and Lory's husband. And Chad, let's
sit down. You got to explain to me how
this happened.
>> So Kay and Larry haven't been able to
speak to JJ since August. He and Tylie
haven't been seen by anyone since
September. And we now know that Lori put
their belongings into a storage unit in
October. So, Larry, how hard is it to to
see JJ's loved items in storage? That's
his scooter, which I I understand.
>> Yes.
>> It It hurt. It hurts. That scooter right
there.
The first thing he does in the morning,
he goes and he gets his scooter and he
runs up and down. We're fortunate. We
live on a dead end road and he's got a a
a
lot of road to ride on.
We were buying him new tennis shoes
about every seven days
>> from riding that scooter.
>> He he he wears out the left foot pushing
and dragging and
>> dragging So when that scooter's in
storage and his his his dog, his service
dog is given back to the organization
after she tried to sell it, I mean, what
what does that mean to you? What does
that signify to you?
>> It it means what I don't want to hear.
It it to me
it's
I we don't use the the dword.
>> We can't. But it means to me is that
somebody, his mom,
his uncle were cruel enough
to either put him someplace
or something else
and not take really the two or three
things that he loves the most. I I see
that scooter and and that's what it
makes me feel like. I am so friaking
angry. I I want to get in a room with
them and just
I want to hurt them.
I know better. I'm not going to do it.
Good Lord's going to take care of that
for me.
It's I I'm I'm not I I I I'm I'm not
going to depend on anybody else. I'm
going to turn it all over
to the Lord because we we can't I can't
take justice out on myself. Even as bad
as I want to, I don't I can't serve that
justice that way.
>> So, let me shift gears. Chad Del, Lory's
new newest husband, fifth husband,
allegedly said his wife, Tammy Spirit,
helped them connect with Lori.
>> Yeah,
>> that's why they were able to get married
so soon after her untimely death.
>> Right. She is an innocent victim just
like Charles is an innocent victim. Just
like JJ, just like Tyle, just like us,
just just everybody in their world. Lori
has just exploded it. and for her own
selfish needs or desires.
>> If I understand correctly, you think
there are people in Rexburg, Idaho who
have more information, but they're
afraid to talk about it.
>> Afraid to speak up. What's your message
for them?
>> Please, please, please. This is easy.
This is about two children. It's that
simple. This is about two children, two
beautiful children. And all we want to
do is is somebody in Rexburg, somebody
around that community, somebody around
that part of the state. They have to
have seen something. So if you know
anything about the disappearance of JJ
Valow and Tyler Ryan, please go to findj
and tylie.com. There's a $20,000 reward
for information directly leading to
their recovery. This family has lived in
states all over the country. So, we
really need to spread the word and find
JJ entirely. We're going to have all the
contact information you need at
dr.com/crimehunters.
Godspeed. We're all praying for you.
Keep pushing.
>> Thanks, Dr. Oz.
>> Thank you.
>> Coming up, if Lori and Chad Del have
been lying to authorities, why why
haven't they yet been arrested?
>> We're back with the latest on the search
for brother and sister JJ and Tylie, who
were last seen in Idaho in September.
Their mom, Lori, and new stepfather Chad
Del have now been discovered 3,000 miles
away in Hawaii, but continue to refuse
to cooperate with authorities. Joining
us now to try to make sense of this is
former homicide prosecutor and host of
Investigation Discoveries True
Conviction, Ana Nicolasi. So, Lori Valow
was given five days to present her kids
back to the police, to the authorities.
That deadline passed. She's still
wandering around in Hawaii in a million
dollar gated community. Why don't they
just throw her in jail? Well,
technically they can, but it's much more
complicated here. If you don't comply
with a judge's order, you can you can be
put in jail until you comply. But here
you have competing factors. You have
one, they are in Hawaii. The order came
out of Idaho, so you'd have to ask
Hawaii. Of course, they're going to help
on a case like this, but they have to
extradite them. You also have the fact
that they are out and about. Who knows?
The authorities's number one priority is
to find these children. And we all want
to hope against hope that these children
are found safe while she is out. Maybe
she does something that leads them.
Maybe she decides to cooperate or more
likely she does something, says
something, goes somewhere that helps
police. So that's what they're looking
at here. And that I believe is what
they're doing. They can't tell us a
whole lot because in Idaho you're
dealing with children. There's lots of
laws about the investigation being under
seal. But I think we can all be rest
assured they are doing everything they
can to piece this together as quickly as
they can.
>> I guess we're all anxiously wanting them
in jail for justice, but that's not
really justice. Justice is finding these
kids.
>> That's first.
>> So letting letting them make more
mistakes while they're out and about is
rational.
>> The case can come later. It's finding
these kids first.
>> Case will definitely come later.
According to Rexburg police, before Lori
and Chad fled Idaho, they claimed JJ was
visiting friends in Arizona, which was
not true. They also apparently told
witnesses that Lor's daughter, Tylie,
died a year before the death of her
father, which also wasn't true. And
around the same time, Chad allegedly
told another witness that Lorie had no
minor children. Also not true. So these
are pretty significant lies that folks
are swearing they were told. So
authorities, I would think, would be
able to charge Lori and Chad with
something. You know, as a homicide
prosecutor, I've had countless
conversations with families like the
Woodcocks. And the end of the day is
while I absolutely understand the
frustration and the pain and how are
these people out and about while we know
that they're lying left or right, it is
not a crime to lie. It may be fantastic
evidence against them. If there is are
charges later, which unfortunately I
suspect there will be, that is when
these come into play. We reached out to
Lori and Chad Dable's attorney for
comment and we have not heard back, but
previously gave a statement saying, "We
look forward to addressing the
allegations once they have been moved
beyond speculation and rumor. If you
have any information on the
disappearance of JJ and Tally, go to
find JJali.com. We also have all the
information as usual, dr.comers."
As you can, thank you very much. Thank
you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good