Today's true crime is this the face of
the deadliest serial killer in US
history. His name is Sam Little and he
recently confessed to 90 90 murders. To
put that in perspective, infamous serial
killer Ted Bundy confessed to 30 murders
and Jeffrey Dmer was convicted of
killing 17.
And what makes this case even more
unusual, this confessed killer is now
drawing sketches of his victims. And
investigators want your help in solving
the mystery of just who these women
are. This is the face of a man believed
to have taken nearly 100 lives over the
course of four decades. Samuel Little.
Now 78, he's a lifelong criminal with a
history of arrests for everything from
theft to attempted rape and murder.
Finally, in 2012, DNA technology and
good detective work linked him to the
murders of three women in
California. Little was convicted in 2014
and sentenced to three life sentences
without parole. That's when he confessed
to the 1994 murder of Denise Brothers in
Texas.
When a Texas Ranger paid him a jail
house visit, Little would confess to 90
murders. A former boxer, Little would
stun or knocked out his victims with
punches before strangling them because
he targeted troubled women. Often their
deaths were not investigated and their
bodies remained unidentified.
Now, law enforcement is working with
dozens of state and local agencies to
match Little's confessions with cold
cases of women who turned up dead in
states from Florida to California
between 1970 and 2005. Investigators
have unusual
assistance. A very unfortunate case of
art imitating life in the most deadly
way. I'm joined by psychiatrist Dr.
Judith Joseph and investigative
correspondent Mars Gawacmpo. I'll need
both of your help on this one. So Mara,
this man Sam Little has confessed to
police that he's committed 90 murders.
How many the police actually know that
he's already committed? Yeah, Little is
currently in prison in Texas serving
four life sentences without the
possibility of parole for four murders.
Now, the FBI says that they can connect
him now to 34 additional killings. Oh my
goodness. And they are still
investigating his confessions. So that
number is likely to go much much higher.
You know, it's really astounding that he
was able to kill so many women over
almost 50 years without getting caught.
And it's largely because he moved from
state to state so frequently that
officials really couldn't connect the
dots until 2012. And that's when they
had this national database provided new
information. There was new DNA
technology. And it was also a lot of
good old-fashioned detective work that
helped put him behind bars. But when you
look at the details of the crimes he was
committing, he could have been put away
for longer for any of those crimes. And
yet he seemed to sliver through a law
enforcement system just wasn't taking
his threat to society that seriously.
Which raises for me a big issue because
what shocks me the most about serial
killers, and we've been talking about
them on the show, is how many people are
actually able to evade police for so
many years and maybe forever. Think
about that. There's some estimates as
many as 40% of murders are unsolved.
40%. How many of those are created by
serial criminals that are able to take
lives with impunity, not get caught? And
you guys think there are more serial
killers out there that we have never
heard of that may actually you rival the
Sam little guy? I mean, there are so
many cold cases out there that when you
think about it is is incredibly likely
just from a statistical point of view
that there are other serial killers out
there operating and killing people right
now. It's very scary. And these guys are
smart, right? They're manipulative. Yes.
And they get a rush from getting away
with murder because that's why they
carefully plan things out and execute
them. And then they look back at their
masterpiece and they feel so proud of
themselves for not getting caught. But
maybe that's what's happening with Sam
Little when he draws these
illustrations. If in fact all these turn
out to be real victims. So the FBI just
recently released the victim sketches
that killer Sam Little is drawing in
prison. Have they received any good
tips, Mara? Do you have you followed up
on some of these pictures? Yeah, they
actually have. So, there's a man in
Tennessee who saw one of these sketches
and he said, "That looks like my
mother." His mother's a woman named
Priscilla Baxter Jones, and she
disappeared on Christmas Eve in 1996,
and she was later found murdered. And
this man who says, "That was my mother
says that he remembers a man like Little
hanging around with his mother in the
'9s." And when you look at the picture
side by side, when you look at the
sketch and her photo, there is such a
close resemblance there. It's hard to
write that off as coincidence. Dr.
Joseph, as a psychiatrist, what what is
going on in the minds of these killers?
Why would this man steal a woman on
Christmas Eve and keep it secret, then
talk about it all these years later by
drawing her picture? Well, what we know
about Sam Little now is that he's 78.
He's got diabetes, hypertension, he's
sitting in a wheelchair in a cell. But
don't let that fool you because the Sam
Little in his heyday was a massive man.
He was 6'3 and he was powerful. One of
the reports described his hand as a
baseball m as big as a baseball mitt and
he got a thrill from beating people
sometimes to death. Some of these women
died in his arms and we know that he saw
the killing as a sort of love. And so
he's a sadistic serial killer who
belongs in jail. So he's very careful
about choosing his victims. Very
careful. He chose people who are
marginalized members of society, young
women of color who were prostitutes,
people that no one would look for if
they went missing. And so that's how he
got away with these murders for years.
No one was looking for these women. Any
idea about why he would do this? If you
consider crossing them now, what would
he say was the reason? Well, we know
that from what we know about him, he was
abandoned by his mother. But you know
what, Dr. Oz, a lot of people don't grow
up with their mothers. A lot of people
are abandoned. But serial killers have
very disturbing paths. And so from his
report of loving these women and killing
them because he loved them so much, we
know that his development was not
normal. He had abnormal attachment and
he does not know how to truly love and
attach to another human being. So coming
up, we speak to the officer who came
face to face with serial killer Sam
Little. He's going to tell us about
their disturbing conversation. And Sam
Little had a longtime girlfriend,
believe it or not. We're going to find
out about her. That is next. I am back
with psychiatrist Dr. Judith Joseph and
investigative correspondent Mars Avao
talking about the case of Sam Little who
may turn out to be the deadliest serial
killer in US history. The FBI recently
released sketches little had drawings of
some of his victims and they are looking
for help in solving these crimes. If you
recognize any of these pictures uh we
want to talk to you. Now Sergeant Mike
Mangaluzo of the Major Crimes Unit in
Marian County, Florida recently
interviewed Sam Little face to face. He
joins us now via Zoom. Thank you again
for spending time with us. Tell me about
your conversation with Sam Little and
what information were you hoping to get
from him? What I was trying to do is I
had to cooperate the initial
investigation from 1982. Things have
changed dramatically since then uh since
invention of DNA and testing the way it
is. So I had to make sure everything was
processed the way it was supposed to be
processed. And uh basically I needed to
cooperate and I needed a confession.
What did he tell you about Rose Hill or
rather Rosie Hills murder?
Uh he told me that he met her one night
outside. She was standing outside of a
bar. Um she had gotten into an argument
with her boyfriend and she decided to go
with him and um it was at that point
soon after that he killed her. And did
he provide details about how he killed
her, why he killed her, what he did with
the body? Yes, sir. He um said he
strangled her uh in his car in the back
seat. He um uh tells me of a story about
a police officer pulling up right after
he had um strangled her and she was
dead. And um he was able to get out of
the car, distract the police officer and
the police officer actually shined a
light inside the car on Rosie Hill who
was deceased at the time. And um the cop
told him to leave uh because u he had
gotten a suspicious vehicle call and it
was them and um he just told them to
leave. He didn't check anybody's ID. um
at that point. So they just drove off.
And so from there, Sam Little says that
he drove up a super highway, which is
going to be Interstate 75 that runs
through Florida to make sure the cop
wasn't following him still. And he was
able to pull off onto a country road and
and dispose of Rosie Hill, dump her
body. And did he specify where he dumped
the body? I'm only asking because I know
these were things that only the
criminal, the perpetrator would have
known. Yes, sir. And that was important
for me. Um he dumped her by a hog pen.
Um and she was located uh decomposed
next to a hog pen in Maring County.
So you have good reason. Yeah. Go ahead.
I'm sorry. Uh that was important for me
because not everybody knows that. And
the and the fact that he knew uh she was
standing outside a bar and she had just
got into an argument with her boyfriend.
That's very important to the case. So
you speak to criminals for a living.
What what was like talking to a serial
killer like Sam Little?
It was surreal and at the same time very
chilling. I realized I was talking to a
delusional psychopath. Um, very humble
man. Very nice man, but nonetheless,
he's a psychopath. He's a monster.
That's the key takeaway, everybody. Nice
man. Humble man who's a psychopath.
Mike, I appreciate you taking time out
of your busy schedule to talk with us.
Thanks for your insights into the minds
of serial killer Sam Little. Now Marla,
let me ask you. It's been reported that
Sam actually had a longtime girlfriend,
which speaks again to the sociopathy,
the fact that he could actually get away
with this, that they could have a
girlfriend. What do we know about her?
Yeah, we don't know very much about her,
but we do know that she was a woman
named Jean. She is now dead. And Little
has told officials that she supported
the two of them by shoplifting. So, she
was no serial killer, but another
criminal.
Dr. Joseph, how does that even work? And
would you think that little would have
shared with his girlfriend the fact that
he had this murder streak and he'd
killed maybe 90 women? Probably not
because she'd pro she would have died a
lot earlier. And the thing about
sociopaths is that they can border on
psycho psychopathy which is a more
severe version of sociopathy. And this
sounds like a a psychopath. Someone who
carefully plans murders out, carries
them out, and then he gets away with
them because he evades authorities for
many years. So, he likely lived a double
life and hid all of his secrets from his
partner. He compartmentalizes the world.
That's the part that I'm really walking
away from. You can be friends with
somebody who's a completely different
and very dangerous person when they're
in a different compartment of their
life. Do we have any idea how Genie was
it? His girlfriend. Do we have any idea
how she died? We have very little
information about her at this time. We
never know. Maybe she she was one of the
90. Maybe she did find out or suspected.
Families do find out sometimes. All
right. Coming up, how can you help solve
the mysteries of Sam Little's murder
victims? The answer is
next. We're back talking about the
disturbing case of Sam Little, who may
turn out to be the most prolific serial
killer in US history, claiming he has
killed 90 people. We are now joined by
lawyer and host of Law and Crime
Network, Jesse Weber, as well as my
other panelists. So, Sam Little has
interesting problem because he had an
extensive criminal arrest record going
back to
1956. It's a long time, right? Burglary,
breaking and entering, assault and
battery, assault with the intent to rob,
armed robbery, assault on a police
officer, rape. These are big crimes he
was accused of, and some of them he's
actually convicted of, and yet he served
only a total of 10 years in prison until
his arrest on murder charge in 2012. I
mean, Jesse, you're a lawyer. Please
explain this to me. How how do you get
away? How do you commit so many crimes
and get away with most of it, and the
stuff you don't get away with, you still
don't pay that much of a price on? Dr.
This is the most troubling aspect of
this entire case because here's a guy
who got arrested for serious offenses
over and over again and the case has
either fell apart or he served with
little time. Let's go to 1976 in
Missouri. He's arrested for the assault,
rape, and robbery of a woman who shows
up on her stranger's doorstep almost
fully naked. Her hands are tied behind
her back and she's hysterical. She
claims that little sodomized her,
strangled her, beat her, and bit her.
What does he serve? 3 months because
he's convicted of a lesser charge. Fast
forward 1982. The nude body of Patricia
Mount is found in Florida. Witnesses say
the last person she was with was Little
and that the hairs found on Mount look
very similar to those of Little. He's
actually tried, but he's acquitted for
lack of physical evidence. Go to another
time. He pleads guilty to two counts of
assault against two different women for
strangling them and beating them. and he
only serves a year and a half of a
four-year sentence because he's
parrolled. So, when we look at this, how
on earth does a monster like this,
somebody who is such a predator in the
community, how was he let out to kill
and attack over and over and over again?
And just to be clear, we've been pretty
vocal about criminal justice reform. We,
you know, there the vast majority of
folks who make mistakes should not be
put away forever. But there are some bad
apples and we are seemingly missing
these guys because they tend to be the
more dangerous ones because they're
sociopathic. They know how to manipulate
the system. Dr. Joseph, let's put your
psychiatry hat to work here. As you look
at these images, what do you see? What
do they tell us about Sam Little. The
most striking thing about this, Dr. Oz,
every single victim had the same
deadlike eyes. And we know that Sam
Little liked to play God. He liked the
power of life or death. And in one of
his interviews, he mentioned being this
angel of mercy where he would put these
poor women out of their misery by
killing them and watching their half-
deadad eyes fade away. Yeah. So, he's
drawing his version of them with dead
eyes. Correct. And he's very grandiose.
He believes that he is God. So, he has
the power of life or death. And that's
scary. Well, he'll ultimately be judged
by God as well. But in the meantime,
Jesse, he's confessed to 90 murder.
Actually, I'm sorry. He's he's been
convicted of four. confessed to 90
murders, right? But at this time, police
are just sort of putting the pieces
together. And Mari mentioned 34 cases.
They have pretty good connection. What's
next? How do they go about unraveling
the the mystery of all these women who
may have been hurt by him? Well, those
sketches that he's drawing are actually
a huge step in solving a lot of these
mysteries. And right now, there's a
collaboration between the FBI and local
agencies to corroborate the details
provided by Little. So, they're opening
up cold case files. They're interviewing
witnesses. They're following leads.
They're doing whatever they can to
corroborate. Now, here's the thing. They
have a time crunch. Sam Little is 78
years old, and by a lot of accounts,
he's in poor health. They need to get as
much information from him as possible
before he dies. So, hopefully someone's
actually talking to him about all these
individual cases. Mara, update us. What
What can What can viewers do if they
want to help out? Yeah, if someone has
information, they should contact the
FBI's violent criminal apprehension
program. There's an 800 number that
we're going to put up on the screen. It
doesn't matter how big or small the
information you think you may have is,
it could be the key to crack these
decades old cold cases. And as you point
out, he doesn't have much time left. The
families want justice. 40% of cases
unsolved.
40%. Remember that number. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good