Today, for years, we've been told to eat
less carbs and more protein. New
research shows that those steaks,
burgers, and bacon could be the secret
culprit behind your biggest health
issue, meat belly dilemma. When you eat
this kind of diet, bad bacteria can
overpopulate. Plus, shocking information
that you never knew about seafood. 90%
of our seafood is important, and the FDA
only takes a look at 3% or less. Coming
up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you
[Music]
[Applause]
guys. Paleo, keto, whole 30. No matter
which diet tribe you belong to, one
thing is clear. We live in a new low
carb culture that has everyone thinking
meat. Meat. But new research shows that
those steaks, burgers, and the bacon may
be changing our gut and could be the
secret culprit behind your biggest
health issues, including what you dread
most, constipation. So, today we're
asking, could a proteinpacked diet lead
to a meat belly dilemma? My go-to
tester, Renatha, is here with a group of
meat lovers right now who have concerns.
So, Renatha, who'd you bring with you?
What are the concerns? So, these ladies
are some hardcore meat lovers, okay?
They pack on the protein. They are in
the meat, meat, meat, and meat and meat,
more meat, right? But they do have some
concerns, okay? So, I mean, this is who
these ladies are. Some meat. Don't look
at me like that. You go first. Don't
look at me like that. I know you all
have complaints.
Well, I pretty much eat meat for every
meal. So, I think if I'd have I think I
probably do have meat belly, so just
worried about how I can fix things.
Carol, what's bothering you? If I if I
said you look good, but maybe you don't
feel so good. What's bothering your
belly? Um, I feel that since the low
carb diet that I've been on, I eat a lot
of protein and meat, but I also feel
that um I'm stopped up and I'm I I'm I
just need like I need a movement or join
the movement. Well stated. You join the
movement with a movement. I appreciate
it very much. That's a big complaint
with folks who eat meat. All right. So,
Susan, what are your concerns? Well,
I've been on a low carb, high protein
diet for a really long time, and I've
done really well with it, but I just
want to know what meat belly is. What's
the dilemma? All right, so this caught
my attention and there's actually a lot
to say about it. So, I brought in a guru
that I trust a lot in this. She's also
my big expert on gut, Dr. Butch Roster.
So, Butch, you just heard, how are you?
So, Carol stopped up. Bernat avoided the
issue completely because I know there
probably things she's worried about.
Zena's got her, you know, concerns about
the pendulum swinging too far. So, there
was a study recently which actually
prompted me to do this show which looked
at the effect of meat on the bacteria in
our gut. Yeah. A study from Harvard, by
the way, ladies and gentlemen, his alma
mada, but it's from Harvard. Give my
hand. The Yellies have to give you the
prompt, right? That's where he went.
That's where he went. All right. Now, so
here's the deal with this. We had
prominent universities uh Harvard and
the University of California that took
two groups and they had equal number of
males and females but they did something
different. They fed them over five days
a plant-based diet and one group a
meat-based diet. And the meatbased diet
was beef, pork, egg yolks, and other
fatty foods. And guess what happened in
five days? Five days of that diet
change, the people in the meat-based
group, their gut bacteria composition
and populations changed. And as you
know, we want to keep a healthy gut
balance in our GI tract for good health.
Actually, we have a little animation
your shoulders everybody because I want
you all to appreciate how gut bacteria
affects your health, especially when
it's the meat that's changing it. So,
baseline, these are all the little
bacteria. Exactly. And we want a diverse
population. It's all about a balance of
power between the good bacteria and the
bad bacteria. But when you eat this kind
of diet, oh, the little nasty bad
bacteria can really overpop populate.
And these are nasty little critters. And
let's just say how nasty are they? You
would not invite them to Thanksgiving
dinner if you had a bunch of these Y.
But they come along uninvited at what do
they release? Exly. And and the big
thing is that they release something
called TMAO.
Now, nobody try should try to remember
this. I remember it by saying tomato.
Okay, that's how I remember it. But the
big thing that you must remember about
this dangerous agent is that it can
cause chronic autoimmune diseases. And
that's that's the bottom line. All
right. So, Dr. Roser has some foods that
can lower the inflammation that could be
caused by meat so you can avoid the meat
belly dilemma. So, what do you want us
to add to our diets? Let's go to the
first one, Dr. because pistachios of all
things pistachios why because they can
decrease TMA or tomato and but sometimes
you know you know Dr. Oz you have to
trick yourself let me go ahead and show
people how I can actually trick myself
into getting those nutrients you don't
mind at dawn this morning I got this
alarming picture put it up there please
if you don't mind Scott that's what I
got this is Dr. roster getting up in the
morning. I don't think he was showing
off either. That's what he was having
for breakfast. Yeah, exactly. But look
at what we do with salmon. You can grind
up the pistachios and make a crusting
agent and then put a little cayenne
pepper. You know, I'm a southerner, so
you know, I'm going to go on you and
wrap that up into something that is
absolutely delicious. It looks
fantastic. And it is. Oh, it is. And
let's go to the next one. Now, this
one, Brussels sprouts of all things. The
only use I had for Brussels sprouts, Dr.
Oz, was in the fifth grade hitting the
boy upside the head that took my
girlfriend. Yeah, I'm still injured by
that. But my wife recently taught me how
you roast these. You roast it and you
can even had have bacon. Yeah, guys,
that's right. We We're not declaring a
war on meat at all. Okay. But you can't
go berserk with meat and especially just
give a little bacon here and then roast
it and and you got yourself a good meal.
And the last but not least, I got to
have something sweet. Do you know that
grapes and berries actually have um a a
special ingredient that helps to
decrease TMAO or tomato? Now, what I do,
Dr. Oz, you can have them frozen, but I
have to put a little um low carb whipped
cream, if there is such a thing, on top.
All right.
So, Renata, he's speaking your language
for you. What do you guys think over
there? You know, he's speaking my
language, Dr. Eyes. Okay, first of all,
mind blown. Okay, my mind is blown. And
I mean, yes, the the frozen grapes. He's
because I do have a sweet tooth. You
know me. Okay, I do have a sweet tooth.
And um using the pistachios as crust for
salmon. You know, we got to trick
ourselves. Yeah. You know, you know, I
love my fried stuff, so I got to trick
myself into u making it a healthier
option. Ran, we call that stealthy
healthy eating. You got trick yourself
to do the right thing. There's one other
dilemma that got brought up earlier,
which is constipation. You know, the
need to move. It's not always being
satisfied. First of all, why do so many
folks who are big meat eaters have
issues with that? Well, and this is one
of the most frequent complaints I have
with patients that they have a difficult
time going. And the big thing is that
the meat has a high fatty content. And
here's the process. And this is going
from the root to the tuda as we say down
south for all you folk who are familiar.
All right. To the root to the tutor.
You eat this heavy fatty food. That
slows down your transit time. How long
it takes to go through the intestine.
That allows more absorption of water.
That makes your bowel movement what?
Hard. that gives you constipation and
Houston we have a problem when that
happens. So that's what it's all about.
So you know once again we're not we
don't have a war on meat. Let's look at
these three items here and this is a way
to find out well help you in the
decision making here when you look at
this steak over here that I'm pointing
to. Now notice Dr. Oz there's not a lot
of white streaking there. No. Okay.
That's low fat content. All right. Now
come over and look at this T-bone. Maybe
it looks good. Oh Lord, help us. And
this is the one we really like, right?
And so the the big thing here is follow
this roster's rule. If you got to have
one, you got to give me four days of the
good meats. If you got to have one, you
got to give me four. Which always a
pleasure, my friend. All right. Got it.
Up next, a meat industry insider is
signing the alarm on an FDA loophole
that's allowing antibiotics to still
sneak into your meat. Now, are these
antibiotics also messing with your gut?
We're going to find out when we return.
All new, the new ecigarette you don't
even know your kids are using. You have
kids congregating and they start to
vape. It looks like a flash drive. It's
not. And then the kids can tuck it away
when they're done. Kids don't think that
they're doing anything but vaping water.
Young people in particular are really
really susceptible. All new Oz. That's
coming up
[Music]
[Applause]
tomorrow. It's the change consumers like
you and the medical community have been
asking for to have less antibiotics in
meat. And the FDA listened, having
banned the use of antibiotics in healthy
animals aimed at speeding up their
growth. But meat industry insiders,
they're sounding the alarm on a major
loophole in this policy that still
allows antibiotics to sneak into our
meat. Today, a rancher speaks out.
Nichollet Han Nyman is the author of
Defending Beef and one of the most
influential ranchers around. She's
actually at Nimman Ranch. So, how are
antibiotics still ending up in our beef?
Well, in our meat generally, what FDA
did was it said you can't use
antibiotics to promote growth, but it
didn't say you can't use them in a non-
therapeutic way, which is where you feed
the whole herd or you put it into the
water and so all of the chickens or all
of the pigs are getting the antibiotics.
So, they're still allowing it for
disease prevention. That's a non-
therapeutic use. And from a public
health perspective and from a concern
about healthfulness on meat, you know,
the antibiotic resistant bacteria being
on meat, it has the same effect. So,
it's a huge loophole in the FDA rule.
The big question is how do the
antibiotics mess up your gut flora,
right? Or do they at all? And I was
going to say something. You know, we've
been just fielding questions about
constipation, other problems like that.
The good news is that doesn't seem to be
an impact from the antibiotics that the
animals are given in your gut. It's not
messing up your gut like if you were
taking the antibiotics. There are strict
rules that require animals to be weaned
from antibiotics well before the
slaughter. So there those antibiotics
aren't ending up in your meat. But there
are other concerns like the animal
passing along antibi resistant bacteria
which is what you're bringing up. And if
I don't mind, if you don't mind, let me
take one second to get everyone on the
same page. Take a closer look at this
loophole because it's vitally important.
We understand because it's the hypocrisy
about all this that really bothers me.
Right? So let's talk about what happened
before the ban. Ranchers used
antibiotics not just for treating
diseases, right? But but for making the
animals grow faster, right? Because why?
Animals get ready faster for the
slaughter. And time is money. So you
know, if you were a rancher, you'd
probably do this too, right? But
recently, this came to an end. The FDA
banned antibiotics used just for growth
promotion. Why? Because
antibiotics and their use became so
prevalent that we started suffering a
national health crisis of antibiotic
resistance. Have you all heard about it,
right? Antibiotic resistance. You know,
it's because in part we believe so many
animals are getting antibiotics for
reasons that don't involve infections.
So the FDA limited the use of the drugs
by saying you can't use it to fatten up
your pig, but you can use it to treat
your pig if they get sick. Right? Pig's
not feeling well. We don't want the
animal to die. Antibiotics are
appropriately used for humans. They can
be appropriately used for animals, for
your pets. Everyone's happy. But this is
a very big butt. The FDA left a
loophole. Ended up becoming a big
loophole. They allow antibiotics to be
put in the feed of animals as a means
for disease prevention. Now that means
even if the animal's not sick, it can be
given preventatively. And the problem is
it leaves a back door open to use it as
a growth promoter again. So Nichollet,
this is a theoretical issue and you know
I host a television show but I'm not a
farmer, not a rancher. You are. So how
commonly are meat growers using this
loophole in your opinion? Well, I think
it's probably quite common. So, really
the problem with this rule as it's
written right now is that it's just
about the intent of the farmer. So,
someone can just say, "I'm not using it
for that purpose. I'm using it for this
purpose." And not change any of their
practices. And and most animals probably
do get antibiotics, right? Um in the
conventional industry, yes. in up in a
few years ago there was a really uh
thorough analysis done by the union of
concern scientist and they found that
100% of pigs were getting it in the
finishing stage and about that much in
the poultry as well. These are in the
conventional industry something that's
not organic and uh it's the usage has
continued to grow over the years. So
it's it's a huge it's a huge issue. You
don't believe we should get rid of all
antibiotics I am told no I think that's
a really important distinction. There's
therapeutic use. It's just like you just
said, when you have a sick human, you
can give them antibiotics and that's
appropriate. Similarly, if you have a
sick individual pig or chicken or cattle
animal, it's appropriate to treat them.
We had a mature mother cow that was 7
years old on our farm a few years ago.
She had never been sick and she had uh
as the fall weather came and it was
getting cooler nights, she got
pneumonia. We treated her with
antibiotics in that case and she fully
recovered and she didn't have to suffer
a prolonged illness. She's still with
our
her that is the right way to use
antibiotics. I should point out there's
a true paradox. You're a rancher and a
vegetarian. Yes, you guys can work that
out later on. It's unusual. So So listen
on this show, we believe transparency is
critical when it comes to your meat. So,
Renatha's group of meat lovers is going
to get a chance to ask questions to a
real life rancher. If that's okay, come
on over. The first thing I want to ask
Renath actually is no antibiotic meat,
right? Is that important to you? I mean,
yeah. I mean, it's important. I mean,
you know, antibiotics was used for meat
growth, but and you know, in the long
run, if you're going to the grocery
store, you get more meat product for
your buck. But, you know, my concern is
antibiotic resistance, you know. So, you
know, it's the right concern to have,
right? Absolutely. Doctors like me are
primarily worried about that as well. I
actually wouldn't mind it so much. I
don't want farmers to suffer, ranchers
to have a difficult time. I just don't
want to create health problems for the
rest of us. You have a question for
Nichollet. Yeah. I mean, what can I do
to ensure that I'm buying the best meat
possible, the healthiest meat possible?
Yeah. Well, if you're in a grocery store
and you want to get the best possible
meat, the organic label is a good label.
It does say that the antibiotics haven't
been used. also tells you more about
good animal husbandry and good um land
stewardship. And I also um there's
certainly an antibiotic free label you
can look for. But for me, I always try
to um find that the animal was raised on
pasture. So grass is kind of the watch
word. If the animal was on grass, it
probably had a healthier life and the
food that it produces, whether it's milk
or meat or eggs, is more nutritious
food. Thank you very much. Thank you.
Chad Nichollet's book. It's called
Defending Beef. You and I are joining a
cow show after the show. We'll be We'll
be right back.
[Applause]
Everything you need to know about how to
buy and cook the perfect fish every
time. I'm letting you into the
magician's circle. Find out all the
secrets coming up next. Look how flaky
this is. Oh my
goodness. Look carefully. This or this?
Fresh or frozen? When it comes to buying
fish for your family, it's hard to tell
which is best. So, today we're
connecting you with a fish industry
whistleblower and a food investigator to
reveal shocking inside information that
you never knew about seafood. Paul
Greenberg is here as one of the biggest
authorities in fish regulation. A sports
fisherman and ecologist who's making
waves lately tracking the fish weed from
sea to store. And Chef Danny Boom is
here.
It's got the consumer red flags that you
have not heard before. Paul, let's start
off with the the first thing. You know,
you were around fish all the time. Is it
okay to buy in a supermarket where it's
cheaper? Well, first of all, there's
something fishy going on with our fish
supply. I mean, that mean so many puns.
He's casting a wide net on these. Got
you on the line. But, um, so 90% of our
seafood is imported actually in this
country and the FDA only takes a look at
3% or less. Wow. So, huge huge
disconnect between what we know and what
we being sold out there. Um,
supermarkets can be a good place to get
your seafood, but you need an extra
layer of knowledge and protection. And
we're going to give you a few ideas, I
think, that will help you get along with
that. You did an interesting experiment.
Yeah. Uh, for all of us to benefit from
you. For breakfast, lunch, and dinner
for a year, you ate fish. I did.
Was it worth it? What was the outcome?
Well, it was a little again fishy, but
um, no. So, you think I'm kidding.
Everything he says is one fish. Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry. Um well, first off, my
omega-3 levels were quite high. Um they
were over 10%. Um most Americans are
about half that. And also my mercury
went up up to about five five parts per
million. So it was super super high.
What I've kind of come to realize is
that two portions of sustainably raised
or sustainably caught seafood is really
great. And the rest of your diet, make
it vegan. So a little bit of fish, a
little bit of shellfish, mostly vegan,
you'll be good. So the the best consumer
is educated consumer. So, if it's okay,
you guys are going to school us, right?
Thank you for getting my puns. Yeah.
We're going to start with the question.
I I I uh opened the segment with fresh
or frozen. What do you guys think is
better?
Fresh. Fresh. You're sure? Yes. Why are
you sure? I feel it has more benefits to
it and it's not really sure. You're not
sure, but it sounds like it's better,
right? You're pretty sure. Healthier.
Healthier. Fresh. But frozen is much
easier more convenient. Yeah, frozen is
more That's the problem, right? Frozen's
so much more convenient, but darn it,
fresh is better for us. Or is it? So,
the first thing you need to know about
buying fish is which one is actually
better, frozen or fresh? Paul, walk us
through this. Well, here's the thing.
Frozen is not bad at all. And you know,
it used to be frozen seafood was gross,
right? It was um sort of rubbery
texture. That was because they froze
things at really um not low enough
temperatures, froze it too slowly. Now
they have these super fast freezing
methods that keep it really really
frozen, really cold. Um and if you
defrost it in your refrigerator
overnight, you will end up with a really
delicious piece of fish. Now, aren't you
happy you came to the show today? All
right, next thing we want to know is you
want to
look for the freshest fish. And you want
to look therefore for clear eyes, not
cloudy eyes. Danny, why is that
important? Okay, first thing is a cloudy
eye. Looks dead in. Look at this fish
here. Look, they got the the fresh and
then sort of like a five day to six day
old fish. Okay, so the eye is cloudy.
But then there's the old wives sayings.
Okay, so let's look at this fish here.
This is how we know a fish is fresh
because we have a clear eye, beautiful
scales. But then we would open up the
fish. This is where we will insert the
knife. We come down. Okay. And then what
we do is we open up from the gills. Now
the gills are here. Okay. Now you most
people are going to look in here and
this is the gill. Look how beautiful
pink deep red that is. Can you all see
that? You see on both sides there. Now
everybody knows the expression green
behind the gills, right? That means when
you're sick. Well, you don't want green
behind the gills when it's a fresh fish.
Okay? You want deep, beautiful pink and
red colors. Okay? Then we look at the
look at the actual flesh of the fish as
well. Okay? When you're dealing with
like white fish or like snapper or even
salmon, you're looking at that bright
color every time. Okay? So, the brighter
the fish, the deeper the colors. And
again, like with snapper, like with
white fish, it should be opaque. It
should be a bright white. Okay? And with
salmon, it should be like a good deep
red. So, get back to these eyes. I read
an article recently because I'm
fascinated by telling about your fishes
being good or bad for you. And there
were there's a tweet that showed that
markets are putting fake googly eyes on
fish to distract the shoppers. This is a
real tweet, right? It's unbelievable,
but that's how you know attractive it
is. It was working for that market, they
wouldn't be doing it. All right. Next
thing you need to know about buying fish
is you want to buy your shrimp and your
scallops in a way that that where you're
sure they have not been treated with a
hidden chemical or if you get the hidden
chemical, at least know that you're
getting it. So, what is this hidden
chemical, Paul? So, it's sodium
tripolyphosphate. It's actually a salt.
Um, and this is a chemical that uh,
seafood makers use to plump up their
catch. Um, it actually causes seafood to
absorb a lot of water, but in the
process, it's also giving us quite a
sodium load. So, these 5 ounces of
shrimp here, that's like 60% of the
recommended daily intake of sodium. So,
that's a huge load. So, the problem is
when you cook this, in addition, this
stuff will shrink down. Shrinkage will
occur and uh, you'll end up with lot
less shrimp on your plate. So, the S is
sodium salt, correct? Yeah. And if you
don't have it, it's only 16% of the salt
that you're allowed for the day.
Correct. So that's, you know, four-fold
increase from adding this. That's right.
All right. So, in fairness, this this
salt stuff, STP, is not dangerous for
your health, right? Small amounts. It's
the price. It's the price. It's the
flavor. Yeah. Right. And maybe the
texture. They all fit together. So, let
me bring Zena in here because Zena's got
lots of questions. This woman has more
questions than anyone I know, I think.
All right. So,
your family apparently can't get enough
seafood. So, how worried about chemicals
like this in the in the store? Well,
first off, I'm just concerned that
there's chemicals being pumped into my
seafood anyway. Um, but now that I'm
hearing it's not bad for you, my other
concern is just being ripped off at the
at the supermarket. Absolutely.
Absolutely. So, how can you tell, Chef
Danny? Well, basically, as we said,
we're talking about the STP is plumping
it out. Okay. So, when we talk about
certain things, you're looking at
differentiations. When you're looking at
the scolops right here, we have dry and
we have wet. The wet is in a milky
brine. Okay, that's your actually that's
your STP right there. Okay, so those
they look off already to me. I don't
actually find that appetizing, but when
you look at the dry, look at them. They
got this beautiful peaches and cream
color. How about shrimp? Because I I
suspect families like ours are eating a
lot of frozen shrimp. It's the classic
thing you get. So, how do you know if
they've added STP, which appears to be
pretty common? This is the problem.
Okay, it's not always on the packet.
Okay, we we're labeling in this country
is terrible. Okay, so when we look at
this uh bag of shrimp here, it just says
shrimp on it. Okay, that's fantastic. So
then when the other bag of frozen
shrimp, it says easy peel, but it
doesn't say anything else. So what I'm
going to tell you right now is when it
says easy, nothing's easy in the food
world, people. We have to prepare, we
have to make food, okay? And and you
have to be within that in your kitchen
culture. When you look at easy peel,
what that means is basically it's been
pumped. It's been sat in the brine of
the STPPP. So, basically, the flesh is
basically bulked up and it's too big for
the shell. So, when you actually defrost
it and when you get to cooking, pops. It
pops. Okay, that's what makes it easy.
You know what? I'm not going to be
eating these. So, you can have these. If
you feel bad buying the cheaper option
when it comes to your fish, we're
absolving your guil your guilt because
it'll break two fish rules that you
always thought were true. Stick around.
The rates for pancreatic cancer are
actually going up. It's one of the
deadliest forms of cancer and has
claimed the lives of legends. The top
three ways to cut down your risk. Plus,
surprising ancestry DNA results. The man
that raised me was not my biological
father. All new Oz. That's coming up on
Wednesday.
[Music]
If you have ever had a wave of guilt
hook at you when you're fish shopping
and you choose the cheaper option, well,
fear not because they were giving you
permission to break two rules, big fish
rules that you thought were always true.
So, I've told Susan buys fish for her
family. So, describe everybody what it
feels like when the the tide rises, the
tide of guilt. Well, I feel really
guilty when I buy frozen fish, like I'm
a cheap mom, like I'm cheaping out on my
kids. So I don't know, you know, I
always think I should get the wild
versus the farm raised. Yeah, there are
budget questions we always have. Now,
you saw that earlier when we started
challenging folks about their
assumptions. So, you know, something
makes sense for your family, but you
think the other thing is better for your
family. So, let's break through this
right now. Pay attention because Chef
Danny Boom and our fish whistleblower
and author of the Omega Principle Paul
Greenberg says, "Farmed fish can be as
good as wild." I hope that sets your
heart at ease because this is a big
issue because it's a big price
difference. Paul, why? Well, I mean,
first of all, I'm a dad and I do all the
cooking in my house. So, I also look for
cheap things. So, um, but farmed seafood
used to have a bad rap and there's all
sorts of instances, a lot of antibiotics
being used, uh, poor sighting of farms
and so forth, but we're really starting
to see this new generation of
aquaculture entrepreneurs who are really
trying to do things as sort of
sustainably as any organic farmer. My
mind has changed completely. 10 years
ago when we started the show, I would
have actively told you not to buy farmed
fish because I'd been to farmed fish
areas. It just didn't seem sanitary. It
seemed sloppy, uh, low budget. It's not
how it is right now. They want because
obviously they heard the consumer. The
consumer had concerns and so the farmers
listened. And so then we're looking at
fish like arctic char, catfish, big
hardy fish now that are being produced
on mass. There is a better and safer
way. So, these are all fish that you
guys are beginning to hear more and more
about because they're they're
affordable. They're farm-raised. I think
from a health perspective, they're just
fine. And I want to applaud guys who
made a big difference. They've changed
my mind on this. All right, Paul, let's
go to you. You love the ocean. You're
committed to sustainability. You say
there's an important rule when it comes
to buying fish. And I'm going to say
this is not about nationalism. Paul says
we got to buy American or from countries
with good environmental policies. Why?
Well, this country has gone through a
tremendous revolution in our fisheries
management. And so we should award award
American fisheries for really behaving
really well. And it's not just America.
It's not just a nationalist thing. We
have Australia. We have New Zealand,
Iceland, Norway. These are countries
that are really following the rules of
science and are really producing good
good healthy fish for us. Iceland, huh?
Well, why not? Listen, we got this very
popular new podcast, the Oz podcast that
uh Paul's a guest on. We do these deeper
dives into these kinds of topics and you
tell a great story. So, you know, check
it out. It's free. you'll learn
something. Our next chef, Danny Boom,
says when buying fish, it's okay to go
for smaller fish. Maybe it's preferable
to go for smaller fish. It really is.
Well, the first thing is they're tiny
but mighty. Okay, they've got tons of
amiggas in this. And the great thing is
you don't have to buy it pickled or in a
jar. You can actually buy them fresh.
They're fantastic for barbecuing, okay,
or on the grill. And uh seriously, also
a little bit of olive oil, a little salt
and pepper, and they just do it all.
They have all the flavor. Pack the
flavor, pack the nutrients. I I tend to
eat this kind of fish as much as
possible. I know it has a strong taste
for things like herring, I turn into a
cat. I can't stop myself. But let me
explain what Danny means and why you
might want to change what you're eating.
So besides the taste, because I do think
it tastes better. Researchers say that
small fish, right? They travel around
and they eat all the different things,
the algae and all, but guess what? They
often have a little bit of mercury in
them because the algae they're eating
and the other seaweed and stuff, they
get contaminated from coal fire plants
and other things in the water, right? So
these little fish have a little bit of
mercury in them. Guess what happens? A
bigger fish comes along, trumps them up,
right? The predator now has all the
mercury that was in the many fish that
it ate. It doesn't stop there because
what happens to the bigger fish? They
get eaten by the even bigger fish,
right? And the process continues and so
on and so forth. And you purchase the
big fish, right? You put it on your
plate and guess what? It now has the
largest amount of mercury of all the
fish. And that can be harmful. I had
high mercury levels. That's why I'm so
tuned to this. so high that I got a
letter from the state department of
health. Wow. Saying, "Hey, what's wrong
with you?" And it was because I was
eating so much fish. And you know, Paul,
we learned earlier did went an
experiment. He was eating fish all the
time. He got higher levels. It doesn't
have to be that way. Eat the smaller
fish, you can avoid the problems. So,
now that you know what kind of fish to
buy, plus it's less expensive when you
buy the small fish. Chef Danny Boom is
giving away restaurant secrets you can
use at home to cook the tastiest fish of
your life. Oh, you're going to like
this.
[Music]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your
[Applause]
podcast. I want you eating fish at least
twice a week, but a lot of you tell me
it's hard to prepare. I get it. So, I
asked Chef Danny to spill the restaurant
secrets to perfect fish. Is there a
special method to cooking fish? There's
I think I think what most people get is
is the timing and the heat. I think we
either cook overcook it or we either
basically really put it at such a high
temperature that we dry out. And that's
the biggest complaints when we talk
about fish. So, there's three major ways
of cooking fish, okay? There's baking,
steaming, and poaching. Okay? The first
thing we're going to start with is
baking. So, we got a baking tray. This
is the the basically the the quick and
easy. And most types of fish are very
hardy that we would do this with. So,
we're using cod today. So, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to go straight
in with a little lemon on the bottom of
the of some foil. Okay. A little salt.
Okay. Now, why I'm putting the salt on
the base and the pepper is because I'm
not going to be turning my fish. So, I'm
going to be baking it. So, I'm going to
be surrounding it in uh at the oven.
It's going to be about 400. And the
magic number when you're cooking fish is
between 7 and 8 minutes. And your fish
will be perfect. When I order fish at a
restaurant, I tell them to undercook it.
Not sushi. Just undercook it a little
bit. And that's gets you to the same
place. Be so happy. We're going to place
the cod on. Okay. On here like so. So,
we place one fill it on, two fill it on.
We're going to take some lemon again.
Give it some squeezes. Okay. The the
lemon really brings it out. And this is
what it looks like after 7 minutes. Not
even eight. Just like this. Now, look at
the difference here, Doc. Because what
you got here is this is it looks kind of
flaky, right? It looks beautiful. And
when you actually put the fork through
it, okay, look how it just just
literally falls away. Look at that.
Isn't that beautiful? Exactly what you
want. Okay, so we'll put that back in
the oven cuz I'm sure somebody in the
audience is going to want to taste that.
Yes, we've been feeding the audience all
day. Yeah, of course you do. Right.
Okay, so that's our bake. So remember
when you're baking, nice hot oven to
start off with. Put it in at 400 and
remember what's the magic number? Seven
eight. Seven to eight minutes.
Brilliant.
So that's baking. Then we're going to go
to the real healthy way. Okay. Steaming.
Everybody loves steaming vegetables.
When it comes to fish, it's even better
because basically you're absolutely
sealing in all the nutrients and you're
not losing anything for overheating.
Okay. So when we actually look at this,
we have a what we call a bamarie. We
have the steamer basket on the top.
That's boiling water. And the great
thing is when you're cooking, you could
be doing your vegetables on the bottom
and then you could be cooking your your
fish on the top. Okay. What I'm going to
show you here is a little trick. We've
got some salmon. It's called the dip
dab. Okay. Dab. Dip dab. Okay. Oily
fishike salmon. What we would do is we
would just basically give it a a touch
of water and then dab it. That just
takes the the over secretion of oil off.
Okay. Because I don't want that white
film popping out. Then I'm going to
place it in. But before I place it in,
I've got to think about air rotation,
okay? Because I don't want it just all
cooked in one spot. I want it cooked all
over the round. So, I'm going to take a
little rosemary. And this is very
controversial in the cooking world to
put uh rosemary in with salmon. You guys
fight over this? Oh, yeah, we do. But
what we do is put the rosemary or a
chopstick or some lemons and some limes
at the base and it'll actually help the
steam rotate around the fish. I love the
smell of the rosemary. Oh my goodness.
So, we place that in there. Don't forget
the salt. Don't forget the lemon because
that brings the flavor party to the
kitchen. Okay, I'm letting you into the
magician's circle. I like this. All
right. Okay, finally poaching. You've
been waiting all day. Yeah. So, look at
what we got here is we've got some water
that's boiling away. It's simmering
nicely. Okay. Now, what we can do here,
if you do that, do the reveal. Now, I've
taken um some halibet just for the
halibet.
He'll be here all week. Thank you. Try
the eel. Try the eel.
the corn beef and the yield. Oh my
goodness. So, what we've got here, we've
soaked it in milk and it's going to
tenderize it down. Okay. So, we're going
to take the two fillets here. I'm going
to place them into the poaching solution
here and I'm going to leave them in
there for how long, folks? 7 to 8
minutes. That's beautiful. It's already
boiling. Then, we're going to add in
some a little paprika. Okay. A little c
uh turmeric, maybe some mustard seeds.
Put them in there. Made a mess, but we
pop it in there. And basically they
breathe in all those flavors. Touch a
white wine and you have got delicious
poached fish in how long? 7 to 8
minutes. You got it. All
right. Who wants to taste here? Let's
see what you got here. Now this is
poached. Now I've never given poached to
an audience. I don't like it usually.
Very good. You can miss me. Chef Dan can
miss me. Head on over to dr.com for the
one sheet. One of the best ways to
prepare your fish, but you already know
it's 78 minutes. Don't forget that one.
We'll be right back.
Are you freezing your food all wrong?
Today, we're revealing the mistakes you
may be making in there and the best and
safest way to store your food. Ooh, ice
cream. Step away from the ice cream,
Mara.
[Music]
Not to sound cold, but you might be
making big mistakes when it comes to
freezing your food and not even know it.
Investigative journalist and resident
foodie Mariampo is here. The original
science has started taking a look at the
food in our freezer, which most of us
have ignored. I certainly have most of
my adult life. Why is it so important?
You know, the freezer is one of the most
important appliances in your house
because it's the key to quick, easy,
convenient meals. It saves you time in
so many different ways. You can freeze
your leftovers. You can cook food ahead
of time and freeze it so you have ready
to go meals. You can grocery shop less
often. You go once a week. You put that
food in the freezer till you're ready to
cook it. And it can help you save money
because buying in bulk is often cheaper.
So again, you stock up. You put it in
the freezer, defrost it when you're
ready to cook it. All right. So Marc
says the first mistake we're making is
we're taking the temperature of our
freezer. Tada. Drum roll. Too high. This
seems impossible to me. 32 is freezing.
So, why is that not the right
temperature? Well, most people think
exactly what you think. So, we did a
poll. We asked our viewers at dr oz.com,
"What temperature is your freezer set
at?" And here's what they told us. They
told us that they were setting it at 0.
Some said they were setting it at 32.
About 41% of people said, "What you
think?" And 28% said they have no idea,
which is exactly what I would have said,
right? I have no clue. But the reason
that it's too high is because this is
the temperature that water freezes at.
But when it comes to freezing your food,
it's too high. The magic number for
freezing your food is zero. You want it
set at 0. All right. Second big thing
is we overfill the freezer. I don't know
anyone who has enough room in their
freezer. Yeah. And ours is a big
freezer. It's still packed all the time.
Yeah. My mom has two. She does. So,
what's the problem with that? Yeah. So,
a full freezer is actually a really good
thing because it helps keep the
temperature nice and consistent, but you
don't want to overfill it because then
you're preventing air circulation and
you're blocking vents. There are air
vents way back in the back there. Let me
show Did you Who Who knew there were
vents back there? Be honest. Good. All
right. Like three people. All right.
Now, come come look at this. Right. I
had to look for a while. I didn't even
know where the ones are at home. I found
it here, though. I take this out. There
it is. See that little thing back there
hiding back there? That vent. If that
gets blocked off, your freezer is not
working. Yeah. And the other thing is is
location is really important, right?
Just like real estate, location,
location, location. The coldest part of
your freezer is here in the middle. The
place that gets the least amount of cold
air is the door. So, you want to put
your ice cream on the door and then you
put your meat, which you do want to be
really rock solid. Put that in the
middle of the freezer. So, valuables
everything you can use. Now, the freezer
may be a big mistake, but it's not the
only mistake you're making. Not wrapping
your food tightly enough is a big, big
concern. We sent two members of our bike
club, Adriana and
Denise, out with a homework assignment.
We gave them an ice pack bag, right, and
a cooler. And we asked them to raid
their freezers. Here they are at home
doing exactly what we asked them to do.
And they had to bring them bring stuff
in that they had to admit we're not
wrapped tightly enough. And we're going
to show you and everybody at home what
we're all doing wrong and why it
matters. All right. So, let's go in that
first bag there. What's Adriana guilty
of and what is the penalty? All right.
So, let's take a look at what Adriiana's
done. So, Adriana has waffles. A lot of
us buy these. We love these pre-made
waffles. And what she's done is she
hasn't eaten all of them at once, right?
When she puts them back in, she just
kind of loosely wraps this up. And what
happens, you get all of this
crystallization forming because it's not
tight enough. If you just put it in a
zipper bag, you'll solve that problem.
Adriana, should you be eating waffles?
That's the question really. Well, I I
knew you were going to say that. I watch
your show all the time, Dr. Oz, and I
they're they're multigrain or whole
wheat. I make sure. But, you know, but
at the same time at the same time, I
only eat like one every month, and
that's why I got that way. So, you know,
so I can't be blamed too much. I'm
honored you brought it in. All right.
So, I I you know, I look in here and I
notice this. Mara, please walk us
through what you've noticed. Yes. So,
this container is not filled enough. And
because there's so much air in there,
you can see that this has gotten all
crystallized. So, what we call freezer
burn, it's actually food drying out. You
know, you see those burned patches on
chicken or what have you and you see the
ice crystals around it. these ice
crystals. This is water that has come
out of the product making it a lot more
dry. So, it's just not going to taste
that yummy. Speaking of chicken, sorry,
we found this at your house also. I
think you're bringing it in again. Same
thing. So, not doesn't matter that it's
frozen. It doesn't matter. But this is a
bit of a problem because you know here
it's obvious you got to fill the whole
thing up. But you just put this in a
baggie, which I thought you were
supposed to do, but I guess you left too
much air. Yeah. And I have a great hack
for you. You're going to love this. This
You want to hack on this one? Let's go.
Let's do it. Yes, please. Come on over
here. So, this is really amazing. I
learned this in reporting the story out.
This is going to change my life. Okay.
So, so vacuum sealers can be expensive.
They're upwards of $100. Do you guys
have vacuum sealers at home? No, I don't
know. Yeah, I don't either. I don't know
who has one of these cuz that's not
going to happen. And they're also big,
right? They take up a lot of space. But
there is a genius hack that will
simulate the the vacuum seal. So, can
you help me with this? So, we have this
chicken. It's in a zipper baggie. It's
open. We're going to put it in a bowl of
water. The water is room temperature,
not boiling, not hot. As you push the
bag down, it's naturally through some
magic of physics going to push the air
out. And then, can you just seal that up
for me? It's displacing the air. That is
so smart. Like you would if you were
swimming. I figured you would know
these. Yes. This is so good. Uh, and
then when you pull it out, you can see
that it's pretty much vacuum sealed. You
see that? A vacuum sealing for the price
of a baggie. That's so cool. And now
your food is safe. No freezer burn. All
right, ladies. Thank you very much for
playing with us today. Up next, the
biggest frozen food mistake that you are
making. It's going to surprise you. Stay
with us.
For 32 years, this 12-year-old's death
has remained a mystery until now. Using
genealogy and cutting edge DNA
technology to create her suspected
killer's face. That's coming up
tomorrow.