Today, it's the disease you fear most,
cancer. But it doesn't have to be that
way. Diagnosis is often made too late
because the warning signs of the disease
mimic other conditions. So, today I'm
giving you the power to detect the four
cancer symptoms women are most likely to
ignore. So, let's get right to the
detective work. The first symptom is
bruising because bruising can be a
symptom of leukemia.
Bruising is a symptom you just might
ignore because you think you're just
getting older. You're klutz. You might
be anemic. They're minor side effects
from your medications. But bruising on
the body could actually be a symptom of
leukemia because this cancer is a
disease of the blood that can slow down
the production of platelets which help
clot your blood. With fewer platelets,
your blood's ability to clot diminishes
drastically, giving way to easy
bruising.
So, how do you know if your bruising is
normal or if it's a sign of leukemia?
Maria's here to find out. You get
bruised often, I hear.
I do. I have a two and a four-year-old
and they think I'm a jungle gym, so my
legs are pretty much all bruised up.
Up and down.
All right. So, the issue of bruising, of
course, is an important one because we
all get it from different reasons. When
you get your bruises, how long do they
last?
Probably about a week,
right?
Which is a pretty normal term. So, let's
go over when to worry. When are bruises
concerning to a doctor? First issue,
fevers and chills. Does it ever happen
to you?
Not really. Only when I'm sick, which is
not often.
All right. Second big quick clue is
whether people have persistent fatigue.
Have you experienced that?
Well, I have the normal fatigue of a
mother.
It's harder question to answer. The kind
of fatigue you have with leukemia,
really, you just can't get out of bed.
It's not related to a tough day at all.
And the last symptom is often bone pain.
Whereas the bone cancer is growing
inside the bone. It will really stretch
it and you'll feel the aching in there.
Does it have happened to you?
No, I feel great.
Well, I think you're good to go. I'm
happy for that. All right. So, if you
answered no to all of these, then fine.
The bruising is normal. But for anyone
who had bruising coupled with any of
these symptoms, I don't want you to
ignore it. We can cure these problems if
we know about them in time. The next
cancer symptom that many people ignore,
women in particular, is indigestion.
Because indigestion can be a symptom of
esophageal cancer.
Indigestion. It's the symptom you ignore
because you think it's caused by
something you ate. Yesterday's late
night binge, cheating on your diet.
You're busy and always eating on the go.
But indigestion could also be a symptom
of esophageal cancer when it's caused by
chronic heartburn or acid reflux. That's
when the contents of your stomach back
up into your esophagus, irritating the
lining. and over time creating abnormal
cells that morph into cancer.
So when is indigestion a sign of
esophageal cancer? Michelle, like most
women, has had some indigestion. She's
here to find out. So I just showed you a
little video explaining why I'm
concerned about indigestion. If I can,
I'm going to actually show you a real
stomach and esophagus.
One normal, one not so normal. So I just
want to point out that is you know as
you have a normal esophagus here moving
into the stomach there's a very smooth
transition. Go ahead and feel that and
compare that to this not so smooth. Look
at look at how the esophagus shrunk
here.
Yeah.
You see it doesn't have these nice
little lines anymore. It's all scarred
in that's makes it shorten but also
pulls it together. And feel right here.
That thick stuff
that's an early cancer.
Oo.
We're seeing a lot more of this problem
because of that acid issue. So how long
does it last when you get it? Cuz that's
a big clue. Um, sometimes overnight. It
depends.
Does it last for a couple days?
No, no, no, no. Um, I'm usually going by
the next day. It's usually over next
day.
That That's a good sign. Do you ever get
sore throats that last a long time?
No. Mm-
That's an important sign because the
acid can go up and burn your vocal
cords.
Oh, okay. Didn't know that.
So, again, anyone who has indigestion
was coupled with the other symptoms I
just gave you to worry about.
They're not going to ignore that. Again,
a treatable problem if we find it.
Okay, great. Thanks for telling me.
Let's get to another symptom that you're
likely to ignore and I want you to
detect this one. It's night sweats. And
the reason I'm concerned about night
sweats is they can be a symptom of
lymphoma.
Night sweats are a symptom easy to
ignore because your hormones go haywire
at least once a month. It's just a hot
flash. The bed's too warm. You're
fighting a fever. But night sweats could
also mean lymphoma, a cancer of your
lymphatic system. That's because the
progression of lymphoma and the way your
body fights infections are similar.
Mobilizing immune cells causing fever,
achy muscles, and night sweats.
So, when are those night sweats a sign
of cancer? Jan's here to find out. She
says she sometimes has occasional night
sweats. So, describe them for me. How
often do you have them?
I'm over 40. So,
maybe uh maybe once a week,
often during the month,
right? four times, five times a month.
So, lymphas can cause problems in many
different ways, but let me if I can
explain what's going on inside your body
when you have that diagnosis. Yes, this
is a normal spleen. You see how it's
elegant and sort of thin? This is about
the size of your cell phone. That's how
you can think about your spleen. It's
way up here in the upper left side of
your belly, right?
Uh, however, when it's infiltrated by a
tumor,
it looks like that.
So you can take your gloves off because
I'm going to teach you when you should
worry about night sweats because you're
right, they do happen a lot when you get
past age 40 and they last a long time
sometimes. So the first clue we always
look for if you were to tell your doctor
you have night sweats is whether or not
you have swollen lymph nodes. You know
how to examine for those?
No.
You all want to do this with me
if we can. So everyone sit straw in the
straw in the chair. I want take three
fingers and then very lightly press
behind your ears. Just gently press
behind your ears. You shouldn't feel
anything abnormal there but you do have
lymph nodes. So you start there and then
work your way down on each side of your
neck like this down to the jawline and
then work it around the jawline here and
then gently move down from the jawline
along these muscles to your collar bone
right here. Now if you feel a small
really uh flexible movable lump
okay size of a kidney bean or so I don't
worry about that. You know when you're a
kid you get those really swollen nodes
you know if they're tender by the way
that's a good sign.
Tender lymph nodes means infection. If
it's a painless lymph node and it's
bigger than that little kidney bean and
the areas I just showed you and that
makes me concerned especially if you
can't move it that readily because
tumors will grow and they'll sort of
stick to the tissues around them.
Okay,
that's one of the first big things. I
don't see anything visually. Do you have
anything?
No.
You felt pretty healthy?
I do.
Yeah, you look good. Your thyroid is
sort of prominent by the way.
Did you notice that?
I have noticed that recently.
So, a little fullness in there. Just a
little little hint since you're on the
show. All right.
Thank you.
Forget about that for now. We're talking
about more important things like
lymphas. Uh how about problems with with
breathing? Any difficulty with that?
No, not at all. Right.
That's another issue I worry about
because that will often go along with
lymphas. And finally, unexplained weight
loss. I know you all want to lose
weight. Yes.
But when you lose weight, when you're
not trying to lose weight, that's what
I'm speaking about.
No, no weight loss.
No weight loss. Darn it. All right. So,
if you get night sweats plus any of
those symptoms, that's when you have to
worry. Thanks very much.
Good. Thank you.
Let's get to one more symptom that I
don't want you to ignore. It's bleeding
in between your periods. Remember,
bleeding between your periods is a
concern for a lot of reasons, but it can
es especially be an issue if you have
uterine cancer.
Bleeding between periods is a symptom
women ignore because you're stressed
out, you're on the pill. It's just
another sign of menopause. You've got
fibroids and you think they're probably
harmless. But irregular bleeding could
be a symptom of uterine cancer. In fact,
it's actually the most common symptom
because the cancerous lining of the
uterus constantly continues to grow and
shed causing the abnormal bleeding.
So, let's look at a uterus and what
happens when you get a cancer there.
Normally, it's pretty small size. It's
like two golf balls attached to each
other basically with these little
ovaries next to it. But that's the
uterus there. Let me show you what
happens if you have a uterine tumor.
It turns to that.
Now, look at the size difference here.
you know very small sort of dainty
looking structure becomes massively
enlarged and it becomes thick and so big
you think how could I imagine not
knowing this is there but you'll miss
the diagnosis sometimes because there's
a lot of space in your belly you'll
think you put a little weight on so the
question is when should you worry about
breakthrough bleeding you worry about it
when it's coupled with bloating you
worry about if it's causing pain uh
during urination or during sex and you
worry about it if you've got pelvic pain
those are the big clues do not ignore
those symptoms all of these issues you
can control. I know we don't want to
sometimes know if you got problems, but
I picked specifically problems that you
can address aggressively and we can help
you with as doctors if you tell us. If
you worry about any symptoms at all, you
can download the Ask MD app on dr.com.
It can help you know when to worry and
when not to. All you got to do is answer
a few quick questions. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good