[Applause]
On the other side of this screen is a
whistleblower who is here to talk
directly to you. She's a manicurist and
has become very worried about the
chemicals in nail salons like yours.
Today we're investigating. Is your
manicure bad for your health?
Whether at the salon or DIY, nail art is
hot. Some estimate last year in the US
there were 100 million nail polish
users.
But now, many are worried if chemicals
from their manicure are entering their
bodies without them even knowing it.
Investigation squad member Tia Brown has
been following manicure and pedicure
health risks for us, even going
undercover to popular salons.
And now she's bringing us a brand new
investigation into what's really in your
polish. And for the first time ever, a
manicurist is appearing live in our
studio blowing the whistle on nail salon
conditions and her own fears over
whether she or her clients are at risk.
Joining me in studio is a nail
technician to talk about work conditions
at the salon where she works. She's
asked that we keep our identity hidden.
So, I'll ask you, thanks for being here.
What is your biggest concern about your
safety at work? Hi, my main concern is
the products that I use on our the skin
and the products that we're breathing in
in the salon are causing cancer cells
that may later on appear in life.
>> And what about the clients whose nails
you manage every single day?
>> I worry about the pregnant women and the
children that do come in. I'm very
worried about them.
>> Well, thank you for stepping forward and
we'll keep your identity protected.
Investigation Squad member Tia Brown has
shipped away at the research to get to
the bottom of this. She's also going to
help me sort through the services
offered at a typical nail salon. Thanks
very much. She just heard the
whistleblower and we've heard from
others as well. Are her concerns about
the working conditions about the safety
of nail salon valid?
>> She is absolutely right to be concerned.
In fact, research shows that nail salons
have the same level of toxic fumes as
oil refineries
>> and car garages. Isn't that crazy?
>> Yeah. Who would have thought? Over
350,000 people in the US work at nail
salons. And studies have shown that
their exposure, their constant exposure,
mind you, they're working 52 plus hours
a week, results in them being at 100
times the risk to develop cancer.
>> That's a real occupational hazard.
>> Absolutely.
>> So the question is, what are the
chemicals and how are they affecting not
just the manicures but also you the
consumer? So let's start with the ones
we have in front of us.
>> Right. So you know the oldie but goody
is the acrylic, right? So that's one
when you use a synthetic nail usually on
top of your normal nail and you put
acrylic which is a mixture of different
components to to add to the top to make
sure it doesn't chip. The thing is you
usually dry under a UV uh ray which
something like this and so you're
exposed to different risk because of
that. In addition, the chemicals in the
compound also put you at risk. They're
toxic.
>> All right, so that's the acrylics.
>> That's the acrylic. The next thing was
gel. Now gel was the thing when it came
out. Looks great. Lasts for two weeks.
Here's the thing again, the powder mix
toxic. So, people heard the complaints
and they were like, "Let's do another
innovation." And it was the gel powder,
which doesn't require the UV ray, but
it's still dangerous because the powder
and the mix are still problematic for
your nails.
>> Of the things you just mentioned, the
three options, which one worries you the
most?
>> Acrylic. By far, research shows that
this is the most the one that you should
be most concerned with, mostly because
of this, right? You use this to file
down the acrylic once you put it on. And
guess what? You're chipping away at all
of the chemical compounds. And guess
where they're going? Right into your
face. You're inhaling it. The manicurist
is inhering it. Inhaling it. It's not
good.
>> So, I get it. So, there's two ways the
chemicals from these products and
treatments can get into your bodies.
Through the skin and by breathing them
in. Let's start with the harmful
potential chemicals in the air.
Jennifer's here. Thanks for being here,
Jennifer. With her daughter, Alana. And
they're waiting for their manicure. But
even before their nails get painted,
they could be breathing in chemical
fumes. Now, we don't typically see the
fumes like you're seeing right here
coming up from the table in a nail
salon. This is a dramatization of how
fumes could be moving through the air
while you're getting a manicure. So,
what have recent studies shown about the
air at the at the different nail salons?
>> Unfortunately, it has a lot of um toxics
in the air. So, the toxins in the air
rather, they have the two major are BTX
compounds and uh formaldahhide and both
are very dangerous specifically to your
lungs. uh we know that it it can
unfortunately lead to asthma or
respiratory issues but there is a silver
lining in this I want to say right so
because we know people still want to get
their manicures and ventilation is the
key
>> right
>> the CDC released a report saying that if
the space is ventilated it reduces your
risk by up to 50%. Why? Because you're
not inhaling all of those fumes.
>> You're going to hear this message over
and over again for everybody. There are
some folks who are investing extra to
make sure you're safer.
>> I mean show them some love. Let's make
it a better industry. Okay, let's find
out if the chemicals from nail polish
are potentially absorbed through the
nail and skin.
>> So, is there any research about the
chemicals from the paint or the products
themselves?
>> Absolutely. Now, this was a little bit
scary, I have to say. Now, Duke and UW
UWG released a study that said that,
well, let me tell you what they did
first. So, they had two different
groups. They had one group of women who
got their nails painted and another
group of women who got their nails
painted, but they had on gloves. Guess
what they found? They did a urine test
and they found that the people who had
the direct contact with the polish had
more toxins in their system. And why?
Because they believe that the toxins are
getting in all around here. So every
time you're getting your nails polished,
you are exposing yourself to different
toxins. And I know it's hard news for
women, but it's just the truth.
>> All right. So we reached out to the
personal care council. Here's what they
said in part. Nail polish products have
been used safely for many decades by
millions of people. For many years,
information has been circulating in the
media alleging potential adverse health
effects from exposure to certain
ingredients in the Elcare products such
as taluine, formaldahhide, diabetalate.
The FDA also states on its website that
all of these ingredients based on
available safety information are safe
under current conditions of use in nail
products. So, they disagree, right? But
up next, we're going to show you what's
really in this little bottle, right? And
are the new better for you polishes less
toxic? You should know about this. In
the commercial break, I want you to go
out and grab your favorite color, right?
Bring your the nail polish bottle back
in front of the TV because we're going
to show you how to tell if yours has
potentially harmful chemicals in it.
Stick around. Have you guys ever
wondered what's really in here? You ever
thought about that? What's really in
your nail polish? So, during the break,
I ask all you to grab your favorite nail
polish and bring it back to the TV. Hope
you got it right. Did you get it right?
Look at the ingredients. Turn it around.
Look at the back. Do you see anything
there?
>> No. Nothing. You can't find them, can
you? Why? Because they're not there.
That's right. And most people have no
idea what's really in their nail polish
for a reason. Because it's not written
on there. Like foods write what's in
there, but these don't. So, how can
someone find out what chemicals are
actually in their bottle of nail polish?
>> It's really important to do your due
diligence when it comes to nail polish.
Every brand will have their list
somewhere on the site.
>> All right. So, we got three nail
polishes here. T and I are going to give
you what's called the toxic trio of
potentially harmful chemicals, right,
that are in your nail polish that you
might want to avoid. So, as I paint the
nails,
>> all right,
>> and reveal the chemical, tell us which
one we should be worried about here.
>> Well, we don't want our nail polish to
chip. And unfortunately, thealdahhide is
the chemical that they put in nail
polish to ensure that it doesn't chip.
But guess what? It's a carcinogen.
>> Yeah,
>> it's not healthy. It's dangerous and
it's in most of our nail polishes.
>> All right, so we want to avoid
formaldahhide. That's a name that you
probably heard before and can remember.
Let's get to the second chemical. This
chemical is pretty toxic. You probably
have not heard of this chemical. By the
way, notice how daintily I paint inside.
>> He's doing a great job, right? We know
he's had lots of practice.
>> This is from
>> He's staying in the line.
>> Painting daughters and granddaughters
nails. All right. And what's the
chemical here?
>> DPB. And we know that this chemical is
so bad that it was actually banned in in
Europe.
>> We should not ingest it. We definitely
shouldn't have it on our nails. And it's
in a lot of our nail polishes. All
right. And the final product here is
something that you probably will
recognize with a little bit of help.
>> All right. So, how many people love when
their nail their nails are like nice and
shiny and smooth. It's no clump. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Tuluene does that and it's in a lot of
our nail polishes. And again, it is a
toxin. It should not be in our nail
polish and it should not be in our
system.
>> All right. So, there's three chemicals
we just mentioned to you that we don't
want to have in there. Let's walk over
here. There's a brand new trend in nail
polishes that'll give consumers more
power in buying nail polishes without
these ingredients. So, the first is
called three free, right?
>> Which means
>> it doesn't have the three biggest toxins
in the nail polish. So, it's what?
Healthier for your system. And a little
bit of research helps you find which
ones are.
>> But even better, there's something
called five free.
>> Five free. That means it has even less
toxins. It's worth finding five free or
more. And it's important for your
health.
>> I noticed something when you came on the
stage today. It wasn't just a beautiful
ring. There's no nail polish on.
>> I don't have any nail polish on because
I was scared for a little while. All
right.
>> You do have to polish on, but my toes
are already polished.
>> We love them. We love our manicures and
pedicures. We just have to do it the
right way.
>> Right. All right. So, when you hear this
sound, right? You know, it's a great
moment to grab your camera, stop, snap,
and share. Right? So, we stop, keep on
the screen right now, this little
message to you, snap a pick of it, share
it on social media, and tag someone who
needs to see the message. I applaud any
new types of labeling that are a step
closer to full transparency. I'm proud
of the industry for making those
changes. You can go to dr.com to read
more on the link between manicures and
cancer. T. As always, thanks for all you
do. Thank you for watching. Don't forget
to subscribe and turn on notifications
so you never miss out on new videos to
live the good