Now, he has helped millions transform
their lives with his inspiring approach
to life's toughest, biggest challenges.
Today, Tony Robbins is sharing his
secret to take back control of the
number one driver of stress, money.
Please welcome my friend Tony Robbins.
[Applause]
[Music]
How are you, brother? I I've never seen
you run before. That's so cool. Have a
seat. How are you all doing?
So, you know, I got to say just as as a
start, I I think emotional issues around
money are devastating. And frankly,
money's become as big a problem as
obesity and the epidemic we have with
that in America. I would love to get a
little bit of your insights about what
it is that is causing this financial
health crisis we have in America. Well,
I think most people don't realize, but
we know we get stressed from so many
things, but money is one of the deepest
ones. And I think it's because we feel
the least in control of money. I mean,
money is an expression of power in our
lives. You know, what we can and can't
do. And for many people, what's happened
for them is when they feel out of
control because it's so complex. Where
do I start? How do I go about it? I
don't know what to do. I'm so busy. What
happens is we end up starting to feel
that stress and we start to eat or some
people smoke or some people drink or it
starts to mess with your intimate
relationship and then everything gets
messed up and that all converts as you
know to physical stress which converts
to emotional and physical health. You've
taken Yeah. You've taken the last few
years of your life to write a book
called Money Master the Game. It's
absolutely fabulous book. Been a lot of
effort putting together these thoughts.
Why would you make that kind of
investment? Well, because you know, my
whole life, 37 years, I, you know, I've
been passionately obsessed with wanting
to know how do you help someone change
their life as quickly as possible? What
are the breakthroughs? And there's only
a few areas of your life that really
affect the quality of your life. Your
intimate relationships obviously do,
your physical body, as you and I both
know, your emotions, and then money. And
what I found is when 2008 happened, I
grew up in a really tough financial
environment. I went out to get the card,
it's gone. Not because somebody stole
it, because we didn't pay it for it,
somebody took it. No money for food. So
when I saw people losing their homes in
mass, when I saw people losing half
their net worth, and I knew it was based
on manipulation, it made me crazy. And I
have unique access. I've coached one of
the top 10 financial traders in the
world, a multi-billionaire for 21 years,
and he's never lost money in 21 years.
So, I thought if I could learn from him
and 50 other other best people in the
world and put in an action plan for a
millennial who just got out of college
and they still have debt and they don't
know what to do or a mom trying to
figure out how do I do this being a mom
and managing my life and my work and my
kids or somebody's trying to retire,
then I'd have a real gift and it took me
four years, but now I've got these seven
steps I can teach people. I want to take
advantage of the wisdom you have about
getting people to deal with their lives
proactively. So, it's right now folks
watching, they've got debt, they know
the money coming in is not going to be
as much as the money going out. How do
you alleviate the stress that they feel
this moment? They have to immediately
take action. They've got to put together
a plan. And I show them these seven
steps. But it starts quite frankly
inside your head. It starts with you
saying, "Okay, I'm going to stop telling
myself this story. Whenever I want to
help someone create a breakthrough in
anything, in their body, and their
relationships, and their money, there's
three S's I look at." Most people that
want to change their body look for a
strategy, a diet, something to do. And
that's great. But a lot of people have
the right strategy, but they don't
execute it. Or they never start because
they have a story in their head, a
belief that says, "I've tried
everything." Or, "I'm big boned." That
was mine, right? You know, I'm big
boned. I am big boned, but I'm 38 lbs
lighter than I was then. So, your story,
your limiting belief keeps you from
falling through. So, what you got to do
is you got to get yourself in a playful
place. I tell people, have you ever been
really angry at somebody and then
suddenly remember everything they've
ever done that pisses you off? Yes. Or
you're really in love and what's wrong
with life when you're totally in love?
Nothing. We're broke. Who cares? cuz
we're in love, right? So those three
S's, changing your state, changing your
story, and changing your strategy is how
you make a shift. I want to apply some
of your thoughts to real life
situations. That's okay. I've got some
audience members. So we're going to
start with Theresa. Come on over.
Perfect. Teresa, if you can join us.
There she is. All right. So meet Tony.
This is so quiet walking over here. You
can feel it. Let me turn you over here
so they can see all. So go ahead,
Teresa. Share your story. I'll get Tony
to work on it. Tony, I feel like I am a
hamster on a wheel. I live paycheck to
paycheck. I have twins who are in their
second year of college. My younger one
is going to college next year and I feel
trapped. I'm stressed and I never
pictured my life the way it is now. Are
you paying for your twins college
tuition? Yes, I am. So, um, easy for
someone on the outside to talk about it,
right? Because your physical stress and
emotional stress, I know, is real. But
if you really want to change it, then
you have to make some new choices. And
right now, the story you have, we all
are affected by the story we tell
ourselves. So we have metaphors. Some
people say, you know, I'm at the end of
my rope. And I'll go, okay, put it down
and come over here. And they look at me
like I'm crazy. Yours is I'm a hamster
on a wheel. And how many times do you
tell yourself that? Every day. Every
day. And so that's what you feel. See,
so whatever we tell ourselves, we
experience. So here's the truth. There's
a couple options for you. One of those
options is you have to understand that
you can still be financially free, but
somehow even though it seems impossible,
you got to take a small percentage of
what you have and pretend the government
put a tax on you. You'd hate that tax.
You'd swear you won't pay that tax, but
they'd still take the money. So, I'll
give you an example. There's a man named
Theodore Johnson. He worked for uh UPS.
He never made more than $14,000 in an
entire year in his life. That's the most
he ever made. At 70 years old, he's
worth $70 million. How is that possible?
I don't know. Yeah. How is that
possible?
I'll tell you when they asked Warren
Buffett, I asked him, "What made you the
richest man in the world?" He said,
"Living in America where there's
opportunity, good genes, so I lived a
long time." And compound interest. And
we've all heard of compound interest.
But what this man did is his friend said
to him, she said, "I can't save any
money. I have no money." Same as you're
feeling right now. And I know it's true.
You do have money. You're just not
putting it in the places that can get
you ahead. So that's why you're the
hamster on the wheel. And what his
friend said is, "We're going to take a
tax 20% of your money you're never going
to see, and it's going to go in this
investment account." And when over the
years it compounds and it's amazing what
it does. Second thing for you, I know
you're not going to like this one. What
if your twins had to actually pay for
some of that college education
themselves? So what I want you to do is
I want you to find no less than a
minimum of 10%. Okay, and as much
ideally as 15%. So if you will make that
promise, I will get someone to coach you
and get you to follow through. Promise.
Will you make it happen? And
[Applause]
we got one last victim for you, Tony.
For sure. Yeah. Hello. Hi. Hi. How you
doing? Should I come down? You stay
right there. You're about the right
height now. You're not evil now. Okay,
Tony. So, my issue is that I'm a mother
of three. I have three boys. And every
time I get my bills, my credit card
bills, anything like that, I just I just
leave them in the mailbox. I don't I
don't even take them out the mailbox
because it's just so stressful, all
these bills and you know, debt like
that. So, you know, what is the best
solution or what do you think is the
best solution? Well, I mean, I've been
hearing what you're you're saying about
saving percentage, you know, a piece of
your income every time. But it's, you
know, that's kind of really hard to
reach that goal when you have children
or other, you know, you know, limited
situations. So, how do you handle that?
Well, it starts with changing that
belief. It's not not true that you don't
have children. It's not hard. Right? We
all know that's true. The story you have
that says, "I have three children and so
it's really hard." The more you tell
yourself, the more you can't do
anything. It's like hypnosis. You're
hypnotized into it's so hard. I can't.
It is hard and you can. You can, but we
got to start small and get momentum.
That's the piece that we got to do for
you. And for you right now, what you
really need to do is get someone who's
going to come kick your butt a little
bit. You need somebody who's going to
not take this stuff. Cuz here's the
challenge. When you surround yourself
with girlfriends, the beauty of feminine
women is they support each other. But
the challenge with that is you can
support each other and feeling good and
then not change. So, we need two things.
No more story and a new game plan. If
you're up for it, I'll get someone who
will actually coach you. Oh, I'm I'm up
for it. How about um also maybe uh you
saying something about the guy part?
Yes,
maybe that has. All right, we're going
to do you know Tonyy's going to create
all kinds of good ideas for all you guys
take advantage of. Tony, thank you very
much. wonderful advice. Check out Tony
Robbins latest book called Money Master
the Game. Be right back. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good