Drink up. This is great. We've got an Oz
approved 3-day tetox. We took all of the
best teas and we combined them with
foods. Get results safely. Everything
gets cleaned out without you suffering
too much without feeling hungry. This
gave me so much energy. Plus, Jamie
Oliver stops by The Dish, a brand new
series with everyday recipes that you
can make tonight. This week, permission
to eat pasta. Heart healthy, carb
friendly.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you,
[Music]
[Applause]
Becca. Don't get tricked by those pricey
TTOX packets they're advertising on your
Facebook and Instagram page. Today,
we're giving you a brand new 3-day tetox
tea detox plan actually that is Oz
approved and perfectly curated to get
results safely. And the best part is,
and this is important, you won't be
hungry. Right? With this tetox, you are
in control. And you know what? You
decide which teas to drink. We're even
giving you pre-portioned meals to keep
you on track this January because this
plan is tried and tested to reset your
body and help you start to lose the
weight. And we are so lucky today
because our go-to tester, the taste
tester galore, Natha, is here as always.
I trust her. But here's the thing. She
is stubborn. You know, she is she wants
to do the tetox, but she's a little bit
nervous. What worries you about
detoxing? Well, yeah, exactly. You see
my face? Mhm. No. Okay. First of all, I
hear tea. Like, what's what's going to
be happening? Am I drinking tea all day
for three days? Am I going to be hungry?
Is my stomach going to be bumbling? Is
my head going to be start hurting? You
know how sometimes you get hunger
headaches. Okay, I get the hunger
headaches out. So, you know, I'm a
little skeptical about this here
three-day tea. I But you know what? I'll
try anything for you, sugar. For me,
I'll give it a try. All right. Over here
on the plan. This is a plan for all of
you who are skeptical, celebrity
fitness, and nutrition expert, and
author of the sugar impact diet. DJ
Virgin helped create the plan for us.
Welcome to Gay. What makes Tox, the one
we've designed, safer than the packaged
pre kinds that people are buying online?
Yes. Well, those prepackaged ones, a lot
of them have senna in them, which
irritates your gut and gives you that
laxative effect and then you get
trapped. You have to use it all the
time. So, what we did instead, and don't
look at so skeptical, you're going to
love this. We took all of the best teas
and we combined them with food. So,
you're going to get comfort detox food.
Yes, you get to eat. You're not going to
be hungry. Okay, this this is detox
without the deprivation, okay? All
right, we don't want to starve you up.
That's the promise. We're not going to
starve you. But I don't want to clean
the pipes out in a healthy way. And so
the food pairings with the tea makes a
difference. All right. Three-day detox
plan approved by Oz begins with
dandelion and milk thistle, blended tea.
But you got to do this when you first
wake up. Jig, explain why you put them
together. All right. So, you got to have
good liver support when you're detoxing.
And that is why milk thistle and
dandelion are so great. Now, if you're
going to wake up, have this hour or two
later. So, we're going to start with
breakfast. And this breakfast is very
special just for you. Bone broth,
oatmeal. Okay. Now, the foundation is
still cut oats and bone broth, but you
can add all the other things here,
right? Yes. Yes. So, this makes it This
is like your canvas to create. But
what's so important here is the
oatmeal's got beta glucan soluble fiber.
It's like sponges. Okay. And I love it
with the walnuts for a little crunch.
The chia that makes a great texture. Can
I add bacon bits for crunch? No.
after after the tea talks. So, I have to
stick to the three days. Anything for
three days. Okay. All right. Next, we
have an Oz approved three-day tea with
fennel seed ginger tea at lunchtime.
Again, we have a pairing, right? We have
a breakfast tea. 2 hours later, you have
a breakfast bone broth and oatmeal,
which I like. Actually, you do too.
Really, no bacon. And then you have the
fennel ginger. Okay. All right. Because
lunch is your biggest meal of the day
and we want to make sure, you know,
we're adding some veggies. We're adding
some fiber. So, we've got to support
your digestion. We don't want you
bloated. So, that's why ginger and
fennel are so important here. Oh, this
is almost gone. Yeah. There's no boost
away. There's no alcohol in that. All
right. Now, the perfect lunch for this
detox is a low calorie, low carb soup.
Soups are good in general on a detox
because take the chewing out of it,
right? They rest your gut. Take a look
at JJ's. This is one of her favorite
creations. I love it. Roasted
cauliflower detox soup.
[Music]
Next on the oz approved 3day tea docs,
sip on green tea. cucumber detox water
all afternoon long. This is critical,
vital because this is your fail safe if
you're starting to pass. Yes. All right.
So, this is amazing because the green
tea of course boosts your metabolism
again, but it's also calming. So, we're
going to add in a cup of cucumbers. Then
some lemons and then some mints
naturally sweet. And then if you are
daring enough, and I sense you might be,
a little dash of cayenne pepper. Again,
that helps boost your metabolism. Right.
All day long. I put a lot of cayenne in
yours.
Fix your dish. I can taste it. Fix your
great, right? A little sweet from the
mint. This is great. This is great. See,
now of course I have to have my my water
all day, but this is like spotted water.
You put this in the fridge. You can
drink it all day long, right? Yes. And I
wouldn't mind doing this all day long. I
can take a big jug of this just I can
make it in the morning, pour it in a
nice little water bottle jug, and just
carry it. Right. We win. We won this
round. The hero. The hero of the detox.
But we're not done yet, cuz up next,
dinner time's the hardest time to stay
strong in any detox. But guess what? We
have the hack to keep you on track.
Stick with us.
[Applause]
Coming up, the foodies of the dish are
back and we have a special guest. Chef
today, Jamie Oliver is here. We're all
giving carb lovers permission to indulge
again. Jimmy has hacks you will not want
to miss. Hey, pass me that bowl or play.
Come. So English of
[Applause]
[Music]
them. Hi everyone. My go-to food taster
and author who like a lot of you is
looking for a jump start on weight loss
to stay motivated. So celebrity
nutritionist JJ Virgin came up with a
full meal plan for the TE's that you can
use to lose weight without feeling
hungry. The TTX plan. Let's talk dinner.
JJ, you got three letters to remember.
Three letters. That's easy to remember
when you're picking your dinner to match
up on the TTOX diet. They are FFP. All
right. So, this is super important
because you don't want to be hungry
after dinner. So, it's FFP for fat,
fiber, and protein. This is the magic
formula. This is the trifecta both for
blood sugar balance, but also to help
keep you full so you shut that kitchen.
Look at me. Shut the kitchen after
dinner. All right. All right. All right.
So, it looks like this. Fat for example,
could be olives, fiber, broccoli. Your
protein is your key issue of salmon. You
put them together. sheep pen dinner.
Easy, fast, simple. And again, this is
pretty comfortable for your body to deal
with. So, you're detoxing away and you
can get a little bit more rambunctious
at dinner time, but then again, the
kitchen closes. Okay. After that, you
have a after the dinner detox, you've
got tea. What do you recommend? Yes.
Now, this is super important because we
got to get you to go to sleep. Right.
Right. So, we are going to give you
Valyan tea. Have you ever tried Valyan
tea? Because it's a key part of the
three-day detox. Now, I've tried it,
right? But I've also tried um chamomile
um which is supposed to put me asleep
but it's just kind of just makes me
cozy. But this one right here, baby.
Okay. This one knock you out. Okay.
Knock you out. Okay. For centuries, this
has been used to help people get into
deep sleep faster and have better
quality sleep. So that's why it knocked
you out. Okay. All right. You got one
last question. I understand you're
always full of questions. So, you know,
I know I gave you a hard time all day
about the tetox. I'm But I'm getting
into it, Dr. Oz. But one thing you
didn't help me with is my sugar
cravings. I got a bag of candy in my bag
right now in the in the back. What What
I'm going to do about my sugar cravings.
Let's do that cuz that'll destroy the
whole detox. All right. Well, I'm going
to go get your purse in a second. But
besides that, you get I'm taking the
candy. I call the police.
So So a lot of times sugar cravings come
because of stress. So, licorice tea is
awesome here because it actually takes
the pressure off your adrenal glands,
but you're also going to pair it with
some almond butter.
Oh, now almond butter is great because
it actually has a compound so you don't
even absorb as much of the fat. Oh, he's
warming up the I'm trying to. But in the
meantime, the key thing about this is
licorice is naturally sweet enough that
without adding a lot of extra stuff to
it, it'll give it just that little bit
of a reminder of what sweet is without
calories, without messing up your
program. Because the detox works if you
don't have sugar. That's the key
fundamental Okay. Right. Thank you very
much. Good luck to you my Tigers. Thank
you all. We're gonna put the entire plan
on dr.com so you can try it at home.
I'll be right back.
DNA, your genetic code. It'll tell me
what eye color they should have, hair
color, shape, face. Now, breakthrough
technology. Does it blow your mind?
She's tracking down cold case killers.
We know she's the mother of the suspect.
I love how bad guys get caught using
science. Plus, can low blood sugar
really lead to murder? They're actually
in an altered mental state. I don't buy
it. All new Oas. That's coming up
[Music]
[Applause]
tomorrow. We just introduced you to the
2019 Tea Talks to start off your new
year the right way. And now get ready to
take tea to the next level. Chefs all
around the world are using tea in new
ways to flavor foods without adding
loads of calories. Should you be cooking
with tea leaves? That's the big
question. Chef and tea lover Will
Gillson is here. He
knows. Explain why tea has so much
untapped potential for our viewers.
Well, Dr. Oz, I grew up on an herb farm,
so cooking with dried and aromatic
ingredients has been sort of the
backbone of my cuisine for most of my
life. But, you know, I think that
adding, you know, herbs into food, tea
is actually a way to enhance the flavor
even so much more. And I think, you
know, you probably have some tea at
home. Today, we're going to show you
that it's more than just a coffee
alternative. Yeah. If we use herbs,
which are dried thingamajigs, we should
use tea, which are dried thingamajigs.
We're going to show you the easiest ways
to start cooking with tea today and they
are all Oz approved. The first is to use
a tea broth to make pasta, rice, grains,
even oatmeal. So, what kind of tees do
you use? How do you actually make these
things? So with like a black tea, I
would use that to make, you know, into
sort of the infusion of making a rice
dish, something like that. Give that
nice toasty flavor. You know, the ulong
tea I actually infuse into milk to make
oatmeal with. Uh it's actually wonderful
background flavor. Uh and then green tea
I actually like to infuse into uh
broths. You know, basically making like
a chicken broth and you can use that to
make a soup, which is what you did here
today. Describe how you made this
specifically. So, we actually start with
a broth, lots of herbs, chicken stock,
and then we just infuse in a little
satchel of the green tea. Take it in
there for just about 5 10 minutes, take
it out. I heard you like soup. It's got
tons of body to it. It's a very fresh
flavor, and I tell you, it's very
exotic. I've never expected an herb to
taste like this. If you tell me it's
tea, I'll figure it out. But I wouldn't
have otherwise. I think this is what's
going to be in your tea in 2019. Hot.
Remember the the highlights here. This
one's going to be what? Okay. But it's
basically chicken noodle soup with broth
made from tea. Yeah. I mean I I would
look at it this way. I mean like it's
basically like bone broth was the thing
that everybody was into in 2018, 2017,
2019. It's tea broth. The new bone
broth. The new bone broth. Tea broth.
Yes. Next.
While you got the tea in the house, we
want you to infuse your oil with tea.
And this adds a whole new dimension to
cooking at home. Yeah. Yeah. So, you
know, maybe you know this past holiday
season you got some tea as a gift. It's
sitting in your cupboard. You don't
really know what to do with it. You
know, this is actually, I think, the
most approachable and easy way to start
learning how to cook with tea. All
right. So, specifically, how do you do
you just add it to the oil? Do you have
to do anything else? Uh, you actually
just take the, you know, I like
extravirgin olive oil, as you know, it's
really great, very healthy. I just
lightly warm it, whisk the tea leaves
into that, let it steep for about 20
minutes, and then you're ready to go.
You can drizzle it on top of feta cheese
or even finish off a roast lamb with it.
How many of you guys a little uncertain
about tea leaves in your olive oil? Come
on, be honest. I thought so.
I'm gonna let you guys be the judges.
Take some of these toast here. Trust me
on this. Yes. Trust trust the chef here.
Pass that down. See what you guys think.
Now, I want some honest opinions
here. What's your first name? Nina.
Nina. And Lorraine. Lorraine. So, what
do you look for when you're trying to
use new techniques in your cooking? If I
was going to try to get you to use tea,
what would it take? Well, it's the idea
of it's something a little different, a
little different flavor, something
infused. Love the idea. So, I think that
would be something I would try. The
taste. What do you think of that?
Delicious. You like it? Yeah. You agree?
So surprising, isn't it? Absolutely. Who
would have thought? Chef, if you can
impress my audience, you can impress
anybody. See, they're on board. Nice
job. All right. Last up, we want you to
use tea in marinating your meats and
fish. Use it as a rub. Yeah. You know, I
think that one of the things that, you
know, you can find in rubs most of the
time is that, you know, you need to
enhance not just the flavor, but also
the texture. This is spectacular, right?
It's got a little tartness to it. How do
you make it? So, you know, I think you
know, a standard rub, you start with
usually salt, brown sugar, some dried
garlic, and then you can add in your
favorite tea. You can add in the mint
tea. You can add in a little bit of
jasmine tea. But this this is smoky a
little bit. Or you can use my favorite
tea, which is lapsang such tea. What?
Say again. Say again. Lapsang such tea.
Lapsang such tea. Yeah. Is that why it's
smoky? So, it's actually a black tea
that's dried over burning pine resin.
So, it gets this kind of cedar quality
to it. You can put it on there. I bet
that tastes like it's been grilled,
doesn't it? It does. It's fantastic.
Never hit the grill. Just right in the
oven. What? Here's what I'm taking away
from this. You take these basic tea in
plant. You can process it in different
ways. We can avoid having to add that
liquid smoky flavor now by using the
lapsang shang tea. Plus, people are so
impressed you can say it. Exactly. Who
wants some laps? Everybody, right?
Everybody. You're all going home with
some chef. Thank you very much. You can
find more of Chef Gilson's recipes as
well as our guide to cooking with teas
at dr.com. Share it with your friends.
We'll be right back. Who is
[Applause]
up a little bit? I love getting to talk
with you on my show every single day,
but when the cameras stop rolling, the
conversation is not over. I still have a
lot that I want to talk about. So
download the Dr. Oz podcast on Apple
Podcast or wherever you get your
[Applause]
[Music]
podcast. Wrinkles. I know how much you
hate them and how you wish they would
just vanish. But I was surprised to hear
what so many of you refer to them as,
the accordion cheek. Yes, I've heard
this. Then there's the angry 11. Boom.
Right between the eyes. And of course,
the smiling staircase where your ey
lines start to slide down your face. So
regardless of what you may call your
wrinkles, there may be hope. Our new
non-invasive wrinkle fighters, the
future of skincare. My trusted
sponsorship partner, Number Seven, says
yes. And here to tell us more is
dermatologist Dr. Doris Day, who's here
on behalf of Number Seven. You're a
dermatologist. Why are these
non-invasive treatments becoming so
popular? Well, they can offer a lot of
agedefying beauty benefits to treat some
of those wrinkles that we're so upset
about. And a lot of patients who come in
to see me really want to avoid
injectables if they can or delay them.
And of course, any in-office treatment I
do, I want it to last as long as
possible. So, these non-invasive
solutions that are still backed by
science are a great option. So, there's
a brand new non-invasive product. It's
on the market right now that had you
very excited, right? It's from Number
Seven Laboratories and it's called
Number Seven Laboratories Line
Correcting Booster Serum. And it's
clinically proven to help you look up to
5 years younger in 12 weeks. And in
fact, when it first launched in the UK,
they had a 17,000 person weight list.
And it's beauty brand number seven's
most concentrated agedefying serum. And
it's clinically designed to be applied
right over those deeper wrinkles that
most women are bothered by. And it
rivals professional grade results. In
fact, 76% of women who were considering
Injectables said they could now wait.
They can wait. You can do it at home.
That's right. Let's step in to your
wrinkles. Write into them and take a
closer look at how number seven
scientists believe their line correcting
booster serum works. So, here we are in
the skin. And if you don't mind, let's
just orient people. I'm the before and
you're 12 weeks after application. I
like being the after. Yes. Well, let's
see how the before is doing. So, first
of all, I'll point something out on my
side. I've got wrinkles so deep I could
twist my ankle in them. See how deep
these wrinkles are? And what's going on
after 12 weeks of number seven? Well,
you can barely see the wrinkles here.
They're much softer and much finer
looking. And that's really powerful.
It's like glass water over on your side.
That's right. Got the Sahara Desert
here. All right. But let's go a little
deeper because we're both physicians.
That's right. Let's look under the skin
to what might be going on. And here, if
you look at my side, the darkness is the
scaffolding. So, I'll get down and I'll
look and up here, I don't have a lot of
scaffolding. That I guess it's
fibrillin. Fibbrillain. Yeah. I don't
have much on my side, but after 12 weeks
on your side. That's right. You can see
that the fibbrillain is restored. And
this is all thanks to number seven's key
ingredient, which is matricxel 3000
plus, which helps with fibrillin repair.
And that fibbrillin repair is that
scaffolding is now restored and it's
back. And that's what helps plump up the
skin and make those li wrinkles look
much softer and finer. All right, so
we're going to try to see if this line
correcting booster works in action.
Michelle and Jen are both here. We both
gave them correcting booster serums to
try. They've been using for 3 weeks. So
Jen, before we get to your after, what
was bothering you about your skin the
most before you started? Well, I'm not
quite 40 yet, so it really annoyed me
that I have the not the 11, but the
other way. I have the horizontal
forehead lines and every picture that's
all I could see is those lines. So, I
was constantly editing out my forehead
lines and I'm a realtor so my head shot
I accidentally edited off half of my
eyebrow the first time. Oh no. So, um I
thought this is ridiculous. That's
actually a tellt tell sign if you're
using some of those software packages
instead of actually looking that way.
It's a call to action. So, show us how
number seven line correcting booster
serum works. Dr. Day. Yeah. So the first
thing you do is you wash your face and
pat your skin dry and then you apply the
line correcting booster serum right on
top of those deeper wrinkles. So in her
we do it right across her forehead,
right across those deeper wrinkles that
are bothering her the most. And after 12
weeks you'll see that those lines start
to soften. But I would start out by
saying that she's quite beautiful. She
has gorgeous cheekbones and beautiful
eyes. And we want these lines to not be
what distracts her from seeing her own
beauty. So applying it right over those
wrinkles. It's not a whole face
treatment. It's really designed for
those deeper wrinkles that bother you
the most. How How does it feel now you
haven't used it for a few weeks? To be
honest, I was a little weary of
something that was going to make a
difference in that amount of time and I
was so pleasantly surprised that I went
out and bought a couple more number
seven products and um it doesn't feel
tight or flaky, which some of those do.
It just feels very light and airy and
put my makeup on. her regular uh serum
and moisturizer right on top. And in the
daytime, of course, she's going to apply
her sunscreen every day, all year round.
And you've been using it for three weeks
as well. How did it work for you? It
worked wonderful. I'm a little north of
the 50. I'm not quite 40 anymore. So, I
noticed a lot in my forehead and the the
11s. It was my issue. And I did notice a
lot of softening in that small amount of
time. So, I definitely will be using the
product more. I can see a big difference
in you. I love that. Yeah. Yeah. The
before was kind of frightening. No, but
you're happy now. I'm very happy with
it. Good for you. I'm very happy for
both of you. Dr. D, break it down for
us. Where can you find number seven line
correcting booster serum? What does it
cost? You can find it at target or
target.com and it's about $42. All
right, but here's the deal. Thanks to my
partner, number seven. Everyone here in
the audience is going home with the new
number seven laboratories live
correcting booster syrup. It's all
yours. Get it and share it. We'll be
right back.
If there's one thing that brings us all
together, it's food. So, we're calling
everyone to the table to dish on
everything. From the latest food hacks
and trends to everyday recipes you can
make for dinner tonight. Singing is my
first love, but my other passion is
baking.
I'm an iron chef, but mostly the
executive chef of Butter Restaurant and
mother to an 11-year-old. This is the
first recipe I ever made in a
professional kitchen. They were
terrible. My cooking is like me. A mix
of Caribbean heat meet southern sweet.
This is like my girlfriend in the
kitchen. I am as a chef first and
foremost about flavor. It's simple. It's
celebratory. And most of all, it's about
having a great time in the kitchen. What
is going I'm trying to help. Let's dish.
[Applause]
Welcome to the dish on Oz. Jimmy Oliver.
Jimmy Oliver is joining the dish with
the champagne. He's popping bottles cuz
we both got to get a party started. Oh
my goodness. We're bringing everybody to
death. What are we celebrating today?
Yes. So much champagne is already
flowing. You guys, it is our cocktail of
the day because we are giving each and
every one of you permission to eat pasta
again.
Oh, double toasted. Oh, thank you. Good.
The right way to do it. Coming up, we
have delicious guilt-free pasta recipes
you're going to want to make tonight,
including a super green spaghetti from
Jamie. Cannot wait to eat that. Then,
you're going to get a hack that lowers
your pasta's carb load. You will not
believe how simple this is to do. It's
going to change the way you eat pasta.
And if you're curious about all the new
low carb options that are on the
shelves, all those veggie noodles and
everything, and some grain ones, too,
we're going to have a noodle off to see
which one holds up to the ultimate
Italian cheesy pasta. I love
competitions. I know, Jenny. Hello. So
nice to be here. Look at me sandwich
between all you lovely people. I mean,
doctor, how lucky are we? The luckiest.
Absolut. And that's toast the pasta back
on the menu.
J, you're a pasta fanatic. That you're
such a fanatic. You one up Jamie. You
take selfies everywhere you go. I mean,
pasta is so indulgent for me. So, I just
kind of do it every now and again, but I
take selfies with them because it's kind
of like taking a picture with with your
boo, your bae. You know what I'm saying?
It's like, "Hey, pasta, I love you. I
like you." So, yes, I'm not the only one
that takes pictures with my boo. Now,
here's my question. Do you then go back
through your camera roll like late at
night and take a look at your pasta porn
and just like relive the moment? It's
kind of a fetish. I do have a moment
like, "Oh, wow. always happen to you
Americans.
Not in England. Not in England. No, no,
we don't have pasta porn in England. We
just we just eat pasta and we enjoy it.
Came here. Well, listen. Look, pasta is
a beautiful thing. It's a fantastic
carrier of flavors. And this one, guys,
this is the craziest, most delicious
thing ever. Can I start, please? Okay.
So, look, if we've got Cavalon Nero
here. This is the black the black
cabbage, but any green leaf, kale,
seavoy cabbage. We've got Swiss chard
here, spinach. Right, go with me on this
one, guys. Um, now we're going to we're
going to prep the stalks off of our
greens. And you can use, like I said,
any greens you want. And then we will
blanch these greens. Um, and that means
sort of cook it for like 3 or 4 minutes.
And what we'll do is we'll take greens
like this, right, which are nice and
hot. Um, and these are just been
blanched because we're doing it on TV,
right? And we'll simply put it in a
liquidizer with a bit of cooking water.
Easy, right? Anyone can do that. Then
get me the garlic in there as well.
Easy, right? Chef. And then we're going
to balance with a little Parmesan or
Parmesan as we call it. Love that. A
little umami. All right. Then um then
we're going to go in with some olive
oil. Now olive oil, as all of you clever
people here will know, is a fantastic
hearthealthy oil. uh the polyphenols
which are the antioxidants you know the
these are these are doctor tell me these
are things that kind of attack free
radicals right anti-inflammatory you
need it to for your cells to function
normally and you mentioned genevese
earlier Italians eat pasta like this and
they don't gain weight so obviously
there's a way of doing this so we don't
suffer and the other thing is guys is we
don't in Italy they don't have main
course portions of pasta it doesn't
exist they're all starter size they're
all small so whatever you have good or
bad in life portion control is an issue
Wind it up, baby. Wind it up. Would
either. So, yes. Now, um we were talking
about five ingredients. Yes. Um my
latest book is um Quick and Easy
Fiveingredient Ingredient Food. Excuse
me. I've got the pasta going in. Uh
normally this will be in from the start,
but we're cheating cuz it's TV. Um so,
um what we have guys here is we'll end
up with this. I don't know if the camera
can show you this, but basically we've
liquidized the greens. Can
I? It's just greens, garlic, oil,
parmesan, and then we'll toss it with
the pasta. And we'll just coat it. And
more cheese. Well, we might taste it and
see. But let's have a little look. Alex,
what a sick fence you are. A little
cheese, please. A little cheese. So,
look. Look at the color. Guys, wait. Let
my dad try that. I want to try my
dad. Have a
little
medical in school. t-shirt. Oh, and
you'll notice I I dress like the doctor
today, so I came in a white outfit just
so you know. So, we're going to we're
going to taste this now and balance it.
Now, also for look for this is ricotta.
Have a look for it. This is This is It
means ricotta means recooked. It's a
really good lowfat cheese which is
supposed to be low fat. You don't want
to put too much cheese. Absolutely. Are
you ricott?
She she just keeps going. Look, it's
kale. Dr. Oz, look.
you. But I swear just just have a look
at this is the most extraordinary pasta.
But what happened to the ricotta here?
What happened to this? Well, you are
going to erotically put it pasta. You
are going to erotically put it over the
top of this pasta. Don't be cheap. Don't
be cheap. Get your camera ready, Jimmy.
Get your camera ready. That's enough. I
know what you're thinking.
Let's use our
hand. Okay, that's she's she's got it.
So, what we have here is a beautiful
kale green pasta. It is delicious. You
have to try it to believe it. It's five
ingredients. Have a try. Please enjoy.
Take us over here. Oh, that's enough
cheese. Come on. Come on. Come over
here. Jamie, come over here. You keep
moving the target. What the [__]
Cheese.
Well, why? You got to start tasting
that. I got to say Daffhne is in the
midst of trying to get her kids, my
grandkids to eat green foods. I'm going
to show you what happened when my
grandkids were first exposed to this
pesto pasta. This is Yeah, I I witnessed
this from behind the scenes. This is
Dy's version of green spaghetti. Take a
look. John Boy, can you taste it? No. I
would like you just to have one bite and
tell me what you think of that green
monster pasta. It It's gooey. It's not
good for kids. Sorry if you No, it's
definitely good for kids, guys. I used
to love this when I was your age. It's
Mommy made it. It's super delicious. It
tastes it tastes even better with salt
on one. One saw one says it's not good
for kids. You were passionate about
children and healthy foods. Why does
this message work for you? Well, the
thing is this actual recipe is not a
trendy new thing. This is like hundreds
of years in Tuscanyany, right? Hundreds
of years. Um I've gone to Italy in the
mountains and I've seen armies of kids
eat stuff like this and you go, "Really?
Really? British kids, American kids?
Really?" Yeah. Because it's normal. My
kids used to eat this like a dream. I
would make pesto all the time and now
they're four and they're a green.
Do do you think there should be some
life balance though? I mean, like we go
to a market, we see the peaches of
Tuscany, you know, that are the best
ever, and then we go to like a pastry
market and see all the cakes. Do you
think there should be some balance?
Here's the thing. I I think I think I I
think a fair and good life is about
choice. I mean, I'm a food lover, so I
love cake. I love burger. I love pizza.
But like, it's it's your stomach doesn't
see food. It's it sees molecules and
nutrients, right? My stomach's like a
six-pack ab of eyes.
No, I see everything. So, I'm hydra. I
admire so much of what you do and in
particularly your gift for creating
books. Five ingredients. This wonderful
book makes sense for adults, their kids
and everyone in between whether you know
a lot or not. Explain a little bit about
the principle. So, uh it it took 20
years I'm a slow learner to work out
that it's actually the length of
ingredients that is one of the first
kind of edits of people cooking or not
cooking. And then the second one is have
I got the ingredients? So, if you flick
through that book, you've probably got
three ingredients in your house already,
and then you've only got to pick up one
or two things on the way home from work.
So, combinations that just want to work.
Well, this dish is in the book, and I'm
obsessed with it. I see why you have
five kids. Your wife is a lucky woman.
You are a phenomenal chef, and I'm going
to keep eating this like many. So, Jamie
Jamie brought two books. You all get one
page of this beautiful book. Is that
right? No. No. Everyone here has got a
copy of my book today. Woo! It's called
Five Ingredients with Hast on the cover.
Up next, a delicious dish made with a
simple hack that lowers the carb load of
literally any starchy food. Stick
around. Oh, that looks good.
The pasta party is still happening right
here in the dish. Come back because Alex
has a chilled pasta dish that'll have
everyone reaching for seconds. I can't
wait to taste it. I'll be the judge of
that, Tanya.
[Music]
[Applause]
Flavor and great tasting food is a way
to truly enjoy life. I'm an only child
product of two Italian parents who both
love to cook. My mom was a cookbook
editor who presided over some of the
great cookbooks. I think that was the
beginning. I'm an Iron Chef, a judge on
Food Networks Chopped, but I am mostly
the executive chef of Butter Restaurant
in Midtown Manhattan, and mother to an
11-year-old. Welcome to my kitchen at
Butter. This is the first recipe I ever
made in a professional kitchen, but they
were terrible. I'm not going to lie.
Some days are work, but I love what I
do. It's like putting on a Broadway play
every night. I never get tired of it.
We are back with a dish on Oz. Jamie
Oliver is here hanging out with us in
the kitchen and it is a total
celebration today. We are having a pasta
party because you do not have to be
afraid of pasta anymore. We're giving
you the tips and tricks to enjoy
everyone's favorite carb. And dad, I
understand you've got another cool
guilt-free hack to eat pasta. Tell us
about it. Pardon the punch. We'll be
here all week. By the way, all week I
get my Here's the thing. It is cool
because it's about cold pasta. I don't
know if you talk about this much in the
UK, but it's become a big issue. As I've
looked at it, it makes sense. Cooling
carbs like pasta after cooking them
increases resistant starch. Remember,
pasta is basically sugar and fiber. It
could be one or the other. If you make
it more like fiber, it's much better for
you. That's what cooling it does. Means
you don't get much of a blood sugar
response. And it's perfect for folks on
the January no diet diet that we
featured on the show last week cuz we're
waving the white flag and we're eating
pasta again. Eat it. Eat it. Good. And
the problem the problem with me saying
this is everyone looks out there and
says, "Okay, what's a cold carb?" It's
potato salad. Yeah. Until today, cuz we
got the dish. And Jamie, telling you the
truth, chilled Chinese noodles. Alex is
going to bring this alive for us. Oh,
he's excited. I mean, Alex, bring Take a
look. She made it for us. Oh, you're
going to like it. One of my favorite old
school recipes from my dad. These tangy
cool noodles. Sesame noodles. I'm going
to start by adding the soy sauce, which
is really the heart of the
recipe. Get that sugar and salt
dissolving in there. The sesame oil in
there, and that's going to coat these
noodles really beautifully. So, just two
teaspoons of hot sauce. And that's a
lot. Love that. So, here's the
foundation of the sauce. We're going to
pop that in the fridge. And while that's
cooling, we are going to take these
noodles and drop them right into boiling
salted
water. Time to
drain. Shake those noodles. This is what
my dad taught me. And now we're going to
fill the pot we cooked it in with cold
water and actually drop those hot
noodles in the cold water.
[Music]
Yum. Alice is very stingy with my
portion, I should say. First, first, why
did you use a towel? I can count the
numbers of strains of pasta here. Why'd
you use a towel to dry the pasta? Well,
we don't think about it when we drain
pasta cuz we talk romantically about
using water to make the sauce, but when
you're not, you want pure flavor. Get
that water out of there. Drain your
pasta, turn it on a kitchen towel, and
pat it dry. Like you dry off when you
get out of the pool, you want to dry
your pasta off and then add that flavor.
I never dry off. No, I don't either. I
let the water dry. I just thought it
exactly. Yeah. So, what what do you
think about Alex's concoction?
Delicious. Oh, please don't patronize
her. Well, why would I? It's beautifully
It's beautifully seasoned. You know,
there's nice ingredients in there. And
thank you. I'm glad to have someone on
my team. I think it's spectacular. And
I'm even more impressed because I like
you are a worldrenowned Italian chef.
But I I don't Where did this inspiration
come from? Well, my father cooked
Chinese food for a hobby. And my dad
would make these elaborate Chinese
dinners. They would take three days to
prepare. Get I would go into the kitchen
to get something and my mother would
say, "Don't go in there till Friday."
Why would it not? Why would an Italian
guy be making Chinese food? He just
thought the food of China was the one of
the great cuisines of the world and that
the Chinese Yeah. and that the Chinese
taught the Italians to make pasta and so
Goshell's think it all began in China.
And so we end up with these um
heart-healthy, carb friendly, wave the
white flag. My problem is it may be
chilled and better for me, but I'm going
to eat double. Mhm.
No, you're a dim sum favorite. I know
you already. I know what you really eat.
I do. This is that nice spiciness, not
much. It's got a brightness with all the
herbs. I think you all to try this. And
I think this is an example how cold
pasta can be even better than hot pasta.
No, this is fantastic. I am feeling chai
Italian, Alex, right now.
I'm feeling that is like the best
fusion. I love that comfort food all the
way. So good. I kind of wonder if anyone
else wants a taste.
What did that mean? Who is that?
[Applause]
Michael first.
Hi, sweetie.
Word on the street is I'm going to try
some noodles. Come join us. Come join.
Come join the party. Oh, nice to have
you. You know you know you know Jamie.
Nice to meet you. Hi, sweetie. Yes,
sweetie. Sweetie, you can't ruin my rep
by saying things like sweetie, right?
That's what we we want to know all that
stuff. What's like the cutesy word you
call each other at home? Um, a few, but
Pooh Bear is the one that sticks out.
Poo Bear. Alex is Poo Bear. Oh my gosh.
Wait a minute. Okay, I got to get the
dish on you, too. Okay, so and I'm that
friend that grills all the boyfriends.
So, okay. So, Michael, how are you? Nice
to meet you. Where you from? Um, what do
you cook? What does Alex like it spicy
or sweet in the kitchen? And what's your
intentions? You want to put a ring on
it? Like I have so many questions. Like
I don't know where you can eat while we
do this. Tell me everything about you.
Do you want to leave? No, no, no. Don't
leave. Don't leave. Come. Grill master
over here. That is me. I am that friend.
I'm so sorry. Um I was a chef in a
restaurant. I made something amazing and
she wanted to meet the chef. I came out
and um
Oh my gosh. You were at the restaurant.
You ate a meal of his. You demanded to
meet the chef. It was that good. And he
was back there in front of the stove and
I said, "I'll take that to go."
[Applause]
I'll take two Bear to go. There you go.
All right, Jamie. Nice to meet you.
Yeah. No, not yet. We can't let him go.
Me and the doctor are going to give him
a full medical now. I hope you don't
mind. Curt, please. Listen, Jamie, I
adore you. Thank you for coming,
Michael. Pleasure. Lots more questions
in the commercial break. Our pasta party
continues. When we come back, we're
putting all the new alternative low carb
noodles to the test to see which one is
the tastiest. You will not want to miss
this.
[Applause]
Hey America, we need you to pick the
winner of the first ever sharing care
award. It celebrates people using their
creativity, expertise, and talents to
tell the stories of people making a
difference in the lives of others.
Working with the New York Emmys, our
partners at ShareCare are celebrating
the best health and wellness content on
digital and on local television all over
the country. Vote for the programs that
are changing and saving lives at
sharecare.org/voting. Share the care.
[Music]
We are back with the dish on us. And all
sure long we've been giving you hacks to
take the guilt out of your favorite
pasta dishes. Now our final hack,
swapping in low carb noodles. From
zoodles to lentil pasta and even the new
kid on the block, quinoa macaroni.
They're the ultimate. But can they
deliver on flavor as much as the classic
white pastas? Dapne has figured out a
way to identify what makes sense. And
your little trick is Well, I don't have
a trick. I'm just going to have you guys
do a noodle off. I want to make you I'm
going to put you all on the spot and you
tell me which of these pastas stacks up
to the real thing. Okay, here's how it
goes. The ultimate pasta in my book. My
personal favorite is
gacha, which is a fancy way of saying
cheese and pepper. It's really like the
simplest, easiest. You definitely have
it in your in your pantry tonight. And
it's just oh, it's so indulgent and
amazing. And you can make it on linguini
or another kind of pasta like that. But
there are so many new noodles on the
market and I kind of wanted to put them
together. Okay. So, what you guys have
in front of you is four different
samples of pasta, all with that kaca
pepe sauce. So, you have a lentil pasta,
you have a um quinoa pasta, you have a
zucchini pasta, and then you have your
traditional ingredient. And I want to
hear from you guys definitively. Make a
choice. Which ones holds up to the
original? Let me go first. I don't know
the words that you will use to describe
yours. I'm into the zoodles. Really?
Yeah. This thing really is fantastic. It
doesn't taste like zucchini. It tastes
like it's supposed to taste like a
zoodle. I mean, all right, Alex, what do
you got? Well, I'm gonna jump in because
I'm following your lead. I think the
zoodles are my favorite. I mean, they're
all cheesy and spicy, which is great,
but I like the crunch in the bite on the
zucchini. It gives me a little more
bite. I like it. I like it. Me and you.
How about you guys? You know what? I
love a zoodle. It's a little bit on the
fresh freshly mowed lawn side of things
for me. I need to see classic spaghetti
visually. So, for me, I'm going to go
with the quinoa. I really like the bite
and the chew. I like that. I might break
up with you, chew to the pasta. I need
it. I can't just delicately eat zucchini
on the way back from the gym and feel
right. Do you know?
I love that. I love I love that. I need
backup, Daffy. I I got You know, I I
want to side with you. I feel like
quinoa was the way that I was going and
I was so not about to go for the
zucchini, but I'm going to go team
zucchini. There is something really
light and refreshing and delicious.
All right, you had a game for us. Yes, I
have a fun game cuz you know I love a
good party game. So, you know that
zoodles are made of zucchini, but let's
see if you can guess what these other
voodles are made of. So, ve vegetable
noodles. Got it. Voodles. All right. So,
coodles. What would that audience? That
sounds like something these two are
doing after.
What would that be? Name the vegetable.
Cucumber. Carrots. Carrots. Yes. Oh,
that's good. Yes. All right. Next one.
Swoodles. What do we think? Squash.
Sweet potato. Swiss cheese. Squash. You
got it. Got it. All right. Next one.
Boodles. Oh, sounds illegal. I heard it
out there. Broccoli. Broccoli. I got it.
I got it. So proud of you. And poodles.
And it's not the dog. Poodles. Everybody
stumped. Poodles. Pumpkin. No. Oh,
that's a good guess. Parsnips.
That's hard. That's hard. That's tough.
One more. And toodles. Toodles. Toodles.
What would be? Turn up. Turn up. She got
it. Turn up. You win. All the root
veggies. And by the way, if you guys
want to make this scotch pepe at home,
we actually have it on Instagram stories
on the dish. At the dish on us, if you
want to make it at home, you can find
our guide to low carb noodles online at
dr.com. And remember everybody, together
change is happening. Our journey is just
beginning. See you next time.
I know. It's really good.
[Music]