He was subjected to one of the most
famous murder trials of our time and
known as part of the West Memphis 3
after being sentenced to die from lethal
injection. Damen Eckles was set free
after serving 18 years on death row for
murder. And today he is here speaking
out on life after being sentenced to
die. His story is being compared to a
real life witch hunt. And although Damen
is out from behind bars, will his past
hold him prisoner forever? Our affiliate
in Little Rock, Arkansas, KEV, covered
the story extensively.
May 5th, 1993,
three 8-year-old boys, Stevie Branch,
Christopher Buyers, and Michael Moore,
went for a bike ride in their hometown
of West Memphis, Arkansas. They never
returned home for dinner. The next day,
their bodies were found naked, tied with
shoelaces, and mutilated in a dish. With
very little evidence, police focused on
three local teens, Damen Eckles, Jesse
Miss Kelly Jr., and Jason Baldwin. The
teen stood out in the Bible belt,
especially Damian Eckles, with his
interests in heavy metal music, gothic
dress, and fascination with occultism.
The young men, nicknamed the West
Memphis 3, were arrested in 1994.
Jesse Miss Kelly had a very low IQ and
was interrogated for a high pressure 12
hours leading to a confession. I saw
Damian hit this one hit this homeboy
real bad. Then the Jason turn around and
hit
Steve Branch Michael Mo took off
running. So I chased him and grabbed him
and held him.
Jesse and Jason were sentenced to life
in prison. Damen was sentenced to death.
While on death row, Eckles met his
biggest advocate, Lorie Davis, who
started writing him letters determined
to set him free. After 3 years, they
wed. Lorie started a movement and
created a media firestorm. Celebrities
and musicians rallied around the West
Memphis 3. Johnny Depp, Pearl Jam's
Eddie Veter, and director Peter Jackson
used their voices to speak out about
what many felt to be the injust and lack
evidence tying these men to the murders.
August 19th, 2011, the West Memphis
three were released from prison, but
their story of freedom is far from over.
Damian Eckles joins me now. You know,
you watch that old footage of the
interviews you did, the trials. What's
it like sitting here,
a free man after having been in that
situation? Has that been imaginable?
It's It's hard to articulate it to
someone who's never experienced
something like that just because the
average person doesn't have anything in
their frame of reference to allow them,
I think, to comprehend like that level
of trauma. Um, some days it seems like
That entire 20 years was just a really
short bad dream. Other days it seems
like being out here is the dream that
surely I cannot be out of that prison
cell. You know, I was sitting there
waiting to die for so long uh that it
seems like
there's no way that I could have
possibly survived that. Um it it's one
it's
really really hard to describe. What was
your life like before this all started?
Before the arrest, before the
accusations, before the time on death
row,
you know, growing up in Arkansas, my
family was, and not just my family, our
entire world, the world that we lived in
was dirt poor. You know, I dropped out
of school when I was in ninth grade. And
that's more education than anyone in my
family has. You know, everyone in the
world that we came from is pretty much
just working to survive another day in
the trailer park.
So, in the midst of all this, you get
accused
you know you're innocent, you go to
trial and then there's that moment when
the judge sentences you to death
hit you to hear those words. People
whenever they see the the documentaries
or or trial footage, they always say,
"You seem so calm." And what I try to
describe to people is what you're seeing
is not calm. What you're seeing is shock
and trauma.
Even now, you know, I'll I'll see people
sometimes who will say, you know, I
wouldn't have acted that way if it would
have been me. You know, if it would have
been me, I would have been screaming in
the courtroom. You know, I didn't do it.
And I think one of the greatest quotes
for that is something I heard Mike Tyson
say one time. He said, "Everybody's got
a plan until they get punched in the
face."
Yeah.
That's what it's like. It's like you
don't know what you would do in a
situation where you're experiencing that
much trauma until you've actually been
in it. So after your sentence, they put
you in solitary confinement. It's a
space, if I understand correctly, it's
12 feet by 9 ft. That's how big the cell
is,
right?
What what does that do to you
physically?
It destroys you in every way a human
being can be destroyed psychologically,
emotionally, health-wise. Uh you know,
just things like there's almost no
medical care, no dental care. They're
not going to spend a lot of time and
money and energy taking care of someone
they plan on killing. So you're not
getting any fresh air, any sunlight,
you're eating garbage. It starts it
started destroying my eyesight. Uh at
one point
that why you're wearing the glasses.
Exactly. I I can see maybe two or three
inches in front of my face without these
glasses. Uh you know, I was in
horrendous pain a lot of times just
because uh like I said, they're not
trying to take care of you. They're
trying to kill you.
And I understand there are nights that
you went to sleep and you didn't think
you'd ever wake up. Why was it that
degree of risk?
Just, you know, when I first got to the
prison, and this wasn't even anything
personal. This was just the guards doing
what the guards do. Uh they took me to a
part of the prison they called the hole.
And for the next 18 days, they beat the
living hell out of me. They they beat me
so bad that I started to urinate blood
at one point. And there were times when
I laid down at night and I thought, I'm
not going to be able to get back up.
This is it. And it's it's not like
you're giving up. It's just like you
can't do it anymore.
You're exhausted. Finished
in every way that you can be exhausted.
There was no DNA evidence, just to be
clear with everybody. No DNA evidence.
There's no witnesses to connect Damian
to the crime. Many have called this a
real life witch hunt.
Why, if you were targeted, why do you
think they targeted you? Why pick on
you, Damen Eckles? You're apparently
minding your own business.
I think a lot of it was due to this was
during a time when um you know, people
are starting to forget it now, but
during the late 80s, early 90s, you had
a phenomenon in the United States called
satanic panic. But then when you start
talking about things like, you know, my
practices like ceremonial magic, when
you start talking about things like
that, then you're out and out blatantly
obviously a Satanist. So that kind of
put a bull's eye on my back in and of
itself.
Ceremonial magic.
Mhm.
Is that meditation? Is it incense?
It it's uh really what it comes down to.
It's like the yoga of the west. It is
the western path to the state of
consciousness that we call
enlightenment. So, as you as you look
back on the 20 years that you said seem
like a dream, maybe,
are you angry?
Honestly, no. Um, I I was for a while.
For probably the first two to three
years that I was on death row, I would
wake up in the morning angry. You know,
from the second your eyes open, you're
angry. I realized if I didn't do
something to overcome that, let go of
that, however you want to phrase it,
then I was doubling my suffering. You
know, I I I decided, like I said, I had
a ninth grade education. So, I decided
at one point that I wanted to educate
myself to just have the same frame of
reference that everybody else has. So, I
started not only doing, you know,
ceremonial magic, but I also tried to
read everything I could get my hands on.
you know, everything from Dorstoki and
and Toltoy and Kimu and Dickens to um
you know, the works of Freud or uh
Vietnam uh military history, anything I
could get my hands on just because I
wanted to keep developing as a person.
This is fascinating. You're not at all
at all what I expected. Coming up, meet
the woman who fought to save Damian's
life and married him when he was still
behind bars. That's next.
After more than 18 years of fighting for
freedom from prison, the men known
around the world as the West Memphis 3
are free tonight.
Very much in shock, still overwhelmed.
You know, you kind of have to take into
consideration that I've spent almost the
past decade in absolute solitary
confinement.
That was former West Memphis 3 inmate
Damen Eckles being released from prison
after spending 18 years on death row for
three counts of murder he says he did
not commit. that Damian is back and
we're also joined with his wife Lori who
fought for years for Damian's release.
So Lori, this whole story is so outside
the norm. I just started. How did you
even hear about Damian's story?
I was living here in New York and
there's a film series uh at MoMA called
New Directors New Films. And I'm a film
fanatic. And so I ended up going to see
the documentary Paradise Lost, which was
screened in 1996.
And being from the south originally and
growing up in a fundamentalist Baptist
home, I understood what was at least
what the community was doing. And I just
really felt for Damian and decided to
reach out to him just to see if I could
help in some way.
So Lori, just from hearing the story,
you had to make a decision that you
believe this man was innocent. What made
you so confident and steal your desire
to get him out of prison?
After seeing the film, my instincts told
me that something horrible had gone
wrong during the trial, but just knowing
him and getting to know him as a person,
I didn't doubt him.
So, Lori rallied behind Damian and
brought some famous supporters in like
Peter Jackson, Eddie Veter from Pearl
Jam. Larry, these are bigname guys.
Yeah.
How did Damian's story resonate with
them? Why did they get involved?
Same thing as far as seeing the film.
They saw Paradise Lost. And most of
these guys saw themselves as when they
were teenagers as rebels and they saw
themselves and Damian and thought it
could have been them.
And with Peter Jackson and Fran Walsh,
they just hated bullies. And when they
saw the film, they they contacted me and
just asked what they could do. They
ended up actually even coming on the
legal team, helping with investigation,
funding, forensic scientists, but
everybody once they got involved stayed
with us for the for the whole duration.
Damian, how important was that do you
think having this celebrity involvement?
And I'm just curious what what how did
you react when this woman's calling you
from New York saying, you know, let's
let's talk about this. I knew from the
second she found me that I was okay. You
know, I knew that other bad things may
happen while I was in there. I may be
beat. I may be starved, whatever. But I
knew from that point on that these
people could not kill me. And I don't
know how to describe that any more than
just that I felt safe. I felt like we
had clicked into place and what was
supposed to be happening was supposed to
be happening. The celebrity stuff, I I
really I think it was I would be dead
right now without it. I would be six
feet underground. and they would have
executed me years ago.
So, while you're Damian's in prison,
Laura, you get married in a Buddhist
ceremony. He's still on death row.
Yeah.
I mean, how'd your family and your
friends react to that?
I didn't tell my family that I was
involved with Damian for four years.
You didn't tell them.
How can you not tell your parents that
you're dating and getting married to a
guy on death row? It does tend to come
up in conversation. Um, well, my
family's from West Virginia and and I
love my family and I'm very close with
them, but I just felt it necessary to
for for them and for me and Damian, I
needed to know what I was doing. I had
to I had to have a plan in place and
before I just went off spouting, I'm
marrying this guy on death row. I didn't
It's It could It was devastating for
them to hear that even four years later.
But at least I was able to emotionally
handle myself.
Did you really think he would get out of
jail?
I did.
But how why would you think that he's on
death row? I mean, maybe commuted to
life in prison or 40 years later he gets
free. It's almost biblical in scope, but
what what would make you think he'd get
completely free?
I have great faith.
And Damian, outside of Lori and and your
own, you know, who supported you? Who
was there for you?
Mostly it was Lori and and people that,
you know, we became friends with over
the years like Johnny Depp, Eddie Veter,
Peter Jackson, you know, people that
kind of became like family to us. My own
family, they weren't really capable of
of offering any kind of support or
anything else. You know, when I was
born, my mother was like 15, my father
was 16, so they're barely more than
children themselves, living these lives
of absolute grinding poverty. They
couldn't even afford to come see me at
the prison. You know, the prison is
several hours away from the town where
they lived and they had no way of even
getting there.
So, against all odds, you're freed. What
was that moment like when you stepped
outside the prison walls after having
been in a 9 by12 confined cell for many
of the years?
This is another thing that is almost
impossible for me to make people
understand. I can barely remember the
first two years I was out of prison. In
hindsight, I was probably suffering from
what people call a nervous breakdown and
didn't realize it at the time.
And how are you doing now being out of
prison?
I think my I am probably happier now
than I've ever been in my life. You
know, it's Thank you.
Why
I part of what happened whenever I got
out um like I said, I was
psychologically shattered. I could not
read like I would I lost all ability to
read. I would read the same page of a
book over and over and could not retain
what I had read when I got to the bottom
of the page. I would reintroduce myself
to the same person over and over because
I could not even remember having dinner
with them the night before. Um, and you
know, my spiritual practice was the core
of my life when I was in prison. You
know, I was I was doing some of these
techniques, these meditations, these
visualizations for like eight hours a
day. When I walked out of prison, I was
so destroyed that I could not even do it
for eight minutes. That was part of of
what made life out here so hard. I had
to work my way gradually back up to
being able to do the same things I was
doing in prison. And that's a huge part
of what made my life more stable again.
This is a fascinating conversation. I
the fact that you were behind prison is
tragic, but the recovery itself from a
physician's perspective, I mean, it's
life-changing. Up next, a shocking truth
behind why Damian will never truly be a
free man. Why not? Why? When we come
back. We're back with former West
Memphis 3 inmate Damen Eckles and his
wife Lori. Now Damian spent 18 years on
death row waiting to be executed by
lethal injection while his wife fought
to set him free. Damian, do you ever any
flashbacks to the time in prison? Times
when you when you had a lot of
difficulty. It was very dark. How have
you learned to cope with that drama?
You know, really I I I wouldn't call
them flashbacks, but I still have
nightmares sometimes. That that's the
main thing. I I have dreams. Uh, and and
in my dreams, it's not only so much that
I'm back in prison, but you know, like I
said, it was my spiritual practice that
allowed me to survive that. In my
dreams, I don't have that to rely on.
It's like I've forgotten everything and
I'm just a victim of all the forces
going on around me. So, it's like doubly
traumatic. Um, I did have other things
whenever I first got out like, uh, any
little thing that would startle me would
trigger PTSD like symptoms. Like it
could be anything from, you know, I
would almost there were there was a time
I almost punched a car because a guy
clicked his alarm and it scared me so
bad. You know, just the sudden noise of
it. Just Exactly. Things like that. As
time has went on, I've been out almost
eight years now and as time has went on
that grows less and less and less.
You have some insights into what happens
in the prison that we all need to hear.
which gave me a whole new way of
thinking about what we're doing. The
folks who are behind bars,
you know, the the one thing that I
always try to get across to people is in
the almost 20 years that I was in there,
I never saw I I did not see one single
shred of anything that could be even
remotely considered uh any sort of
rehabilitative program. Um and and
that's pretty much life in there.
My goodness. So, you're no longer behind
bars, but I don't want people to sit
here and think Damian is an innocent man
because you're not considered to be a
free man.
That's That's correct.
Please explain why you have not been
exonerated, even though that does seem
to be what everyone thinks.
We what happened in our case, I had
never heard of this thing before our
case. It was completely new to me. We
were uh given what's called an Alfred
plea. In our case, what happened is
they, you know, when I was arrested in
1993, they could not do the same kind of
DNA testing back then that they can do
now. So whenever they finally started
doing DNA testing and found that it
didn't match me or the other two guys
they convicted. We had new eyewitnesses
come forth and put the person that the
DNA did match with all three of the
victims within an hour of the time they
were murdered. The state still did not
want to let us go. To this day, no one's
ever been exonerated from death row in
the state of Arkansas ever.
They wanted to maintain that record. We
were given what's called an Alfred plea.
An Alfred plea means you are
accepting a guilty plea while still
being legally allowed to maintain your
innocence. It makes no sense whatsoever.
And the entire reason that this thing
exists is so that the state can't be
held responsible and doesn't have to pay
you any sort of compensation.
I mean, we got a problem here. I you
can't vote, right? You can't get a job.
Hard to travel. You don't get
compensation, which I frankly think
you're deserving of that. But
independence, you can't even earn for
yourself, which is a bigger problem.
Exactly. So the offer plea was
originally designed so you could take
people who should have gone to death row
and give them life in prison for copying
a plea. You save everyone time, money,
and it sort of made sense. It wasn't
designed to be used for someone like
you.
Exactly.
There's someone else who was pivotal in
getting you out of prison. And we had a
chance to talk to him very recently. His
name is John Douglas. He's considered
the original mind hunter and he created
the original criminal profile and helped
you with your release. Now when I heard
the story, I was stunned. But he
recently was here and he had a few
things to say to you. Take a look.
Damian is a survivor. He's he he was a
victim of this crime. Wrongfully
convicted. I'm really proud proud of
him. He's just a wonderful uh
individual. Extremely bright bright uh
and and what a waste of talent for these
past 18 years when he was incarcerated.
What's it like hearing that? I mean, the
guy's a world famous worldass
individual.
He is. But not only is he that, he is
also kind. He's one of the kindest
people you'll come across, which was
something that meant a lot to me because
after everything I'd been through, I
started to look at anyone who was
remotely involved in the field of law
enforcement as the enemy. These were the
people who tried to murder me. These
were the people who tried to cover up
evidence to make sure that I was killed.
So, whenever you meet someone like John
Douglas, you realize not everyone in
that community is a bad guy. Some of
these people do actually want to see
justice. some of these people do
actually care about you as a human
being. So he John Douglas is is at least
partly responsible for restoring some of
my faith in the American judicial
system.
So Damian Jason Jesse the three men
arrested were victims of a broken
system. That's what it seems like to me
anyway and folks have investigated this.
Whoever killed those kids, what happened
to them? We don't know. They didn't go
to jail. So they could have killed
again. And we can't forget the three
boys that lost their lives. They still
have not gotten justice. What would that
word justice mean to you, Damian?
You know, whenever people ask me that,
the the only thing I can say is that
there there can be no justice in this
case. You know, you there may be a sense
of closure. You know, if they arrest the
right person, if they exonerate me and
the other two guys, that would be a
sense of closure, but it's not justice.
Justice is not going to give me back 20
years of my life or undo all of the
trauma that I experienced. Justice is
not going to bring those three children
back. You know, even there there's all
the ramifications and the ripples that
were created by the devastation that
this case brought. I now have a
grandson. I never even got a chance to
know my son or my grandson. He grew up
without a father. Nothing is ever going
to give us that opportunity again.
Nothing is ever going to bring that
back. There can be no justice in this
case.
But closure is there.
Closure.
At least that was something we can seek.
Thank you both for being here.
You can find out more of Damian's story
in his new book. is called High Magic, a
guide to the spiritual practices that
saved my life on death row. You can also
hear more from Damian and Lori on season
two of my podcast. We'll be right back.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good