Lorraine Bronco. She's had an amazing
career from modeling, which I didn't
know she did, to her breakout role in
Good Fellas, I love that movie, and her
starring role in The Sopranos. But all
of her success didn't mean Lorraine was
happy. She found herself depressed,
overweight, and unhealthy. But now she's
fighting back, in great shape, and
feeling good. How did she do it? We're
about to find out. Line Braco, come on
out.
[Applause]
[Music]
lots of love. Lots of very very well.
You look wonderful. Very well. Really?
Come have a seat. Thank you. I feel
good. Yeah. You look happy, too. How
much weight have you lost? May I ask? 35
lbs. 35 lbs.
It's pretty cool. 35 pounds, but I did
it slow and steady in about over a year.
Well, you talk about it a lot. This is
Lorraine's new book. It's called To the
Fullest. It's about your journey towards
health. I am intrigued by the title to
the Fullest. Because you, if you don't
mind, I'd love if you could explain why
you called it that. Because I'm 60.
It's time to fill
up. And the truth of the matter is is
I'm in the third quarter of my life and
I want to live every day as strong and
hard and fun as I can make it. And
you're doing it. I am. Let me go back a
little bit because there have been times
where it was more difficult. And we
always celebrate success, but we also
want to figure out how you got here.
Your co-star in the Sopranos, James
Gandalfini. Yep. When you lost him, uh
it was painful for everybody. How did
that affect this this journey you're on?
Well, the truth of the matter is is, you
know, Jimmy was always a big guy. He's
was 6'4. He's a he's a big man. And um I
I remember this so well. We were on the
red carpet for something at HBO and I
hadn't seen him in a while. And I
grabbed his belly and I was like, "You
need to get rid of this." And he was
like, "Ah, it's all muscle. It's all
muscle muscle." And I'm like, "No, you
really have to pay attention." And you
know, we we laughed about it and he
says, "I'm working on it. I'm working on
it. I got a home gym now." And and
whatever. But the you know, he was the
thing that killed me about Jimmy is
besides loving him and and thinking that
he was the greatest sparring partner I
ever had, um he was a decade younger
than me. Yeah. A decade younger. And I
was like, "Wow, if that can, you know,
if if you can pass like that in in a
minute, well, then it can happen to to
me. It can happen to anybody." And a lot
of times it's the sadness in our lives
that lead us to do things like
medicating with food. You've had sad
times in your life. In fact, you
describe some of the circumstances in
the book. Could you help everyone
understand what was going on as you
gained weight, as you were doing the
things that were unhealthy for you?
Well, you know, my parents started to
fail and they were both 84. They are and
they were never healthy and they never
did anything that they should have done
uh o over the years. And I swore on my
life when we buried them that I was
going to do everything to get my health
back and I'm going to go down fighting.
Yeah. Come back for a second. I'm going
to take you a little journey.
Uh, this is a picture of you, a very
different version of Lorraine. When you
see this, Lorraine, you see this? Yeah.
What's going on? Describe that person to
me.
Well, unaware.
Unaware. Unaware of her health and her
weight. So, how did this woman become
this woman?
I I wanted to live the third part of my
life in in a in a big way. Not in a
little way. Not in a sick way, not in a
in a way where where I didn't have any
energy. I'm I'm a grandmother. Oh, I
love that. I love that.
And I know you are also. And I'm a
grandfather. I Well, yes. Yes. I've
noticed. Come sit down. It feels good to
be a grandparent. Yes, it's special. But
boy, you got to have energy for them.
That little thing is around the corner
and back before I can turn around. So,
you have lots of tips in the book, very
helpful anti-aging tips, but the one
that really caught my eye was to don't
was to avoid being invisible. In fact,
the tip is don't be invisible. Well, the
truth of the matter is is I think a lot
of women who are 50 or or older feel
that they're no longer as powerful as
they were. And I happen to disagree with
that because I think we are smarter,
wiser. I think we should run the world.
I
think I
mean we are the caregivers of the world.
We are the the the ones that give birth.
We we do incredible things. And to get
to a certain age and I think menopause
is is is something that women dread. And
I don't think that should be dreaded. I
think it has to be embraced like like
everything God has given us. So as all
this emotion happens in our lives, a lot
of us turn to emotional eating. You did.
That's part of how you got there. Sure.
How do you recover from that? It's not
just a long-term motivation. There
tactical things you have to deal with
when you want to overcome emotional
eating. Okay. Here's my trick. All
right. Oh, pay attention. Now, the trick
for emotional eating. The trick is is I
will look at a piece of cake that I
really, really, really want or I will
look at a bowl of berries and I will say
to myself, well, I really want that
piece of cake and I could eat that and I
could probably eat another piece after
that, but what are you going to give me?
Are you going to give me any nutritional
value? And the answer is most of the
time, no. I want that bag of potato
chips. I really do. But you know what? I
look at my berries and I go, "Ooh,
antioxidants."
They're whispering to you. They they
they talk to me. She's the berry
whisperer. And And you know what? I make
my decisions that way. Now, listen. I'm
I'm not a crazy person. I still eat a
lot of things,
but I on a daily basis turn around and
say I'm gonna have a protein, a veggie,
and fruit. And I'm proud of you. And you
also like to exercise. So, I've saved
this for the end. I want you to
demonstrate exercise. I never said I
like it. Oh, I misinterpreted. No, no,
let's get extreme. I misqued the
book. Come on over here. Show me what
you do. You don't like it. What do you
like?
Well, I like to move and I think moving
is important, especially if you want
energy. I want energy. That's my whole
thing. I'm taking my high heels off. I
like this. We can go dancing now.
Perfect. Boy, we could get in trouble.
Yes, we could. Now that you're free,
demonstrate. This is Lorraine's favorite
activity to teach us today. This is a
30day plank challenge. That's correct.
So, I think this is really hard because
it works your entire body. You're coming
down. I'm coming down with you. Yep. Go,
Dr. Ar. I'm going. All right, we're
getting in PL. Regular plank. Look at
you. You know it. So,
ready? Look at that posture. That's Look
at that form.
Look at that tushy.
All right. Now, how do you do this the
first day? This can be hard to do. It's
very hard to do. Very hard to do. I
agree. So the thing is is no matter
where you are in your life, you can do
this for 5 seconds. Yep. Do it for 5
seconds. The next day do it for 10. Do
it for 20 and fight it. I mean, my whole
body is shaking. Okay. But you know
what? I'm going to I'm going to fight
through it. See how stable you are? Oh,
she's like a rock. Oh my goodness. You
cannot tell. She is not invisible today.
Lorraco, where are you going? I'm I'm
I'm going to do a child's pose so I can
knock you over. The R's book to the
fullest is available now. Check it out.
It's well very well done. You can also
see Lorraine on Resilient Isles on TNT.
We'll be right back.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good