Today, the latest revelations into a
health alert we were the first to raise
the red flag about. Five years ago, we
asked the FDA to release information
about the long-term effects of
corrective laser eye surgeries, which
they did. Now, we're investigating the
disturbing link between suicide and
these eye procedures, these surgeries
that promise to make your vision go from
this
to this,
but is leaving some people seeing this
and in constant crippling pain. In a
recently claimed the life of a beloved
meteorologist who took her own life two
months after the surgery,
I am struggling a little bit. So, I do
still need all the prayers and the well
wishes cuz it's uh this is a hard go.
The doctor said it could take up to 3
months or so before I feel like 100%
again.
That's beloved Detroit meteorologist
Jessica Star sharing the pain she was in
after complications from a newer LASIC
type surgery. Jessica struggled with
poor eyesight all her life. And after
the surgery, the mother of two tweeted
that her recovery was a struggle and a
challenging time. Jessica never
recovered. Last December, she took her
own life. Her death has raised questions
about the disturbing link between laser
eye surgeries and suicide as more cases
emerge. In October, Canadian TV reported
Paul Fitzpatrick, father of two, took
his own life, blaming the laser eye
surgery he went through back in 1996.
In a suicide note, he wrote, "Since
1996, pain, pain, and more pain. Please
forgive me for not being strong enough
to cope. The past few months have been
unbearable."
Every year, about 600,000 people get
LASIK. Many lured by the ads. But a new
FDA study revealed LASIC risks were
higher than some originally thought.
If you type into Google LASIC
complications,
you'll get pages and pages. You can
never predict when an eye is going to go
wrong after LASIC. Here's what can go
wrong. Patients may achieve 2020 vision
on an eye chart, but be seeing that
chart in double or seeing halos or
starbursts, especially at night. And the
most concerning problem of all, dry eye
pain. so severe that some people have
committed suicide.
All he would talk about was his eye pain
in his eyes and how he couldn't live
that way and it eventually cost him his
life.
In past investigations, we went
undercover to see what LASIC centers
tell patients in person. Could I really
toss away my glasses like the ads say?
You can. Yes, sir. Use 15 minutes. Right
after that, you can you don't need the
glasses at all. We have the technology
to uh get rid of reading glasses and
distance glasses. Really? It's pretty uh
foolproof at this point. And when we
asked about side effects, the LASIC
specialists downplayed them. Are the dry
eyes temporary? It is. It's not that
common. I would say have probably less
than 5% of the population. I shouldn't
worry about the night vision.
Okay. Never want to say zero, but it's
certainly less than 1% chance.
Today, what do you need to know about
laser eye surgery?
[Applause]
Joining us are Sarah, who wish she'd
never had eye surgery 3 years ago, and
Paula, a patient turd advocate, who says
LASIC destroyed her eyesight and left
her with chronic pain. We're going to
start with Sarah. Why did you decide to
get the LASIC procedure? It was pretty
simple for me. I just wanted to wake up
and be able to see without glasses and
contacts. So, a few weeks after the
operation, you started experiencing some
symptoms. Yes. Right after the
operation, um I could see I could see
2020. I still do. But I immediately had
dry eye. It just kept getting worse and
worse. Um it eventually turned into uh
corneal neuralgia, which is basically
nerve damage, nerve pain. Um so I take
something every day for the pain. Um I
put in eye drops eight times a day for
the past three years. So, it's important
to know some of the risks of LASIC.
There's the dry eyes and the pain that
Sarah just described. There's also
visual aberrations like seeing double
which looks like this, right? Or glares.
And glares again like looking at the
sun, but it's not really the sun causing
this. There's halos, so you'll see
little rings around lights. And then
there's starbursts, which are especially
problematic if you're driving. Sir, were
you informed of any of these risks? I
remember when I was reading my consent
form, it said something like 1% chance
patients get dry eyes and then it listed
the things you just listed, but I had no
idea what that was. The 1% complication
rate, which was also in that little tape
piece said to us by a doctor, is what I
had always heard as well. Mhm. We're
going to challenge that number for good
reason. I think I don't think anyone
really believes that number anymore. No.
But the issue that really got my
attention was the pain that has led to
we believe suicides and life destroying
challenges. How bad is your pain bid?
It's really hard to explain if you don't
have it, but it's this burning deep
intense pain. It's kind of like there's
like a toothache in your eye and it it's
not something anybody would want to live
with. I understand you've considered
some drastic measures because of it. I
completely understand um someone wanting
to kill themselves over it because when
I was at my worst um I I told myself if
if I don't get better, if I don't find a
way to get rid of this pain, I I don't
want to live anymore. How can someone
live like that?
So, you're not the only person we spoke
to. Obviously, we spoke to a lot of
folks. Others have experienced the same
excruciating pain. One woman we spoke to
lost her eye as a result of this
surgery. And I want to get Paul into
this conversation. And you had your
lasacic surgery 18 years ago. That's
right. And you've been living with
long-term side effects from that
procedure.
That's correct. Let's start with your
vision. Is it 2020? My vision,
if you if I sat down and looked at an
eye chart in a doctor's office, I might
be able to make out the 2030 line with
both eyes open. But my vision was a
complete train wreck. Massive starburst,
halos, multiple images. I could look up
at the moon at night and see up to eight
smeared overlapping moons with a massive
halo around the whole thing. It was just
ghastly and that was considered as a
success.
And were you warned at all about these
complications? I was given a one single
sheet consent form front and back and it
listed a lot of different complications
that could arise but it never said
anything about permanent chronic. Those
words were not used. Everything was
dismissed as temporary side effects.
It'll get better. Give it time. No one
ever told me that I could be visually
disabled for life. So, what do you want
people watching right now to know about
what you went through? I want people to
understand this surgery is not as safe
as it is portrayed. It is not like going
to get a manicure or or a haircut. It's
a dangerous surgery. It's a risky
surgery. It's it's one it's an
inherently harmful surgery. I wish
people understood that. All right. So,
when we come back, our investigation
continues. Do we know enough about the
risks of the surgery and the suicides
that we're reading about? Are
complications from this popular surgery
more common than we thought? The dry
eyes that you get from LASIK, they don't
go away. I'm 19 years posttop and I
still have horrible headaches, dry eye
pain. I spend so much money on eye
drops, ointments, supplements, anything
to just make the pain stop. We are back
investigating the disturbing emerging
link between laser eye surgeries and big
complications that sometimes result in
suicide. Do we know enough about the
long-term side effects of the world's
most popular elective surgery?
Opthalmologist Dr. Yun Rapaort joins us.
She not only performs LASIC, she had the
procedure done on her own eyes. That was
important for me because a lot of
doctors haven't had it done themselves
and you took that step. What do you and
you know some opthalmologists are
reporting very low incidences of
complications but we're hearing more and
more studies reports of people having
big problems again in these suicides.
What do you make of these? Yeah, I mean
suicide is definitely a very serious and
devastating issue and it's under
discussed in society in general. Uh
those patients who committed suicide,
their families definitely deserve a
voice. they were unhappy with their
outcome and they had severe pain and
issues that led to that. Uh I think that
as physicians we want to hear from these
patients because our role as physicians
is to care for patients, optimize
outcomes and treat complications.
And um in some of the studies they found
that patients didn't report all their
complications to to their physician. So,
I think the takeaway message for me is I
would want to know if any of my patients
were experiencing things that were so
unbearable that that led to these. That
might explain part of the gap. Uh, we've
been talking to people, you've been
hearing people complain quite loudly
about the fact they had complications
far beyond what they expected. So if if
you can explain to us LASIC which I know
is just maybe half of all the total
corrective procedures that are done so
people get an idea of what's going on
and maybe when you do this you can
explain why some of these complications
especially the dry eyes and nerve damage
are happening. Sure. So uh LASIC is just
one of many types of refractive
corrective procedures but it is the most
common. So in LASIC a laser creates a
flap about so you actually cut into the
cornea here. It's created with a laser,
right? Not no blade. And then it's
lifted. That flap is about 100 110
microns. The flap is lifted. The laser
then ablates or changes the shape of the
cornea right here, the surface. I'm
sorry. That laser is is shaving off tiny
bits of a half a millimeter thickness
material, even microns. Tiny tiny tiny.
So, it shaves it and it's custom uh
performed to the patient's prescription.
Um so everything is custom done and then
the flap is put back down. So that is
what LASIC is. Whenever you lift the
flap you are going through corial nerves
and for some patients that does result
in worsening dry eye and corial damage
later on. So when we first heard about
the complications of LASIC the industry
said it was a complication rate of less
than 1%. That's what I was told and it
seemed surprising to me because I was
hearing about it so much. I thought
maybe I spoke to everyone who had a
complication. But when we looked at the
published reports, the actual incidence
was about 20%. Now, since we did our
first show, the FDA did a clinical
trial, and here's what they found. Most
people who had visual problems prior to
LASIC actually improved after the
surgery. So, that part seems to be
pretty pretty good and legitimate. The
vast majority of folks are pleased with
results, but this is a big butt. About
30 to 40% of people without problems to
start with reported problems 3 months
after lasic surgery. So let's walk over
and join our two women who've had
unsuccessful lasic surgery. If
epthalmologist quoted a complication
rate or a side effect rate for let's say
three months, is the right number 20%.
They don't report it accurately. I'm
sure that I'm a a success in where I
went and got my surgery because I can
see 2020 and they don't the dry eye was
just a side effect. It's not taken
seriously. I don't So you're both
success stories then? Yes.
I I can tell you they use what I call
fuzzy LASIC math to get these numbers.
So reached out to the FDA for comment
and here's what they said in part. The
FDA's work with LASIC is ongoing. We are
also in the process of developing a
LASIC patient labeling guidance that
will provide recommendations to industry
about how to clearly communicate risks
of LASIC to patients. The Academy of
Opthalmology says LASIC is not for
everyone. They agree with what you're
saying and we reached out for a
statement. Here's what they said in
part. The risks of LASIC surgery are
known to the opthalmology community.
More than 300 peer-reviewed studies have
shown that on average 95% of patients
are satisfied with their outcome after
lasic surgery. But the FDA study found
that 30 to 40% of people without
problems start to report problems after
the lasacic surgery. So, Dr. Rapour, how
do you reconcile those numbers? How can
95% of people be happy but 30 to 40% are
reporting complications? Those are
short-term statistics. one month, three
months, no more than six months. They
want you to look at shortterm
satisfaction. They don't want you to
look at long-term safety and efficacy.
They want you to look at short term. You
agree, Dr. Apport? I agree. I think um
the point is that this is one snapshot
in time uh that they conducted in
questionnaires. It'd be interesting to
see the statistics at a year, at five
years, at 10 years. Dr. Ratport, thank
you very much. I really appreciate you
spending time with us today. I know it's
been a very difficult road for you. I
wish you the best. Thank Thank you.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good