[Applause]
Are you exhausted every day even though
you try to get enough sleep and eat the
right foods? Well, it turns out your
favorite health foods may actually be
causing your fatigue. And one of these
sneaky sleepy foods is actually one of
my favorite snacks of all. My audience
doesn't know this, but earlier we had a
yawn cam to capture some unsuspecting
sleepy people. Take a look at these
yawners. Here's the audience. There they
are. Oh my goodness. Oh my. Oh my. There
they are. Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh.
This is before the show in the holding
area. Well, they happen to be sitting
next to each other here. What happened
here? Are you tired? Oh, yes. Um, I
caught the 6:40 a.m. train and I haven't
eaten yet. So, I'm Yeah, I keep on
yawning. Same thing. And I had a half a
cup of fiber cereal for breakfast, which
has not really filled me up. So, we got
hunger, we got early awakening. Are you
big yawners in general?
When you when I start, I can't stop. How
about that? And you think you eat well
generally? Yeah, you do. Yes. All right.
Give me your names real quick. Carly.
Carly. Melanie. Carly and Melanie. I
want you to be part of my bite club
today. Okay. Awesome. There's a table
over here. I'm going to have you taste
solutions because I'm going to show you
some things you guys and others are
eating and drinking to get yourselves in
the right place. But actually, I'm doing
the opposite. All right. Sounds good.
Awesome. Let's see the bite table. Okay.
Let's bring in nutritionist JJ Smith to
unmask the biggest sneaky seepy foods.
The first one is what many would think
is your go-to onthe-go food. It's the
healthiest thing out there for most
people. It's your morning smoothie.
They're dominating the the country.
They're all over the place. But some
people, they just don't feel good. They
feel tired the rest of the day. Mhm.
Well, you know, I love green smoothies
for breakfast. However, when you buy
storebought or you kind of get a green
uh a smoothie on the go, you're going to
get a lot of additives. You're going to
get loaded sugar. I mean, let's look at
this one. It has 68 gram of sugar. Gosh,
this is pineapple juice. You know,
that's just loaded with sugar. And when
you without the fiber? Yeah. Without the
fiber. And so when you drink a uh when
you drink a smoothie like this, it's
going to cause you to have energy dips.
You think you're getting all these
healthy nutrients, but you're getting a
lot of sugar and you won't feel
energized throughout the day. So, we put
it to the test. We actually did got a
timeline of a smoothie from one of our
viewers, Asha. We asked her to take a
photo diary of her energy throughout the
day. So, here she is drinking the
smoothie, right? Hot. Look at her.
Peppy, ready to go. Lots of energy
there. Then two hours later, with the
evidence, by the way. Right, she's ready
for a nap. Right. So, you're the queen
of smoothies. You You got more smoothies
up your sleeve than anyone I've ever
met. You know, I'm about that green
smoothie life. And so, I actually uh
pulled a recipe that is actually all
natural ingredients. It has low sugar
fruit. It has pears, which is only 19
grams of sugar. You're It's going to be
delightful, too. And it has, see the
difference with that one is this has
greens which will slow the absorption of
sugars. It has some mint. It has some
ginger. Is this water? Yes, that's
water. I was say it's just the the right
amount of sweetness, right? Not too
sweet, but just enough to give you
energy without causing you to have those
crashes because the ingredients,
particularly the fiber and the greens,
will slow the absorption of sugars. So,
you'll stay, you know, you'll keep that
pep in your step all day long. Yeah. You
know, I've got my Spike Club members
over there. So, do you agree with me? Do
you think it's the right amount of
sweet? It's perfect.
Oh, yes. This mint, like, it's so light.
It's not like a regular smoothie. It
tanalize your taste buds without having
to explode sugar in your mouth because
you can do this all day long. Okay,
absolutely. Let's move on. Okay, next
sleepy, surprising food. Surprised
you've been made. Did not expect it.
Humus. I grew up with this stuff. I love
it. One of my favorite snacks of all
time. Surprise. And yet, it makes us
want to take a nap. Yeah. Well, hummus
um provides protein for energy, but not
as much as we think. And so when you're
eating uh hummus, you get um it also
provides elptophen. Yes. And what that
does is causes us to raise the levels of
melatonin in the bread in the brain,
which can make us feel sleepy. That's
what turkey has in it. Yeah. And think
about it, when we eat hummus, we often
use pretzels, we use pita bread, more
sleepy carbs that make us feel very
tired and sleepy. So you have a hat. I
got a better alternative, Dr. Oz. So
this is a very simple threeingredient
alternative. Greek yogurt,
peanut butter, and vanilla extract. And
when you combine these together,
right? You like Okay. This is like lick
your fingers good though, right? Very
good. It's a great alternative. I It's
surprising. Peanut butter and yogurt. I
don't know why we haven't done it
earlier. I know. is such a good protein
power punch that will help you stay
energized all day as well. Michael, keep
us honest. Your thoughts on this? It's
like a fluff nutter. I love it. I love
fluffern nutter. It's like fluff nutter.
Did I hear love? They love it. Yeah,
this is my favorite. Definitely. It's
light and I I just love that it kind of
tastes like a cream cheese because it's
so like light, but it's lighter. The
texture, the mouth feels light. I love
All right, next got a seafood here that
a lot of people think is it's part of
their their foundation for health is
tuna fish. How's that possible? It's
another food with with tryptophan in it.
Yeah, I know. And also eating tuna, it
has high amounts of vitamin B6 which
will all also cause us to produce
melatonin. Yeah. So, if you're going to
do tuna as a protein punch, you got to
do some lettuce wraps. Looks how look
how divine this looks, right? But when
you use lettuce wraps, it's a much
better alternative. Fight Club. What do
you guys think of these things? I love
the combination of the tuna and the
lettuce. I need a good way to put those
two together. Very light. It's perfect.
And this is crunchy. Like I feel
something crunchy in there and that
makes it so good. We love crunchy.
What's your favorite one so far?
Oh, like this. I like the tuna in there.
Tuna lettuce. Yeah. Ah, it's it's it's a
tie. But this this has got pear in it,
right? Yes. Well, Dr. Oz, it is very
good. I can tell you that. It's a minty
pear power smoothie. You know what? I'm
gonna take the Greek yogurt with the
peanut butter, but they're also darn
good. You're gonna get a ton no matter
where you wonderful advice as always.
You can find those recipes on dr.com. Up
next, it's a quiz to find the perfect
DIY all naturatural energy drink
customized for you. Even better, they're
only two ingredients. Just two
ingredients. Stick around. Today, a quiz
to help you find the perfect natural
energy drink just for you. Even better,
these energy drinks only need two
ingredients. Nutritionist JJ Smith is
back to help break it down. Everyone,
please follow along. Keep track of your
answers. So, you can find this quiz on
drraz.com. JJ, the first question is
Question number one. When I wake up in
the morning, I feel Well, do you feel
like you need to be dragged out of bed
or you're like a zombie? Right. These
are the bees. And if you're a C, you're
look at this. You're so perked up.
You're ready to go. Don't you hate
people like that? I do. Right. All
right. So, those are the three options.
Okay, JJ. Next question. Okay, question
number two. During the afternoon, I am
Are you a starting to gain momentum?
Remember, you couldn't get out of bed in
the beginning. You had the pillows over
your head. Now you sort of get you're
going. The A's feel that way. The B's,
you're still like a zombie, right? I
spar you the picture this time. And the
C's, you know, you were so tripper early
in the morning, but you now you're
exhausted. Someone tucked me into bed
already. That's how you feel. All right,
last question in the quiz. It is JJ.
Question number three. In the evening,
when I look back on my day, my energy
looks like A, an airplane. Take it off.
It started slow, right, in the morning.
Couldn't get out of bed, but right now
you're picking up speed. You're going to
keep going. Or are you B,
the zombie? You're still the zombie.
You've been the zombie the whole darn
day, right? Or C, your phone battery,
right? It's like that's like you. It was
100% in the morning when you got up,
chipper, ready to go. But now in the
evening, it's down to 5%. you getting
alarms and you know people aren't happy
with you, right? So, tally up your
letters, A's, B's or C's. Okay, JJ, you
got solutions for us for the A's. Mostly
A's out there. These are the slow to
rise people, right? What do they ought
to do? Okay, the mostly A's. These are
the people who need a boost first thing
in the morning as soon as they wake up.
So, what we have for them is the Green
Monster morning shot. Oh, I like that.
You like it? Yes. And remember, these
are two ingredients. So, it's simply
matcha powder and almond milk. What
we're going to do is basically pour some
almond milk. Okay. We're going to put
some almond milk. You're going to put in
the matcha powder. And this is a little
martini glass. How many people know
about martinis?
And you just basically mix it up like
this. I I can see you doing martini. So,
over the shoulder like this, right?
Stir. You don't want to get too cute
with it. You know what I'm saying? Yeah.
And then basically you pour it and you
know you turn up. You drink it like a
shot just like you would a shot
anywhere.
Where's the a mostly a I want to have a
mostly a come on down lady in blue. Come
on down. Now I you you identify with
A's? I do. All right. You want to taste
this with me? I would love to. We're
going to do it in our own unique way
though. We're going to do it with a
shotski. Are you ready? Okay. Don't
spill this. Don't spill it. No. You got
it. On on three. One. Got to drink the
whole thing. Okay. Okay. Have you ever
done this before? No. All right. You
break? I I'm not admitting to it. Are
you awake yet? You're one of the eight.
No, I need this apparently. One, two,
three.
Wow. Did you like it? Absolutely. You
taste the green tea a little bit. Taste
the green tea. It's refreshing. Nice. I
like it. And the coconut deserves the
deal. Well, she knows that. She's a
master with two ingredients. Makes it
fantastic. Here's a little gift from the
show. Oh, thank you so much. I'm
kidding. Oh, apparently. All right. Next
up, what if you're mostly bees? Do you
known as the zombies?
Zombies. What do you do? Okay, this the
mostly bees. They are basically have no
energy from the time they wake up all
day long. So, we have a very simple
twoingredient drink for them. It has
chia seeds and it has coconut water. And
so, it's a really nice drink where you
get the chia seeds and and I like
coconut water because it keeps us
hydrated all throughout the day. So,
this is a fun one to drink as well. I
think it's brilliant. It'll also soothe
some of the angst of the zombies. Yes,
that's a great idea. Next, let's talk
about the seas. These are the people who
burn brightly but briefly. Yeah, the
mostly seas. Okay, you know, they're the
ones that need a little boost in the
afternoon. 2 3:00. How many people need
a nap? Those are the seas. So, what we
have for them is the flying inner bee
drink. And this is inner bee. This is
simply iced ginger tea and honey. What's
that? How can I see who are the seeds
out there? Where are seeds? You keep
talking over there, J. Why I like this
drink? It has ginger tea in it. And what
ginger is going to do is reduce
inflammation, but it's going to improve
blood circulation. It's going to improve
your blood sugar levels, keep you very
energized. And how about the honey? The
honey is going to have fructose. And
when you have fructose, it gives you
that boost of energy right away. We do
we have happy customers here? People
taste like them. Yes. Yes. Well, they
use them all up and they're happy. All
right. All these recipes everybody on
josh.com. JJ, thank you as always.
Absolutely. We'll be right back,
everybody. Thank you for watching. Don't
forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good