Pre-marinated meat is quick and full of
flavor, which makes putting dinner on
the table that much easier. But is it
safe to eat, or will you be sorry you
took the shortcut? We're kind of paying
for a lot of stuff that really we're not
going to be able to eat. Plus, a food
investigation. How does it spread? How
do they melt? How do they taste? Is
there a better butter? Buttery spreads
and spreadable butter, they couldn't be
more different. There's a difference.
There's a huge difference. Coming up
next.
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
[Music]
I love you back.
[Applause]
When it comes to supermarket stuff,
convenience is king. That's why I know
so many of you love to buy pre-marinated
meats. Now, besides the cooking, right,
all the prep work is done for you, which
makes putting dinner on the table that
much easier. But our grocery store
pre-marinated meats safe to eat or you
end up being sorry you took the
shortcut. I've asked several audience
member to participate in this. Tamara
and her husband Mike are here. They are
at odds over pre-marinated meats.
And it's the only meat that Mike will
buy. But Tamara, you've got some
concerns. So, why do you love it so
much? I like pre- marinated meat
basically cuz uh I can come home, I can
pop it in the oven, I can put it on the
grill. I can I mean, it's already done
for me. It tastes even a guy could do
it. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Tammy, you're
unsure about these. What's What gives? I
kind of feel like it's not going to be
as healthy as just regular meat. I know
exactly what's going in it if I'm
putting my own seasonings on it. Lot of
wisdom to what women say. You probably
learned that. Absolutely. Yeah. You'll
get the lesson if you haven't yet. All
right. Here's why. I got some experts
here. We'll help figure this out. This
is something I've been looking at a lot.
I think we can actually open it up a
little bit. So, to bottom to to a bigger
light, award-winning chef Sheamus Mullen
is here, and Sheamus has built his
career around sourcing the very best and
sustainable meats. So, break it down for
us. Welcome to the show. Good to see
you. Good to see you. So, you saw Tar
Mike there struggling. When it says
pre-marinated like this does, what does
it mean? And what does it mean if you
get it from the butcher that way? So,
they're basically when we're talking
about marinades, we're talking about two
different things. Either you go to the
supermarket and you get something from
the butcher that they've made and
prepared for you or you get something
that's pre-marinated that's packaged
from the manufacturer. The difference
mainly is that you kind of have a better
sense of what's going into this. There's
nutrition facts on the back of this, you
know, tell you exactly what's in there.
So, those are the two kinds of marinade
meats we're talking about. See, I
thought the butcher in the store made
this. This is from a a company. This is
going to come directly from the
manufacturer. Okay. So, break down
marination for us. What does it all mean
to you? So, when we're marinating,
there's basically two things that we're
talking about. We're talking about uh
enhancing the flavor. So that'll come
from different flavoring agents and then
tenderizing the meat. Those are the two
elements that we're talking about.
Flavorizing and tenderizing. All right.
So we asked all of you at home what
kinds of concerns you had about
pre-marinated meat. Maria on Facebook
asks, "My supermarket charges more per
marinated meat per pound. Is this extra
charge worth it?" It's a good question.
Very good question. There is some liquid
in this thing. Oh yeah, there's quite a
bit of liquid. So when we're talking
about meat, we're actually talking about
a significant amount of liquid in the
meat already. But now here we have a
piece of chicken breast. If you look at
it, weighs about what do we have there?
Uh 6 oz. almost 7 oz. Yeah. So, we've
got that and then we've got the same
breast which weighed the same amount.
Now, it's in a marinade. We're going to
put it on and you're going to see this
is good. 9 oz. So, 3 o 10 o. Yeah. So,
we're almost at 10 ounces. So, about 4
ounces more. And that's all water
essentially. So, we're kind of paying
for a lot of stuff that really we're not
going to be able to eat and get much out
of. Mike, did you hear that?
Paying a lot of money. Wasted money. All
right. All right, so Linda asked via
Twitter, "Did I heard two of Marcus
marinate old meat they can't sell to
mask the smell? Is that true?" I decided
to go straight to the source to figure
this one out. Not just a butcher, but
someone I consider the butcher. James
Perk
is the co-founder of Porter Road, a
butcher shop that makes some of the
country's highest quality meats
available to people nationwide. So is
it, you know, it concerns the doctor
that you might get sick for meat? That
question comes up a lot. Could that
really happen?
You can always get sick from things you
are eating. That is true. Um, and the
myth of are we masking something with
the marinade? Yes, that is true. But
nobody's going to sell you rotten meat
knowingly. It's bad for business. It's
not going to work out very well in the
long run. Um, but what they are masking
is oxidation, a little bit of
colorization. Nothing that's going to
harm the flavor or you as a consumer.
So, you would feed it to your family, I
gather. Absolutely. Absolutely. And a
lot of the times marination, uh, what
they're trying to do, like I said, is
just color cover up a little bit of
oxidation because like I said before, if
your consumer gets sick, they're not
coming back to you. Tam, you hear that?
You're worried about nothing. Listen to
the man. All right. Thank you, James.
You're wrecked via Facebook, are
pre-marinated meats basically a sodium
bath? How unhealthy are they? So, what
is the deal with the amount of sodium in
these marinades? This is a really,
really great question. And in fact, uh,
Cooking Light did an experiment where
they took a turkey, they took three
turkeys, and they, um, they they brine
them for 12 hours, for 18 hours, and for
24 hours with a half a cup of kosher
salt, which is a lot of sodium. You
know, that's a significant amount of
sodium. But what they found was that
after 12 hours, the sodium content
actually only gone up by 1%. And then
after that, it didn't go up anymore. So,
what ended up happening in the the
subsequent hours, in the 18 and then in
the 24 hours, is you got a more tender
turkey, but no more sodium. So, it's not
actually as bad as you might think. I'm
surprised it's only 1%. Only one%. I
looked at the salt content. I'll tell
you the bigger issue when when I know
this is to make sure you're looking for
sugar in the marin. Exactly. That's
especially if you're doing keto, it can
sabotage everything. It would actually
come along with the sugar this time.
Absolutely. All right. Next thing we
want to know about curious about is how
much does marinating change the flavor
and how long do you really have to
marinade in order to get the effects? To
put this to the test, we're going to do
a little marinating science here. I
brought in someone who really tastes the
nuances of flavor. A professional taste
tester. That's what she does for a
living. Professional taste testing. Ivy
Kolicker from Century Spectrum. Before
we get to all this. Yes. I mean, do you
study to become a taste tester? How how
does that work? Are you gifted with
incredible taste buds? Sure. So, I have
a background in food science and we go
through a lot of training and have a lot
of education, practice, and experience
to be able to describe the
characteristics of food. So, it's not
that I can taste better than you can.
It's that I have more words to describe
the flavor and the texture. So, we could
taste what you taste. Yes, absolutely.
Give me some words I should be using
next time I go to a meal to impress my
wife. Sure. So, if you want to talk
about the texture, which a lot of people
have trouble talking about, you can
start thinking about how the food is
kind of chewing down in your mouth. Is
it soft? Is it tough? Is it fibrous? Is
it mealy? Is it very moist and juicy? Or
is it very dry? Hopefully not dry. If
you're eating something moist and juicy
is good. And the full compression fiber
length that comes up sometimes.
Absolutely. Absolutely. And we'll see
that here with the chicken. I'm going to
seem so smart next time I go out. We set
up a taste experiment and one that's
very practical for all of us to know
about. We marinated chicken, right, for
three different time intervals. There's
30 minutes, there's 2 hours, and then
there's the overnight, you know, if
you're really prepared in life. So, how
much did the time it was marinated
actually change the flavor? I I'm going
leave it to you as the expert. Give us
your professional assessment. You have
tasted them all. So, you were talking
about flavor and texture changes from
the marinade. So, in my tasting, what I
saw is the 30inut meat had the most
chicken flavor and the least amount of
marinade flavor and also had a tougher
and more fibrous texture. So, some of
those longer, more stringy fibers um and
took more chews to kind of break down in
the mouth before you wanted to swallow
it. At 2 hours, I didn't see a huge
change in texture, but I did see an
increase in the marinade flavor and a
decrease in the chicken flavor coming
through. So, if you still like some of
that kind of more meaty texture and you
want a little more flavor, I would
recommend the 2hour. Um, at the
overnight, I definitely saw a big change
in the texture. It's much softer, much
easier to bite through. The muscle
fibers break down into kind of shorter
pieces, so it's a little bit easier to
chew. You can chew it up more quickly,
and it by far had the most flavor of the
three. So, it really is customized to
what you want. They're all fine.
Absolutely. But I can offer one thought
as a physician on this. I do think
marinating makes sense because it
reduces some of these cancer-causing
compounds that you make when you heat up
meat. So marinated to keep the outside a
little cooler to avoid some of those
products. Okay, great. Right. We all
benefit from this. Thank you. Cheers,
come over here. She says that
pre-marinated typically means over
marinated. So how do you over marinate
meat? So first let's talk about flavor.
First of all, you're going to the
molecules of a lot of the flavoring
agents are too big to actually go into
the meat. they're going to bounce off
the meat after a long period of time.
But when it comes to the salt and acid,
once they get in there, they can change
the texture. The salt will toughen it
up, give it sort of like a ham texture,
and the acid will start to break down
the fibers and make it mushy. So, if
you're letting it go for too long,
you're not getting any more flavor
benefits, and you're changing uh the
texture to a negative texture. So, how
much is too long in your opinion? In my
opinion, if you go over 24 hours, it's
too long, right? So, you all got your
rules of thumb now. Keeping keeping them
in mind from an expert. When you come
back, we're going to break down the
science behind the best marriage that
you can do at home. It has only four
ingredients and it takes less than an
hour. Stay with us.
[Applause]
A trail of unsolved murders in
California. Now 50 years later, can DNA
evidence track down the Zodiac Killer?
We can take these crime cases that have
haunted us for decades and actually
solve them. Plus, a medical error ended
this innocent 2-year-old's life. What
you're supposed to get, what was
actually given, it was tragic. Now the
family comes face to face with the man
that made this deadly mistake. All new
Oz.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
If you want the most tender, succulent,
juicy marinated meat without putting in
the time listen up because we're going
to reveal the science behind what makes
the very best marinade that can be done
in under an hour. Meat expert and
renowned chef Sheamus Mullen is back
with us. So, what what cuts of meat
benefit the most from marination? So,
here's the deal. Meat is mostly water.
So, if you think of meat like a sponge,
we've got a sponge here. If it's soaked
with water, you can't really absorb more
water. You can't clean up a mess. We
want to look for small, thin, thin
strips of meat. Those will it's more
like a surface treatment. So, just
include. So, this is this is what a big
big piece of meat. Exactly. It's not
going to absorb much more of the
marinade, but a thin piece like, you
know, a thin piece of meat is a is going
to give a nice uh surface treatment. So,
what we did to show this, it's pretty
interesting. We took a nice, really
plump piece of chicken, and we've
marinated overnight in a marinade that's
got some blue uh food dye in it, so we
can see just how far it penetrates into.
Talk about a world class chef. Doesn't
this look tasty? It looks amazing,
right, guys? Smurf food. Smurf food. So,
you left it overnight. The best that our
marinade would do normally. Exactly. So,
this is a 24-hour marinade. And what
we're going to see here is that
it really did not penetrate at all. It's
just on the surface of the meat. Yeah.
Pretty amazing. See that? That's
surprising. Actually, I thought a little
bit would get into the inside. Yeah, it
really is just on the outside. And if
you think of it, because there is so
much liquid inside, you just can't put
more liquid into it. All right. So, you
say you've got a little hack for us. One
that may actually allow us to penetrate
the meat a little better. Only four
ingredients. And if we are late like I
usually am in 1 hour, a guy could
actually help out at home and make this
happen. super easy. And as you know, Dr.
Oz, I'm a big fan of healthy food. This
is all stuff that's naturally
anti-inflammatory and it's very good for
gut health. So, what I've done is I've
got some papaya juice. Now, papaya is a
pre-colian fruit that has been used for
thousands of years to tenderize meats.
There's enzymes in papaya that help
break down the proteins. It's also
really, really good for uh digestive
enzymes for helping you break down your
food. Has anyone ever used papaya in a
marinade here?
Oh, we've got some papaya over there. In
Mexico. In Mexico. Exactly. Mexico. And
there's no spattering over here.
But that's I that's one handful out of
200 people here. I I this is I'd never
thought of it even, but it makes so much
sense because it gets into the meat. It
gets right into the meat. And if you
want to be really fancy, you can take
the seeds, dry them, and grind them up
and they get like a peppery spice them,
which is better. Show off your chef. I
know, but I love show off. So, what
we've got, we've got the papaya juice,
we've got some ground coriander seed, a
little bit of cayenne pepper for heat,
and then ginger, which is a natural
anti-inflammatory, and it's great for
gut health. So, we've got all that stuff
together. We'll just literally I put all
the dry ingredients here like that very
simply. And you can get to work on
mixing those in. I'm going to add in the
papaya juice. You can even just crush up
some fresh papaya, too. And then if you
want to make a sauce to go along with
it, some fresh papaya salsa is great.
And that's all it takes. We're going to
add that in. And then add your chicken
directly into that. So, grab that
chicken. That'll go in. And then this
can literally just go into the
refrigerator for half an hour before you
cook it. Because what happens is the
enzymes in the papaya, in all of the uh
the ingredients we've put in here, they
don't become activated until you heat
the chicken up. So between 140 and 175°
is when the enzymes are going to
actually start to break down the
chicken. So why bother marinating it for
even half an hour? That's not you're
going to some of the flavor is going to
impregnate. You're some of the flavor
from all these great ingredients. So you
will get a little bit of flavor from it.
I mean, significant amount of flavor.
Before I say anything, Tamar and Mike
are here. They have the finished
product. They've been bickering all show
long. How about this darn pre-marinade
stuff?
So Tamara, you've effectively won the
argument. Did you feel good about that?
I do. I feel great about that. It's a
nice feeling in it. I'm used to it. Used
to it, right? Absolutely. So what do you
think about this? Mine was very good.
It's a light flavor. It's not It's not
overpowering, but it's easy. It's easy
on the palette. So here's the deal. In
all seriousness, you listen to the show.
There's nothing wrong with buying
premarinated meat. You can do that. But
it seems to me that we've given some
pretty good reasons why you just make it
yourself. And if it tastes like this,
you've tasted it. Would you be willing
to do this instead of buying the
pre-marinated? I would because I love
chicken and I love to eat. You know, you
definitely can taste the flavors. It was
good. I would eat it again. Thanks all
for being here. Sheamus latest book is
called Real Food Heels. Look at him
walking around looking so healthy. We'll
be right back.
[Applause]
Up next, an investigation into the new
butters on the supermarket shelves
today, including the ones with healthier
oils added to make them more spreadable.
Are they really better? Find out when we
come back.
[Music]
Butter. We all love the way it spreads
on a warm piece of bread or how it melts
on an English muffin. You can just see
it right there. Right. Most of all, we
love how it tastes. That creamy, fatty
mouth feel is it's unmatched. But there
are so many butter alternatives in the
market today, including new ones with
healthier oils added to make them more
spreadable. Today, we're investigating.
Is there a better butter?
Once considered public enemy number one,
super delicious butter is working its
way back into the American household.
From traditional uses like on your toast
and in your cakes to more modern uses
like in your coffee and on top of your
oatmeal, Americans now eat almost 23
sticks a year. But the new market for
healthier butter alternatives is just as
rich with buttery spreads, spreadable
butters, and even avocado butter gaining
in popularity. Are they butters better
half? An important question when there's
no margarine for error.
James Beard, award-winning chef and
restaurant tour Michael Schlow, who has
shared his expertise on the Tonight's
Show, is here with a brand new food
investigation to help cut through the
clutter like a hot knife through through
butter.
Butter is back, everybody. It's big and
everyone loves it. And as a chef, Chef
Michael loves it. Where do you stand, by
the way, this butter renaissance? And
and what about these butter
alternatives? Well, butter being back, I
mean, as a chef, I never thought it went
away, to be honest with you. I always
thought it was around and I always loved
it. But, you know, as a as a dad, as a
husband, we're always thinking about
butter alternatives, like how can we eat
a little bit healthier. So, this was
exciting. I got to really experiment and
buy a bunch of different kinds and
explore and uh I've got a lot of
different results for you. So, these
better butters, what are they up
against? What are the qualities they've
got to mimic in order to win over a
butter lover like you? And me, too, by
the way. Well, I think you said it
earlier, you know, how does it spread?
You know, so that's the first thing. Is
it going to rip the bread? Cold butter
rips the bread.
These spreadables, are they are they
nice and smooth and creamy? You know,
how do they melt? Uh, I think that's
important also. But most important of
all is how do they taste? If they don't
taste good, we're not going to buy them.
All right. So, we assembled a group of
really purists. These are butter purists
who are looking to be buttered up by us.
Butter purists. I I like I like the
term. That was my uh my band in culinary
school. We were called the butter. Yeah,
that's what we called ourselves. These
are they're looking at better butters
here. They're going to be putting each
of the butters through a three-part
test. Adriana, your job is to check on
the spreadability. Yes. Does it rip the
bread or not? Ashley is manning the
melting torch. Let's see the torch. Oh,
look at that. Look at that. Look at her
go. She's She's hot. And Maggie is
cleansing her palette as we speak. She's
ready to taste. Little water, but not
for too long. Okay, we're going to check
in with you in a bit. Let's go over the
first group we're going to be looking
about are these spreadable butters,
right? And the spreadable butters are
made with vegetable oil, right? They
offer about half the saturated fat,
correct, of butter. So, there's real
butter in spreadable butter. Yes. And so
they do add some oil and there's some,
you know, aside from the saturated fats,
I mean, one of the the benefits, I
guess, is that it does spread easy right
out of the refrigerator. You don't have
to take it out and leave it on your
counter to spread easily. That's to me
one of the biggest um, you know,
advantages in using something like this.
Okay. Next, buttery spreads. These are a
little different. These are also made
with vegetable oil. So, I'm sorry. Well,
these are different for sure. Buttery
spreads and spreadable butter. I I you
know, when I started out on this
adventure, I didn't know what the
difference would be, and they couldn't
be more different. There's a difference.
There's a huge difference. Um, and we're
going to find out. And so, uh, the
buttery spreads don't have any butter at
all in them. They're all made from oil,
which is, you know, fine. Uh, some of
them even had yogurt, some of the ones
that I found, but I could tell you that
there's definitely no butter in the
buttery spreads. All right. Besides the
oils, which obviously have to make up
the difference. What else did you find?
Well, I found that, you know, butter
obviously has two ingredients. Has cream
and it has salt. and buttery spreads
have just a couple extra ingredients
added to them as well to give you that
mouth feel. And uh the science is lost
on me a little bit here, but there's a
lot going into this stuff. And how many
of you knew that a spreadable butter and
and buttery spread were different?
No one, right? Like one person up there.
Literally one person, the entire
audience, 200 people. Yeah. So if if if
these aren't butter, how are they
different? I mean, they sound like
they're margarine then. Well, similar.
But here's the deal is that butter and
margarine both have a regulation by the
USDA and they have to have 80% fat, but
with a buttery spread, there is no uh
there's no regulation on it at all. So,
it doesn't have to have 80%. Is less fat
a good thing? Well, it can be certainly.
I mean, it depends on diets and things
like that, but for flavor, I mean,
butter certainly has the highest fat and
it has the strongest flavor. I made
cookies uh with three different uh fats
to see the difference and see how they
would react differently. And definitely
the buttery spread had the a stranger
reaction is the way I could put it
compared to the butter cookie that I
knew. I made chocolate chip cookies and
I just thought, well, let's see it. Same
oven, same recipe, same quantities. So
one more time. So this you this is a
buttery spread, correct? Right. And that
had it was half and half and cookies
there. We're going to compare that. You
have margarine and margarine didn't have
a big change to the cookie. way. Uh this
one and you could see the color
difference even in just even the way
that spreads out um when you and these
were baked in the same oven, same time,
same exact recipe. And you made one with
butter. Yeah. And I think those look
kind of similar. The butter and the
margarine one. They look the same to you
guys. They look same to me. I'm going to
taste them right now. I'm going to taste
one of these babies. I'm going to
compare it to one of these buttery
spreads. But these are actually look
very different looking. They do. And and
the same amount of scoop. Like when I
when I was trying to measure them out,
it was the same scoop, same everything.
But they definitely bake differently. So
I'm going to taste this in a second. But
margarine has the same ratio of fat to
water as butter. Right. Correct. But
anyone ever wonder what happened to
margarine? We don't talk about it much
anymore. Take a look.
[Music]
Margarine received bad press for being
made with artificial ingredients and
artery clogging trans fats. But it has
been trying to make a comeback in the
last 10 years.
In fact, last June, the FDA made it
illegal to add trans fats to products,
and they are allowing companies until
January 2020 to completely eliminate
them from their labels. In the meantime,
here's how you can tell if your
margarine or butter alternative is trans
fat-free.
Check the label. Even if it says zero
trans fats, it can legally still contain
up to.5 g of trans fats.
So look for the words partially
hydrogenated on the ingredient list.
Also know that palm, soybean, and
vegetable oil all mean that there may be
trans fats in the product.
So I got I tasted these the the butter
and the margarine, right? And you know
they the spreadable butter. I think this
is crispy, crunchy. It's got better
mouth feel than the other one. Personal
belief. I I agree with you. It got a
little cakey almost is the word and a
little drier. But when it comes to
baking, definitely I think butter is
going to be better. From a James Beard
chef, we take his advice. Okay. Finally,
the newest kids in the block. Trendy
butters made with Are you ready? Boom.
Avocados
and coconuts.
These are blended with other oils. Often
times they may just have a little bit of
this in there, right? And they
definitely had when I tasted these,
there was some flavor that you could
were distinct, especially the coconut
one. All right, time for our test.
Butter lovers, did you find a better
butter? our butter lovers. I have a
favorite, but you're only looking for
spreadability and you compared
spreadable butter, butter spread,
avocado, and the coconut. Yes. Okay,
take it away. The butter spread. Really?
A butterspread winner. So maybe it was
worth putting all those things in there.
Yeah, for sure. Because I I I'm
surprised cuz the spreadable butter, you
know, I I it seemed to go okay. But look
look, I got all of this. I got all of
the butter spread. Yeah, you colored in
your lines perfectly. Very nice.
Exactly. So, let me go to Ashley.
Melting. You compare all their
meltabilities and the winner is spread.
Oh my goodness. Butter spread again. I
never thought that was possible. I mean,
honestly, coconut oil spread it melted
better. But I like a little bit flavor
in it. Like I want it to be a thick. I
wanted to have still be buttery but melt
and go down easy, I guess. Oh my god. So
yeah, I like the butter spread better.
Did you like the blowtorrch part of the
experiment? That was the best part. And
finally, Maggie, I'm going to leave it
to you, Maggie. On taste, which is what
the chef cares about, who would win? I'm
going to go with the butter spread as
well. Oh my goodness. Science wins here.
Science wins. Oh my goodness. Science
won. You're right. I never would have
expected. I thought everyone would go
with the spreadable butter, but that's
what the win. That's what the data
shows. That's the new healthier butter
that some are saying is the Greek yogurt
of butters. Find out what it is when we
come back.
Greek yogurt.
Today we are having a butter
investigation and spreading the goods on
new trends that could change way you
think about your favorite dairy spread
forever. You will not want to miss this.
[Applause]
Welcome back to our butter
investigation. I'm here with Chef
Michael Schlow who's here to spread the
word about the new butter trend getting
all the attention in the dairy aisle
these days. Some even say it is the
Greek yogurt of butters. What is it? Put
the picture up there.
No, Scott. No, that's not the right
picture. That's the ban culture club.
I'm talking about cultured butter. It's
even better.
Many culture club. Chef Michael, there
are many butter roll terms on the market
today and a lot of us have tried them
all, but this has taken over everything.
What makes cultured butter so special?
So, cultured butter is so interesting.
Um, it's like regular butter except for
they've added a little secret
ingredient. There's some some active
bacteria here and it just develops a
whole another flavor. So you can use
live bacteria. Live bacteria goes into
this. Uh it is like Greek yogurt. It is.
Yeah. So I mean whether it's, you know,
using kef kefir or something like uh you
can introduce uh sour cream or
buttermilk. I I made some with uh
yogurt, you know. I mean you can do lots
of different things, but time is the key
here. So it's uh it's like making wine a
little bit. So the big difference
between regular butter and cultured
butter is bacteria and a little thyme.
And also that flavor. You got that
tanginess, that slightly nuttiness to
it. I think it's uh it's it's more
interesting quite frankly. Come over
here. I know you brought me a little
present here. Sure, I did. So, I want to
know more about the difference here. So,
you brought me actually you actually
made this yourself. I did. Yes. So, um
heavy cream. You introduce some sort of
bacteria. This is kefir, but you could
do as I said, you know, sour cream or
something else. And after 2 days, this
is what it looked like. You leave it
out, by the way. This guy, you leave it
out. You leave it out. You don't put it
in the refrigerator. It needs to be out
at room temperature or in a warm place
in your kitchen. You got to be kidding.
I'm not kidding. And violates every
premise. I know, right? But this is how
it works. And it really uh it gets a
little bit of that tanginess. And then
what you do is you put it into a
blender. Actually tastes good. It should
taste bad. Just like that would be fine,
right? So you put it into a blender. I
mean, or a food processor like this. And
you just want to you want to cover this
so that you know, nobody gets uh I'll
stand behind you. There we are. Go
ahead, chef. We're good to go here. And
after just about 2 or 3 minutes, it will
break. It will literally break. What do
you mean break? You separate. separates.
Yeah. So, it's getting close. That's
when you get it all over the place. Let
me just see this. I want to see what's
going on in there. So, we turn it off
and you can see it's starting to
separate. You see that it's starting to
get a little bit of water. Making a mess
is half the fun of the show. Exactly.
Right. So, what ends up happening is you
have buttermilk and then the the culture
butter separates itself and you have to
basically bring it down with a little
bit of cheesecloth and then you end up
uh with something beautiful like this.
It ends up being beautiful, gorgeous
butter. So, why is this a hero for chefs
these days? So, that's an interesting
question. This has a lot of different
properties to it and a lot of different
applications. One of the my favorite
ones to do if you want to look like a
pro at home, use a little bit of
cultured butter to say sear a steak, get
that crispy, crunchy, gorgeous, you
know, brown sear like you see in
restaurants or a piece of fish and a
little goes a long way. You based with
it, you're going to you're going to
impart new flavor to it and you're going
to look like a pro. You're making me
hungry. So, we we know the bacteria is
good for the gut. I want to know if it's
even enough per serving to make a
difference of this bacteria because it
is sort of cool that you're adding it.
So listen, here's the deal. I don't want
you trading your morning yogurt. The
Greek yogurt, especially for buttered
sandwich, it's not quite the same. The
amount of bacteria in this cultured
butter is just not enough to make up for
that. This is for flavor, right? Yeah.
But if you want flavor, you want to make
that meat the way you desired, the fish,
etc. I think it's a brilliant idea and I
love that you celebrate food. Now that
stated, I got one more challenge. We got
two audience members who have been
trying popular hacks, butter hacks from
the internet. So, chef, I want you to
judge whether these are better butter
hacks or are they just bogus butter
hacks. Sounds good. Right. The first
butter hack is to heat it under a glass.
Mariana, show us how it's done. All
right. You just pour some hot water into
a glass. It's hot. Oh, yeah. It's really
hot. And this this is theoretically
frozen butter. So, it's cold and it's
going to destroy like all sorts of baked
goods you worked all day on.
So, you don't want that. And then you
just keep it under there and kind of And
then just the warmth of the glass is
we'll steam it and soften it. How long
do you have to keep it for? Um about 30
seconds is all you need really. You did
it here, right? Yep. Let's cut the
middle and see if it got into the middle
of it or not. Look at that. That looks
pretty good. That's Oh my goodness, that
actually worked. Is that better? Yeah,
it looks All right. Next butter hack is
to roll it out on plastic wrap. This
again, if it's frozen, you're in a
hurry. You got to get it out. Princess,
show us how it's done. Well, I put the
butter in between the two plastics and I
got to roll in real hard. You saw this
on the internet. I could use a little
bit help. I would do this. This is how I
would do it. This is how I start on the
internet. Like this. I saw this.
What do you think of that idea? I'm
going to go with this is pretty bogus.
Why don't you just leave it out in the
morning? You know, if you know you're
going to bake, why don't you just take
it out of the refrigerator the night
before? Thanks for playing with us,
Princess. Nicely done, Mariana. Chef,
it's been a real pleasure. My pleasure.
Thank you. We'll be right back.
Damon John is revealing why he had to
have unexpected emergency surgery. It's
actually a procedure that one million of
you will be told by a doctor you also
need this year. Stick around to hear the
story.
[Applause]
About two months ago, I received an
urgent call from one of my producers
telling me that my friend and Shark Tank
star Damon John had to cancel his
appearance on this show because of a
medical emergency. Now, he was supposed
to be on with Barbara Corkran for a
segment that was going to be pretty
cool, but he was rushed into surgery
just hours beforehand. And then I
received this video message from Damon.
Hey Doc, sorry I can't make the segment
tomorrow. Um, something came up.
But you got Barbara. I know she's not
that bright. Um,
thank you for understanding. See you in
a minute. All right. It's been a little
more than a minute, but Damon is ready
to share with you the shocking health
scare that caused him to have emergency
surgery, a procedure that a million of
you will also need this year. Come on
out, Damon. John.
[Applause]
[Music]
Oh yeah.
Oh my goodness. That was funny. Come on
over here. That was I laughed and
laughed when I got that. I didn't know
you were going to show that video. So we
have they already medicated you when you
recorded that? I'm just curious. Yeah, I
was already juiced up. So
So I haven't showed it to Barbara yet.
Should I? Sure. Absolutely. She'll
agree. She'll agree. How you feeling
now? I am feeling great. I really am.
Yeah. I was very happy for you. I was
very nervous because emergency hernia
operations sometimes happen because you
got having complications. But I love if
you could take us back to that day. What
happened? What went down? When did you
know something was wrong? So it was
Sunday night. I was getting a tattoo cuz
I'm going through that midlife crisis. I
just turned 50. So is it Oz Oz full
name? My full the tattoo. Is it my full
name or just part of it? Oh, it's it's
it's Oz Daddy. Uh so um
so I was getting it and you know the
tattoo was about 6 hours and I was
clenching you know because of the pain
of the tattoo almost like planking for
that period of time. The next morning I
go uh to Miami to to film something for
Shark Tank and all of a sudden I feel a
pop like a little literally a pop two
inches over my belly button and I feel
and I could push it in and out. Ooh. And
I'm like, "Oh, I don't know." You know,
the next day I go home and I tell my
wife, I said, "You know, I have a little
pop here." She says, "Go to the doctor
right away." I said, "Nah, what are you
kidding me? I'm a man. I'm a big boy.
I'm not going to the doctor." Then she
says, "You better go to the doctor." So,
I go to the doctor. He says, I should
point out, by the way, nagging saves
lives. In point, it does. It does. In
point, it really does. Um, I go to my
doctor. He sends me over to NYU. He, you
know, you know, I' I've had him for 20
years and and I go in and uh a very um
very experienced uh doctor comes in,
looks at it, touches it for a second.
You need to go to surgery right now. He
says, "Have you had any problems
eating?" I said, "No, not at all." He
says, "Okay, well, that's a good thing."
He said, "Did you take any aspirin
lately or any blood thinners?" I said,
"No." He said, "That's a good thing. We
need to get you into surgery." Oh my
goodness. So, you know, at that point,
I'm like, "Why am I going to surgery?"
He said, "Well, you know what we're
looking at is probably a hernia and this
little hole probably the the what you
feel is like probably fat that came
through and sooner or later your
intestines are going to come through and
we may have to cut your intestines." Oo.
I called Robert. I said, "Robert, you
know, fat came through." He was like,
"And and my intestines didn't come
through." And he said, "Robert from
Shark Tank." He goes, "That's the reason
for all your fat." I said, "Yeah, how
compassionate. How compassion." Um, why
would you call Robert of all people to
get his advice? I don't know. Because
he's just the happiest person on the
planet. He is happy. And listen, then I
go I'm in surgery about 4 hours later.
Oh my goodness. Yeah. Can I show
everybody what was going down? I I made
a little animation. Come on up here. You
You might enjoy this cuz you can help me
narrate it. Come over this side. All
right. So, let's pretend that this is
you stand there. I'm going to
demonstrate the why the abdominal wall
gets weak and why when it gets weak it
can pop through. Okay. So, let's lie on
your back. Play the animation. Right.
And when you lie on your back, right?
Right. There's the belly button. Let's
say just above it, you have areas of of
the muscle that are pretty strong. And
when you have a little hole there, a
little bit of you from the inside can
pop on the outside. Now, you can see in
this person, there's got some intestines
that are popping out. But this is
freezes for a second. And with you, that
bump was probably a little bit of fat.
Even though Robert was joking, the first
thing that comes out is a little bit of
fat. That's the beginning of the hernia.
As the hernia gets larger and larger,
you get loops of bowel that'll come
through. And here's the thing. If left
untreated, yeah, you'll have, you know,
green stuff going through there,
intestines, but then eventually it'll
turn black because it's being suffocated
because this hernia is strangling the
intestines down below. And when that
tissue is strangled, if it were to fall
back in on its own, it would release all
that toxic stuff called major problem.
Sepsis, even death happens. I mean, I've
taken care of a lot of people with
hernas. Yeah. Because before you become
a heart surgeon, you got to do hernia
surgery. I've seen people really get
sick from these things. So, I am proud
of you for intervening on yourself and
listening to your wife nag you. Thank
you. Absolutely. Yeah. Because at first
you feel like, you know what, it'll go
away. It's a little bump. You know, you
get you get things around you, but then
you know obviously the way they rolled
me right in, they they obviously felt it
was something serious. So, do you think
that you're more sensitive to taking
care of yourself because of your thyroid
scare? Absolutely. because all I talk
about now is early detection because uh
you know I would have just been buying
time and after this it would have been
much much worse. You know it's it's only
now been about 5 weeks since um I'm I'm
better than ever now. I feel like I can
go out and do everything. But you know I
would have normally ignored that 5 years
ago I would have said nah I'll wait till
uh you know I'm I I'm curled over and I
got to go to the doctor. Barely holding
on. Absolutely. All right. When we come
back, we got the three warning signs
that you need to know to catch a hernia
early, just like Damon did. Got to get
it before it gets out of hand. Stay with
us.
[Applause]
We are a nation riddled with allergies,
but what if you outgrew them and didn't
know it? People are walking around
thinking they have this allergy and they
no longer have it. We're doing a big
allergy experiment
that's coming up on Wednesday.
I got a call from my man who was like,
"Hey yo, son, let me find out somebody
sold you a deadly bagel. Give me the
number to the dude who sold you the
deadly bagel." You know what I'm saying?
I was like, "No, nobody sold me a deadly
bagel." "Oh, now you want to protect
your man who's selling you deadly
bagels." "Well, check this out. I'mma
find your man regardless. Regardless.
Love you, bro. Later." Click. I was
like, "Uh,
love you, too. Bye."
Look at you. Yeah, John got that call
from a very confused friend who who saw
that he was rushed to the hospital right
after he posted a picture of a bagel. I
was saying, you know, life is funny. One
minute you're eating a bagel, the next
minute you're in the hospital. My friend
thought somebody sold me a deadly bagel.
You know, that's how social media is.
You got to love social media here. All
right, so here's the deal. It wasn't a
deadly bagel that caused David's hernia,
but there are warning signs to look for
so you can catch a hernia. Remember, a
million of you going to have a procedure
for this this year. It's common. Number
one, there could be a bulge that looks
like this. Look at look at the picture
carefully. See, it looks pretty
innocuous. Smooth bulge. If you catch it
at this stage, you can get it before it
gets out of hand like Damon did. Look
familiar. Much bigger, but yes, that
that that's it. Yeah. So, it's it's
different. It's not what you normally
look like. And it's not symmetrical.
It's not like you put a little weight
on, right? Number two, you could have
severe digestion issues like
constipation, nausea, or vomiting. Did
you I didn't have any of that. None of
that. Yeah. Remember I showed that
intestine getting pulled through. Yeah.
So if that gets strangulated, suffocated
that gets squeezed at the base, then you
don't have all those symptoms at once
because your body's travel through.
Yeah. Food can't go through there. And
your body's immediate response is stop
eating and get out whatever's in there
cuz we're in a panic mode, right? So So
you didn't have any of that. That's a
good sign. Thank God. And number three,
a sudden onset pain like the world's
worst gas pain that makes you clutch
your belly like this. I had a little bit
of that. Yeah. How would you describe
the pain specifically? A pinch. And it's
it was a a pin like right here. Just a a
strong pinch and I kept going, "What is
that? What is that?" All cuz of that
darn tattoo. Yeah, that's right. Did you
finish the tattoo yet? No, it's not. I'm
going I'm going to leave it undone.
I don't know if I want to get any more
tattoos. Let's do that. All right. So,
here's the deal. Because their hernia
can poke through when someone's
abdominal wall is weakened, we want
everyone who's worried about hernas to
strengthen their abdominal wall. So,
come on over here. We're gonna do a
little game here. Kate CVY is here from
Symphony Yoga. She's agreed to come and
show everyone watching some yoga moves.
So, okay, go ahead. If you don't mind,
show us two simple yoga moves that
everyone can do now to strengthen their
belly, their core. Okay. It's good to
prevent hernas, but it's also good to
keep strong. All right. And then after
we're done, Darren, we're going to
exchange your health advice for some
business advice from the pro here. We're
going to shark tank it. That sounds
great. Big fan of the show. Thank you.
I'm ready. All right. Great. So, some
simple leg raises that you can do is lie
on your back all the way down and then
you're going to inhale as you raise your
left leg to start. You keep your belly
firm the whole time. Yep. And you engage
the core so you feel it engage and then
keep going slowly up. You got a 12-pack
in there, by the way. Very impressed. I
wish. That'd be great. And then and then
you start on the right leg. So, you do
alternating. So, do this while you're
watching commercials, what whatever you
want to do, but it's not long. You can
do about about 10 on each side. Exactly.
As long as you don't feel pain. So don't
like raise your leg too much so you
don't feel like So simple leg raise. The
next thing is a shoulder stand, but this
is a half shoulder stand. Exactly. So
you just bring your legs all the way up
and you use your hands to support your
low back and then you if it's too much
on your leg to support you just bring
your legs lower down slowly. That makes
it easier or harder? Makes it easier.
All right. But the the hard version is
way up and that's the abdomen. Yeah.
Right. But you got to hold your legs up
because your legs they they would be
tense before. Right. Exactly. All right.
Now, hop up now. Now, you beautifully
taught D a few things. So, business
advice. What's the pitch? You just
opened a a spot in Jersey called Yoga
Symphony, right? Exactly. Exactly. Build
your audience. So, take it away. Yes.
So, my my question would be, how do I
gain more corporate clients because
there's so many companies out there that
are attracting corporations for yoga?
So, I just wanted to see how I could
direct differentiate myself. Well, if
you have people locally, how how are you
giving it a giving them an offer they
can't refuse? Meaning, you know, giving
free classes for x amount of time. If
they like it, they'll convert, right?
And then no matter what brand or product
you have, social media is the easiest
and the cheapest. But you got to look at
social media as a half an hour
television show. If your favorite half
an hour television show, 28 minutes is
commercials, then you're going to switch
your channel. So, what you need to do is
give them as much information you can
for the 28 minutes on your social media.
So, the two minutes that you're offering
something for them to buy, then you do.
So too many people on social media just
go sell sell buy help me out instead
just give them information so this the
smartest person the water cooler on
Monday morning and then when they're
ready to buy they come to you. So those
are those
advice and more importantly I love you
and I'm glad you're doing well. Thank
you Doug. Thank you. God bless you my
friend. All right last on Shark Tank.
We'll be right back.
A trail of unsolved murders in
California taunting police with letters.
Now 50 years later, can DNA evidence
track down the Zodiac Killer? People
think this is the guy. All new Oz.
That's coming up tomorrow.
For years, I've been telling you that it
is natural and that everyone does it.
And sometimes it's by action, sometimes
it's on purpose. You got loud ones and
silent ones, smelly or not. Talking
about flatulence, of course. And one man
is saying he was fired for doing it at
work.
Get this. Paul Flart was working as a
security guard when he decided to
document all of his work farts on video
and post them online. He said it was a
breeze
and he got away with it for six months
until the bosses found out. So, take a
look.
[Music]
Why are you recording? Because take it
off. No, sir. Yes, sir. You're not going
to record me wearing that uniform? I'm
not recording you, sir. I'm recording
me, sir. Okay, you turn it off. Okay.
Well, sir, you're firing me anyway,
right? Yes, I am. We are joined today by
the man who goes by the name Paul Flart.
What made you post videos of your
workwind, if I can call it that, for six
months? First off, how you guys doing?
Thanks for having me here. I appreciate
it so much. But, uh, you know, I just
one day I farted in the lobby of the
hospital and, uh, the acoustics were
just so great that I had to share it
with my friends. We brainstormed about
it for a bit. They loved it. Felt like
the world needed to see it. So, we came
up with Paul Flart, made the Instagram
account, and then the rest, as you know,
is history. So, we saw that video of you
getting fired. Uh, you're still out of
work, right? That's what I believe.
Yeah. And you're pursuing your dream of
being an athome online gamer where I got
to say you're going to get far fewer
complaints there. So, it might be a good
position. But, but we spoke to uh the
online performers group. Uh one of the
largest talent management firms for pro
gamers and they actually want to do an
interview with you to give you some as
they said it career advice and even
discuss possible representation. How's
that sound? That sounds amazing.
Awesome.
Yeah, I was not expecting that. Awesome.
Well, I I hope you enjoy your time with
them. Thank you for joining us, Paul.
You're an everyday hero in a whole
different way. Together, everybody,
change is happening. Our journey is just
beginning.
[Applause]
[Music]