[Applause]
A warning. The photos you're about to
see are graphic. These are scars, scabs,
and open wounds that are often hidden by
closed ribbon makeup. And they're caused
by people who compulsively pick away at
their own skin. Today, the secret life
of skin pickers. We're going behind
closed doors to uncover how this secret
obsession can control lives.
[Music]
I just woke up about to get ready to go
to work. Um, the first thing I thought
about when I woke up this morning was
how the scabs that I picked out
yesterday have probably healed over so I
can pick up them again. I never account
for the amount of time in the morning
it's going to take me to pick and
sometimes I end up being late to places,
too. Um, but it's uncontrollable.
[Music]
The urge to pick has been in the back of
my mind all day. Um, I was thinking at
work, like, am I going to be able to
pick this one? Um, am I going to be able
to pick the ones on my legs? It's just
something that's constantly there. My
fingers are constantly scanning. I'm
just constantly doing it. And sometimes
I even pick until I bleed. And
I just don't know how to stop or how to
resist that urge.
[Music]
I just got home from work. I was picking
a lot at work and I just got out of the
shower and that stung because the some
of the wounds were still open. Um
I still have the urge to pick. I'm
literally skinning my body as I'm like
doing this right now.
>> Katherine is here. Thank you for coming.
>> Thank you.
>> This is sensitive.
>> A lot of us pop pimples. We pick at
skin.
But in your case, at around age five, it
became much more significant than most
kids experience. What happened?
>> Uh so when I was five, I had really,
really sensitive skin. So it would be
down to sitting in the grass. I would
start to itch. Chlorine from pools,
scented lotions, perfumes. And so I
developed eczema around age eight. And
then eventually that went from just
scratching at my skin to starting to
pick and to pick and to pick. And
it was just something where it was just
I was constantly doing it, but I didn't
really think that there was anything
that was wrong with it. It was just
something that I was doing.
>> And notice how you're dressed now.
You've you've covered up your skin.
>> Yeah. How does it affect you when your
skin's not covered and people see the
scabs in your legs or your arms and and
comment?
>> It's It's definitely a little bit
embarrassing. Um, at first when I first
started picking, I didn't think that
anything was wrong. And then once I
started going out and I had like the
scabs and the scars all over my leg,
that was when people would be like,
"What's wrong with you?" Like, "What
happened to you? What happened to your
legs?" Or they'd be like, "Who beat you
up?" or something like that. And then
that was when I started to think, "Maybe
there is something wrong with me like
maybe this isn't something that other
people are doing as well. Do
>> you plan your day around whether people
see your scabs or not?
>> Yeah. So, I would wear like long pants
even in like the dead of summer when
it's like a million degrees outside. And
then I switched. I figured, okay, I want
to wear shorts, so let me put on makeup
now. So, I'd start to put makeup all
over my legs, all over my arms. And I
remember very specifically I was like on
the bus and the makeup was not the same
color as my legs at all. So people they
knew like they could tell that I was
wearing makeup and it was raining that
day and I remember the kids on the bus
were like oh well if you are like they'd
be trying to like rub at the makeup on
my legs and stuff like that and they'd
be like well if you are wearing makeup
when you go out into the rain we're
going to see it. It's going to run. And
I remember it was like a two-minute walk
from the bus to my house, but it felt
like I was walking for miles just to get
back to my house, trying to walk fast,
but not too fast so they wouldn't say
anything. And so then I tried to switch
to covering up with a bandage. And so I
would wrap like my entire shin with like
an ace bandage and I told people that I
sprained my shin. It was just
strategically planning the things that I
wore, trying to find different ways to
hide all of the scars. Is there ever a
moment of the day where you're not
thinking about picking at your skin?
>> No.
>> I'm just thinking about you and how
you're navigating life with these these
scabs.
>> What's your biggest fear?
>> My biggest fear would be that I wouldn't
that I can't stop it. Cuz when I was
young, I'd be like, "Okay, well, when
I'm in my 20s, that's it's going to go
away." And then I'm like, well, I'm 24
now and it's still it's still going on.
And so I worry that it's something that
I'm always going to have and it's not
going to go away.
>> So I did a little homework after I heard
of your story and there are many many
women like you and it's the shame as you
mentioned that hold so many back from
moving forward. So I'm going to
challenge you. How hard would it be for
you to show your scabs right now to all
of America?
It all started when I was a teen and I
endured some bullying and some abuse. It
started as a bad habit and a little bit
of an addiction. And then in my 20s, I
experienced some trauma where I ended up
in the bathroom for about 6 hours a day
kind of disassociating and in a zone. At
that point, I entered a partial
hospitalization program that really
helped me find what my triggers were.
Start surrounding myself with people
that loved and supported me instead of
toxic relationships. And then finally,
forgiving myself. There will be
relapses, but there is hope and you can
get there.
We're back uncovering a secret skin
obsession that women are hiding behind
closed doors. They need to constantly
pick at their own skin. Whether it's
pimples or bumps on their face or scabs
on their legs, they're consumed by this
urge to pick. Catherine is back. Ever
since she started picking her skin at
the age of five, she has not been able
to stop. And I know that you don't like
to show your skin. What do you think?
>> It's a little nerve-wracking.
>> Oh, I can imagine.
>> But I don't know of a better example of
how we face our fears than to show
people what you really look like.
>> Yeah.
>> And the skin is the most visible thing.
So, if you can do this, you can do
anything.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> I'll let you lead you pace it.
>> Okay.
So, what parts of your skin
were you the most are the parts that you
would regret us seeing?
>> Um,
>> I see you have some
>> definitely. Yeah.
on my left arm.
>> When you think look at these, what do
you feel?
>> Um,
it's a little bit embarrassing to look
at them, to see my skin like this and
know that I did that to myself.
>> Now, how about the judgment that I
suspect you feel when people see this
and wonder what's what's she doing?
>> Yeah, I've I've had some crazy
questions. Um people have asked me if
it's a cigarette burn, if it's um like
addictions to drugs, like different
things like that. And um so I think just
like the perception that people have of
what it is is
Yeah.
>> Do you feel it's an addiction?
Yeah, it could be an an addiction
because,
you know, it's something that I do every
single day and I know that it's harming
me and I know that it's harming my skin
and I just continue to do it. And since
it's also providing me that relief at
the same time, it's like
I don't know. I just it's just something
I keep doing.
>> Come over here. I want to show you what
I'm most worried about. Obviously the
emotional aspects of this are important
but I made a little simple illustration
right very rudimentary of the body right
skin is your largest organ you know that
already and if you look at the skin take
one step back so you can see you'll be
able to see it better if you turn back
here
>> so I just outlined the fact that you've
got a lot of surface area it's a it's a
great line of defense right protects you
against germs it makes sure everything
stays inside like it's supposed to right
however when you start to itch at it a
bunch of things happen first of all you
chip away at your body's own defense
system so each of these scabs
You're worried about the scars and what
people say about you. I'm worried about
these open wounds where you no longer
have a natural body's defense against
viruses and germs getting into you. And
those infections can be problematic. But
even a bigger problem is the infection
go deep into there and actually get into
your blood vessels and that can lead to
a bad problem called sepsis. It's a much
deeper infection or you could actually
literally burrow infections into veins
and arteries which can be catastrophic,
life-threatening even. And when I see
someone who's got everything actually on
the surface going for them threatening
their own well-being in addition to to
torturing themselves emotionally, it
hurts me. Obviously hurts you.
>> So I brought a world expert in to help
us if you're willing to get the help.
>> Yeah,
>> you are. Okay, come on over here. Let me
introduce you to psychologist, a
psychologist who specializes in picking
and they're not that many, but they're
out there. Dr. Kristen Banke, thank you
for joining us, Kristen.
>> Thank you for having me. So she she's
from the center of anxiety and
behavioral health and
just help me understand in the audience
as well what's going on. What what is
this compulsive repetitive behavior?
>> Sure. So it's called excoriation
disorder and the behaviors associated
with it. Picking scabs, squeezing pores,
popping pimples are what are known as
body focused repetitive behaviors. What
we know is that the most common triggers
that we see are stress,
boredom, anxiety.
>> So what's the first step? How do you get
started?
>> So the first thing that we would
recommend is to keep a behavior tracking
diary. And then lastly, we want them to
pay very careful attention to the
purpose that the behaviors serve. How do
they feel immediately afterwards? Do
they feel relieved? Does it provide a
sense of satisfaction or gratification?
Does their anxiety reduce?
>> All right. So, the big question is
actually for you.
>> You spent most of your life struggling
with this, embarrassed by, you use the
word ashamed.
>> Are you willing to make a change today?
>> Yeah.
>> Good.
>> You'll make it happen.
>> I want to make it happen.
>> Dr. Bianke wants to help you.
and you have a center that focuses on
this. What What do you want Katherine to
know about the next steps?
>> Um, so we use cognitive behavior therapy
and that is the scientifically supported
therapy for this disorder. What we're
going to be doing is hard work. I I want
to be honest about that. I want to be
upfront, but we're going to work
together as a team. And I can commit to
you that I will work as hard as I
possibly can for you. And in return, I
need that commitment that you will work
as hard as you can for me. Okay,
>> I can do it.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> In that spirit, I'd love for us to work
together as a team so that we can help
you beat this.
>> Okay.
>> And I hope that you accept my offer.
>> Yeah.
>> So, she's going to take you under her
wing.
>> Okay.
>> She has all these cool little ideas.
Many of them I've never thought of.
never even heard of that I I think will
be successful for you and want to keep
following you to make sure you do well.
Okay.
>> But it starts with you and it'll end
with you.
>> All right.
>> God bless you.
>> Thank you for
>> sharing your story. Dr. Mankey, thanks
for sharing your center and helping out
this wonderful guest of ours.
>> Thank you for having me.
>> We'll be right back.
>> Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good