[Music]
Today on Oz. That's a big issue, folks.
An identity victim shows Dr. Oz how easy
it is for thieves to steal his medical
info. Is your password the name of a TV
show host? Do you actually have that?
How to outsmart crooks after your cash
and medical data? The tools you need to
protect yourself. Plus, sure, it's great
for popcorn and heating leftovers, but
wait till you see what else your
microwave can do. Coming up next on Dr.
Oz.
Now, you have seen the headlines.
Security breaches at banks and major big
box stores have left all of us feeling
pretty vulnerable to identity theft. And
now the FBI is warning your personal
health records are the latest target.
That's why today I'm giving you the
tools you need to protect yourself from
the identity thieves after your money
and your medical
records. It's become a common
headline. Identity theft. Crooks
stealing personal information for
financial
gain. And now, medical identity theft is
being called an epidemic. Already
affecting over 2.3 million Americans and
growing. But unlike traditional credit
card crime, medical identity theft
victims are rarely informed about
suspicious or fraudulent activity, which
could lead to incorrect treatment and
devastating effects on your health. Yet
most of us are still unaware of how to
protect our medical and financial
information or just how easy it is to
steal. With 90% of healthcare
organizations admitting to breaches and
ATMs and cell phones also being
targeted, no one is safe. CEO John
Silio's identity was stolen and the
thief embezzled $300,000 from John's
clients. The crime destroyed his
company. So John made it his mission to
help others protect their personal
information. With your medical and
financial identity at risk, you may feel
like a sitting duck, but John says there
are ways to outsmart the thieves and
keep your identity
[Music]
safe. John joining us. What is the
biggest misperception you think people
have about identity theft? You know,
we've all gotten very familiar with
regular identity theft, loss of a credit
card number, social security number, but
increasingly thieves are going after our
medical data. They want the health
insurance information. They want the
doctor's records. Um, it's it's
terrible. And that's what I fight back
against. This is shocking to me. I
thought it was all about just us as
doctors being careful. You as the
consumers are getting robbed when this
happens in a much more important way
than with credit cards. So, the first
scam we're going to identify today is
having to do with health. And I've asked
Nikki Burton to join us. Nikki actually
went through a crisis of her own and I
I' I'd love to hear from you and just
tell us the story of how surprised you
were and what happened. Okay. Um well,
what happened to me is that when I was
17 years old, I tried to donate blood at
the Red Cross and I was actually unable
to do so because their records showed
that my person and my information um had
HIV and was HIV positive. That's pretty
shocking. Yeah, it was. Especially Were
you HIV positive? No. No. Nope. and not
then. Um, and I was 17, so I was rather
overwhelmed. But I later learned that a
man had used my identity and my
information, my records to obtain
treatment for HIV, and that was how that
information had gotten into their
database. So, I tried to correct it
right away. Um, but it was actually 6
years before I was successful. It's an
unbelievable tale. Six years. You you
walked around with a diagnosis of being
HIV positive and God knows what else so
far. But yeah, we think it's just that
it was I was HIV positive. So, how do we
outsmart these medical identity thieves?
So, first of all, you got to share with
care. You've got to um give that
information only when it's absolutely
necessary and ask your doctor's office,
do they need your social security
number? If in doubt, give put a dash and
put the last four characters. You don't
have to give the whole thing. Now,
women, let me tell you that for a
second. That's a big issue, folks, cuz I
must even in my own office, I always ask
patients there are social security
numbers. We have 15 different places we
can get that. I don't even know why we
ask it now that you bring it up. I think
we ought to start there. Why are people
asking for our social security numbers
all the time whenever we sign in in a
hospital? I'm with you. Right.
Absolutely. So, let's But from now on,
let's just do what you just said. Put
the last four digits in there so we know
that it's you if we have to double
check. Everything else should just be
dashes. Yeah. You know, if it's
Medicare, you're going to have to give
it right now. But for all other
purposes, only give it if you absolutely
have to. Another thing you can do is
monitor those records, those vital
documents that you've got. So looking at
the explanation of benefits that you get
in the mail after a procedure to see if
somebody's, you know, draining your
account, looking at your actual doctor's
records, ask for a copy and see, has
something changed since you were there
last. Yeah. Monitor your vital signs in
a whole different way. And you know,
because medical identity theft, uh, it
bleeds, it's contagious. It contains
your financial identity, your social
security number, as it did here. So you
also have to protect that side of it.
You can do that by uh monitoring your
financial identity for free on a website
called annualcreditreport.com.
All right, good information. Thanks for
sharing your story. Of course, come on
over. I want to talk about the next
problem we have, which is ATM machine
skimming. Uh Carolyn's here and like a
lot of folks, how are you, Carolyn?
Uh so, we're all worried about getting
ripped off when we go to the ATM
machine. This is something that's been a
long-term concern of yours. Has it ever
happened to you? Um, it hasn't happened
to me, but you know, I can probably see
where it could happen. So, uh, John, if
you don't mind, I'd like you to walk us
through how this skimming happens. The
folks, pay close attention here. This
happening all over the country, and it
is absolutely stunning. So, this is a
typical traditional ATM that you might
see in any type of store. Go ahead and
put your card in, okay, as if you were
banking. And you better pull out all the
cash because if you don't, the thieves
can. You see, without even knowing it,
if you don't know what to look for, this
device here, protruding from the
machine, if you wiggle it a little bit,
it comes off. Oh my gosh. And it's got a
digital skimmer, this is called
skimming, it skims the data off of your
card without even knowing it. It's
unbelievable. It looks just like the
machine. So, what happens if someone
once someone skims your card? Yeah, it
looks like the regular old machine. Then
what? They take the the data off it.
Yeah. So they take the data off of that
and then the thief creates an exact
duplicate of the card that you have and
now they're shopping as you. They're
they're literally cashing it out. So
they're two cards online. Yeah.
Literally. Exactly. Make it a digital
copy and then they go on a shopping
spree. Go on a shopping spree. They cash
it out before you even have time to to
react. This all happens very quickly
generally online. If someone was taking
your cards while you're still at the
machine and buying dresses, outfits,
swim gear, whatever, how long would it
take for you to figure that out?
Honestly, I probably wouldn't know for
about a month because that's when I
checked my credit card statements. So, a
whole month would go by. So, how do we
outsmart the skimming scam? Yeah. So, I
mean, if you see something sticking off,
these were made to be flush, right? If
it's protruding like this, wiggle it,
pull it, see if it comes off. They put
these on with two-sided tape. You can
foil it really easily just by looking at
your ATM machine. Unbelievable, Carolyn.
Thank you very much. Here's a little
momento of your stay with us with you.
All
right, the last scam we're going to talk
about today is called
smishing text scams. It's something that
happens on text phones pretty regularly.
Now, you say this is done quite
frequently and most of us don't even
know what's happening, right? Yeah. In
fact, uh we've we've done it to you. Did
you get any uh strange Yeah. get a
strange text last night?
I got a text from someone whose email I
thought recognized, but it was a weird
email. Yes. So, I I I clicked it. It
didn't take me anywhere. What did that
text say? Well, that text was bizarre,
but I did send text. I text my wife. You
sent a text after that? Yeah, I sent my
my wife's traveling, so I sent her a
text. It's uh I I don't remember how
intimate it was. It was something uh I
hope that's not on television. Well, I
think it's about to be. Is this the text
you sent? Miss you. Lots of kisses.
XOXO.
That was the uh that was the first text.
She's been gone for a couple days. So,
so this software actually recorded that
text. You're kidding me. As you wrote it
and sent it off to me so that I could
see what you were texting. So on your
computer, you were monitoring what I was
doing on my phone. What else could you
able to track? You know, you can uh if
this key logging software, which records
every keystroke you put is on there. I
can see emails, I can see contacts, I
can see photos. If you have a banking
app, I can see you log in. If you have a
health app, I can see your health
information. So So if I have Do I have a
banking app? This is my phone. So, if I
wanted to use this, could you read what
I was doing? Yeah. So, keep it keep it
close. I'm going to move back here with
the iPad. I want you to log in to your
bank account right now. Keep it keep it
tight. All right. I'm on the account.
Here's my password. This is now taking a
look. It's sending me what he's writing
on there. I just logged in. All right.
So, let me ask you a question.
Is your password the name of another
daytime TV show host?
It is. You actually have that. And is it
five characters? That's it. That's it.
That's unbelievable.
I've got your password because of that
software that you loaded when you
downloaded when you clicked on that
malicious link. So, how do I I mean, how
do I avoid that? How does the average
viewer avoid that happening? Yeah. So,
you can either not click on the links in
text. That's kind of a radical way. or
if you have to click on a link, think of
three things. Number one, do you know
the sender? Do you trust them? Do you
know that they've still got control of
their phone? Number two, is the URL
something you recognize? Is it a
legitimate site that you've checked out?
And most importantly, were you expecting
the link? If you're not expecting a
link, don't do it. It's probably an
advertisement. It's the scam trying to
get you to download your uh the malware
or give away your personal information.
This has been fantastic advice, John.
Thank you so much. You bet. Thank you.
To learn more, you can read John Silio's
new book. It's called Privacy Means
Profit. You'll learn John Silio's dos
and don'ts of creating a safe password
as well. Do this. I'm doing this today
myself on dr.com. We'll be right back.
Next, the study that's rocking the
agricultural world. Could the world's
top weed killer cause cancer? And it's
not just used on farms. It could be in
your garden as well. Top food and
environmental advocates go head-to-head.
Is your family at risk? Next, Juliana
Rancic. How you doing now? Sets the
record straight on the eating disorder
rumors, the stress and scrutiny of her
marriage, her job, and her heartbreaking
baby news. All new Oz. That's coming up
tomorrow. It's the world's most used
weed killer found not just on farms, but
also in your garden. It's called
Roundup. Now, there's breaking news. A
new report from the World Health
Organization, which has also declared
today World Health Day, says Roundup
might cause cancer, and that could be a
gamecher. The study rocked big
agriculture and could have major
implications for home gardeners, too.
The World Health Organization's
International Agency for Research on
Cancer recently gathered together 17
experts from 11 countries to answer this
question. What is the likelihood that
glyphosate, the active ingredient in the
world's most widely used herbicide,
might cause cancer? After analyzing 30
years of research, their alarming
conclusion, glyphosate is probably
carcinogenic. With the use of glyphosate
in Roundup soaring over the last 20
years, is it time to ask, are the risks
worth
it? Dr. Alan Green is a pediatrician who
has been studying the use of pesticides
and foods for over 20 years. Scott Faber
is the vice president of the environment
working group. Scott, 30 years ago, the
EPA, the group that protects us,
determined that Roundup might cause
cancer. And then six years later, they
actually changed their minds and said,
"Well, it's not really a problem." So,
who can we believe? Well, at the end of
the day, the world's cancer experts, the
folks at the World Health Organization,
have concluded that this weed killer,
which has exploded in use as more and
more farmers have used GMO corn and GMO
soybeans, is a probable carcinogen. And
this is the body that every regulator in
every government across the globe relies
on to determine what does cause cancer.
Right? So, my goal is always have an
open and honest conversation. You all
know that. But I couldn't get anyone to
appear on the show who supports
glyphosate. Now, we reached out to the
Grocery Manufacturers of America, Crop
Life America, that's an advocacy group
of fertilizer, and Monsanto, that's the
maker of Roundup. They all declined to
be on the show, but we did get
statements from them. Crop Life America
said the IRC report contradicts
established scientific consensus on
these products and reaches inaccurate
conclusions based on a flawed process.
So, Dr. Green, why does this report have
everyone so up in arms? Well, a couple
of reasons. One is that glyphosate is so
commonly used. It's top weed killer in
the world. Uh the US Geological Survey
says that in farm parts of our country,
it actually shows up in the rainwater,
not just on the farms. And it's not just
used in agriculture. People use it on
parks. People use it in ball fields is
people spray it in their own yard. So,
one is super common. The second thing is
that this isn't just another study. You
know, you you hear one study and then
another study, but this is IRC. This is
the world's leading experts. It's not
the policy makers or regulators are
saying, "What should we do?" It's not
the chemical industry. It's people with
one question. Can this chemical cause
cancer in people and they gave it one of
their highest levels of concern.
So, we also got a note from Monsanto. I
want to share this with you because I
want you to have, you know, be pushed to
answer their questions. They said in
part, "All labeled uses of glyphosate
are safe for human health. Many of the
regulatory bodies and science
organizations have reviewed three
decades of data on glyphosate. Their
overwhelming consensus has been that
glyphosate does not pose a risk to
humans, wildlife, or the environment.
So, defenders of these pesticides argue
that this data is coming from mice, not
humans, and they're making an accusation
that we're raising an alarm too soon.
Yeah, I I think that's just not right.
Now, when people have uh have cancer,
it's really hard to go back and trace
what exposure might have caused that,
when, where, how. It's really hard to
tease out. There's so many factors. But
I released their findings in the one of
the world's leading medical journals,
and they had three strands of evidence.
First, they did have animal studies
where you can control everything, and
the only difference is they got exposed
to this weed killer, and they found
strong evidence that in mammals it can
cause cancer. Um, secondly though, you
can't do that in people.
Thankfully, but what you can do is
expose human cells to the weed killer.
And when that was done, they found DNA
damage and chromosomeal damage. And then
the third strand of evidence which could
lead to cancer. Which could lead to
cancer. Exactly. And then the third
strand of evidence is they looked at the
people who are routinely exposed to
glyphosate just in the course of their
work and they found and this was done in
three countries including the US and
they found higher rates of a certain
type of cancer in the people who are
exposed. So, taking all of that
together, all of the evidence together,
they said this is probably a human
carcinogen. Yeah, this is a big debate,
everyone. Folks who make these products
say, "Well, we need more data before you
can make that statement." I think it's
the opposite. Not enough research
doesn't mean it's safe. It means we
actually don't know, and it's sort of
upon us, our obligation to figure it out
before we start releasing it and
exposing kids and the other. So, I'd
like to bring Robin O'Brien in. She's a
mom and a food advocate. You've heard
all these comments. Is it frustrating to
you to hear these responses from the
folks who make these products? You know,
it's really not at all surprising. I was
a financial analyst to cover the food
industry and if you step back for a
minute and think about this big chemical
company, this is one of their most
profitable products. So, of course,
they're going to try to dismiss any
concern around it or refute the science.
But like these two have said, these are
our leading cancer researchers from the
World Health Organization and the
National Cancer Institute. And countries
like the Netherlands have already taken
this precautionary measure. They've
already banned this product. And here we
are in the United States. And you look
at the rates of cancer here in this
country. One in two men and one in three
women are expected to get cancer in
their lifetime. The CDC now says that
cancer is the leading cause of death by
disease in children under the age of 15.
It's time to take some proactive
measures to exercise precaution. I mean,
I know as a mom when we're pregnant, we
do everything we can. we take all these
little precautionary measures to give
that information to citizens today here
in the United States so that they can
take personal responsibility for their
health. I think it's absolutely critical
at this point. So the good news for me
is that we reached out to the
Environmental Protection Agency and
here's what they said in part. The EPA
is currently reassessing glyphosate and
if at any time the EPA discovers that
the use of a registered pesticide may
result in unreasonable adverse effects
on people or the environment, we will
take action to remove it from the
marketplace or limit its use. I mean,
Scott, this sounds huge. The EPA is
actually re-evaluating again this widely
used product and and of course EPA
should take another look at it, but
let's not forget EPA got this wrong. For
20 years, we've been told that this
herbicide is a better alternative than
other herbicides. We've sprayed more
than 200 million pounds of it every year
on hundreds of millions of acres of crop
land and around our homes and schools.
And it turns out that the experts, the
world's leading cancer cancer experts
now have found that this is probably a
human carcinogen. So that doesn't mean
EPA won't get it right next time. But
what it does mean is that we ought to
show a little humility, use a little
precaution, and at least let people know
whether their food is being grown with
these incredibly dangerous herbicides.
Robin, what do you want to see done as a
mom?
No one wants to be told what to eat.
Nobody wants to be told how to feed
their kids. It's hard enough as a mom
just trying to get your kids fed, but
nobody wants cancer either. And I think
about how our grandmothers when they
were confronted with the tobacco
industry claiming that their products
were safe, they asked for a label. They
asked for a warning label and today the
majority of our food supply is now
genetically engineered to be Roundup
ready to be tolerant of this very weed
killer that the World Health
Organization is saying it might cause
cancer. And I think if you can give that
information to parents, if you can give
that information to our country to try
to head off the escalating rates of of
this disease, that's just a smart
precautionary measure. Thank you,
Robert. We we all know what the health's
risks are and we need Washington DC to
listen. That's why in September, if you
remember, I asked you to sign the take
action petition to urge the president to
stop the approval of a more powerful
pesticide made with glyphosate. And you
answered the call. We received over a
100,000 signatures. That's what the
White House got. It is time for change
and it's your right to demand safer food
and environmental safety. You can find
all the statements mentioned here on the
Dr. Raj show on our website.com. We'll
be right back.
Next, the housewives of New York are
getting real. From their fights to their
figures, they're all about to face the
truth. Good regular sex is one of the
best beauty products you can have for
your skin. Is it true? Answering your
questions about what you want to know
most. Whoever said a doctor's visit
isn't fun has obviously never been to
the Dr. Oz show. Is that right? Make
your appointment today. You can go to
dr.com/tick and sign up for free
[Applause]
[Music]
tickets. Betrayal, crumbling marriages,
new loves, and plenty of wild nights.
That's a typical week for the Real
Housewives of New York. But no matter
what the ladies face, their faces will
always look good. So today, Bravo's
season 7 cast of the Real Housewives of
New York are answering all of your
questions. So, welcome out Carol
Newan. Sonia's behind her. There's
Kristen and Dinda, the newest member.
You guys look great. How are you? Nice
to meet you. Oh my goodness. They all
look fantastic. I'll get I'm going to
get in trouble. So many kisses.
I'm so happy you're here. Thank you for
being here. So, we're going to try do
something completely different. Just to
start us off, you've all agreed to face
the truth. So, they've agreed to
honestly answer all of the viewers
questions. I have the ones that are most
commonly asked from at least my team, my
viewers. You ready? Ready. Honestly, you
all pledged to be honest. Why not? Why
not? Exactly. So, you lead the way. All
right. Here goes. Who cares most about
how they look? Which of the housewives
cares most about how they look? We have
a Kristen there. Kristen. Oh my
goodness.
Kristen, is that true? I think I think
it might be. Why would they all accuse
you of caring so much about how you
look? I don't know. I think you should
ask somebody else. She She's a model.
So, she grew she grew up with the
territory everywhere we go. I do like I
like my hair and makeup and I like my
clothes and she's so pretty. So, oh,
they're being kind now. We'll see how
this might get a little cattier as we go
along. How about this question? Who's
most obsessed with their weight? Oh,
this is goodness. We have an obvious
choice here.
Oh, we have splits. A split here.
Maybe Dinda, you have to pick somebody.
Dinda choosing because we just had this.
Dinda. Darinda. Dinda. I should be
obsessed with my weight. Okay, let me
So, Dinda, why is it that they think
you're most obsessed about your weight?
Oh, they think I'm obsessed about my
weight. I change it cuz Carol's always
because she just brought it up to me in
the dressing. I'm obsessed with
Carol's weight right now. I think that's
all I talk about. I changed it. I I'm
obsessed with Carol with that actually
projecting because it doesn't love her
body. She's so She has such a great ass
and she's thin and beautiful and I love
her. That was She's natural. I'm I'm
obsessed with my weight. I'm obsessed
with your weight, too. Okay. So, you're
off the hook. You're being very honest.
I appreciate it. Now, ask away. I
promised I'd answer your questions. Take
it away. You go in any order you want.
You want to start, Carol? Okay. These
are our health questions. Okay. I'm a
believer that
um good regular sex is one of the best
beauty products you can have for your
skin. Now, is that a wives tale or is it
true? Does it affects your is it a good
anti-aging? I think it's very good for
and I'm not I'm not advocating
promiscuity. That's why she looks so
great. No, consensual consensual
monogous sex the right thing to do. I
tell a couple things to do. First of
all, on average, on average, the
interaction is about 6 minutes long. We
burn about 21 calories. That's all.
That's all. So there's not much action.
What are you having sex with?
I'm not asking about me. I'm just saying
that's what the numbers are across the
country. Is that very dissimilar from
what your experiences generally? Very
dissimilar.
But it releases hormones,
right? It's not because it burns
calories. It distresses you. the
hormones you release actually are the
ones that rejuvenate you, makes you feel
better. But in addition, if you look at
makeup, what makeup primarily does is
make you look attractive in a sexual
way, right? The the red rouge, the
blushing of the cheeks, which happens
when you get excited. The the lipstick
makes your lips more red. Much of
cosmetics is about making us look
sexually excited, not just attractive,
excited, right? So, it mimics youth.
That's what the makeup does. So, it's
good to spend more time in that space in
your life. Okay. Thinda, the newest
member of the group. Yes. I have a
question talking about weight. How do
you stay thin or get thin without diet
and exercising all the time? What's the
magic the magic thing? I am not the
sex diet and exercise. Isn't all these
magic diets? Tell me one of them works.
Some magic diet. No, there is no magic
diet. And you don't want a magic diet
because what you want is a lifestyle
that let you be what you want to be. The
best way to do that is to focus on the
calories you take in, which is by eating
foods that have rich nutrients. Because
your brain's not measuring calories,
it's measuring nutrients. You give it
food with nutrients in it, it'll stop
you in time. Don't think exercise will
get you there. That's a big mistake
women make all the time. But the way you
lose weight is by eating rich
nutrientdense foods, then actually your
body will naturally stop you when it's
happy. And so, we talk about that in the
show all the time. And we find many
things work, but for different people at
different times. So, the seventh
season's coming up. I have no idea why
you guys sign up for this stuff because
it's brutal in there. Right? So, I want
you all to watch The Real Housewives of
New York in action. This promises to be
very dramatic.
Why? Why? Why do you sign up for this? I
mean, it looks incredibly stressful to
me. Oh my gosh. You know, we really do.
For the money, for the money, we love
each other. I have everything. No, we
had a lot of fun. I mean, you know,
there's a lot of stress, sure, added to
the situation, but we had really a lot
of fun shooting this season. I I
personally had the best We argue our way
to solution every time. Yeah, we really
do. Family. Okay, a little surprise for
you. I've been thinking about this
segment for a while. And each season,
you guys have those new taglines. So
coolly done, nice, beautifully, elegant.
It's the iconic opening of every show.
So, I wanted in on the fun. So, I took
the liberty yesterday of crafting a few
of my own possible taglines, but we
couldn't decide which one was the best
one. So, I'm going to let you and our
audience decide which ones you like the
most. Are you willing to help? Okay.
Don't be too catty about these. Take a
look.
The big apple in keeping this doctor
away. The doctor will see you
now. When I bring healthy back, I do it
in style. I can handle drama, but I
can't deal with drama.
So, what's your favorite?
I like the third one. The third one. You
do it in style. Do it live. You do it in
style. We'll all do our tags. You want
to do it together? Yeah. Do yours again.
Oh, tag lines from the show. Yeah. You
guys get up right now. Everyone get up
right now. Your tag lines for this
season. Oh my god. All right. And I'll
do mine at the end. Okay. Are you ready?
Okay.
You're going to go first. Really? Yes.
All right. Okay. Turn.
Yes. I give up town a whole new
attitude.
Pretty is smarter than you may
think. Everyone tells me to do just one
thing. I am. I'm doing Sonia.
Okay, I'm going to do mine from last
year. The Big Apple has never tasted so
sweet.
Um, if you're going to gossip about me
behind my back, at least check out my
great ass.
How do I That was ranked number one of
all the T. That's a good one. I noticed
you all turn your backs.
That's how you get that turn going. You
know, when I bring healthy back, I do it
in style.
Sweet guest real housewives of New York
City Tuesday nights at 9 on Bravo. Check
them out. We'll be right
[Applause]
[Music]
back. Next, it's your go-to appliance to
heat up leftovers and pop your corn. But
did you know your microwave is good for
a whole lot more than just TV dinners?
Unleash its true potential with these
time-saving, unconventional uses. Things
you didn't know your microwave could do.
Next, all new Emmy nominated Dr. Oz
show. Juliana Rancic. How you doing now?
Sets the record straight on the eating
disorder rumors, the stress and scrutiny
of her health, her marriage, her job,
and her heartbreaking baby news. Plus,
what's for dinner? Healthy one pot
wonders that are cheap. That's my kind
of meal. And we'll feed the whole
family. I'm putting my bib on now. All
new Oz. That's coming up
[Music]
[Applause]
tomorrow. Your microwave. You know it's
great for making popcorn. Fantastic for
heating over leftovers. But today, Dr.
Oz viewers are stepping inside our
microwave laboratory right here to show
us the things you didn't know you could
do with a microwave. First up is Nikia.
What do you do with Nikia? How are you?
Hi, Dr. Eyes. How are you? What do you
like? What do you want to show us in our
microwave lab? Okay. Well, you know
what? This is a trick I learned from my
husband. Um your husband? From my
husband. Uh what I use it for is to
clean certain things in the kitchen. One
being the cutting board. He taught me on
the rag that he would like clean the
dishes with. And I was like, "You know
what? If you could do it with a rag and
a sponge, I'm going to use a cutting
board." And it absolutely works. Show us
how you do it. I can't I'm going to show
you. You actually trained him to wash
the dishes. Is that right? Not only did
I train him to wash the dishes, I
trained him to cook, pick up the kids.
Yes. Where is he here? No, he's busy
with the kids. I bet he's actually um
he's on the shoot. So Oh, wow. I'm very
proud of him. Okay, so let me show you
how to do this. You see it's a little
dirty. You put the Oh, wait. Hold up. We
got to open this. I use the dish soap
like this. I wet the sponge. You don't
put the soap in the water. You put the
soap right on. You don't want to do
that. I just put the soap right on. Kind
of want to go like this. Right. Just dab
it a little bit. And then what I'm going
to do is pop it in the microwave. Oh,
you don't have to actually scrub it. No,
no. This kills the germs, too. You put
it in the microwave
60 seconds. You know, I am a mother of
four, so I need things that are quick
and convenient. But, you know, if you
consider my husband, I'm a mother of
five. So, you just And then you hit
start. That's it. That's it. And when it
when you get it out, you have to scrub
it down a little bit. You don't. You
don't. It's actually clean. It
disinfected. You use it for a sponge.
You use it for a rag. Please don't use
any metal materials because I can't be
responsible if you blow something up. Of
course not. Your husband would tell me
that. Thank you very much. I appreciate
it. All right, let's see what else is in
the microwave. So, we've got our
something here that's pretty cool. It's
a cake in a mug. Looks pretty cool like
that. So, I want you to understand how
to make this. Gemma, she actually made
this in less than a minute. Take a look.
Hi, Dr. Oz. I know you can do a lot of
amazing things in a microwave, but did
you know you can make a cake in a
microwave? Let me show you how. In a
microwavable mug, you're going to mash
up your ripe banana. Next, we're going
to add in our peanut butter and mix it
well. Next, mix in your little bit of
sugar. Then, crack in your egg and mix
well. Keep on mixing until you see the
egg combined with the peanut butter. And
then, lastly, add in your cocoa powder.
Our chocolate mug cake is ready for the
microwave. Our chocolate mug cake is
done and it smells gorgeous. This
chocolate cake is full of protein,
gluten-free, and it tastes great. So,
one of the great things about these mug
cakes is that they're portion controlled
for those times where you just need some
cake.
All right, Constus is here. He says,
"Our microwave can make up for all your
mistakes." How is that, Constus? How
does it protect us from our errors? All
right, so the microwave is my best
friend. I am a very busy person. I'm out
the house by 4:00 in the morning and not
home until probably like 8 or 9. I need
my beans. I'm a vegetarian, so I eat a
lot of beans and rice. I don't have time
to soak beans for 24 hours. And if I
did, I probably forgot about them. I
would, too. So, here is a life hack.
You're going to take three cups of water
per one cup of beans. All right. So,
roughly this much. Yeah, roughly that
much. You're going to pour it in
here. All right. So, we have it poured
in. And what you're going to do, you're
going to take it take this and we're
going to put it in the microwave for 15
minutes. After the 15 minutes, you're
going to let it soak for an hour so that
the water will absorb into the beans and
make it really soft. All right. So, 15
minutes. 15 minutes. And then 1 hour of
just letting it cool off and everything.
That's the same. And then you can make
whatever you want to make out of it. You
make whatever it really really soft.
Yeah. I got It seems too good to be
true, but you're absolutely right. I'm
telling it works. I do it all the time.
So why would anybody soak their beans
from now on? I don't understand. Like
this is 2015. It's time to move on.
We're done with soaking beans. All
right. Very nicely done. Thank you so
much to all my guests. I appreciate the
tips. You can find out more things you
can do. We can microwave on dr.com. I'll
be right back.
[Music]
What's your favorite microwave hack?
With a young child, we're always looking
for ways to save money. When our sponges
get a little old, I moisten them and put
it in the microwave for a minute. Perks
it right up. Good as new. Share yours on
facebook.com/drz. Next. Do you get
confused when you shop the dairy aisle?
From whole to skim to the new designer
milks on the market, what do these dairy
labels really mean? Are these new
enhanced milks really worth your milk
money? Find out which carton is best for
you coming up next.
[Music]
This video might have appeared on your
Facebook page. It showed up on mine and
it's gotten over 13 million hits. Take a
look. I got to get the bread of milk. I
got to get the bread of milk. I got to
get the bread of milk. They said snow. I
got to get the bread of
milk. Oh my god.
I got to get I got to get the bread of
milk. I got to get the bread of milk. Oh
my
god. The truth is, no matter what the
weather, milk's at the top of everyone's
grocery list. But let's face it, the
milk aisle is getting confusing. From
whole to skim to new designer milks.
Today, I'm going to tell you what milk
labels really mean to help you become a
savier shopper. And there's someone here
today who, well, as you just saw, is
really concerned about milk. Please
welcome the bread and milk guy, comedian
Vic Dado.
Hey, I gota get the bread and milk. Got
to get the bread and milk. I got to get
the bread and milk, doc. I got to eat
the bread and milk. They said snow.
What's What What is the emergency here?
I love it. It's ridiculous. We have lots
of friends. Come on over here. Come on.
Let's have fun. Nutrition divine, author
of Secrets for a Healthy Diet. Monica
Fried Nagels here. How are we, Monica?
Hey, Monica. So, she's going to simplify
it for us. make it easy for people like
me and you who don't get this stuff
sometimes. So, look over to the side
there. You see the skim milk? This is
We're going to talk about the skinny on
skim milk here. Which of these do you
normally buy from that top shelf? I
actually go for the skim milk. This one
right here. Well, that's enhanced skim
milk. Is that what you drink or you
drink the regular? I drink the regular
skim milk. There's nothing better than
an ice cold glass of skim milk with a
box of chocolate chip cookies.
You had me. I can cook. Am I right? All
right. Help us. What does the label
mean? First, what does enhanced mean
versus regular skim milk? Okay, so I'm
sure Is this the first one that's gone
on the shelf during a snowstorm? This is
the last one. This is the I I got
knocked over lady with a walker for this
one. So, they enhance this is skim milk.
I'll model it. So, non-fat milk, but
it's got extra protein and extra
calcium. And they do that by adding
dried milk powder to it, just like the
instant milk that you might have in your
cupboard at home. So, this is regular
cupboard. Is this the enhanced stuff?
This is the enhanced over here.
Does it taste different? It's much
fuller. Yes, that's right. It tastes a
little bit less watery than skim milk.
Are these becoming pretty popular? The
enhanced ones, they've been around for a
long time and people do because it
tastes a little bit less watery than the
skim milk, but it's still non-fat and
people like the extra protein. So, this
is I agree with her. She's a
nutritionist. I think she knows. Stick
with me. Drag him over here while you
come. All right, next drinking area. No,
leave that. Leave that. We got more
shopping to do. So, about whole milk.
One of the biggest misconceptions is
whole milk. You say it's misunderstood
for a bunch of reasons. Well, actually,
yeah, I'd love to clear this up. You
know, people are afraid of whole milk
because they think it's high in fat,
right? All right. So, compare whole 2%
and skim, right? So, whole milk doesn't
have any of the fat taken out of it, but
it's still almost 97% fat-ree. And
that's what people don't understand. So,
here's here's what we have to kind of
explain this. And this this is right out
of my book. I tried to break this down
because people are really confused about
this. So in one whole container, one
whole quart of whole milk, you have just
six teaspoons of butter fat. That's what
that represents. But in 2% milk, the
reduced fat, four teaspoons. So it's,
you know, it's a little bit more than
half. Different, right? It's about 2/3.
And then down here in skim milk, just a
smidge. Yeah. But as Dr. Oz said
earlier, the more fat you take out, the
more milk sugar you're left with. So
everyone, my announcement today, I think
we should go to whole milk. I think
we're paying a price in taste and not
getting a benefit. And studies have
shown you're actually better off with
the whole milk. So that's not adultery.
Yeah, it's not a big difference in
calories. This is New York City. We got
a big three card monty. How about now?
Talking about it. Yeah. Go ahead. Now we
got All right, let's finish up with a
whole new milk. New kid in the block.
What do we got here? It's called
designer milk. Designer milk. What the
hell is designer milk? What is Gucci
going to make milk next? Yeah. You want
to lose weight? Take a few sips and
forget about the weight. You'll lose so
much weight, you'll disappear to put
your picture on the back of the milk
carton with a perfectly manicured milk
mustache. Milk from Gucci.
Well, you know, it's not far off. What
you just picked up there, that is called
Fair Life. Coca-Cola makes that. That's
right. Please explain to me to Why are
people making designer milks? Why would
the consumers want to try it? Well, this
is brand new and I'm getting a lot of
questions about this. So they start with
fresh milk and then they use a special
filtration process and they dial down
some of the nutrients that we might want
to limit like the milk sugars and then
they dial up some of the things that we
might want more of like protein and
calcium. So that's the deal with the
with the design. That's that's not these
are both.
You sure you can afford that? I tell you
I think this is really good. Oh, how
long has this been in here? This isn't
milk. This is cottage cheese. This is
this is
f are you concerned that a soft drink
company is making milk? Yeah, this is
raising a lot of eyebrows. I think you
know it's probably a lot better for us
than a lot of what they've been selling
us for the last years. On the other
hand, you know, all that processing
costs something. So, you are going to be
paying more. It's designer milk in more
ways than one. And some might argue
maybe milk is a food that doesn't really
need to be improved. Yeah. I got to say
I'd rather companies make products that
are good for us. And I want to applaud
people for trying to do that. All right.
You can catch Vic. I got a one question.
Is this chocolate milk? Oh my goodness.
Give me that. You can't afford that. You
know why I can't afford it? He's
starting with That's true. My wife told
me chocolate milk doesn't come from
brown cows. Is that true?
You know, he's starring with Kevin James
now when he says that kind of mall cop.
A mall cop part two. Fixing the movie,
right? April 17th it comes out. Do you
survive? Yes. I'm in a whole movie. I
play Gino Chisetti, a mall cop from
Staten Island who drinks his milk. Yeah.
All right. You can also catch him on an
exclusive oz video.com. We'll be right
back. Thank you. Thank you. I got to get
the bread and milk. I got to get the
bread of milk. I got to get the bread.
All new Emmy nominated Dr. Oz show.
Juliana Rancic. How you doing now? Sets
the record straight on the eating
disorder rumors, the stress and scrutiny
of her health, her marriage, her job,
and her heartbreaking baby news. Plus,
watch for dinner. Healthy one pot
wonders that are cheap. That's my kind
of meal. And we'll feed the whole
family. I'm putting my bib on now. All
new Oz. That's coming up
[Music]
tomorrow. Now, it's time for, in case
you missed it. First, we had some real
fun today with the Real Housewives of
New York. They dropped by. And I'm not
sure what Lisa will think of this, but
my staff came up with a few possible
taglines if I were a housewife. Take a
look. The big apple wasn't keeping this
doctor
away. The doctor will see you
now. When I bring healthy back, I do it
in style. I can handle trauma, but I
can't deal with
drama. So, do you all have a favorite?
You can let me know by voting on dr.com.
Let me know which one you think I should
be using next year. And before we go,
today is World Health Day, a day for all
of us to bring important health issues
into the spotlight. And I want to take
an opportunity to highlight three topics
that were not being discussed six years
ago when we started this show. So, I'm
going to share a special video on my
Facebook page that highlights these
issues. I feel strongly they ought to be
on your radar. So, take a look and share
it on your own Facebook wall to keep the
conversation going.
[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey. Hey.
[Music]
[Applause]