[Music]
I was told it's a little surprise in my
dressing room. But my goodness, it says
I'm smart, strong, brave, even fun with
a smiley face. It's pretty cool. But
who's responsible for this? And where
did it all come from? Got a feeling it's
from one of my guests today. So, I need
to do a little investigating. And I
can't wait for all of us to find out who
it is. Who did that?
[Applause]
Well, good news. I found out after a
long investigation who my mystery mirror
messenger is, she's the ultimate
survivor. From dominating daytime TV to
coping with serious health battles in
her daily life, Elizabeth Hasselbach is
here today
with a brand new view on what matters
most. And she's revealing how her faith
guided her into her new most important
role. Please welcome my friend Elizabeth
Hasselbeck.
[Applause]
Hi. You are brave and strong.
You're creative and fun and wise and
joyful. What else could I put on that
mirror? Brave. You put brave there.
Don't forget that. Brave. You are brave.
Oh, I'm kidding about that. You're brave
to sit with me. Well, you're kind of you
kind to come visit with it. Uh, thank
you for decorating the mirror. I'm
curious where the idea came from. You
know what? I think that and maybe it's
true for men, too. And I it must be
right because we're all human and
imperfect and we have those weak
moments. But I kind of I started doing
it for my kids and realized that I
needed it because I think the moment you
step away and even step into that mirror
like lies can sneak in. And I think
there's an enemy that wants you to
believe that you're not strong, that
you're not brave, that you're not
creative, and that those are lies. So I
really think that seeing yourself with
those words at the same time at the same
time every day um is just a
reinforcement of the truth. Where do you
get your daily strength, your your
motivation? You've always been such an
upbeat person. Well, I mean, I have to
credit my mom and dad for just raising
us to be like good, hardworking, um,
optimistic. Can I show them off? You
can. Mom and dad are here. They're here.
They're actually They dragged them into
the studio. There they are.
Congratulations. I know how hard it is
to raise an an adult child. Well, here's
what they did. I I love that they they
raised thinkers, um, hard workers, and
compassionate people, and I'm so
thankful for that. So I I adore how
people who are resilient can share with
the rest of America some of their little
tips and tricks and some a lot of it has
to do with faith but sometimes for
example with your ciliac ailment. So
when you were suffering through that how
did your faith play a role then how did
you actually you know surmount it? Well,
I thank you too because at the time that
I was writing about being Gf free and
gluten-free, there wasn't really like
ton of like movement with that and you
really I think encouraged me in that
movement to kind of take the lead. And
um you know, I love being a celiac. I'm
thankful for that because I think what
it's done is allowed me to kind of like
forge new territory and find food that
in fact is anti-inflammatory. So whether
you're a celiac or you're gluten-free
and you're that other percentage, I
think years ago was a 13%, it's probably
greater now. Um, I I think it's great.
I'm a cheerful celiac.
A cheerful celiac. I love that though
with the friendships that that you've
created in your life and I I'm blessed
to be one of your friends. So, I see
that close up. It reflected nicely in
this beautiful book. You mentioned point
of view, but uh point of view is is a is
a testimony to who you have become. And
I must say when when you left Fox and
Friends several years ago, I was very
worried about you. I didn't know what
had happened. I I I I didn't You reached
out to me, too. And I thank you for that
because I I could sense your your
concern and I I really needed to I think
as a person who works hard through
challenge and I talk there's some
stories in there about pushing through
things to a point. Um I think that maybe
I think I lacked rest and not just
sleep. So sleep I was really deprived of
sleep. I was probably for the first year
sleeping about three hours a night. Oh
my goodness. Because I wouldn't give up
on the day. Um I just knew I was hitting
the wall every day hard. And um I got to
a point where things and really I think
God allowed knowing how hard I would
work and how much I'd push through a
situation that for me I was mismanaging
the clock, not getting full rest and not
surrendering to the fact that if he has
you where he's called you to be, he will
enable you to do it. I was so worried
that I wouldn't get it right, that I
would get something wrong for my team,
that I wouldn't know enough information
about Syria or um a plane or I would I
wouldn't trust my capabilities. But I in
trusting your own capabilities again
there's a limit. I needed to trust his.
And so I wish I had figured that out
before I burned out, but I burned out
first. But God was kind because he let
that happen to lead me where ultimately
I think he knew I desired to be. It just
was the wrong season for me. I wish I
was at that position 10 years before my
kids were little. So it's not lost on me
you titled the book point of view
because the view is where most of us
came to know you well. And how did that
experience change you in ways that maybe
we didn't perceive from the outside?
That's why I've always been curious
about because I I've been on the show
enough times that I see how much
dialogue goes on. People are purposely
put on the panel because you're not
supposed to see eye to eye. Yeah. And I
think sometimes like it's a great thing.
I'm a champion of women who have passion
and opinion about topics and I think
gathering there each and every day and
everyone from Whoopi to Candace Cameron
to Barbara Walters and Joy Behar um and
the women that are on there now know
that you have to come back again and do
it the next day. So I don't think you
can I think categorizing it as some sort
of punching match or a cat fight
undermines the value of women having
thoughtful conversations about the tough
toughest topics and then doing it again
the next day and every day. Um, so I'm
I'm really thankful for that time and my
lens on it is gratitude. I'm thankful to
have learned under Barbara Walters for a
decade. Um, so I'm so thankful for her
leadership. Was she hard on me?
Absolutely. Because like a good coach,
she was refining me and I just watched
her for 10 years. I mean, I loved what I
studied about her and how she was such a
good listener. And when I needed a
doctor, a great one, she made the call.
When I was fired and needed another job,
she made the call. Oh, she did. Yes, she
did. She was the one I turned to to say,
"Hey, I'm in trouble now." And before I
could even breathe out another sob, she
was writing Roger's at Fox for me. So
there was I would not be where I am
today without her. So in the toughest of
moments, I turned to Barbara. And I
would also say Whoopi Goldberg and I in
terms of having a point of view, we
haven't always agreed on topics. And I
tell you in this book, we don't see the
same, but we love the same. So in the
book you talk a little bit about being
approached that fateful day that you
alluded to earlier when you were fired
from the view which I don't know if you
expected it at all the country was
shocked. I had no inkling this was even
happening. Two executives knock on the
doors. What happened? They walked in.
They walked in and you know they listen
fired is clear terms for we're not
renewing your contract when it expires
and it's like advanced notice on losing
your job. You're like I would have just
liked to know at the last day. Right.
Um, that was hard for me. It was hard
because I'm a loyal person. Uh, because
I had I really felt a duty and calling
in my job at the view. I think I must
have been hanging on a little too tight
to it. You know, if something has the
power to knock you down that hard, then
it must be a little bit of um an idol
and have a grip on you that it doesn't
deserve. You know, I really felt like
knocked down by it. And I literally kept
asking, "What can I do? What can I do
differently? Do you need me to do you
want me to cut my hair? Do you want I
described the moment it was it felt like
a mini suffering because I was losing
something that I was clinging to and I
was clinging to maybe the identity that
I needed to be there. And so that was a
hard transition for me, but I'm thankful
for that too. I'd get fired again if it
brought me everything after it. So So
what it's a beautiful way of looking at
it, but for someone right now sitting at
home who's suffering with the fact that
they don't have a job or they've lost
their job or they don't feel they're
valued by the people they're around,
what's the advice you give them? I think
you just nailed it. I think you don't
feel your value and it's just a matter
of not placing your value in the things
and even the things that bring you joy.
You just can't. Yeah. You got to write
your own story. Up next, if you'll stick
with us, I will. Liz is going to help
some of the audience revealing her
ultimate survival skills for overcoming
change when you least expect it. You
won't want to miss it.
We are back with the wonderful Elizabeth
Hasselblack. You know, she's going to
share a survival skill that can help
anyone face change in their own life.
It's to do some forgiveness math. we
need to forgive more. You got a little
mathematical equation mathematical. I'm
very proud of you for constructing.
Well, listen, I think it's it's pretty
common sense. And I think um I used to
think that there had to be a wrong plus
an apology to equal forgiveness, right?
That seems like the normal way of
thinking about it. Like, I'm going to
wait for you to say you're sorry and
then I'll forgive you. Yeah. But I what
I realized was that that doesn't lead to
a freedom in your heart and you just
kind of carry that around waiting. And I
don't think that God wants us to wait
around for forgiveness because he
certainly didn't exemplify that um with
us. So he forgave us first. And I'm
thinking, well, how can we do that?
Okay, so forgiveness comes first. Like I
forgive you before even you might feel
sorry. And then my heart's free. And
then you don't know the gift that you're
giving to someone else who might feel so
shameful or bad about how maybe they did
a wrong to you. Maybe you unlock their
heart too. But I will say I learned that
I didn't find freedom until I first
forgave. Um and the beauty of
acknowledging that we've been forgiven
as real.
I actually just to play on that a little
bit. I I think it's also very empowering
for the person who made the mistake. In
fact, I'm going to speak about something
that I care a lot about. Rosie
O'Donnell. She's been on the show. Yeah.
I know she's controversial, but I I I
really appreciate what she tries to do.
Her
apology to you, I think, came in part
because she felt that energy. I suspect.
I haven't talked to her.
How do you make sense of that? You know,
I think, listen, I think God does more
than we could ever imagine. And he knows
your friend's heart. He knows your
heart. And I think he wants us in
relationship with one another. He
doesn't want us holding our ground. He
wants us holding hands. And so I think
what happens when you just go first
like there is a domino effect in heart.
Be the person to go first. Go first in
your relationships. Go first in your
friendships. Go first in apology. And
just watch, you know, just watch. Go
first in your marriage. You know,
sometimes I wait for Tim. I'm like,
"Let's see if he like tells me I'm cute.
Let's just see." And I'm waiting. I'm
like, "What am I waiting for? Am I
scripting for failure?" That's right.
And so if you go first and you speak the
love language first, I promise you this.
God blesses that. You're going to have a
joy in it. We're meant to give stuff
away, give our hearts away. And so I
think when you do that, the beauty is
that um it it does end up creating this
sort of momentum of heart and I like
that. Like I'm I'm going to go first.
Yeah. Well, I think I think all of us
really appreciated how you handled all
the issues with Rosie, but all the other
things in your life as well. You're a
classy woman. You go first. You send a
very clear message that people matter. I
think the way you even describe the
relationships that matter the most to
you. The fact that you can disagree, but
it's the love that'll bind us. It's
ultimately the biggest message we all
have to hear. And I'm glad that's all
God. That's all God because without that
I'm kind of cranky.
Elizabeth has back. God bless you. You
can hear more about her brand new book,
Point of View. It's a fresh look at
work, faith, and freedom by picking up
the book and reading it because it's
very well done. Lots more her in the
book. Thank you for watching.
[Music]