Today on Dr. Oz, new uses for everyday
things, summer edition. And the best
part is these great ideas are absolutely
free and they really work. Deodorant as
nail polish remover. This one I've got
to see. Watermelon to prevent wrinkles.
I think you should try it. A new twist
for flipflops and how tea can make your
toes smell better. It works. Coming up
next on Dr. Oz.
[Applause]
Thank you everybody. It is July and
everyone is stocking up on summer
essentials, including me. Deodorant,
check. Flip-flops, check. Watermelon and
iced tea, check, check, check. Check.
All the good stuff. Because today there
are new health uses for everyday things.
And the best part is these great ideas
are absolutely free and they really
work. You know how I know that? Because
you have tried them. In fact, you're
going to reveal them to me. First up is
Carol. She says she has the new health
uses for her summer essential, which is
deodorant. How are you, Carol? How are
you? And the first thing you apparently
like deodorant for is as a nail polish
remover. Nail polish remover. Why not?
So, basically, you take a nail polish
rem the spray, I'm sorry, and you spray
it on your nail, making sure that you
don't get your skin because you don't
want to get freezer wipe. Then you you
let it just sit for a little bit. You
take your cotton
ball, you take it off. Oh my goodness.
Look at that. To come off. Yeah. And you
don't have the smell of that um acetone.
How would you ever figure that out?
I mean, honest to goodness, why would
you ever think nail polish could be
removed with that deodorant because
deodorant just has lots of uses. So, why
not try it? And again, it doesn't have
that acetone and it has to be the spray.
Has to be the spray. Yeah. You can't use
a roll on. It has to be the spray. Any
spray will work. Any kind. Any spray
will work as long as you spray it. You
leave it on for a little bit. Let it get
saturated. Don't get it on your skin.
Get a cotton. I love when you guys come
up with these ideas. It's so smart. The
other thing I understand you do with
deodorant is you get into your jeans.
Yes, I do. I get into my
tight. You actually got some proof for
us, don't you? I sure do. Take a look at
this. I use deodorant on my legs to slip
into tight pants. It's my favorite
summer fix. I take any deodorant, apply
it all over my legs, and then slip into
my favorite skinny jeans. It works great
every time. There you have it. Deodorant
is not just for under your arms anymore.
Are these the jeans? These are the
jeans. But they fit perfectly. Yep. Not
just for your armpits deodorant. Who
would have thought? Once again, I have
to ask, why would you ever think I mean,
no, most people do not put deodorant on
their thighs, right? That's what my
husband said. Basically, what I do,
understandably is I took the deodorant
because when I come out of the shower,
I'm a little bit clammy. My skin is not,
you know, really smooth. So, I decided,
well, let's see what's the worst that
can happen. I rubbed it up and down. I
put one leg the other leg and before I
knew it, I slipped them up and I was
good to go. You're a very industrious
woman. I try. So, this time of year, a
lot of mosquitoes, right? See if this
picture looks familiar to you. These
things buzzing around there. And Carol
says she uses deodorant to take the itch
out of mosquito bites. This one I've got
to see. That is correct. So, basically,
when you get a mosquito bite, you take a
deodorant stick. You simply just I
pretend I was bitten here. Fantastic.
Right here, you pour. You just rub it
back and forth a little bit and before
you know it, that sting goes away. You
don't feel the itch. You don't have to
rub it in a bite. No, because now just
let it be. No pun intended. Just let
Very, very good. Thank you. Actually,
you know, come over here for a second. I
want you to help me, though. I got some
watermelon here. I love watermelon this
summer. It's so sweet. So, if you don't
mind, hand that out to the audience.
I'll take a couple of these to our guys
here.
All all the eaters out there. By the
way, here napkins here. Throw these
napkins around there.
So Natasha, Dalita, and Caitlyn, they've
all created a very interesting way of
using watermelon. They have a watermelon
skin spa here. You can pass that around,
too. Go take that up there. Thank you.
Don't spill it for the people in front
of you. Okay. In this spa, they're going
to show us their everyday uses for this
summer item. Natasha's going to start us
off. She uses watermelon to prevent
wrinkles. Yes. You already had it on. I
already have it on. The wrinkles are
going away as we're talking right now. I
literally see no wrinkles, but I see
other things there. So, what are you
wearing? It's a very simple facial mask.
It's one teaspoon of watermelon, one
teaspoon of crushed avocado. Leave it on
for 20 minutes, and it's going to
moisturize. It's going to replenish any
lost water into your skin, and you're
just going to feel great. I think you
should try it.
Well, it feels good. It does feel good.
It tastes good. It tastes good. Yeah.
Once again, I'm so fascinated the
viewers come up with these ideas. This
is not one of the obvious things you
would do to your face. It's not. But I'm
from California. We use avocados for
everything. So, why not put it on your
face and have the oil moisturize your
skin? Let me see myself in here. Yeah, I
like it. Yeah, I I could go there. And
it's really refreshing. You could feel
the the cool watermelon. I like the idea
of using the avocado because it's been
useful in many other areas. And I think
the idea on skin makes sense. Okay,
that's the first big problem. Dry skin
is very common. Delita uses it to help
her deal with the dry skin that
understandably you have trouble soothing
sometimes. Yes. Yes, I do. So up with
this mixture and what you want to do is
a teaspoon of watermelon juice, teaspoon
of honey. Just mix it together. Apply it
on the face. Leave it on for 20 minutes.
And then while you're waiting that 20
minutes, you can put a little tea little
honey and tea and have a little piece of
watermelon damp cloth. We could combine
these two approaches. Have a full meal.
Yeah. Have a spa party. Well, I I I get
honey as a as a emoleant, right? It
would seal the moisture. And I guess the
watermelon must get in there first.
Absolutely. Because watermelon is about
90% water, so that's more hydration.
It's got lycopine, too, which I also
love. Wonderful. Great idea. And how
long does it take for you to see the
results that you desire? Uh, actually,
for me, immediately. Leave it on for 20
minutes. Nice warm cloth to take it off.
I could actually feel how soft my skin
was. That meant hydration. Helps the
heat, too. Finally, Kayla's here. She
uses watermelon to treat summertime
breakouts. Is that a common phenomenon
for you? Yeah, definitely. Um,
especially with the gym, working out, a
lot of time the sweat on my face can
lead to acne and breakouts. Um, so I
came up with this mixture. It's one
teaspoon of watermelon juice and one
teaspoon of mashed bananas. Put it on
your face, leave it for 15 minutes. Um,
and then instantly within a week, I saw
better results. Um, and I use it. I
still use it all year round, too. Yep.
You know, I guess one thing I I like
about the concept in general is that
it's, you know, a lot of moisturizers
are oily, so they'll clog the pores. So,
if you can use watermelon, doesn't do
that. No, not at all. And I had tried
other products before. Um, they don't
work and you can spend a lot of money on
them. I was looking for an allnatural
fix. So, I went with this and right away
within a week, my skin was great. Well,
I'm very proud of you. Keep going to the
gym, by the way. All right. So, I've got
another everyday use for a very common
thing that you all have. It's an old
pair of shoes like these flip-flops.
Now, Angelique has found some very
creative new ways, healthy, valuable
ways of using old flip-flops.
Hi, Dr. Oz. I'm Angelique. I'm going to
show you three uses for flip-flops in
the summer. The first use is a squeegee
to remove all excess soap and water when
cleaning surfaces. Second, use as a
doors stop. Wedge it underneath the door
for a cost effective doors stop. The
third use is as a pet hair collector.
Sweep the floors, sofas to pick up the
pesty clumps of hair.
Yes, it's off my floor.
I love that concept. You know, I have a
lot of pets. These are pictures of me. I
took actually last night. These are all
my rabbit Buster and and Rocky the cat
and of course Rosie. All different
colors, but they all have lots of hair.
I'm going to start using my flip-flops
or other kinds of old shoes to clear up
those those hairs. So, we'll try it and
see if it works. Okay, let's get to one
more health use for a summertime staple.
It's iced tea. Molly, if you don't mind
joining me. So, you say you can use this
head to toe. So, let's start with the
head. I understand you use it for for
grays. Yes. I um do three tea bags in
boiling hot water with rosemary and
sage. Let it steep overnight and then I
spray it on my roots and it takes away
the grays for a few days. Why? There no
there no grays up there for sure. I use
it in between when I can't get to the
salon or if I'm busy or whatnot. So, I
understand you had a friend actually do
this. Here's before and after picture.
Is that right? So, she can do her full
hair because she's brunette. But as me
being blonde, I just do my root area.
That's a big difference. Yeah. Yeah.
Surprising, isn't it? But, you know,
think about it. You know, dark tea will
stain cups. It'll stain your teeth,
right? Yes. So, why wouldn't it stay in
your hair at least for a short period of
time? So, I like Yes. And I use black
tea. So, perfect. I don't know. Now, I
said head to toe. So, that's the head
part. Let's go to the toe part. So, also
I would steep um a couple tea bags in
hot or warm lukewarm water and soak my
feet in it to get rid of the summertime
odors from slip-on shoes and that type
of Do you folks have odors usually in
your uh in your toes and feet? No. Let's
just do you since it's your idea. You
sit over there. You smell your feet. I
usually they're steeping in it. I will.
Okay. All right. So, let's come on. Just
check it out here. I'll do one toe. You
do one toe. Let's go. Baby feet. Yeah.
Smells like tea. Smells like tea. It
works. It does. Mhm. Thank you very
much, Molly. Thank you. Anything else?
Are you good? No, I'm good. Thank you. I
like the tea because it helps dry out
the feet. One of the reasons they work
so well. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Next, Olympic swimming legend Amy Van
Dyken. The day her world changed when an
accident left her paralyzed, undaunted,
and unbroken. How she came back stronger
than ever. I'm going to live every
single moment to its fullest. Her
winning spirit is a lesson to us all.
Next, all new odds. Tips from a
worldrenowned cancer fighter. A very
special guest shares a provocative new
way to help you prevent the disease you
fear most. He even introduced me to my
wife. He my father-in-law.
Stop cancer before it even starts. This
is practical information oncologists
right now are using in their practice.
Steps everyone should take to live
cancer-free. All new Oz. That's coming
up on
[Applause]
[Music]
Monday. I've been waiting for this show
all year long. Today, how one of
swimming's iconic Olympic legends, Amy
Van Dyken, is turning her injury into
inspiration.
Decorated Olympic swimmer Amy Van Dykin
has been going for the gold all her
life. She was the most successful
athlete at the 1996 Summer Olympics in
Atlanta, winning four gold medals,
accomplishing what no other American
woman had done before. Her success
landed her on the iconic Wedis box, made
her ESPN's female athlete of the year,
and got her inducted into the US Olympic
Hall of Fame. In 2000, Amy won two more
gold medals in Sydney, setting even more
American and world records. After six
gold medals, Amy retired and married
former Denver Broncos punter Tom Ruan.
But this past summer, a tragic accident
changed Amy's life forever. Losing
control of her ATV, Amy drove over the
side of an embankment, severing her
spine and leaving her paralyzed from the
waist down. Today, how the beloved
Olympian is facing her biggest challenge
of
all. Amy Van Dykin is here. I remember
hearing the story when we spoke over the
summer. Uh it still to me is sort of
stunning and I have no idea how you
cope. So, if you don't mind, the key
question for me is was there ever a
point throughout this process where you
just wanted to throw the towel in where
you wanted to give up? Never. Not one
time. I'm so happy, Dr. Oz, to be here
every single day. I'm living on borrowed
time. I'm not supposed to be here. So,
I'm going to live every single moment to
its fullest. Turn lemons into lemon
cello, if you
will. So, that picture that we just
showed everybody of the spine that was
severed, that that's your spine. And
right next to the spine is the aorta,
the big blood tube. So, the operation
they had to do to stabilize you was a
very dangerous one. This is an operation
that people died during. In fact, the se
this the risk and severity was so
significant you said goodbye to your
husband. I understand before you went
into the O. I did. Yeah. My doctor, my
neurosurgeon, Dr. Tumi Allen said,
"Listen, I'm working in nanometers.
Chances are you're not going to make it
out. So, you guys need to say goodbye
just in case." And I thought in that
moment, I said, "Listen, in order for
him to live a full life, let him date."
So, I said, "You could move on. You
know, date, do what you need to do."
Because you hear stories about people
going, "I don't know what my spouse
would want me to do. Would they want me
to date?" And I wanted him to know that
it was okay. But surgery was over. And I
immediately, first thing I had to do was
say, "Whoa, whoa, take it back."
And who's the hot blonde in the corner?
No. That's right.
These are trying moments. Yeah. What
inspired you to keep pushing? Listen,
I'm happy to be here, Dr. Oz. I truly
am. So, I'm working so hard. I'm working
probably harder now than I did for the
games cuz I'm not going for a gold
medal. I'm going for my life back. I'm
going to be able to walk some someday.
Knock on wood. So, I have to push it.
So, you brush your husband along for the
trip. Tom is joining us front row, a
professional athlete. You've challenged
yourself in the past just to be the best
you can be. It's a whole different level
to watch your wife have to take the
brunt of this. How'd you find the
strength to be there for her? You know,
it was tough. it. But it was one of
those things where I knew what she was
going through laying there on the on the
table and what she was facing ahead of
her that I just had to just keep calm
and and just kind of be the rock. What
about the offer to get married again or
find somebody else?
Yeah, she took that right back right
away once once she came out of surgery.
So, if I can share this to everybody, we
did speak over this summer and I was and
I was following all this the you know
the the tweets and the social media that
you're putting out which is you know
most of the information we were getting
and this is the part that amazed me.
This is your attitude. This is a little
tweet that she sent out after the
accident. How many of you would would
say this if you're lying on your back
having been a multi- gold medal winner
just thinking out loud now I will get
really good seats at Diamondbacks games
and other favorite sports teams.
Awesome. Bring in my own chair as well.
So I got my own chair. I got good
parking too, right? And how do you do
that? I I I just I sit here thinking,
"Oh my god, I'd be so bitter. I'd be so
angry. All this I was given so much."
Yes, you did things most of us could
never imagine doing. Walking away with
gold medals in different Olympic games.
But then it's all seemingly taken away
from you. Mhm. If you would have told me
after my first games this would have
happened happened to me, I wouldn't have
handled it well at all because at that
moment I really didn't have a life
outside of swimming. Right. So now I've
had the life experiences, you know, to
be able to look at this and say it's
okay. Well, that was the undaunted and
unbroken. Amy put her winning spirit to
work. She's been working seven hours of
physical therapy every day. And we have
this footage. If you don't mind,
describe what this is there. I mean, the
amount of work that I know it's taking.
This is you in the pool. Yeah. And it
was very different. Um, you know,
because here I'm trying to do what I
used to do in swimming. Um, but it was
very, very different. Here I am learning
how if I fall on the floor, which
happens a lot, how to get back up, get
back up into my chair. Um, worked very
tirously at that. And, you know, you
learn how to live your life. So, there's
a milestone I know you've been seeking
and you have a big announcement about
it. So, I'd love if you don't mind to
share the news with all of our viewers.
Okay. Well, we had um an exciting day.
Uh not too long ago, a couple months
ago, I got had this big contraption that
was just strapped on me and I actually
walked. You did? Oh, there you are.
There you are. I did. Look at that.
Right. It makes me so happy. No,
seriously, it shows the wonderful
ability of the human body to regenerate
itself. And I do personally believe
we're going to be able to get ahead of
spinal cord injuries and find ways
connecting these nerves. is one of the
great frontiers. Yes. But it's the
undaunting spirit of people overcoming
the challenges they face day in and day
out day out that makes it all
worthwhile. I guess it's unbelievable.
You're back doing swimming competitions
now. You're you're refereeing them now.
Yeah. I actually call them. So when you
watch them on TV, I'm the person going
and that stroke really shouldn't look
like that at all. So yeah. Yeah. There's
me and one of my partners, Jason Knap.
So yeah, I'm back at it. And here's the
thing, Dr. Oz. put that headset on and
when you hear me, my brain and my mouth
are not paralyzed. You would never know
that I couldn't walk. It was a great
honor to meet you. Congratulations.
Thank you. And I have something for you.
I do. I do. Listen, when I got injured,
people started something and we have
made a foundation and I want you to be a
part I want you to be a part of Amy's
army if you don't mind. I would
love Amy's an honorary member. Thank
you. Amen. We'll be right back. Right.
[Applause]
Next. Can colors reveal your personality
and what does it mean for your health?
Colors impact our choices, feelings, and
behaviors. Decode your personality hue
with three simple questions. Find out
what color you are and the clues to
protect your health. Next, All New Odds
tips from a world-renowned cancer
fighter. A very special guest shares a
provocative new way to help you prevent
the disease you fear most. He even
introduced me to my wife, my
father-in-law.
Stop cancer before it even starts. This
is practical information oncologists
right now are using in their practice.
Steps everyone should take to live
cancer free. All new eyes that's coming
up on Monday.
I love learning about things that we
don't realize impact our health. So,
today I'm exploring how color can reveal
your true personality and what that
means for your health. It turns out your
personality color could be either red,
yellow, orange, or green. Here to help
find your personality color is an
innovator in the field of personality
behavior, Dr. Carol Whitberger. How are
you, Carol? I'm fine, thank you. So
color and psychology, how do you connect
them and how does that tell us much
about our health and our personality?
Color is a common language. We use it
all the time. Uh in the western culture,
it actually talks, we apply it to
behavior such as I'm red with anger or
I'm green with envy. So it's a very easy
uh way for us to look at personality.
All we got to do then is teach people
how to find their color. Dr. Ritberger
wants you to answer three simple
questions. It's multiple choice. Keep
track of your answers. Everyone in the
audience is going to do it. Everyone at
home do the same. First question. When
faced with a big project at home or at
work, you are a deadline driven while
you're watching the clock all the time.
B, you're worrying, spending most of
your time pretty anxious. C, you're
always scanning, looking for better
ideas. You got the best ideas for the
best concepts. You're happy then. D, you
make it a group effort. The more the
merrier. So, you have four choices. Pick
the one that applies to you. We all
clear on this. Okay. You pick your You
picked your letters already? All right.
Second question. When someone asks you
for a favor, you A want to know what
you're getting in return. B, you say,
"Yeah, sure." But you have second
thoughts right afterwards. C, you tell
them you're going to get back to them so
you can agree about maybe what you could
do together. And D, you agree and you go
full throttle and there's no turning
back. No changing your mind. All right,
that's remember your second letter. Now,
this the last question I'm going to ask
you. When you're stuck in traffic, A,
you honk your horn a lot. You got to get
home and you deserve to get home. B, you
never honk your horn. Why add to the
stress? C, you know all the shortcuts.
You're always finding new routes to get
home. And D, you dance along to the
radio, having a good time. All right,
you all got your numbers down, your
letters. You all clear on this. You know
what I am? Would you have to You
probably I do know what you are. What do
you think I am? I think you're a C. I
think you're a yellow. She's right. I'm
a yellow. I'm a prototypical yellow.
You're just a perfectionist.
All right. So, we're going to start with
the A's, though. I'm going to save
myself for later on. So, who Let me see
hands up. Who's all the A's out there?
There's got to be some A's. There's like
three A's over here. No one's
acknowledging it. All right, come on
over here. We're going to see what color
goes along with the A's. So, please
reveal the personality color, Carol. All
right, it is red. The red personality.
It's not unusual to not have a lot of
reds in the audience like this. That
personality is one that just get it done
people. They're competitive. They're
driven. They're deadline oriented. They
like to have control of their
environment. They like to just see that
everything gets done. No measurement on
effort. Bottom line. And what are the
health problems that A's typically have?
Uh A's typically tend to hold the stress
and the tension in their lower back.
Maybe that's why I have so much back
pain in America. A lot of A's in the
country. We do a lot of what we call
type A's literally and we see red.
Absolutely. They see red. All right,
friends. Angelina Carol joining us to
help us now. Carol answered mostly B's
and Angelina answered mostly C's. Dr. Go
ahead and show the color that goes along
with the bees. It is orange. Orange. The
orange personality is the just let's get
it along people. They just they're
cooperative. They're kind. They're
generous. They always put other people's
needs before their own. Yep. Well, one
of the things with the orange is that
the way your brain works is you have to
make sense of things and it has to feel
right. So, it's like your brain is
always going back and forth and if you
don't have the time to do that, it shows
up in your lower stomach. Okay? And then
what you do is then it can uh cause you
to worry and then that changes the
chemistry of your body and dog gone they
end up with depression. Depression.
Angelina. Is that possible for Carol? I
don't think so. Actually, I was drawn to
Carol cuz she's so happy. So I don't
Yeah, very happy people. But they do
worry. Do you worry? I do worry. Yeah,
most definitely. Yeah, they worry about
anything and everything. Yeah. Does that
sound right? I could see her worrying
about some things. Probably a little
bit. Let's Let's turn the tide here. Go.
Go into the seas over there. I'm going
to see what they think now. So, Angel,
it's your turn. Okay. You want over
there? Go ahead. Reveal the color to All
right. So, the question is for all these
seas out there, your color is yellow.
Yellow. I'm a yellow. You're a yellow.
You're a yellow. I'm a yellow. You are
great people. We get great people. We're
just wonderful people. That's one of our
qualities. We're not necessarily the
most humble. No. Yes. No. Take it. Take
it humbleness to a new low. Exactly.
Exactly. So, what's our personality
type? So what that says is that you like
to do things different. Kind of the
motivation is to build a different
mousetrap. Everything about you is
visionary, innovative, and never wanting
to be really boxed in so you can really
think about things. And so what are the
health problems Angelina and I are going
to have? Well, one of the things is we
actually hold the stress in our stomach
area. It's like we following that gut
instinct. And then what happens when we
don't do that? We get all this tension
and we actually are prone to tension
headaches. Yeah. And that's one of the
things that we end up with. It sounds
like it might be on target. Absolutely.
I hope that's helpful to the two of you.
Let me turn to the last color. D's. How
many D's are out there? Show hands. D's.
There are a number of D's. All right.
The D's are greens. That's correct. So,
what what does the green color mean?
Very happy people. They like everything
to be teamwork. They're dreamers. They
love to create. They love to see all the
possibilities and things. And they truly
believe that if you think you can do it,
you can do it even if it's the very
first time. And what are the health
problems they run into? One of the
things with greens when they get
stressed is they tend to hold their
breath. And when they hold their breath,
uh, then what happens is those shoulders
start creeping up. So, they have a lot
of neck and shoulder problems. Let me
see the greens again. Put your hands up
here. We got some here. Let me come over
here. I want to see how accurate this
is. Stand up if you don't mind. Does
that sound like you at all? What's your
first name? My name is Cara. Cara, did
that sound like you at all? That sounds
100% like me. 100%. Number one, I'm I'm
a fizzad teacher and a coach, so I'm
constantly encouraging my students and
motivating them. I'm always happy. Like
anyone who sees me, they're like,
"You're always so happy and so
energetic." So that definitely fits me.
Yeah. Just a silver lining with
everything, isn't there? Yeah. Thank you
very much. Wonderful news. Pleasure.
Appreciate being here. You can find out
more about your color personality. You
can take the online quiz at dr.com.
Check out Dr. Vber's book, What Color Is
Your Personality? I'll be right back.
Next, television icon Larry King. His
controversial plan to live forever.
Freeze your body as you die. If they
cure whatever I died of, I come back. I
want to be around. You know who's going
to win the World Series. Coming up, all
new odds. Tips from a worldrenowned
cancer fighter. A very special guest
shares a provocative new way to help you
prevent the disease you fear most. He
even introduced me to my wife. Leave my
father-in-law.
Stop cancer before it even starts. This
is practical information oncologists
right now are using in their practice.
Steps everyone should take to live
cancer free. All new eyes. That's coming
up on
[Applause]
[Music]
Monday. Larry King is a television icon,
a true survivor. He had a major heart
attack, quintuple bypass surgery.
Neither stopped him from becoming one of
the great interviewers of our time. At
age 81, he's still going strong and has
what most will consider a controversial
plan to try and live forever. Please
welcome my friend Larry King.
[Music]
[Applause]
I like the look here. You like this look
like
this. So that was always the
look. So when I was please, you know, I
would always be in the hospital late at
night, you know, trying to finish my,
you know, last case of rounds and I'd
watch you every evening. It was a very
formative experience for me. And you had
the the suspenders on all the time. I've
never worn suspenders on the show
before, but they actually have a health
benefit I've learned from getting your
posture fixed. Is that true? You're
kidding. No, I'm serious. I looked it
up. Is there any reasonable person who
would wear suspenders in this day and
age? And the argument is if you want to
remind yourself about a good posture, do
what Larry King does. I never thought of
it. I do it just cuz I lost a lot of
weight after my open heart surgery. And
it was suggested that I would look good
with braces. I used to wear You look
very good. There's one clue I could give
you, though. Please, please help me.
Don't wear a belt when you wear braces.
Yeah. What? This is a bad idea. I don't
know what I was thinking. Yeah. Much
better now.
Gone. Here, duck. Yeah. Surprise. All
right, let's get right to it. Uh, we've
been talking a little bit about this
idea you have of living forever. I'm
going to define it for everybody, but
I'd love to hear your thoughts on it.
When I say living forever, this is not
sci-fi anymore. Now, there's the ability
to do cryopreservation to freeze your
body as you die. So, what is your hope?
I I'm I'm I was raised Jewish, but I
lost my religion a long time ago. So,
I'm I'm an agnostic atheist. I don't
think you're going anywhere. All right.
So, I think when you die, that's it. And
I don't want it to be it. I want to be
around. So, I figure the only chance I
have is to be frozen. Yeah. And then if
they cure whatever I desire of, I come
back.
What's the thought? Oh, what is it? a
better thought than being in the ground,
being cremated. What would you like to
be educated a bit about what exactly
happens when they freeze you? Yeah, I
would like to know exactly what
happened. Y'all want to know that a
little bit? Come on
over. The reason I had a belt on was my
mic pack, but there okay. That's all
right. It looks okay. Just like this.
Oh, come over this side. It's better.
It's a better view for you. How do you
know about everything? I study. I study.
So, hold your suspenders. Should hold
yourself up just in case. So this is
what happens. Okay, so they just said
you're gone. They throw you in ice as
fast as they can. The cry pres
preservation starts immediately. They
start pumping on your chest with this
machine to circulate the blood. Then
they can put a breathing bag to give
oxygen to you at the same time. So now
they're basically doing what they would
do if you were still alive. The reason
they do this is as everything
circulating through, they now have time
to put a needle in your arm and give you
a medical grade antifreeze. This cold
solution is then pumped not just to your
arm, but into your chest. very low
temperature until you ultimately get to
a really really cold place where there's
no metabolism happening. The cells that
are there are still alive and they're
kept that way. Then they put you in this
big casket. It's a freezer basically.
They flip you upside down. They freeze
your body and they put you with three of
your best friends because you're going
to be stored in these containers for
some time. And then ultimately, as you
say, if there's a reason to unfreeze
you, we figure out how to unfreeze you.
Then you're unfrozen together with your
three colleagues there. What about the
story they cut your head off? So, you
can also just freeze your head. That's
cheaper, by the way, if you're
interested. Yeah. They cut your head off
and then they can put that fluid right
into your head. Although, I got to say,
I'd preserve the whole body. If you're
going to do it, do it right. I'll do it
right. I'd preserve the whole body. But
then, how do they know in in in that
tunnel there, that guy died of this?
Well, they're going to have all the
record. They got to keep the record. But
as a physician, the part that's
intriguing is keeping enough of your
cells alive that one day they could make
a bionic version of you. That's sort of
the hope, right? That's why they
preserve just a head. They figure
they'll get a different body. That
body's done. They'll put a different
head on a machine and you'll have
awareness. Now, my wife, whose picture
you have up, I see that. Yes. Uh she
said to me, "You come back in 200 years,
you won't know anybody." So, I said,
"I'll make new friends."
Well, actually, what is the first thing
that you would do? The very first thing
you would do if they were to all of a
sudden unfreeze you and you had
awareness that you were back in life 200
years from now. Oh, I' I'd be asking
questions. Who's who's around? What are
they can you transport uh can you go to
the moon? What was science
fiction 40 years ago is fact. For
example, I had bypass surgery. There was
a book in
1947 in which a doctor put a person on a
heart lung machine. It was science
fiction. It was they did bypass and they
wrote about this and people said it's
nuts. Yep. Wasn't done till for 10 more
years and we never thought it was
possible. In fact, doctors would get
fired if they exposed the heart because
no one had ever survived. They've been
seeing the heart was a lethal injury.
But your heart was seen. It was seen
when they did the bypass surgery you
discussed. You went from being a fairly
sickly person in 1987, right, with when
you had the operation, smoking and the
like. So, here you are all these years
later, healthier than you've ever been.
How did you do that? How did you make
that change? Well, I got first I stopped
smoking immediately and I thought I'd
never stop smoking. I was a threeack a
day smoker. A doctor told me, a
psychiatrist, a friend of mine said what
I became
was scared straight. Yeah. that I still
wanted a cigarette, but that emergency
room brought me back. I never smoked
again. Well, kudos to you because a lot
of folks don't hear that much. This show
at its very core is about getting people
to realize they control their I watch
you all the time. I'm amazed at you
because I never saw a guy. You know
about everything.
God knows. The man knows everything.
Well, talk about an inquisitive person.
You're a curious fellow. You're always
moving around, keeping active. In fact,
in your own neighborhood, you know, he's
walking going around in LA and you got
caught by paparazzi recently. If you
could tell this story, I would never
considered this possibility, but Larry
King pow-wowing with Justin Bieber. What
is going on here? This is a P. Look at
this picture. Look at this. He's
assaulting you. He like a driveby. It's
like a fan. First of all, cars are
honking. Other people are yelling.
People are screaming Justin Bieber.
Larry kid got it almost. It was wild. I
love it. It was crazy. Now, you must
your kids must beautiful wife, as you
mentioned already. gone. Uh, and two
wonderful children. They must be the big
fans, I gather. They keep you young, and
having a young wife keeps you young. But
you know what I do? No, this the truth.
You saw the
picture. You see that picture of her,
when you have someone who looks like
that and I look like I look and there's
obviously an age difference, right? I
mean, come on. So, I know what people
are thinking when they see us. So, I
always say the same thing. If she dies,
she dies.
Larry King, you'll be here all week. Be
sure to check out Larry's show. He's got
Larry King now and politicking on Aura
TV. Wonderful programs. We'll be right
back. Love
that. Thank you very
[Music]
much. Next, are you stressed and have no
energy? Learn how you can heal yourself
with an ancient Chinese remedy. With
simple body movements and breathing, you
can use your body's natural energy to
promote healing and help prevent
disease. Three moves to have you feeling
great. Next, whoever said a doctor's
visit isn't fun has obviously never been
to the Dr. Oz show. Is that right? Make
your appointment today. Go to
dr.com/tick and sign up for free
tickets.
[Music]
All right, let me do a little experiment
with the audience. I want you, anyone
who is stressed, stand up right now. Oh,
yes. We got a lot of Hallelujah here.
Stand up. If you have no energy, stand
up. Got a couple stragglers here. Okay.
If you're having any pain in your life,
stand up. We got just about everybody
here. Yeah, actually, we did literally
get everybody. All right. I just gave
you three good reasons to try Chiang.
So, go ahead and sit down, get
comfortable. Nothing bad's happening to
you. Kung Fu master and Chiang expert
Carl Roma is here. He's going to show us
how these ancient Chinese remedies
really work. How are you? Good. How are
you? So, explain to everybody what
Chiang is. Why should they be excited
about if they stood just now? Chiang is
a practice that has been used in Chinese
medicine for centuries. Includes breath,
movement, and mental imagery to move the
body's energy to prevent disease. So,
how does it heal you if you actually
already have a problem? Well, cheese
energy gung is work. So, chiong is using
the body's natural energy to promote
healing. You know, the Chinese believe
that all sickness in the body is caused
when chi or energy is blocked. Western
research is just catching on to this.
Here's why I trust Carl. He taught my
wife how to do these martial arts
techniques on me. It's terrible. It's a
very dangerous place when they go home.
It's like getting attacked by KO. All
right. This stuff is so powerful that
it's actually been taught all around the
country now. Major medical centers
teaching Chiang. And of course, it's
used by, you know, more than a billion
people in China. So, we got six audience
members to help us out today. And we're
going to get to all these different
causes. Welcome everybody. I hope you're
nervous. I am. We're going to do a bunch
of Chiang moves. They're going to work
for some of the most common ailments we
have in America. The first reason to
chai Chiang is stress relief. And the
first move is called cooling the fire of
the heart. How does this help to reduce
stress? Well, it calms the mind and
soothes the heart. The heart in Chinese
medicine is connected to the mind. So,
this is great for stress reduction. All
right. Do you want to show us? Yeah,
absolutely. Work along with us. So, what
we're going to do is we're going to
start with our feet shoulderwidth apart,
knees slightly bent. Okay. Back is nice
and straight. Good. Posture is very
important. And we're going to breathe
deep diaphragmic breaths. And we're
going to bring our hands out to the
side. And you want your palms up. I'm
just going to slide over a little bit.
Raise your hands overhead. Take a deep
breath in. Exhale. And slowly let those
hands fall. Good. Now, it's really
important to keep the tongue in the roof
of the mouth and teeth together. And
breathe through the nose. All right.
Here we go. I kind of
inhale and exhale. Nice and slow. Don't
let those hands touch. Keep those hands
apart. Bring them right down. That's it.
Good job, Bashar. One more.
Inhale and
exhale. You can feel how relaxing that
is. That's nice, isn't it? You keep your
tongues up to to the roof of your mouth.
They weren't able to talk that way. All
right. Next, we're going to boost your
energy with Chiang. And this is a move
called bouncing the ball. How do you
bounce the ball to boost your energy?
Well, in Chinese medicine, the kidneys
are in charge of our energy. So, we
don't want our energy to be too high or
too low. We want our energy to be even.
The best time to do this is late in the
afternoon when you have that afternoon
slump and you need a pickme up or if you
suffer from insomnia and you can't sleep
at night. It's a great way to bring your
energy down so you can relax. So it
balances us. Balances. Show us the move.
All right. So here's what we're going to
do. Again, starting from the same
starting position. Very simple. We're
going to slide our foot in. As we slide
our foot in, we're going to raise the
opposite hand. That's it. And then bring
your foot down and slide the other side.
Excellent. Move from side to side. Deep
breath in. Exhale as you come up. And
you feel that nice gentle rocking
movement. Very soothing, isn't it? Your
hands are parallel like that, not Yes.
You want them parallel to the ground.
And you want your standing legs slightly
bent. You also want to find one point
with your eyes to focus on. That'll help
you to keep your balance. I'm focused on
you. All right. Anyone falling back
there? No fallers. It's actually once
you get into the rhythm, it's it's it's
a little sleeker than you think. Yeah.
All right. Last thing you guys were all
talking about was pain. So if you want
to reduce pain, there's a move in Chiang
called castingqing chi from side to
side. So how does this cleanse the body
and reduce pain? At least in the Chinese
mindset. When there's pain and
inflammation in the body, that's because
there's a buildup of toxins. This
exercise works on the liver. And the
liver's job is to clear, purify, and
remove those toxins to ease the pain.
Okay. Okay. So this is real simple and
fun, too. All right. So pretend we're
splashing water on each other. Guy's a
world champion martial artist, by the
way. So, when he says it's going to be
fun, I get I get nervous. Anyway, keep
our knees bent. Okay, back nice and
straight again. And I want you to
pretend you had a bucket of water in
your hand. And I want you to just kind
of lean over to the side. And as you do
it, keep your feet flat and just kind of
exhale and let it go. And then inhale
back to center and let it go to the
other side. Inhale and exhale. And you
can feel that pain leaving your body.
Right, Dr. Oz? I was feeling okay
before. Now, now my back hurts. All
right, so we got to put them all
together. Nice and slow. How would you
do it all together? All together. So,
we're going to do one of each. Okay. So,
first, ready? Inhale. Cooling the fire
of the
heart.
Exhale. Right from here, we're going to
slide our leg in and raise the hand.
Opposite hand, opposite leg. Inhale and
exhale. And then bring it down. Ready?
Hands in front and off to the side. So,
this is what they're doing in the
streets of China all the time. You see
older folks doing this all day long,
actually in the morning usually. And
it's so gentle. Anybody can do it. You
can do it anywhere at any time and start
reaping the benefits of it. You can get
all of Carl's wonderful moves. They're
on dr.com. Just, you know, look on
Chong, you'll find it. We'll be right
back.
[Music]
All new Oz tips from a worldrenowned
cancer fighter. A very special guest
shares a provocative new way to help you
prevent the disease you fear most. He
even introduced me to my wife. Leave my
father-in-law.
Stop cancer before it even starts. This
is practical information oncologists
right now are using in their practice.
Steps everyone should take to live
cancer free. All new eyes that's coming
up on
[Applause]
[Music]
Monday. Now it's time for in case you
missed it, I got a special treat at the
end that you're not going to want to
miss. But first, incredible news today.
Talk show legend Larry King has a plan
to cryopreserve. That means freeze his
body as he dies or after he dies. Right
afterwards. Ever wonder how this works?
Well, I showed it to him. I'm going to
show it to you. It's not science
fiction. Cryopreservation starts the
moment that you pass away. They immerse
you in ice to try to preserve the cells.
And this vice bath is augmented by
pumping into your body medical grade
antifreeze. Your blood's removed. It's
antifreeze. Allows the body to be
preserved. Keeps the cells alive. The
body's then put in a sack and in in a
box in a and that is basically put into
a freezer, really really cold freezer
with three close friends now because you
can be there for a while. But here's the
catch, my friends. Science has not
actually figured out how to unfreeze
people yet. You know, we know how to
freeze them. We just can't unfreeze
them. So, if one day this comes in
handy, it'll be quite a bit of time in
the future. But you never know. Lari
made pretty good arguments about how the
world changes so fast that you can't
keep up unless you do things like this.
All right. Now, I want to welcome a very
special guest on the show today. Her
name is Marne. Marne the dog. She's
what's called Insta famous. She has
wiggled her way into the hearts of over
1 million people on Instagram and
Twitter. And it's easy to see why. Come
on out. Marty is the
[Applause]
[Music]
dog. What I love about Marty, at the
first glance, she doesn't look so
perfect, does she? She sort of winding.
She actually has an illness that makes
her head and that causes her tongue
to hang out. But I think that makes her
really cute cuz there's actually nothing
wrong with her. She's so cute. And look
at this. I look at this. Come on. That
is How are you? Hi. Nice to meet you.
She's always turning. I guess she goes
to her left, right? Only to the left.
Never to the right. True. And why is
that? Um I I'm not sure, but that's the
way she's comfortable walking. And so
that's cool with me.
What is it that made you want to adopt
her? I mean, this is so cute. Well, I I
was looking to adopt a dog. I found her
on petfinder.com, which is a website to
adopt homeless animals. But she turned
out to be the most amazing dog. Yeah.
Amazing in a lot of ways. Now, she also
adopted Marty knowing that she was a
senior dog. I did. Yeah. Um, we don't do
a lot of that in America. Well, they're
so grateful when Yeah, absolutely. Here,
you can just hold her like a baby. She
likes to be held that way. I love this.
This is the cutest. Can you see this?
Look at this.
Oh, come on. She's central casting for
cute. Yeah. So, um they say that senior
dogs have the hardest time getting
adopted from shelters. And um you know,
there's millions of dogs that get killed
every year. Um so, to me, I just never I
never even considered buying a dog when
there's so many that need uh homes.
Well, I'm very proud of you for finding
Marty. I'm sure she's loving her life
with you. Marty, see how cute she is.
We'll see you all next time.
[Music]
[Applause]