Today, a health alert for everyone who
has taken one of these sleep aids and
medications. New startling data shows
one out of three of you tell us you're
taking sleep aids to fall asleep,
whether it's over-the-counter or even
allergy meds. And for the first time
ever, I'm revealing the results of a 4
million night sleep investigation to
find out just what these sleeping pills
are doing to your sleep and to your
brain. Are these pills hooking you up,
taking good care of you, and or are they
keeping you in a vicious cycle of poor
sleep? It's a health alert that can't be
ignored. Doctors around the country are
sounding the alarm about patients over
relying on sleeping pills. Sleep loss
and sleepwake problems are considered a
national epidemic. Self-medication with
over-the-counter sleep aids is okay in
some circumstances. It's not okay in
others. It's not a good idea to rely on
those for long-term help. You can also
have difficulty with dizziness and
confusion and falling over. And
long-term it can cause problems with
severe difficulty with memory. For the
nearly 70 million Americans struggling
with sleep disorders, a pill may seem
like an easy answer. For the past 3
years, I haven't been able to fall
asleep organically. So, I've had to rely
on this over-the-counter sleep aid to
help me fall asleep. I cannot fall
asleep unless I take a sleeping
substance. That's why I launched my
sleep investigation using sleep score
data from 4 million nights of sleep
across the
country. Using sleep score, we were able
to track not only the hours of sleep,
but also the quality of sleep by
collecting information on light sleep,
deep sleep, and REM sleep. What we
uncovered might make you rethink taking
that nightly sleeping
pill. Our sleep team is here today.
Sleep expert Dr. Tenuja Hamilton and Dr.
Jennifer Codle along with the sleep
challenge group of viewers who say they
all have taken sleeping pills within the
past month and they have volunteered
their sleep info for our four million
night sleep investigations. A lot of
people. So, we're going to dive right
into what we have uncovered. Four out of
10 women in our study tell us that they
are using sleeping pills. four out of
10, which means it's even a bigger
problem in women than in men. So, Dr.
Carter, why why are they relying so much
on sleeping pills? Well, you know, you
have a really good point about women
using sleeping pills. We know that the
majority of people who use sleeping
pills are women. Could be a number of
things, whether it's like the pressures
of life or stress or maybe even
hormonal. You know, as a family doctor,
I have a number of post-menopausal
patients who uh complain that their
sleep has been disturbed since um going
into menopause. But the thing about it
is the sleep uh pill medication, you
know, industry is a $ 41 billion
industry. Goodness, we're spending over
41 billion dollars a year on sleep
medications. And now with over-the-c
counter medications, they're more and
more readily available. Dr. Hamilton,
why are people making mistakes? What are
the typical ones they're making with
these pills? Well, people need to
realize that over-the-counter sleep aids
are not intended for nightly usage. In
fact, people are taking them more and
more, and if you take them nightly,
you're going to need them nightly. There
are warning labels out there that say
you shouldn't take them more than two
weeks at a time, and people are mixing
them with medications, anti-anxiety
medications. This can increase
confusion, sedation, disorientation, and
even worse, cause a drop in your blood
pressure. I'm going to emphasize
something. The label actually says don't
take it for more than two weeks. Am I Am
I right? That's right. So, even if we
just read the instructions, we see it
right there. We ought to be smart about
this. So, let me bring in some of these
women who say they are using steep meds.
If you don't mind, get me show hands and
thank you for volunteering to be honest
and a part of this. How many of you take
a steep aid once a week? Hands
up. We're pretty much almost everybody.
All right. Three times a week. Who's
using three times a week? Who's using
them five times a
week? My goodness, it's a lot of you.
Are you surprised? Exactly. According to
our 4 million night investigation, most
women who take a sleep aid you you they
use one of these over-the-c counter
sleep pills. So, it's not a doctor
prescribing it to you. Joy, I noticed
that you put your hand up when they're
the five times a week issue came up,
which implies that you're taking
probably more than you want to. Yes,
correct. So, what do you think about
this? You're not alone, by the way. No.
So, what when did you start taking them?
Um, I would say I travel a lot. So, I've
been I'd say for the past 15 years.
15 years.
Yeah. On and off for 15 years. What kind
of worries do you have about that? Um I
would like to find something more
holistic to, you know, help me sleep
instead of taking a pill to help me
sleep five to seven nights a week.
Right. Are you are you all desirous of
getting off sleeping pills? Yes. Okay.
So, you're on something you don't want
to be on and we got to find some answers
for you. So, Dr. Hamilton, what exactly
are people taking to fall asleep? Well,
dyenhydrine is in many over-the-counter
sleep aids, and that's an antihistamine.
Now, it can help you sleep when it
crosses the bloodb brain barrier, but in
the body, it can also help with
allergies. Now, people might take
allergy medications to help them sleep.
They might have other ingredients. You
may not know the correct dose, and that
can become a problem. In fact, if you
mix it with other medications, alcohol,
there are dangerous results that could
happen from I mean, if you're taking an
a pill for allergies and you try to
sleep with it, it's that's not not the
primary reason folks came up with the
solution. Right. Now, you say there's
some side effects we can run into. These
are sleeping pill hangover side effects.
Something that I hadn't thought of much.
So, please walk us through them because
I bet a lot of you, especially if you're
taking a lot of these pills, might be
running into these. Yeah. Well, patients
will take sleeping pills and say, "Why
aren't I feeling refreshed? Why aren't I
feeling great? I'm still tired the next
day." Well, in fact, the effects of the
medication can linger into the next day
and that can cause you to be overt
tired. It can give you blurry vision and
it can affect your mental alertness and
that can be a problem with work
performance and even worse motor vehicle
accidents, right? Can be very severe and
it seems so safe you're taking an
overthe-c counter product, right? And
that's the problem. Who would think? In
fact, here's a sleep confession Julie
made after taking an OTC sleep med.
I take the over-the-counter sleeping
pills because I have a hard time staying
asleep. I can fall asleep, I just don't
stay asleep. So, I've tried everything
over the counter. And every morning, I
wake up and I feel groggy and cloudy and
I can't shake it off.
Julie, you don't look very happy there.
So, what is it like when you can't get a
night a good night's sleep? I can't
function at work. I'm cranky. I'm angry.
I'm on edge. I I just feel like I need
to go back home and go to sleep. Yeah.
Which is how a lot of American females
are feeling now. That's called How does
a sleep pill hangover work? Well, and
this is a real thing, let me tell you.
So, you might have problems sleeping,
okay? And you take a sleep pill. Okay,
that's fine. But the problem is the next
morning you might feel almost hung over.
That's what a lot of my patients call
it. You might feel groggy. You might be
forgetful. And but you're at work, so
you got to function. And what do you do?
One of these pills is gone. One of these
pills. You've taken a pill. Thank you,
Dr. Oz. So, we're going to reach for the
coffee because we got to we got to stay
awake. You like coffee? Yes, I like
coffee. I suspect that you might from
that video. We're going to do a cup of
coffee because it's got caffeine. It
might help us stay alert, but the
problem is that may not cut it. So,
we're going to do another one. And I
don't know how how many people drink
more than two cups of coffee a day.
There are a lot of people. You might
even need that third cup of caffeine to
help you stay awake. The problem with
that though is that by the end of the
day, you then might have problems going
to sleep and may need another sleep
pill. What this does is it creates a
vicious cycle and it really doesn't deal
with the underlying issue. It can
actually be very problematic and this is
the cycle that we fall into. It's
actually more like a whirlpool getting
sucked down the drain. Another problem
of course Dr. Hamilton is one that you
talk frequently about which is not just
a quantity of sleep. Yeah. According to
research, although these sleeping pills
might help you sleep longer, are you
really sleeping better? Not really. In
fact, it can affect the amount of REM
sleep that you get. And that's your
restorative stage of sleep. Uh, and that
affects your daily functioning. So, moms
are right, I guess, right? Quality over
quantity. Absolutely. Which most of us
aren't even aware of, but ends up being
really important when trying to live
your life the right way. So, up next,
the biggest question that we get asked.
Can you become addicted to sleeping
pills? Find out what you need to know.
All right, it's time for the number one
question I get asked about sleeping
pills. Are you ready for it? Can you get
addicted? It's a wise question to ask.
So, we've talked about the cycle of
seeping pill, you know, abuse, but we
get the hangovers. But then there's also
another problem that's probably even a
bigger one. Tolerance, right? So, if
you're out there, you know, counting
sheep, right, let's make you a sheep.
You take your one pill, then you take
another pill very slowly, very gently,
walking your way through this, and then
hopefully, right, yet you've gotten
where you need to be. That's not what
happens. Your body knows you're taking
all these pills, right? So, what does it
do? it races through the rest of these
pills and soon the same pills that used
to help you over here don't help you
anymore over here. That's the biggest
fear that we have and that's why I think
although we talk about addiction with
opiates, this is a different kind of
addiction. This is being addicted in a
way where the pill no longer works for
you. So, let's go on over here. I got a
little quiz. All of our sleep challenge
women are here and I know you you have
all got questions. But before you ask
us, I got one question for you. You've
witnessed us talk about some of the
concerns we have about taking sleeping
pills chronically. You've been violating
what the box warns you about. Concerns
about that worries. What kind of
insights?
Sorry. What's it going to do to your
liver eventually? Well, might might
damage other organs that you have. Other
concerns. Dementia. Dementia. Definitely
from personal experience and knowing of
older individuals that did that and
demented. Yeah. Yes. How is it going to
affect our mental state, our brain?
Yeah. Even even before dementia. So, I
would hope that in general you're not so
happy about what you heard, right? It's
not the cure all that you were hoping it
was. Is that a fair reflection? So, I I
mean, I wanted to know like is there an
actual safe way to use the pills and
like when can you like use them? All
right. So, just let's wrap all these up
in the one if you can and specifically
address the issue of how long you can
take them and how many you can take.
Right. Really, sleeping pills are
intended for two weeks at a time when
you're going through a difficult period
or transition. So, limit it to two
weeks. Uh, you also want to avoid taking
sleeping pills more than three times a
week. And listen to your body. If you're
if you're having side effects, it might
mean that that's not right for you. You
might need to talk to a doctor to switch
to something else. And also a lot at
least eight hours when you're taking a
sleeping pill because you don't know how
you're going to react the next day. And
we don't want you to have that morning
hangover which can increase risk. When
you say three times a week, what's the
benefit of not taking it every day in a
week? By avoiding taking it every day,
you're decreasing that risk of
dependence where you need it every night
and tolerance where you start needing
higher doses. Thank you very much. I
appreciate it very much. I want to thank
all you women for being honest and
thoughtful about these issues. I know
they're affecting a lot of us. Thank you
for watching. Don't forget to subscribe
and turn on notifications so you never
miss out on new videos to live the good