Today's a dream come true. Jay Leno was
the reigning king of late night for
almost 30 years, winning an Emmy award,
a star in the Hollywood Walk of Fame.
He's even a master mechanic. But his
high cholesterol is putting life into
perspective for him one joke at a time.
Please welcome Jay Leno.
[Applause]
Good to see you. Thank you for having me
on. I'm so happy. I appreciate it. Oh, I
like this.
Hello.
Well, they love seeing you. Well, thank
you. It's great to be here. This is my
first time. I forgot we met backstage
where a while back at today's show. I've
seen you a couple times. But today's
show. But I tell you, I used to I
started this show 10 years ago at 30
Rockefeller Center. And Fallon and I
started the exact same time. And I would
watch the feed from your studio and see
think see to myself, this guy's an icon.
He is working his tail off. Well,
actually, I've got a bit more work to
do. If you look at my tail,
you quite quite a bit more work to do to
get it off. But thank you. I appreciate
that. So, although you haven't seen me,
I've seen you plenty and we've all
admired your work. Actually, when you
watch the news these days, you ever sort
of think my oh man, that's a good joke
in there. You know, it's different. You
know, everything now is so polarizing.
You know, I I when I did the show, it
was kind of, you know, Clinton was horny
and Bush was dumb. It was a simpler No,
you know, I mean I mean it was it was a
different time, you know. It wasn't this
Everybody's very angry now. Everybody's
very polarized and and and I I miss the
idea of just sort of poking. I always
like to to make fun of people to their
face if if they laugh at it. only one I
remember once I was doing the Washington
correspondence dinner and John Kerry was
sitting right in front and I said John
why the long face you know and it got a
and I got and it got a big laugh you
know but it wasn't I wasn't attacking
somebody's patriotism I wasn't saying
they were unamerican you know I I did it
when you question people's judgment not
their motive yes you know now everybody
questions motive and it just makes it it
makes it tricky. You know, the the funny
part about comedy is taking it to the
next level. It was like a punch line
used to be that's like the president
being with a porn star. Okay. Well, now
the president is with a porn star. Where
do we go? Okay. Where do you go from
there? Where do you take it now? You
know, you can't you you can't there's no
there's no out there's nothing
ridiculous enough now. You know, I used
to watch that show House of Cards and
go, "Well, that's ridiculous." And that
could never Now it looks like a
documentary, you know. But it does.
[Applause]
So you and your beautiful wife
approaching 40 years of marriage. That's
right. 40 years of marriage. It's
biblical in significance. How do you I I
look all the things you've done in your
life, that's what I would respect you
for the most. Okay. So how did you pick
the right person for you? How do you
keep the marriage healthy? Well, you
know, I remember once I had Drew Barmore
on the show and she was getting married
and she's asking and I, you know, I
would say to people, you always marry
your conscience. Marry the person you
would like to be. If you marry someone
like yourself, well, now I have two
greedy people in the house. You know
what I'm saying? You know what I'm
saying? I mean, I learn cars and
motorcycles. My wife likes to work with
women's groups and help give
scholarships and stuff. So, oh, I can,
you know, she learns a little bit about
cars. I learn a little bit of the Bronte
sisters. It works out pretty good, you
know. I I mean, for me, the 40 years has
gone by like that. We have fun. We laugh
every day. You know, when I do gigs, I
fly home every night. You know, I don't
I don't stay in Vegas because you get in
trouble. Just fly home every night and
and it's good. We have you you know, uh
you know, the real key is to make show
business money and lead a normal life.
Yes. That's that's hard. Cuz like in in
my
house, in my family, I'm a big shot. I
can put, you know, I can afford to put a
roof on my uncle Lou's house. And when I
go home, no, the big meatballs for Jay.
No, no, no, that big meatballs for Jay.
And I get the big meatball and works out
okay cuz you put the roof up. All right.
You mentioned traveling. So 210 nights a
year or not nights, days a year I'm
told. You're scheduled and busy. You're
68 years old. I mean, how do you do
that? And what do you eat, by the way,
when you're on the road that much? We
see what our president. Well, again, my
diet is not one to envy. I wouldn't, you
know, uh, yeah, I I mean, I eat mostly
guy food, you know. This is your guy
food from a a past era. What is that?
Has it changed? It was unidentifiable.
We tried. Oh. Uh, that Well, I'm rich.
It's one of the five food groups. Pizza,
hamburgers, hot dogs, chicken, steak,
you know. So I I I take from those from
those five food groups.
Now that has had a repercussion as it
does for many Americans. You you found
out, I guess, that your cholesterol was
high. My cholesterol is high. Yeah. And
that's why I got involved with Amgen
doing this uh cholesterol 911.com
campaign because cholesterol is one of
those deals. You know, in the last
couple years we lost Rodney Dangerfield,
John Panette, Gary Shanley. Now, Gary,
oh no. played basketball, boxed. I mean,
he was an athletic guy. And it's one of
those things where high cholesterol just
hits you. You don't know. You know, if
you've got a stomach pain, you can go,
maybe we'll go to the doctor next week
if this keeps up or something. But with
high cholesterol, you can be in the best
shape of your life and then boom, it
hits you like a like a truck, you know.
So, did you expect to have high
cholesterol? Does it run in your family?
Any other risk factors? When you have an
Italian family, you don't really discuss
cholesterol.
Noat was you know yeah you don't really
Yeah know you eat
meat meatballs I get the big meatball
yeah you get yeah your cholesterol is
not really in it see I again when I see
I'm dyslexic here was the cure for
dyslexia when I was a kid smarten up
smarten up smarten up okay and and you
know I smartened up and it was it worked
you know so that's sort of how no nobody
ever made I have no idea what my parents
cholesterol was I had no idea but in
recent years. It's so easy to check now.
Yeah. And I tell people, go to ask your
doctor. Like for example, they've
recently found that laughter is not the
best medicine. In fact, it doesn't work
at all. It doesn't do anything. If a
guy's having a stroke and you tell him a
joke, two guys going to a bar. No, he's
he's not going to get better. So, don't
believe that whole laugh. But since you
brought that up, I mean, you you saved
Rod This is maybe Urban Law. Please
correct us, but Rodney Dangerfield was
having a stroke in your studio. Well,
true. What happened? I had Rodney on the
Tonight Show and I'm a huge fan of
Rodney and comics. We all study one
another. I know Rodney or Rodney. Hey,
Taylor. You know, he always had he had
that funny way about you know respect.
Yeah. And he was on the show and his
movements were just a little off and he
was sweating a little bit, not much. And
I remember I was sitting at the desk
enjoying Rodney's and I said to Debbie
Vickers, our producer, I said, "I think
Rodney's having a stroke. Call the call
the paramedics just in case." Really?
Okay. So Rodney sat down. Hey Jay, how
you doing? you know, and and he just
seemed a little more hyper than
normal. And he's in the dressing room
and the paramedics came back. I'm all
right. What are you doing? I said,
Rodney, they think he might have I'm
Well, he did. He had a mini stroke. And
I It's true. I remember I remember that
the paramedics said to me, you know, you
may have saved him from having a heart
attack. And I thought I didn't really do
anything. All I did was just look out
for my friend who seemed a little off
and just took the most minimal
precaution. It was no effort on my part.
I mean, you're not a hero. I just Oh,
but it just to teach people, watch out
for symptoms, even what they are.
Something just seems odd, you know.
Yeah. That's why we have this uh
cholesterol 911.com campaign. I'm not
selling anything. I'm not a reverse
mortgage guy. I I'm here to screw your
grandmother out of her house. No. I
mean, it's not it. All it is is it's
just a campaign to make people aware
because we've lost so many. Well, I'll
tell you a funny end of that Rodney
story. Rodney eventually passed away
about six years later and I went to see
Rodney in the hospital and he was in a
coma and his wife Joan who was just a
great lady. She said, you know, Rodney
said, "I think he can hear us but he
can't respond." I was so talking to
Rodney and Rodney was lying like this
and and and Joan said, "Jay, put your
finger in Rodney's hand." And she said,
"Rodney, if you know it's Jay, squeeze
his finger." So I felt him squeeze my
finger and I said, "Rodney, that's not
my finger."
So,
so yeah. So, but he went like this. I
mean, he moved, you know. No, no, he
did. He did. And And the funny part was
he he went like that and I thought, "Oh,
I made him kind of laugh when he coma."
I mean, I cured him. I mean, I I know it
sound I don't mean to sound mean as
dumb, but it's just when you're a comic,
you know, you make one of your idols
who's in a coma laugh. And I and Joan
thought it was funny and I I hope Rodney
thought it was I mean he passed away
soon after that but it was just a great
moment you know with one of my heroes
with one of my friends it's on my
finger. Yeah. We come back more with the
hysterical Jay Leno and his advice for
all of you at home.
I'm back with late night superstar Jay
Lento who is somehow making cholesterol
and health funny. All right, let me show
you. I got a little surprise for you
guys. Bring it out here. You know, a lot
of people give their guests fun prizes.
I like to do it quite this way. So,
here's You'll find out. Put the purple
gloves on. Why you gloves on? Put the
pal gloves on. So, I thought I'd uh This
is not a rectal thing, is it? No.
I mean, I see this show. I don't know. I
never know where it's going. So, I need
both of them on. You need both of them
on. So, I brought you a human heart. Oh,
you know, I I understand they taste like
chicken. Is that correct? Yes, they
taste like chicken. Well, thank you. But
I want because you're taking time talk
about cholesterol. That's an actual
human heart. Yeah. Now, I want you to
just hold. Now, I hope some guy isn't
waiting for a transplant and this you
stop.
Cuz some somewhere in a hospital open
the beer cooler. It's got beer in it.
Where's the heart? What happened to the
heart? Leno's got it. Leno has it. So,
this is a real heart. This is the heart
here. Okay. And this is the aorta. And
I'm just pointing out You see how it's
like crispy like potato chips here?
Okay. Yourself. So, I've got a heart on,
you might say.
Sorry. I'm sorry. Don't be here all
week. I'm sorry. I I like it.
I'm sorry. I I couldn't resist You
know, this is fascinating. I've never I
you know, never held a human heart. And
this is This looks like a pretty flimsy
mechanism, doesn't it? This is why we
need to take care of it. So, but feel
see these little plaques here? These
are, you know, aorta chips. Basically,
you don't want that too much. They're
delicious. Yeah. But that's the
cholesterol you're talking about. Those
are what cholesterol plaques look like.
Oh, okay. Wow. All right. So, there you
go. Well, since your heart is in cars.
Yes. I built you something just for you.
You made something for me? Yeah. A
little heart model that's based on cars.
Are you okay? Well, you gave me a human
heart. I don't know what else you could
give me. This is going to top that.
Bring it out, guys. Bring it out. What
do we have here? We have a
racetrack. All right. Now, this is
something special.
Thank you very much. All right. So now
I'm no expert. If it looks like a
modified Hot Wheel set, maybe
I'm No. I've got two cars here. This is
a normal racetrack. Notice how thin
these linings are. Nothing corroding it,
messing it up. Right now, I got a little
car in here. Now, watch this. If there's
no blockages here, the heart moves
really quickly with the blood. All the
blood flows through there. Let's put
that in slow-mo because I think Jay
missed that. So fast. That's how fast
the heart is able to pump blood through
itself. There you go. Oh, there it is.
Now, this is what happens in that plaque
heart that I just showed you earlier.
So, when you put rocks in the road, I'm
guessing it could be a problem. Yeah.
Yeah. In fact, oh, what are the odds of
that? God, who? Go figure. This is why
you got to focus on your LDL
cholesterol. It matters. Well, the funny
thing, you know, there's no symptom to
it. That's the thing that's weird about
it cuz I have a friend of mine. He's a
jogger. He runs three miles every day
and he had a stroke and he's furious
that I'm sitting home watching Dr. Oz
and the Today Show and I'm not doing
anything. I'm eating bon bonss and and
I'm fine and he runs every day and he's
just yelling at me because it wasn't
fair. But life is not fair. That's the
way it works. It's it's genetics. It's a
combination of factors. You know, that's
why if you go to that
cholesterol911.com website, just
questions to ask your doctor because if
you don't know anything about it, well,
here are the questions you can ask so
you don't sound like an idiot. So, what
has Jay Leno changed in his diet? Do you
eat any different? No. What? Huh? Well,
I'm I'm I'm trying to change a little
bit. I'm trying to change. Have you
given up any food at all? Given up any
food? Yes. Uh uh. No. I've given up I've
given up kale. Granola.
Yes. All right.
I had no idea how delicious gluten was
until I ate gluten-free. I I I had no
idea how delicious gluten was. It was
fantastic. Thank you for watching. Don't
forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good