What would you do if you were face to
face with an intruder? Now this is a
weapon that you can use. When you walk
into your house, this is how you walk in
just in case. And Lisa Lampanelli shines
a powerful light on fat shaming. No one
ever made permanent good change by being
yelled at or yelling at themselves.
Plus, helpful home tips from Leila Ali.
To have organization in your home does
wonders. Coming up next.
[Applause]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
[Music]
I love you, Da.
[Applause]
Welcome to the show.
I may have just made a big mistake. I
bet many of you would have made the same
mistake. Putting myself at risk.
According to my guest, security expert
and author of the new book, Prepared,
Not Scared, Bill Sten. He's here in
person. What did I do wrong? Well, Doc,
the first and potential last mistake you
made was coming outside that door. You
came out and unless you specifically
know who's on the other side of that
door, I don't care if it's the butcher,
the baker, the candlestick maker, you
know there are bad people out there.
Now, my initials are BS. There are too
many bad guys out there looking to throw
it your way. So, today show everyone
it's about being safe in what sometimes
seems like an unsafe world. But you
don't have to run scared as long as
you're prepared. So being prepared not
only keeps us safe but it also gives us
a sense of control of our lives. Gives
us calmness in the face of disaster as
well as reducing your fear and anxiety
because you know what guys we fear most
or we don't understand. So you here to
prepare us with some common scenario
defenses things that happen all the
time. Why did you pick the ones you
picked? Well doc what happens is we
don't rise to the occasion in times of
stress. Studies have shown we default to
our training and that's what this book
goes to. It gives you actionable tips
how to be situationally aware and how to
be prepared, not scared, if tragedy
strikes. These are all common scenarios.
So, Ashley's going to start us off.
She's a single mom, wants to be better
prepared to protect her family and
herself. How much anxiety do you have
about a stranger entering your home? And
we see these reports daily now. Well, as
you said, I'm a single mother of two
girls, and every time I hear a noise in
the house, I become startled and alert.
So, I just want to be prepared just in
case. Okay, Bill. bad guy enters the
home, what's she supposed to do? Okay,
it's about having the proper mindset.
Now, Ashley and I have rehearsed this a
little bit. So, don't be startled
because she is now prepared. She's not
going to be scared. So, most attacks
come from behind. So, if someone's going
to come back, they're not going to go
nice. You know what? Do it from over
here cuz I want everyone at home to see.
This is really cool stuff. If someone's
going to come up, it's going to be it's
going to be really hard. And she's going
to do what?
And what's going to happen is she Wait,
hold on. Hold on. All right. What she's
going to do, what she did was she found
transitional space. If she found a way
to get me away and she did that groin
strike, thank you, doc, for that. She
does that groin strike. She knows how to
get out of dodge. She's going to do
that. Now, if you're walking to the
door, you have keys. Good habits are
hard to break, just like bad ones.
You're going to go like this, and if you
don't have the keys, you're going to
strike and then rake the face with your
nails. Why? Because you've now just
identified that person with their DNA.
So, they run, they take off. We know who
they are. They go to jail. It's like a
horror film. But if you don't mind, I I
That happened so fast for me. I want to
do that again one more time. Really
strike hard this time. No, seriously.
Thank you, Doc.
Now, I actually want you to go slowmo
cuz I want to show people what you did.
So, first of all, so you be Bill, you be
the intruder. She comes up. So, she's
going to make herself big, right? So,
you do that means you put your arms
apart and take a deep breath there.
That's right. Now, she's going to drop a
little bit. She's going to come with her
fist and as hard as she can. Boom. Oh,
jeez.
All right. It works. It works. All
right. We went over that, right? She
said, "You trained her too well." All
right. Yes. That was very good. Okay.
So, now if Now I'm going to give her the
keys. If she's walking to the door and I
come up from from from up front. Let's
not make a mistake this time. So, you're
going to strike right to the face. Boom.
Right. Right. Now, where the keys? No,
the keys got to be down. Keys are in the
fingers interlaced. Right. And she's
going to strike straight to my face.
Right. And now I'm I'm gonna show that
for a second. What I'm hearing, see this
is not quite what I'm It has to be in
Right. Because what you're saying is
when we walk into our house, when you
walk into your house, you're going to
take your keys and you're going to do
what he's doing now. Inter. So one key
in in between. No. Yes. You can go into
as many keys as you have. Right now,
this is a weapon, right, that you can
use. Can everyone see that? From now on,
when you walk into your house, this is
how you walk in. Just in case you have
the keys in your hand anyway, instead of
holding it inside your hand where it
can't help you, do what Bill's doing.
You channel your inner wolverine and you
come right to the face, eyes, nose,
clavicle, right? And then if you have
the time, you rake their face. You have
that I you have that DNA identifier and
you just run. Don't stay to engage. You
run. You get out of dodge. All right.
So, how does that make you feel just
hearing this? And I I bring this up
because years ago, I I remember uh going
to a school and they were having big
problems with assault, right? And my
wife was the one who said, you know, you
can teach to women how to run away, but
maybe better teach them how to defend
themselves so it's not just a one-sided
threat. Does this make you feel more
comfortable? I feel more prepared, a lot
more comfortable, more confident. And
from now on, I want everyone at home,
you get those keys out, do what Bill
just did. You don't have to meticulously
do it every single time. We've all got
keys. Put them the right way and and
have them there just to protect any form
like that. Good habits are hard to
break, just like bad ones. And your
mindset coupled with the knowledge will
make you prepared, not scared. Right,
Ashley? Thank you very much. Thank you.
All right, our next be prepared scenario
also involves the front door and some
conmen in uniform. You're not going to
believe this.
Police want you to be on the lookout for
this guy. Police say he is posing as a
utility worker and he's trying to get
inside people's homes. Police report
last month two men in a dark collared
vehicle tried to get inside homes,
claiming they worked with the utility.
Police say two men posed as PGW workers
before attacking and robbing a man who
let them in his home. This is home
surveillance video showing conmen who
gained entry posing as water company
employees. Watch as one distracts the
homeowner while the other sneaks into
another room looking for valuables.
These two men came to the door of an
unsuspecting teen home alone. When he
answered, they forced their way in. He
was uh beaten and tied with zip ties and
clothing. A third suspect was shown on
security cameras leaving with plastic
bags. According to police, the suspects
got away with more than $200,000 worth
of cash, jewelry, and personal
valuables.
That's some scary stuff. So, here's the
question. How do you look past the
uniform and find that if someone on our
doorstep is legitimate? What what's
what's what am I supposed to do when
someone walks up there and says they're
here to check the gas? Well, the famous
saying, trust but verify. Same thing
applies here. Use your mindset. You see
someone at the door. What you do is you
want to say, "Let me see your ID." You
want to have your phone ready to call
and you may want to come to con man. You
may want to say, "Hold your ID up cuz we
have a camera." You may not have a
camera, but they don't know that. And
you monitor how they react. Yeah. No
one's going to stick around if they
think you're calling their boss and they
don't have one. Exactly. All right.
Let's go outside for our last scenario.
Bobbing a car. Not. You never know.
Never know. You might need to be
prepared just in case the worst happens.
This past winter, a man in Oregon was
trapped in his car during a snowstorm
for 5 days surviving on guess what? Taco
Bell hot sauce. That's all he ape. Now,
it tastes good. I get it. But that's not
what you want to do voluntarily. So, our
next scenario is going to teach you what
you should do if you find yourself
trapped in a car after an accident. Bill
says, "Your car can actually be your
best friend when it comes to being
prepared for life. You should outfit it
for survival." So, this is your car.
That's right. I like the license plate,
by the way. I I love it. Vanity. So,
what we have on our person, we should
have what's called an everyday carry. I
say do this to the car. This every car
should be different where you live, but
this should have the staples. Every car
should have protein bars. They should
have a flashlight, a first aid kit, you
have duct tape. Now, this is very
important. This is a seat belt cutter.
You have it in the front of the car. And
a jug of water. These things should be
in every car and where you live.
Depending if you live in a desert, in a
cold area, you may want to have a
blanket or water purifier, things like
that. Right? So, all the essentials, put
them in a little bucket, easy to cart
around. Now, Bill wants to use his cell
phone to show us his next demonstration.
How to escape from the trunk of a car if
you have been kidnapped. Now, if you
think it'll never happen to you, well,
think again because this Alabama woman
was making her brave escape. Happily
caught caught on video, but
unbelievably, she was in the in the back
of the trunk. All right, Bill, you ready
with this? Let's do it. Get in the
trunk. Explain what we're going to do.
Okay, so in case you're ever put in this
trunk for whatever reason, you're going
to go in and if it closes, if you're
taken, if you're here by mistake or on
purpose, you're going to find that Well,
hold a second. Do Do I You want You sure
I'm going to close this? Let's give it a
shot. Okay. I'm sure that Ready? 3 2
Deep breath in. All right. So, I'm in
the trunk and I'm quickly looking. I
need to find that exit. There it is.
Pull it. Kick it open.
And I'm out to freedom. You survived.
Who would have thought? Oh my goodness.
I was counting on you coming back. All
right. He made it. You can, too. It's
super simple. I never knew that little
catch was there, but they're there.
They're simple. They're put there for a
reason. Not like the old movies when you
get stuck and they get cart your way
everywhere. Anyway, up next, Bill is
sticking around to show you how to
survive a dog attack because they
happen.
[Applause]
[Music]
Over 100 young men mysteriously drowned.
All death ruled accidental. There's GHB
in in the system. The date rape drug,
but some say it's the work of the smiley
face killers. This is a big idea. The
theory there's a gang of serial killers.
An Oz true crime investigation. Plus,
love after lockup when your soulmate is
an inmate. What is it about men who are
incarcerated that attracts you next? Oz,
that's coming up tomorrow.
We've got good news and bad news. Well,
first, welcome to your home. And here's
the thing. I walked around. I did a
security check and the lower windows,
everything seems up locked nice and
tight. But then I noticed a ladder on
the side of your house. So, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to use your
everyday item tool as a weapon against
you. Don't worry. The doc and the good
people at the Dr. Oz show said they got
this covered. So, here we go.
Oh, so the window's open. It's just a
screen. That's This is a screen.
What? Is that right? You left the window
open. Yes. Not just unlocked. You left
it open. It's like an invitation.
Oh my. He's inside the house. So, I'm
inside.
You see how easy that was? Yes.
All right. So, we're back with police
officer Bill Stanton who's here making
sure we're prepared to stay safe. That
was Bill breaking into one of our
audience members' home. Now, he's about
to recreate a real life dog attack so
you can survive if it happens to you.
Now, I want to say this. We're all big
dog lovers here. I've got my little
Khesi doesn't attack anybody. But most
of our furry pals are friendly, right?
We all know that. But there are some off
chance dog attacks. They happen. We want
you to be prepared for your safety and
for the safety of the animal involved.
So, we're at a park. We're going to
recreate it here. We have, you know,
let's say we got the kid with us and we
see a dog and this this is and we think
it's getting ready to attack us. What do
we do? Well, it's called situational
awareness. You want to see the trouble
before it's coming. So, you want to put
your body in front of your child and
make yourself big. You want to yell and
try scare the dog away and let that dog
know who's in charge. And why do you
turn sideways like that? Well, you want
to cover your vital organs. You want to
give you want to present just the thing
that is, you know, you want to give that
arm so you protect everything else. and
your child. All right. And if it doesn't
happen, what what do you do then? Well,
then doc, you got to take the hit. Take
the hit. You got to take the hit from
the dog. Let the dog attack you. You're
gonna let that dog attack you because
you know what you have is priceless.
Your child, you know, I love the way you
explain that, but I don't know.
Audience, you want to just see this,
right? I mean, you want to show and tell
it, not just tell it. Why am I not
surprised, Doc? Did you take the hit for
us? I'll take the hit for you. All
right. Go ahead. Let's do the show and
tell. So, so now now the the mindset is
there's is an adore coming and we see
that dog. No, back back
go.
[Applause]
Okay.
Oh my goodness. Oh my goodness. Hold
that dog. She is not happy with you at
all. So, you're hoping Well, big hand
for Quella by the way. Quella,
I just say Quella is not really an
attack dog. She's beautiful and she
actually from our friends from Kines's
for Cops. Kines's for Cops has donated
police dogs over 200 communities and
removed $300 million worth of contraband
off the street. So, thank you for being
here for keeping us safe. But be all
that said and done, Quao was pretty
effective in ripping your arm off. Yes.
And what we have to hope for is that
someone's going to see this, whether
it's an owner or a bystander, and
they're going to safeguard your child,
and then eventually that dog will leave
you alone. Right, Bill, thank you very
much for helping us always. His book,
Prepare, Not Scare. It's available now.
Check it out. We'll be right back. Thank
you, sir.
[Applause]
Funny lady, Lisa Lampanelli is now a
life coach. Stay tuned as she helps twin
sisters stuck in a fat shaming loop.
Willie, we're going to fix it up. I
trust her. Yep.
[Applause]
There's a lot of anger in the world
these days. Bullying and fat shaming,
insults, and this all too familiar
language is genuinely unhealthy.
Something funny lady Lisa Lampanelli
knows all too well. She's been on both
sides of it until now. Lisa says she's
had enough and wants to help others
cope. She's been coined America's queen
of mean. Lisa Lampanelli was the funny
plus-sized gal of comedy. She rose from
stand-up comic to stardom with her bold,
shocking, and brutally honest humor.
That came out wrong. And Lampinelli
scares no one, including herself. In 6
months of dieting, I have lost three
lbs.
writing candidly about her struggles
with food and weight in her best-selling
book, Chocolate, Please, about her
battle with the bulge.
At nearly 50, Lisa went under the knife
to have a drastic weight loss procedure,
a gastric sleeve that she hoped would
help her finally shed the weight.
Since the surgery, Lisa Lampanelli has
lost over 100 lbs, and made a few other
changes. She changed up her classic
blonde look, got divorced, and shocked
the comedy community with her decision
to retire from the mic for good. Today,
Lisa Lampanelli shares her remarkable
journey, stepping out of the comedy
spotlight and into her new role as a
life coach.
So, let me show you all what Lisa looked
like before. There's a before picture.
She was a beautiful soul, right? But she
wasn't happy in her body. Here is the
new Lisa. Come on out.
[Applause]
[Music]
Oh my goodness. So happy.
Look at you. Look at you. Oh, thank you.
I'm so happy to be here.
Please say happy family.
I like the energy of movement. It's you
can see it in your eyes. Oh, I love it.
There's so much more joy in life when
you actually like what you're doing and
you feel better about yourself. And you
know, obviously you shed the hair. Yes.
You shed the weight. She shed a husband.
You should know, right?
Walk us through how this transformed
you. You know what was wild was I
started working on the weight and I came
on the fir first time I was on here. We
talked about no more emotional eating.
Working on that. That's the hardest part
of this whole thing. And as I stopped
stuffing my emotions with food, I
started figuring out, oh my god, I'm not
that happy in my marriage and we broke
up amicably. Then I was like, well,
comedy really isn't giving me that joy
it used to. And helping people, I'm
telling you, there is nothing like it. I
get on a I'm doing Oh my god, it's so
much fun.
Oh, I just feel like every coaching
session with someone gives me that joy
it used to as when I first started the
standup, but better because it actually
hopefully is making a change in people's
lives. So, by the way, she her 10year
challenge. Take a look at this picture
if you don't mind. This is your #10ear
challenge which you just posted. You're
fantastic.
And you have always been uh willing to
talk about food and the relationship
issues. That must have changed
dramatically now. Oh my god. so much
because when you get beriatric surgery,
if you work on the emotional eating, you
really figure out, wow, it was never
about food. It wasn't that I loved food
and that I was always hungry. No, the
fact was I was using food to medicate,
just like people use alcohol or drugs or
shopping or anything else. And what was
so cool is now that I'm not doing that,
I go, "Boy, this is kind of still hard,
but every day it gets a little better."
And every day you still have to work on
it. It never ends. I may be 80 and still
working on it, but at least I'm working
on it. Well, you say the word work, but
for most people when I I think of work,
work is a whole different kind of
escape. And and you use comedy. Yeah.
Not just as a as a profession, but you
also could use your comedic talent to as
a solve. Oh, absolutely. To deal with a
lot of this and you decide to give it
up. That's pretty risky. Well, the risk
was only if I stayed in because I didn't
want to do something that didn't have
that happiness and joy for me. This is
how I deal with life. People, I say,
"What's the worst that can happen?" But
then I do it anyway. A lot of people let
that talk them out of doing something.
Me, I said, "What's the worst that can
happen? I never make another penny. I
sell my house. I move in with my mother.
God bless her. Hopefully, I'll be in the
will and I'll get the house." And then
you go, "You know what? That's the worst
that could happen. You're with your mom.
It's always Yeah. If if if you have to
go down to a certain little tiny
apartment, who cares if what you do
every day brings you a little bit of
love, you know? So, when you have the
usual ups and downs in life, Yeah.
What's your hack? How do you Normally,
you just throw a joke out there,
everyone would sort of decant it and
you'd be okay. Well, not only that,
usually I'd eat or throw out a joke. So,
those were my two ways of sort of like
distancing myself from my emotions. Get
this. Now, when I have a uncomfortable
feeling, I have to feel it. There is
nothing worse than having to cry, having
to be really truly frustrated, angry,
lonely, and then guess what though? They
say you have to feel it to heal it. It
ends up it's not that bad. You live
anyway. And do I succeed all the time?
Hell no. I'm always going, you know
what? 20% of the day I probably don't do
the right thing with food or anything
else, but at least that's why I wore
that shirt that said work in progress
because I'm always going to be doing
that. Well, let me your your approach to
feeling it because a lot of the crazy
things people do is because they want to
feel life. A lot of you sitting around
right now watching this program are
thinking I I just I feel dead. I feel
dull. Feeling it actually does reawaken
you because we're supposed to have that
there. So, we're talking about body
image issues a lot these days in
America. And you went through a period
when you weren't in the body you wanted
to be in, which is your business, not
anyone else's. Were you ever fat shamed?
Oh god. The minute I discovered this
Twitter and this Facebook, I had to do
it professionally. I don't do it
personally. I had to do it for Oh, my
own. Every time you say some joke they
don't like, they call you names. They
get on you. I was very thin skinned at
the time. Now, now, thank goodness I've
worked on liking myself more. So, you
could throw at me whatever you want
because I kind of laugh about it because
I'm like super pretty and it doesn't
really matter. So, but that's the weird
thing. No.
But it's weird like once you start
working on the internals, you start
liking the externals better and you go,
"Oh, you just said I was ugly and old on
Facebook." That's okay. I I throw
compassion at them to be honest with
you. I ignore it and they say, "Whatever
happens is fine. Your words are
powerful, your spirit undaunted. You're
the kind of person who changes the
world. We all have the power, but you're
actually doing it." A thank you. Would
you be willing because you've been there
to help me with a couple guests? Mhm. I
want to do a little intervention. Sure.
And this is an intervention between two
sisters. And they're fat shaming. Oh
wow. That's rough. Each other. Oh boy.
Which is not what I would have expected.
But if even sisters can do it, we all
might be doing it without realizing it.
So this is Lexi and her twin sister
Mandy. They are both 40. They still do
almost everything together. They even
live across the street from each other.
But there's something emotional going on
between them that's starting to tear
these sisters apart. And it is the fat
shaming that we started the segment off
with. Lisa's fat shaming. And you going
to do the sister's intervention? Oh,
yeah. Absolutely. You'll see it live
when we come back.
[Music]
[Applause]
We're investigating foods you think are
healthy. This one happens to have a lot
of artificial sweetener. Oh. But are
there hidden sugar substitutes causing
you to gain weight?
That's coming up Wednesday on Dr. Oz.
So, Mandy called me again tonight and
asked me to come over to exercise with
her.
And my body just cringed. I'm at this
point. I'm just like, "Leave me alone.
Please, just leave me alone." Um, and
she's like, "What did you do today?" I'm
like, "I slept." And she's like, "You're
not gonna lose weight by sleeping." And
that just made me just cringe even more.
She feels great. She's confident. Like I
said, she can walk around, prance
around. Everybody compliments her, can
say things to her all the time. And I
just feel like
and
I do feel like all the time, but I just
don't have the energy or the strength to
really do anything about it.
And
I just I I know she wants to help, but
she just doesn't get it.
That's Lexi. She says her sister, her
twin sister Mandy, constantly fat shames
her about her weight. Now, they've been
inseparable since birth and bond over
their shared love of dogs. But fat
shaming, well, it's pulling them apart.
Life coach Lisa Lampanelli is here to
help out. So, Manny, I I look at
pictures of you guys when you're young,
and you seem inseparable. We totally
were. Look at this image. It's
fantastic. When did this riff start
happening between you guys? Probably
about five years ago. Um, some
differences started to come into the
picture. I think when our bodies started
to change and kind of put a little
distance between us. Lexi, you've been
very open and I applaud you for this
about the fact that you have a diagnosis
of being bipolar. Yes, I do. How does
that affect the way you deal with food?
Um, it has a big effect actually because
because of the fact um of the fact that
I do have a bipolar diagnosis. I am on a
lot of medication. And unfortunately,
these medications
um have a side effect of weight gain.
Everything is weight gain, weight gain,
weight gain. And it's not only just
weight gain. Um it causes a lot of binge
eating. So Mandy, you sent us a little
video clip about how you you truly feel
about the situation in Lexi's weight
gain. Can may I play this for everybody?
Yes, you can. Okay.
Every day I am trying to help her. Help
her. That's all I'm trying to do. And I
feel like I am getting nowhere. I
understand she's got her daily struggles
because of her illness, because of her
depression, because of her medication,
but honestly, like lately, I feel like
she's using it as a crutch. I've offered
gym memberships. I've offered personal
trainers. I've offered you to come to my
house and use my workout equipment. I've
done it. And honestly, I can't enjoy
what I've achieved right now because
every time somebody compliments me in
front of her, I'm like, "No, no, no, no,
no, no, no. Don't don't don't say
anything in front of her because it's
going to just set her off and make her
upset." And that's the last thing I want
to do is make her upset. And that's why
I'm trying so hard, but she just does
not listen to me. I mean, my family has
said things to me. It's like, what do we
do? Like, we want to help her. So, she's
got to cut and get on this with me. All
right. So, I have a question for each of
you. Lexi, how does it make you feel
when you hear that? Oh,
frustrated. Um, I almost uh want to keep
building that wall up around me and just
pull the covers over and just turn away.
Run away. Manny, what does it say about
you? What are you doing to actually
allow Lexi to to live in the body she
wants to live in? You can give her
something that no one else Lisa can't
give her. I can't give her that only you
can give her cuz she loves you and she
trusts you. She cares about what you
think. Maybe too much. Yeah.
you. It's like you with all your good
intentions and love for her, you need to
be a partner along the journey. And you
know what? No one ever and I I've seen
across the board, no one ever made
permanent good change by being yelled at
or yelling at themselves. So just to sit
and listen and hold her hands
metaphorically and also physically be
like, you know what, be her soft place
to fall. you know, be that person who
helps her dissolve those unworthy
thoughts in her head. So, let's work on
the thoughts. And if you guys I'd love
to offer you both coaching on the house
by me for as long as you need it, cuz I
I'm so passionate about you guys being
together as a twins and also just
dissolving those bad thoughts we have.
So, please take me up on it and really
work on this relationship. You're
adorable and worthy.
Thank you for the free life coaching.
Take her up on it. get your relationship
back on track. For more information on
Lisa's upcoming storytelling shows and
workshops, you can check out lisa
lamp.com. I love being with you. Oh, I
love you, man. Thank you so much. Love
you. I wish you all the best, Daniel.
Let's be right back.
I'm here with an undefeated boxing world
champion, Leila Ali, and today we are
giving your home dilemas the one-two
punch. That's right. We are bringing you
simple home and food makeover hacks
you'll want to try today. You won't want
to miss it.
[Applause]
My next guest is an undefeated boxing
world champion who learned the power of
giving back from the champ himself. Now,
Leila Ali is using what her dad taught
her to help improve the lives of
families in need of a fix with simple
home and food makeover hacks that you're
going to want to try. We are going to
the kid family. They've got this living
room that needs a little help. It's
beige on top of beige on top of beige.
Cue the transformation team. Tell me
what you don't like about it. We picked
up the furniture at a garage sale. It
was a curb sale. It wasn't even in the
garage. Now this makeover. How you
feeling about this? It looks dangerous.
Will take major skills. It's time to get
the last pieces in place to pull off the
ultimate surprise. It's beautiful.
Please welcome back to the show, Lea
Ali.
[Applause]
Oh my goodness. How you doing? Nice to
see you. Are we working out today? We
are working out. We'll do everything
with you. You usually make me work out
when I go. Well, I adore having you. The
walk from the from the workout. Exactly.
I'm so proud that you're here and I'm so
proud of your new project. Thank you.
And I love to understand how it carries
on the legacy of your dad because he
really instilled in you this powerful
love, this need to help people who are
in need. Yes. This show, Homemade
Simple, gives me the perfect opportunity
to do the things that I love. We're
working with families that are so
deserving. We might have someone that is
um you know, battling terminal illness
or someone who has um their own kids as
a single mom and took in foster kids.
So, you definitely want to give back to
them and I get to, you know, give them
spaces that are just as beautiful and
inspiring as they are and get in the
kitchen and cook with them. Well, you've
helped a lot of folks. You rearrange
their homes if you work in their
kitchens, which is a in itself a pretty
brave thing to do. And you've been able
to make some big-time changes with with
with simple moves. That's the part
that's coolest about it. You know, it's
when people are going through a lot and
they're stressed, they the last thing
they think about is, you know, a
relaxing master bedroom or a spa retreat
for themsel in their homes. And then we
just expanded into a plantbased line of
cleaning products. Oh, I'm proud of you
for that. Got lemon, lavender, rosemary,
which is good for memory retention. So,
I know you love. So, just those small
changes, incorporating them into
people's lives and making them better
just makes me feel good. Of all the
people that you've helped, who what
problems have you knocked out that
you're proud of? A family that's most
rewarding. You know, one that really
stands out is a family that had a dad
that lost his arm to cancer about eight
years ago. Mom suffered from heart
problems. They have two children. Mom
homeschools and they have a small home,
one big space, but they do so much in
it. She wants a place to homeschool, a
place to read, do art, you know, living
area. I'm like, how are we going to get
all this in one space? We have such
amazing designers and carpenters and a
whole team that we work with and we
actually got it done and it of course
destressed their lives and they're so
much happier now. Well, it's something
to behold. In fact, here's an example of
the room. We just saw a glimpse of it
before. This is the pre- Leila Ali
version, right? And let me just show the
audience what the room what the first
part of this room anyway looked like
right after Leila and her team were
done. You see the the after there. Walk
us through what's what's different
there. So I notic you you you painted
the back wall different. Yeah. So
there's different angles of that room.
You're not seeing the whole room. That
was their entryway. But we definitely
had to create defined spaces. So they
when we left they had a living area.
They had their music area, their reading
area. So they were defined
compartmentalized. So to have
organization in your home does wonders
for for families. So there's a couple if
you're up for it that I would like you
to help us with. Of course. Similar to
what kinds of cases you've had. Maybe a
bit more severe. You'll see why. Come on
over here. Oh, severe. That's a scary
word. We got Belinda and Eric here.
Okay. They're wonderful people. Hi.
You guys look good. How you doing? Thank
you. Thank you. May I
promise? Exactly. She asked for this.
Right. So, here's the thing. They come
here and they say when it comes to
making decisions about the home, they
just can't seem to meet in the middle
and they're starting to cause problems
in the relationship. And if you know
them like I do, there's not a lot of
middle here. You got two very strong,
intelligent people with with we're
opinionated. All right. So, Eric, you
you've been trying to work on this for a
while, right? I have. I have.
Absolutely. I have. Um I'm a stylist as
as well. So, to me, life is all things
beautiful. You got a white palette. You
got to splash in color and make it bold.
You know, we live in an amazing space.
We're going to be buying a new home very
soon. And um as far as I'm concerned, if
you move into it, I don't care if you're
there for six months or a year. You want
to know that when you walk in, it's
exactly what you want. It's worth your
working for and everything. But my
precious angel here. So you actually
look at this room behind you. One
second. You see that? Now that's the
warm-up, right? Before they've actually
moved, he got a little trial running. Is
that right, Eric? I did. All right. So
Linda, your honest opinion, and you
always are honest. What do you think
about Eric's work here? Okay. I like it,
but I think it's a bit much for where we
are. Uh, and also
color then the little picture frames and
something inside of the picture frame.
It's a bit much for me. She being
polite. She you do you like it? Yes or
no? I don't like it for where we are.
No. Okay. So, this is the way it
currently is. Yes, that's the way it it
currently. Right. So, how common is it,
before we get into the specifics, for a
couple to have very strong opinions,
both know they're right, and there's no
place for at least it seems like there's
no place where you could actually design
together. Well, first of all, Eric, you
did a really nice job, and I can see,
you know, that you have you both have
styles. Okay, I see that you both have
styles.
Thank you, Eric. She's patronizing you.
Yes. Yes. I appreciate that. Thank you.
As we know in design, there's so many
different styles, right? So, it doesn't
mean just because you don't it's not
your style per se. Exactly. Doesn't mean
it's not nice. But you both live there.
So you mentioned white with splash
splashes of color. Like if we have a
white canvas, we need splashes of color.
But there is no white here. And I
actually think that the design aesthetic
really pops more when you have a neutral
tone. Cuz one thing I do see is like I'm
like, where am I looking? Because you
know the the the artwork is blending
with the wall and the furniture and then
the carpet. Where does it start? Where
does it end? You would have more
contrast and then you would get what you
want and you would still have your
design. I think it would actually pop
more and then it'll have like a fresh
look. And a coat of paint is one of the
first things we do on the show on
Homemade Simple because it's such an
easy, inexpensive transformation and
it's instant. I'm buying Eric a
paintbrush.
Happy life. Happy life. I hope that's
helpful for you. You're trying to figure
it out. You just need to look what I'm
saying. Working with me here. I hear
you. I hear you. Right. Right. When we
come back, switching from home makeovers
to food makeovers was something all of
you are going to want to try for
breakfast. Stick around.
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
[Applause]
We're back with Lea Ali. Now it's time
to make over breakfast. The cooking has
always been a big part of Leila's life.
She's been making delicious meals for
her family since she was a kid. You
know, you were not at that young age.
Not at that young age. About nine, 10.
I've been cooking. My mom didn't cook,
so I got in the kitchen early and
learned. I like to eat. She did it
right. Yeah. And today she has a
breakfast using leftovers. That's all
you need. Leftovers that will keep you
full all day long. It's a quick meal
that will change the way you look at
breakfast for good. Eric and Blinda are
back. They stopped fighting over that
little room. They're about to taste the
breakfast. When it When it comes to
breakfast, you guys get tired of the
same old thing. Yes, absolutely. Yes, we
do. Yeah, we eat the same thing every
morning. Mix over the the meals, not the
people. That's what I say. So, all
right. So, what are you making today?
So, we are making breakfast pasta. Now,
my kids love pasta and they don't love
breakfast food. That's how I came up
with this idea. My daughter's like, I
want I was like, okay, how can I make
this healthy? Get some eggs in it. You
going to help me do this? I'm going show
you. So, crack these eggs for me. Dr. My
sue chef today. Okay. So, we're going to
go ahead and just How many do you need?
Just go ahead and do like two or three.
It don't matter. Um, depends on what you
like. So, we're going to go and put some
oil in the pan. We've got some precooked
pasta here. Now, everyone likes their
pasta a certain way, right? We've got
whole wheat. We got regular pasta,
quinoa pasta, all sorts of pasta. So, if
you're gluten-free, you can still do
pasta. Yeah. You can pick your choice,
right? But you're making whole grain
today. We're using whole wheat. Yep.
Okay. All right. So, you can go ahead.
Um Oh my goodness. That's a lot of
garlic. It is. We're not going to put
all that in. We We like to season to
taste. Season to taste. Go ahead and mix
those up. So, you know, you can
obviously can boil this pasta, but I
like to use I always have pasta on hand.
Like I said, my kids love pasta. Okay.
So, we're just going to go ahead and
toss those in without without spices.
I'm going to put the slices in next.
Yeah. There's no wrong way to do this.
It really ends up in the pan. So, I have
some turmeric here
cuz it's just good for you. I like to
just get in. Tumeric's good for your
brain. Yes. And then we have the pepper,
right? Yep. And then I'm going to use
depending on how much do you like
garlic? How you I happen to love garlic
cuz I go to work usually after
breakfast. Oh, yeah. So, we'll just use
a little bit cuz I don't want anybody
talking about you. I don't want anybody.
That's a little bit. Yeah, that's a
little bit. Oh, jeez. Don't worry. I got
this. I got this. You want to mix it?
You like you're ready. Go on and mix it
up. I tell I tell I love breakfast foods
that have that have dinner components to
them. I like to eat what I love. So,
whenever it is, just eat the foods that
you like and make them as healthy as
possible. And that's I used to pretty
competitive. Very. That's why I took
this back over cuz I saw you were taking
over my dish and I was like, "Hold on,
Dr. Eyes. Hold on. Come on over here,
Eric. Come. Are you guys competitive?
Okay, we're going to play a little game
I play at my house. Grab one little
strand there. And you grab one, Eric.
Linda, good. You guys ready? Yes, we
grab a really long one. All right,
here's the deal. All you got to do is
slurp it up a You got You're short. It's
a lot shorter than mine. Yes. I'm All
right, let me see yours. You're the one
I care about. I'm going to beat you.
Yeah. No, I'm going to beat you. Are you
ready? Put your mouth, guys. Sh. Three,
two, one.
[Applause]
You lost. I lost. How did you even do
that? Let the ladies out the way. Yeah.
How'd you do that? God, do you have that
on slow-mo? Is it weird? Did you hide
it?
Slow. Come over here. Oh my goodness.
Seriously, I just stir up that fast. I
know. You practice at home. No, I
didn't. I might have cheated a little
bit. I think I just kind of used my
fingers, but it's okay. I just couldn't
let you win. I couldn't let you win.
Well, you won. You won. All right. So
this is basically making a scrambled
eggs with some pasta in it. Yes. So
basically this is done. Okay. And what I
love about this is you could add
vegetables. You can add whatever you
want to it. You know, make it your way.
Do like a pasta bar. But I have some
turkey, some meatball um that I we
pre-made here. But I love to do meatball
turkeys. I'm sorry, I said meatball
turkey. Turkey meatball. They comes in
both forms. Yes, exactly. And you put a
couple in there. And these could be from
last night. Yeah. And we already have um
some for us to taste. So, I'm just
showing you how you put this. Put a
taste that see what you guys think. Very
good. And here's one for you and one for
me. Are the kids usually happy eating
this? That's the question. They are. I
wouldn't put too too don't want to put
the herbs on for my kids or they would
eat it. Yeah. You don't want them to see
that. No, definitely not. Blend the
slurper. Miss the slurper champion of
the world. What do you think? This is
delicious. Very good. Go like it. Eric,
you happy?
I tell you what, in my home I, you know,
this is a design question. I think
everyone ought to focus their lives
around their kitchen, eating the right
foods, but it also is where community is
always happen. Oh yeah. My my kitchen is
my happy place and my in my family room
is right off the kitchen because then my
family knows I'm going to be in the
kitchen so you better want to be you
want to be close to me. Well, I'll make
it the first room you make over when you
come to my house. God bless you. You can
check out by dr.com or more importantly
check out Lea Ali show homemade simple.
It's not owned every Saturday. Thanks
Angel. Thank you. We'll be right back.
Over
100 young men mysteriously drowned. All
deaths ruled accidental. There's GHB in
in the system. Gate rape drugs, but some
say it's the work on the smiley face
killers. This is a big idea. The theory
of there's a gang of serial killers.
Next, Oz.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
He is being called one of the most
influential thought leaders of our time
with nearly 100 million views on
YouTube. Dr. Jordan Peterson. He sat
down in my studio for a very special
series of Oz talks that I'm sharing
exclusively with you. He's breaking down
the biggest issues we face in our
society from depression and
disappointment to anxiety and lack of
meaning. And he's given us the tools we
need to fix them with a simple click of
a button. Here's just a taste of what he
had to say. happiness. You talk a lot
about it. Should it be our life goal?
And if not, what should we be seeking?
Well, it shouldn't be our life goal.
Um because there are times in your life
when you're not going to be happy. And
then what are you going to do? Your goal
is demolished. And there are going to be
plenty of times in your life when you're
not happy. There might be years. And so
it's a shallow boat in a very rough
ocean.
And h and it's it's it's based upon a
misconceptualization.
Happiness is something that descends
upon you. Everyone knows that you know
it it it it comes upon you suddenly and
then you should be grateful for it
because there's there's plenty of
suffering. And if you happen to be
happy, well, wonderful. Enjoy it. Be
grateful for it. and maybe try to
meditate on the reasons that it
manifested itself, right? Because it it
can come as a mystery. You know, you
don't necessarily know when you're going
to be happy. Something surprising
happens and
delights you and you can analyze that.
You can think, well, I'm doing something
right. I'm in the right place right now.
I've done something right. Maybe I can
hang on to that. Maybe I can learn from
that. You can hear more of our
conversation on dr.com as well as on my
podcast starting this June. Together my
friends, change is happening. Our
journey is just beginning.
[Music]