Apple cider vinegar. For years, we've
shown you the benefits, and you've
listened. Now,
there's a new kid in town.
A lot of people didn't even know this
existed. It's actually been very big in
Asia for many, many years.
Taste this.
Oh. Oh, that's good.
Plus, Chuba Gooding Jr. on the role that
almost cost him his health. Coming up
next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10?
Yeah.
[Music]
I love you back.
[Applause]
It is my biggest challenge to you in 10
years. Are you ready to take the apple
cider vinegar challenge? Right. It's the
star ingredient that we not only
introduced you to, but have tested and
also investigated. And for the first
time ever, we have crowdsourced a
vinegar prescription plan that's
specifically designed for you by viewers
all around the country who've made
vinegar a part of their daily routine
and then jump started their health to
the next level with it. There's also a
new vinegar people are going crazy for.
I want you to find out what this new
trendy ingredient is and another first.
Everybody behind me in my studio
audience is standing by to set a new
world record with the largest vinegar
group shot ever. Go ahead and grab it.
Y'all see it? Is that excitement or fear
on their faces?
We'll find out in a second. But first,
let's start with what this little shot
can do for you. Here, you get two shots.
Save that for me. Apple cider vinegar
not only can help you control your blood
sugar, but we've received countless
success stories from viewers about how
it kickstarted healthy transformations
from all over the country. So, Janette
says that after taking apple cider
vinegar, she felt less bloated. This is
a before and after on her. Then,
Michelle says she saw a major
improvement in her energy throughout the
day. And Tamara says she dropped more
than a dress size by adding vinegar to
her everyday routine. They've all shared
with us their information, how they used
the apple cider vinegar, when they drank
it, what they ate it with, all the
details. And I've got diet expert Jen
Weeders, who's going to help us look
through all the data and is here with
the ultimate vinegar prescription that
you can try, too.
Hi, baby.
How are you?
I can't come to New York and not do your
show.
Well, I'm very happy you're here. And
there's so much to talk about because
this apple cider vinegar has become,
first of all, it's so easy to do. People
want to do it. It's affordable, but most
importantly, it seems to work for a lot
of folks. So, why do you think it's so
powerful? To me, I always describe it as
like the Ringo star of the Beatles. Like
he's been here the whole time and he's
always been in the background. And
that's apple cider vinegar. I mean, my
grandparents, grandparents told them
about it. They told me about it. And I
think it's one of those best kept
secrets because it's effective, it's
powerful, it's natural, and as you said,
it's really affordable as well.
But there are lots of opinions, tons of
opinions about apple cider vinegar, and
everyone's been taking it. But I want to
get those opinions into one place. So,
first off, you've crowdsourced some
data. Yeah. So, from your research, how
much apple cider vinegar should the
average person be taking?
I think ultimately what you want to
start with is three teaspoons a day. And
I like that spaced out and you can kind
of see how you're reacting, what your
body's talking and saying to you, and
then go from there.
All right. So, give us a quick glance of
what it might look like. A typical day.
Yeah.
Looks like this. The the prescription
plan with vinegar.
Exactly. Because we got a doctor. We're
going to prescribe you guys. So, here we
go. We got a teaspoon just before
breakfast, a teaspoon of the apple cider
vinegar just before lunch, and we have
that mystery vinegar just before your
dinner.
All right. So, we we did the crowd
sourcing. Turns out breakfast is the
most popular time to take the apple
cider vinegar. It's to do it in the
morning. That's the first part of our
plan. We're going to say that the
teaspoon of apple cider vinegar ought to
be taken before your breakfast. Yeah.
You actually agree with what people are
doing that you think it makes sense.
Take it early.
I I love it because basically it it's
it's the perfect warm-up for your
workout and your body, right?
All right, let's see how our viewers do
with this. Come on over here. Made it
part of their daily routine. Joining us
is Jamie. This is her before picture.
And here she is after.
I like it. I like it.
Thank you.
So, I it's I mean, you look great, but
it's it's not so much the looks. You
actually say you have a lot more energy.
I have a lot more energy. I was having a
a when I was starting my new lifestyle,
I was having a hard time like getting
into like a schedule like eating
breakfast and I was like just lacking
the stamina, the energy. So, I started
taking uh a few I started with a two few
tablespoons of apple cider vinegar. you
were going for a party
and then I was shooting it like like a
shot. So I was going hard or that that
was it. I needed to jump start it. So it
helped me with my stamina for my
swimming and really I mean I lost weight
but it really helped me to you know get
into this new healthy lifestyle like
naturally and I've really reaped the
benefits.
I admire you for doing it but I don't
know how you take that much apple cider
vinegar. This is my personal experience
with apple cider vinegar when you take
it as a straight shot. Take a look. Very
um sour. It's actually burning.
Sour. Tangy.
Are you ready to see if the kids would
taste this?
[Music]
Oh, it's tangy. All right.
[Applause]
And the lemon really gives it a nice
little zing.
I thought I had no thing to begin with.
Now he's
now you see the problem that I have. Did
you have a hack? A hack that allowed you
to take apple cider vinegar.
I sure do. Okay. So, you're going to
start with some warm water. And then
you're going to put in a teaspoon or a
tablespoon if you're, you know, zesty
like me.
Going hard like this one. Yeah.
And, uh, you're going to add some
cayenne pepper, some lemon juice.
Cayenne pepper.
It's,
it's hard enough as it is.
I'm a little spicy. And so should you
be. Okay. So,
she's giving you a prescription.
Yeah.
This is going to make you feel great.
It's gonna, you know, make you feel like
you're ready for the day. You're gonna
jump out of bed. You're gonna, you know,
whatever you need to do. It's going to
give you the stamina and energy that you
need. But part of what I like,
there's no way.
Now, we can add that to the real, okay,
on all of his reactions. But part of
what I like about the vinegar, too,
though, is it's actually uh because it
does kind of regulate your blood sugar.
It keeps you guys from crashing. And
that's where she says stamina. I light
up. I'm like, "Oh, good." Because
there's that feeling when you crash and
you don't have the energy for the
workout to keep going. It kind of levels
you off and and equips you with that
energy, right?
Absolutely. Absolutely.
How about still burning? Tell me what
I'd pair it with. I'd have to eat
something else.
Yeah. I'm gonna I'm gonna be your best
friend now. So, this is actually all the
recipes today are out of my book, but
this is what I call protein oats. Uh I
want you guys starting your mornings
with protein and fiber. And when I say
oatmeal, people are confused. They think
what? Protein, fiber, and oats. Yes.
Okay. So, what I want you to do, I want
a third cup of those raw oats, which I
know sounds funny. Half a scoop of
vanilla protein. You get your you get
your uh kids cereal. You put it on there
and a little bit of almond milk, the
unsweetened. And it gives you a little
bit of what I need in you, which is the
protein and and and the and the fiber.
And then you also get a little of what
you want, too.
So, you have the apple cider vinegar
first and then do that.
Yeah. I want this almost like 30 minutes
before your breakfast, you guys. And
then this can go in after. Yes.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
Let's Now, let's get to lunch.
We got lunch over here. And Jennifer is
waiting for us.
The vine the vinegar prescription for
lunch is a little different. Now, you've
noticed some changes in yourself as
well.
I've noticed some changes. I've noticed
that I have a little bit more energy. It
also I'm a person that's so busy on the
go all the time. And I feel like when I
do this in the morning that I don't get
at lunchtime, I would just grab for
anything the the snackiest snack I could
find, the chips, the all the salt. So I
feel like doing this in the morning, it
curbs that where it kind of gives me
time where I can it helps me get to the
point where I can pick something
healthy.
Right. So you have the apple cider
vinegar in the morning, but you also do
it at lunch.
I do. And I I I can't do it just like
this. So, I'll put it maybe on some
lettuce and take that with me to go.
Don't add cayenne, by the way.
This is
But you have another hack that you use
at lunchtime that actually works for
you.
I do. And I like to call it the pretty
and pink iced tea.
Oh, pretty. So, I get it now. One. Now,
I get it. Yes.
So, you just take about I'd say about 16
ounces warm water, one teaspoon apple
cider vinegar, a couple slices of apple,
some lemon, some grapefruit, and a
couple leaves in there, and you're good
to go. I also I also like
this is so much better. Are you kidding
me?
Taste this.
I can't believe he's pitting you against
each other.
Oh, that's good.
It's good.
That's good. It's not as You know,
you Jamie
assed my mouth. This this actually could
work.
It's good. And if you make it the night
before, enough for the week. Every all
the ingredients incorporate and it's
it's great. Then you have it ready to
go.
And what's the pair for this at lunch?
So, you're going to love this. And
Jennifer, I actually really much uh very
much synergize with with that kind of
lifestyle. You're running, you're going,
you're grabbing. Like I'll eat cardboard
if I'm hungry. I don't care. So, uh,
what I'm going to give you is not
cardboard, but what I suggest is a high
protein pita pocket, okay? Because it's
literally you can take it on the go
wherever you need to. Often we're eating
in our cars more and more. This is
something you can also pre-make like
Jennifer's drink. And literally, we got
we got salmon, we've got Greek yogurt,
we got some dill, salt, and pepper to
taste. Throw some greens in there. And
plus, you've got that benefit of the
probiotics in the Greek yogurt, which is
basically like friendly bacteria for
your
It pairs nicely with the apple cider
iced tea.
Oh, there are no mistakes. The pink
dress, the pink drink.
Okay, we're going to put all these
recipes on dr.com. When we come back,
the new vinegar, there's a new one that
we're adding to the mix that could be
the next power combo with apple cider
vinegar. Plus, get ready for the biggest
Oz show record. Apple cider vinegar
challenge is next.
I'm ready.
[Applause]
[Music]
How to murder your husband. The chilling
romantic suspense story that made
headlines. Did the author turn her
fantasy fiction into reality?
All new Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
We're back with the ultimate vinegar
prescription plan for you by you. My
team has crowdsourced all over the
country to find out what really works
when it comes to adding apple cider
vinegar to your routine. And they found
a new vinegar that could be a power
ingredient to your meals. Are you ready
for this everybody?
It is coconut vinegar.
Coconut vinegar.
The diet expert Jen Reerm is back. She
says the buzz building about coconut
vinegar is huge. So what is it and how
is it different different from apple
cider vinegar?
So I like a lot of people didn't even
know this existed. So, I had to research
into it and it's actually been very big
in Asia for many many years and it's
just kind of making a splash now in the
States. Um, but essentially it's the way
it's made that makes it so different.
They they take the leaves from a coconut
tree and there's a sap that forms from
them and we take that sap. We like I
made it. They take the sap and they
allow it to ferment for like eight
months and then that's how they they
formulate their their vinegar.
So, it's not from the actual meat. It's
not from the coconut water, not it's
it's the leaves on the trees and the sap
they make.
So, how do you find it? What does it
cost? What do you look for?
Yes, it's definitely not at your local
uh convenience stores. So, I would
definitely look at your health stores.
They'll carry probably an array of
really good ones. Um, make sure you're
looking for it's that it's fermented and
it's made from the leaves. And do not
mistake this with coconut water that is
not the same and it's going to be a
totally different show.
Yeah. And they've also they they make
versions of this that are made from
coconut water where they add, you know,
sugar to it. Basically, this is the real
stuff.
Exactly.
All right. So, is this the way you make
it into a mocktail?
Right. Thank you for pointing out my
mocktail, guys. So, and that's right.
It's again, it's one, like you said
before, it's one teaspoon. Yes. But this
is before dinner, not breakfast or
lunch.
Yes. Exactly. Right before dinner. And I
don't know about you, when I'm cooking,
I kind of want a cocktail or a glass of
wine. And I felt like what a great way
to bring in the coconut vinegar. And
it's great before dinner is at the end
of the day, we're tired, we're beat up,
and imagine a long shift to the hospital
for you or even here. And our immunity
is low. And so, this coconut vinegar has
potassium, vitamin C, all these things
that help with those immune boosts. So,
I've kind of made this up. You're gonna
give me a yay or a nay?
This is really good.
Oh my god, I was so nervous. Okay.
No, this is really really good.
So, you just take the mint leaves. You
you you you basically grind it into the
coconut vinegar. You give me a splash of
lime juice here. Give me some seltzer.
Throw it on the rocks. Put a martini
glass like Mr. Fancy Pants here. But
either way, you're set. You're good.
You're taking care of your body and your
immunity. And it tastes pretty good.
I like it. And the pairing is with
Oh, yeah. There are no mistakes here.
So, I've paired it with uh slow cooker
uh chicken fajitas. At the end of the
day, we're talking about how there's no
time left. Let the food cook itself.
There's everything with protein,
vegetables, flavors. Awesome. It pairs
well with the cocktail/mocktail.
See what I did there?
Yes.
And guess what? Come over here. We've
got some for you.
I'm going to challenge the audience. I
want you guys to give me a choice. You
want to have it straight up or you want
one of the mocktails that Jen's
offering?
Mocktail. All right.
All right. Go ahead and taste these
things. Oh, everyone. No one's taking it
straight up. You won straight up.
They're all mocktails. I guess
I like
Well, you're left with their You guys
like them? Taste it. See if you like I'm
not the only person. I hope. Pass here.
See if you like those. Take a little
bit. Shake it down. That was me. I'm
guessing
one last one for you.
What do you guys think?
Could it work?
Yes,
it could work, right? I think it's
different. I got to say, you know, apple
cider vinegar is so popular that the
having a little diversity and something
a tiny bit sweeter because it's a little
sweeter would make a lot of sense.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. All right, Jen, you're
brilliant at all this. I want you all to
check out Jen's book, by the way, Diet
Right for Your Personality type. If you
got a great personality like hers,
you'll definitely like it. And we're
going to put the vinegar prescription
plan on dr.com.
But now, the moment we have all been
waiting for. You all have your apple
cider vinegar.
Raise them high, guys.
Everyone here, we all take a shot
together. This is how you break the
world record, right? You take a shot
together. The record on the biggest
apple cider vinegar group shot. I have
never had this many people take a shot
with me on a show before. Period. You
know, I don't love apple cider vinegar
by itself, but I'm doing it for you.
Some of you don't like it either. It's
okay. Just as one time. You all want in
on this?
Everyone's taking their shot all around
the studio, in my offices, even
backstage. Y'all ready? Three, two, one,
go.
Okay.
I like it.
All right. Now, everybody at home,
you're a little quiet.
Are you okay? Cheers to help though.
Not bad.
We got not bad. We got people like me. I
want you to take a shot with your
friends. Share it online with the
hashtag ACV challenge. I'll share the
best ones. We'll be right back. Was that
fun? You like it?
Up next, Cuba Gooding Jr. is here
opening up about the new role that he's
taking on that might surprise you and
his health offcreen. Can you drop us a
little hint? Little tiny hint.
Show me the honey.
Stay tuned.
Yeah. Well, you know, uh, me and your
trainer here, we was in the Olympics
together.
You remember Diane from track and field,
right?
Ah, you was going to bring that. You
remember when I used to stop you in the
second round of sparring, right? You
peed yourself that left hook.
Now, you pushing it too far. Yeah, you
pushing it too far now. Just you pushing
it just a little too far. So, now you
Dr. Seuss. You going to write a You
going to write a make believe.
I just wish your hands moved as fast as
your mouth.
Okay. Well, I tell you what, whatever
you want to do, we can do. Money,
however you want to get it.
He is one of the most versatile and
influential actors of our time. From his
Show Me the Money moment in the hit film
Jerry Maguire to showing us a more
serious side in his unforgettable role
portraying OJ Simpson. Oscar winner
Cuber Gooding Jr. is here opening up
about his life offcreen and the health
hurdle he never saw coming. Please
welcome to the show Cuba Gooding Jr.
[Applause]
[Music]
How are you, man?
That was very dangerous what you did.
That audience would have grabbed you and
taken you in, never let you go.
They adore you.
How you doing? You look good,
man. You, too. It's strong. He's strong.
I'm just trying to keep up with to keep
a good ease of the world. So, we just
saw a little clip of Bayou Caviar. Yeah.
And just because he he not only he's
acting it, but he directed it. Yeah.
Right. And you are incredibly in good
shape to be able to even keep up with
that. How do you do that? It's a show
about a retired boxer.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, I've been boxing for
about 25 years now. And um we were in
New Orleans when we shot it and I had
real professional pros come play with us
and uh there's one scene in the movie
where I took one to the face and I I
kept it in a movie.
It hurts.
Yeah, it does. It really does. Yeah.
The last time I boxed I was in college.
Yeah.
And the first thing I and most important
thing I learned was the duck.
That's right.
Which is a good lesson in life.
And to keep your keep your hands up.
Keep your hands up if you're not going
to duck.
That's right. So he you all remember won
the Oscar for best supporting actor for
football player Rod Tidwell. That was 20
years ago. And so I want to go back a
little bit.
I I think all of us were influenced
profoundly by the role and and
welldeserved Oscar victory and your of
course your speech when you got up
there. Unforgettable.
Thank you.
If what would you tell yourself back
then if you could right now? What wisdom
have you gained that we could all learn
from?
Um
I think I think the most thing is to
stay focused on your artistry as an
actor, the passion of your work and and
continue to grow even though you because
you remember
I became Academy Award winner Kubernet
Jr. So I was too precious about that
title when I should have just worked
just kept working with great directors.
Yeah.
Can we talk about your dad?
Sure. iconic musician, legendary soul
singer. I mean, an inspiration to a lot
of folks, but especially to you. And you
lost him. What was that like?
You know, it's hard. I think any the
loss of any parent, you feel a part of
you dies with the parent. And um my
father uh and mother had split up when I
was young. And I uh never understood
what was more important to him um family
or his career until I actually stepped
on stage in London um and got the
opportunity to sing in front of an
audience and and I I think that's why I
accepted that the the Broadway um offer
to come and do Chicago here as Billy
Flynn. Um yeah, it made me understand my
father a little bit more.
So which is more important? I think if
you can marry those two together, your
life will truly be enriched.
So, you're making this this wonderful
piece about OJ Simpson
that you really brought alive.
Thank you.
And in the middle of that, you lose your
dad. I mean, how how do you how do you
deal with the emotional trials and
tribulations of being in that character
at the same time there are things
happening outside and off the film that
are pulling at you? Well, that's a that
was it's a very that was an very
interesting time in my life because I
think all of my roles that make a real
impact in my career have been the ones
that have been closest to what's going
on in my personal life. If you look at
Boys in the Hood, I played the, you
know, Trey who finally gets that
scholarship and gets out of, you know,
the inner city violence. And at the
time, that was my first lead in a film
and then I became on the radar of
America. Then my next um part playing
Rod Tidwell in Jerry Magcguire, it was a
guy who who was a a famous football
player who kind of loses his way and
then he gets the big contract. And here
I am six years after Boys and Hood
finally getting a role that not only
brings me back into the spotlight, but I
win the Oscar for
uh OJ. I had just split with my my wife.
I had a young daughter uh the same age
as Sid Cindy and I lived in the area
where the murders took place in the same
city. Um I was always running into
people who knew OJ who had stories about
him and the reality and and fantasy line
started to blur for me and I used to
laugh at actors who say you know this
was a character that took me a while to
shake as dark character. I understand
what that means now because I think each
character kind of makes an imprint on
your soul. Mhm.
And to go that dark in that dark a place
to open my psyche up in that dark a
place affected me for several months
after finishing that role, you know,
it's pretty dark.
But having put yourself in that role,
Yeah. what do you think now about the
criminal justice system
and African-American men? I mean, how
does Yeah.
How does your perception about being
charged with a crime
change having played that?
Oh, you know, I don't know if it
changed. I just I know that there was
something broken especially in that time
period 1992.
You know, I was uh pulled over by police
when I was a break dancer with my crew
because I looked a certain way in a
neighborhood that they felt I wasn't
supposed to be in.
But yet I was an actor who was making
money and yet I got um pro uh racially
profiled. So um and I get it. I get it.
you know, uh there's there's men and
women of our law enforcement that that
you know, they have a lot of stress, but
to see and the walk in those shoes of a
character that is exposed to that life
without no uh way to get out, it's it's
very eye opening.
Now, I don't think you've ever spoken to
OJ. Is that is that correct?
No, no, no, no.
If if you could what would you ask him?
What would your question be just to get
a conversation going?
You mean if if I asked him what about
anything about life about just to
understand you know him probably better
than almost anybody else time period
more than I thought I ever would being
now stepped in his shoes but
specifically with OJ I believe when he
passes away if they do a autopsy on his
brain they'll find the CTE concussion
syndrome I truly believe that because um
you know that coupled with the fact that
men like that who show this ability to
have uh you know this athletic gift that
God gives them and everybody around you,
they literally stop your social um um
development
young because they want you to just
focus on this athletic ability that you
have. They make money off of you and
then they spit you out of the system and
yet you still have a mentality as a
child.
It's so interesting you say that because
we had OJ's lawyer on the show
and he brought a question to me from OJ.
They haven't talked about this much, but
OJ wanted to know about chronic
traumatic enapylopathy, CTE, this head
injury that football players are
getting.
Wow.
So, I was sort of caught up off guard by
him wanting to know more about head
trauma, having played football. You
know, he rushed for so many yards, every
time he rushed, he got hit and tackled.
But you think that might be something
that
you may have found just playing the
role?
Oh, 100%. You're not taking all that
abuse to your head and not having
bruises on your brain. It is trying to
cause lots of other problems as well.
But let me turn from that to you
personally. Okay. I just noticed your
voice a little horse.
Yeah.
And I know that you actually
Yeah. Come on, Dr. H. What you going to
do? Don't break it down on me now.
So, in order to play the role of OJ Yes.
You had to adjust your voice.
Yeah.
And did this start after that?
Uh, a little bit before it. A little bit
before it, but yeah, it was in
intensified with that.
I'm just smiling at you. I'm curious
what happened.
Well, you know, it's so funny. I had
went and saw an ENT and they put that
rod down my throat and looked at my book
because they want to make sure there
wasn't any palyps or any
anything cancerous or anything. They're
like, "No, no, it's just uh swollen and
sore and uh you need to relax a little
bit. You need to really relax."
And what I found is I I have this issue
where I I'm a night owl and I would
sleep before I I mean, sorry, eat before
I'd go to bed.
Yes. And what I would do is I would eat
and then I'd sleep and all of the food
would go up and then the the stomach
acids would kind of mess with my vocal
cords.
How do you like that?
So I finally realized that I had to stop
doing that and uh and it and it's uh
it's right at it.
Well, since you have become a world
expert on this, Dr. Gooding
and since you played Ben Carson called
me Dr. Good and I didn't go to school,
y'all.
So there's a really common reason you
can be a horse. When we come back, it
affects millions of people. Dr. Goody
Cub is going to help us hit reveal this
hidden cause. Stay with us.
[Applause]
Warning signs that can go unnoticed.
I was undiagnosed for 22 years.
How do you know if you're at risk for
thyroid cancer?
It sneaks up on you, which is one of the
reasons we miss it.
All new Oz.
That's coming up on Wednesday.
[Applause]
We are backstage with Cha Gooding Jr.
We're about to reveal the number one
hidden reason for a horse voice,
constant coughing, throat clearing, and
lots of other stuff. And we're not
talking about a cold. So, I know you're
worried about vocal cord issues. You got
through your performer. But, you know,
he's starting on Broadway in Chicago
playing Billy Flynn. Oh, you're the
perfect guy to do that, too.
But since we're backstage before go out
and reveal our audience, what kind of
exercises do you do before you start the
theater every day? Well, with the v
vocal cords, you want to keep them warm
and loose, just like any muscle. So, a
lot of humming.
And then you also want to make sure that
your neck and your face is relaxed. So,
we do this thing called the lion pose.
Lion pose.
Yes. You want to get your tongue out as
far as you can, your eyes as wide as you
can, your fingers as spread as part as
you can, but breathe normally.
And then slowly afterwards go into a
yawn. Ah.
Ah,
that's a lion's pose.
I like it. Maybe I'll go to Broadway.
Yeah,
come on over here. A different kind of
vocal cord check that I want everyone to
think about today cuz so many of you
complain to me about this problem. There
probably 20 million people who have the
underlying issue and I'll come back to
that in a second.
It has to do with silent acid reflux.
Mon'nique, how are you?
Good. How are you?
Is it Monique or Monica?
Monnique.
Monnique. All right. You may know this
gentleman
a little bit.
How are you, Milo?
How are you?
A little bit. How are you?
Are you able to continue
seen your face before?
Is that all right?
Have you seen my face before?
I did backstage.
I know. Actually, I didn't realize you
were the one in there and I was like,
"Oh, God."
You want me to You want me to leave?
Oh, no, no, no. You can stay. You can
stay. It's okay.
So, you know about silent reflex? We
just talked about it. Have you ever
heard about it, Monique?
No.
Never thought about it.
No, not really.
How many of you think you might have
silent reflux? Hands up. Oh, you're a
smart audience. I always say that. So,
this is the vocal cord check I want you
all to do together. Come on over, money.
Sure. And Dr. Dr. Goody, you come on
over with me. Gonna help us out. Okay.
If you have horseness,
you ever have horarsseness?
Absolutely. And it's a little
embarrassing because I already have a
funny sounding voice. I think
I like Oh, you sound great. Stop it.
Oh, you're the flatterer. But my voice
will get horsearo sometimes or break. I
sound like a teenage boy who's like
going through puberty. It's
embarrassing. Well, that's one kind of
horses. He's got another kind of horses,
but lots of kinds of horses we can get
into. Second thing, I'll put them up
here. Nagging cough. You ever get that?
Yes. Absolutely. And it's not a cold.
It's not allergy.
Yeah. Pretty common. Sore throat.
Yes.
So, all this fits into this little
constellation of issues called silent
reflux. And I'll never forget going to a
free clinic because we do them all over
the country and finding this young woman
who had been a very bad aszthmatic her
whole life.
Wow.
And then found out she didn't have
asthma, she had reflux. And that's where
a lot of folks end up finding out
they've got problems because the math's
pretty simple. You end up with a problem
with the with your stomach be able to
get the acid in the right direction. So
come on over. A lot of these symptoms
and then they make sense is basically
because acid's been burning you. Money,
you can come over me.
So if you look at this list, these are
the things I want you to start doing.
First, I want you to eliminate certain
foods from your diet. So look over that
big monitor over there, right? Which of
those foods do you see over there you
think you might want to eat less of? I
got a little chocolate there. Coffee,
tomatoes. What do you think?
Don't take my chocolate away. I love
chocolate. I do.
Cube, how about you? What are you eating
up there?
Well, coffee and the citrus. Uh, French
fries.
The French fries.
French fries.
You eat French fries.
That's right. I eat the French fries.
All right. So, stay safe. D,
you don't back your way into this. up on
the French fries. So, you're eating the
French fries. French fries.
Well, at least I like the French fries.
At least at least while you're singing
it on Broadway, put the fries away. All
right, that's number one. Number two,
you brought it up. You eat late at
night. Yeah. You go right to bed. Y
What time you had dinner on me,
Monique? Usually around 9:00. I try to
eat before 9, but sometimes it's 9 or
later, but then I'm going to bed right
afterwards. So,
yeah,
you know that already.
Let me show you something. This is
really interesting. This little
animation, not too complicated. If you
eat less than 3 hours before bedtime,
you cause this problem. Food comes down
from your esophagus, that swallowing
tube drops in there. Let's say it's a
burger and fries, right? If you give
yourself a couple hours, even if you're
having fries, you dissolve the food, it
goes out with your stomach. But
especially if it's fatty food or that
acidic food and it stays in there, you
can't get it out there in less than
three hours. So when you fall asleep at
night, you lie down ideally, right?
Gravity takes the acid back up the
swallowing tube and you're not even
awake enough to protect your airway.
Yeah. So your bu vocal cords, those
beautiful precious vocal cords in your
case especially, but they get to bathe
in acid. You can do as many lion poses
as you want. Now part of the reason I
wanted Monique here.
Yes.
Is you have a little secret solution?
I do.
Are you willing to share it with Cuba?
Um I guess so.
Oh, please come.
That's a solution that you take.
Yeah, this is a solution.
This is a little home remedy that helps
with the with the horseness.
Yes, I've heard a lot about ginger.
So describe it to everybody. So, I
usually do ginger tea. I do it plain. I
don't add any sugar or honey or
anything. Of course, you can, but I just
do hot ginger tea. Some cold really
doesn't work. It usually works on my
voice if it's hot. Not too hot, you
know, like a good
saying it's like a muscle. You got to
sort of loosen everything up in there.
Yeah, absolutely. Sus. And
some people find the ginger a little bit
uh
Oh, it's strong pungent. I got a little
better idea. Goodbye.
All right.
Show me the honey.
Yeah. Yay.
Dare I say it? I'm showing you the
honey.
You got me. It makes it sweeter.
I need my cat tree.
I actually This is my own honey. I
actually have bees.
Oh, wow.
And so I I have be I have my bee outfit
by the way with my son getting the bees
out.
So this this is a little gift from the
show.
Show me the honey.
Look at that.
Nice.
Hey, thanks for being here.
Thank you so much.
It's been a real honor to have you, my
friend. Best of luck to you. Cuba Cody
Jr. You can catch Cuba on Broadway, the
hit musical Chicago, the big screen. His
new film by you caviar. They're both
great. Right back.
[Applause]
How to murder your husband. The chilling
romantic suspense novel that made
headlines. Did the author turn her
fantasy fiction into reality? All new
Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
[Applause]
Now look who I am with backstage. I've
got her myself, Tiffany Theon. Now you
fell in love with her as Kelly Kapowski
on Save by the Bell and Bad Girl
Valerie. She was bad and naughty on
Beverly Hills 90210. And today she's
here to give you delicious and healthy
hacks for your favorite comfort foods.
Are you ready?
I am so ready.
Going to brave the audience.
The smartest one in television. Come do
it. I love it.
All right, everybody.
I know. You're the best. You're the
best.
[Applause]
Come join me in the hot seat. Welcome
everybody.
Hi up there.
Well, they like you.
Oh, they're so cute. You have cute
audiences.
They're the best. Absolutely the best.
So now I I my one of my goals today is
to allow your mom and mother-in-law to
come here without you. Not you in the
way.
I have no idea. My mom and my
mother-in-law especially are kind of
freaking out that I'm here right now.
They are.
Oh yeah. I mean my whole career they're
like Yeah. Yeah. Dr. Oz. I saw your
schedule. You're going to be on Dr. Oz.
It's huge. Huge.
So they can come without you.
Okay. Got it.
What What are their names? Um, Joanne is
my mother-in-law and my mom is Robin.
All right, Robin and Joanne. This is an
honor to have Tiffany here today. I hope
you keep watching today's show, but
forget about her. You come in person
someday. I'm right in the front here.
A love it. You're so sweet. You're so
sweet.
I'm so happy. So, you're a fantastic
cook and I didn't even know that much
about that side of your life. I I know
you do have shows and all, but when I
picked up Pull Up a Chair,
which is beautifully illustrated, but
also wonderful recipes, and I was
actually convinced, you know, Daphne, my
wife,
yes, I do know. I know all about her.
They're both chefs. They're highly
critical of recipes. This they liked.
First of all, why'd you call it pull up
a chair?
You know, it's funny. I I uh I grew up
in a family where family dinners were
every night and this way we connected.
Um we would kind of decompress. We talk
about our day, good and bad. And um I
feel like nowadays with phones and TVs
and a lot of distractions that we're
missing that connection. Um, so pulling
up a chair to me means reconnecting in
the day, having a meal with the people
that you love, um, and really kind of
sharing moments.
What does your mom say about your
cooking? Is she happy?
I'm very happy. I think she's happy
because she doesn't have to do it
anymore.
Come on over here. Let's show off to all
of America. First of all, you got
something very special that you make.
I do. I do. Um,
I'm interested. Yeah. Give Give the
title of it, by the way.
Okay. It's called Not Your Mama's
Meatloaf.
So, what does mama's is Robin? You said
what does what does Robin's meatloaf
look like?
Yeah.
Well, I think I think most people can
kind of probably relate to traditional
meatloaf being a little on the heavier
side using pork and ground beef. And I
actually use turkey and instead of using
breadcrumbs, which is also on the
heavier side, not so healthy. I use
oats.
Oh.
And that's what actually binds it just
as much as breadcrumbs.
So, real quick, we got a turkey.
Correct. You said you mentioned the
oatmeal.
We got the oats. We got onions, which
we're sauting right now. Um, look at
you, sir.
I'm going to be your sushi.
I love it.
I know it looks very clinical here.
Oh my gosh, I love it. And purple. I
like you. I like it.
Color coordinated.
Um, we have a little worsture. We have
tomato paste, eggs, of course, which is
another binding. Great way to add some
more protein. And
what's this?
Um, and that is Sriracha. Now, of
course, if you're feeding this to the
kids, you know, don't need to put that
in, but I like it a little hot. So,
I like that about you.
Thank you.
So, we've got the onion sauting. You
want to make sure you cool these first,
of course, before you throw it back in
because you're going to be literally
mixing this all up. Okay? And you're
going to stick that in. And then you're
basically going to put your eggs. All
right? So, I've got the oats. I'm going
to throw that in. We've got our tomato
paste. All right. And you just literally
mix. And this is actually really
something fun you can do with the kids.
All right. So, this whole thing gets put
into the
Yes. So, let me just a little salt and
pepper. You got to make sure you season
your food.
All right. You're going to actually put
this in the pan. Stick in it. Look at
you. Is it reminding you of something?
Yes. This is sort of like bowel surgery.
Okay, great.
Okay.
Okay. All right. Now, it's good enough.
TMI, Dr. TMI.
Okay. And then oldfashioned thing. My
mom used to do this and I kept it. I
literally flatten it out, right? And
then I actually put a coat of ketchup on
top of it again. And it kind of leaves a
really nice little glaze, which you can
see there on the finished product. I
love it. It's so good. I like a little
kind of crust on the top. Right.
What temperature? How long? Um 350 for
about 45 to 50 minutes
and you get this
and you get that.
Okay, now the moment of truth.
Okay, come on. I'm telling you, you're
not going to miss.
First of all, let's describe the
texture. It's full. It's rich.
Well, and it's it's good, right? What do
you think?
The mouth feels fantastic,
right? It's good.
It fills you. And the oatmeal is
actually better than bread crust.
Yeah, I know. And then if you want
something even better, like throw it
between two pieces of bread and call it
a sandwich. So,
I like that.
Up next, Tiffany has a healthier take on
brownies as you. And this is you will
not believe what fruit there's a clue
what fruit she uses in place of some of
that butter you guys throw in there.
You're going to like it even better.
That's next.
It's actually very good.
Calling all nursing students. The Dr. Oz
show wants to celebrate you. If you're
currently enrolled in nursing school,
you could have a chance to win $10,000
and be on my show. Go to dr.com to enter
by November 15th.
We're back with Tiffany D having a
blast. She's revealing healthy hacks to
some of your favorite comfort foods.
Listen, everybody loves a good brownie.
The problem is you guys sabotage with
how you make your brownies. So,
Tiffany's got a hack to get yours a
little bit healthier than it used to be.
A little bit. A little bit. Look, I have
two young kids and anytime I can kind of
like throw a little something healthier
in there, but still get them to eat
something that I know they like. Um, and
I do it with my desserts as well. So,
um, one thing that I have is avocado
brownies.
Avocado is the fruit.
So, avocado is the fruit. Um, it
basically is a healthier fat and can be
used just like butter. So, I take away
some of the butter and I use the avocado
and the kids have no idea that it's
there. No,
you will not know it's there. I promise
you.
I'm going to taste, but more
importantly, we have a very discerning
audience who's anxious. They're about to
rush the table. But, so go over the
basic ingredient.
Yeah. So, you've got your basics. You
got your chocolate. You've got your
butter. You just don't need all that.
You've got your flour, your sugar, your
brown, your cocoa, and I I actually love
espresso as well. Um Oh, espresso.
Yeah. But it's super super easy. I'm
telling you, like using avocado, make
sure you put it in a blender. Really
puree. So So it like it's really super
super creamy.
We actually did this here.
See, look how creamy that is.
So just put it in.
This is not chunky guacamole, people.
This is like, you know, creamy creamy
creamy. There you can see it.
Perfect. Exact. So again, take this,
puree it. You add it in with all the
ingredients. Bake for how long? Roughly.
Uh I'm trying to remember. It goes in
the oven 350 for about like 25 minutes I
say.
Okay. And your family loves these.
Oh my gosh. And what is this? This
paper. What is this?
Parchment paper. Now look, my husband is
great. He does not cook. Right.
He's only the He does the dishes, but
anytime if there's a pan in there that's
stuck with stuff. He's like, "Parchment
people, parchment paper people, please,
please just make sure you use it." This
is so great. Look at this. It lifts
right up.
And really, look, that's not bad.
Why doesn't your husband understand this
basic stuff? So great.
Does your mother-in-law supports you or
your husband in these kinds of battles?
Both. She's very neutral. Sensitive
point.
She's really good. She's really good.
You want to try it?
Yeah. I'm just going to cut one, but I
want to take the other.
I'll cut it for you, honey. I'll feed
you. Don't you worry.
Who's interested in brownies here? Okay.
Oh my goodness. All every hand went up.
All right. But here's the deal. I want
some honest feedback here. You know
what? Leave that. We'll take this over
there. Yep.
Grab this over there.
All right. Are you not gonna eat some?
I'm gonna take that one, too. Bring that
with me.
All right.
Here. Grab Grab the mic. Come on over
here.
I'm grabbing the mic from your tush.
All right. Now, I want to I'm going to
give you some I want some honest
opinions here. All right.
What do you think? What do you think?
Let them Let them taste. Let them taste.
This feels very
I mean, right.
Tell me if you actually taste the
avocado.
Oh my god.
Not at all. It's amazing.
Do you love it?
So good.
Yeah.
Like a scale of 1 to 10.
All right.
What about yours? Go ahead.
All right. You guys keep passing that
along. Stop. I see you whining and
complaining over there.
Make sure you share. Be sweet now. What
do you think?
It's rich. It's velvety. It's silky.
Creamy, right?
This is brilliant.
We will change your lives. This is how
to eat these from now on.
You can find today's recipe and a bonus
recipe on dr.com.
This cookbook is fantastic. Here's a
picture of it called pull up a chair.
It's available now. And guess what
audience?
You're getting a copy.
All of you enjoy it. Make the recipes.
We'll be right back. Eat this.
[Applause]
How to murder your husband. The chilling
romantic suspense story that made
headlines. Did the author turn her
fantasy fiction into reality?
All new Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
[Applause]
It is time for a 10second selfch check.
What can your forehead tell you about
your heart health? There's a new study
who says you might want to grab a mirror
or get your phone to look at your
forehead right now. Take a quick photo
for an early sign, a warning sign of
heart disease. Everyone checks their
forehead out, right?
Yes or no?
Well, you see your forehead anyway.
All right. What are you looking for when
you look at your forehead?
How big it is.
How big it is. How about you?
Wrinkles, obviously.
Wrinkles.
Yes.
So, it's interesting. We got two
different things, right? Size of the
forehead and where you got wrinkles.
Here's something that's pretty cool. And
this is you may not. I got some
anonymous pictures of the forehead for
my audience. Come on up. You can help me
with this. All right. I'm not sure. You
might be in there even. Stand right
there. Okay. Now, this is pretty cool.
So, this is a member of the audience.
You notice there's no wrinkles at all.
This is a a youthful forehead. All
right. This is a very stately forehead,
right? There's a little bit of of a
wrinkle here, but not much. Right. And
then we found this one. All right. Now,
this is a wise forehead. I actually
don't mind the the appearance of
wrinkles, but I am a little concerned
about what they mean because for
everyone who has wrinkles, this new
study says you got to check for deep
forehead wrinkles like this or it could
look like this, too. You see this? These
deep wrinkles, they're important because
research has found that the deeper your
forehead wrinkles are, the more likely
you are to have heart disease like
atherosclerosis.
And the reason for that is the forehead
has very small little blood vessels. And
so if you have hardening of the
arteries, those small vessels, they
block up more rapidly. You'll get cracks
in your skin, right? These deep lines
became become creases and it's a sign of
blood vessel aging. So if it's happening
in your forehead arteries, it could
happen in your heart arteries. So you
all clear on this?
Yes.
Right. So it's a good idea to do a quick
forehead check every once in a while. Do
it in friends and family. It might help
you track what's going on inside your
body. In fact, what you want to do is
take pictures of your forehead, share
them with your friends, share them with
me, do with your other friends. Make
sure everyone's watching everyone
together because together change is
happening. Our journey is just
beginning.
Nicely done.
[Music]