[Applause]
Today I am weighing in on dairy. Now
we've known for some time that fat has a
place in our diet and that's raised a
lot of questions including which is
healthier, whole fat or low fat. Now a
new study making headlines around the
world not only questions the type of
milk you serve your family but also it's
maybe finally setting the record
straight on dairy in general.
Three servings a day. The government
says that's how much low or fat-free
dairy you should consume every day. It's
been the official recommendation since
1985 when the USDA made the switch to
low-fat dairy as a means of managing fat
intake.
Since then, fat-ree dairy has been
filling and flying off supermarket
shelves. There's low and no fat versions
of milk, cheese, ice cream, even
fat-free half and half. The fat-ree
trend first took root in the 1970s when
a controversial government commission
touted a low-fat diet as the best way to
tackle heart disease and shed pounds.
Now, two new landmark studies suggest
people consuming full fat dairy actually
weigh less than their low and no fat
counterparts and have lower risk for
diabetes.
But with controversy still surrounding
saturated fat, the kind found in full
fat dairy. What percentage should you be
pouring?
Joining us is a world expert in this
field, Dr. David Cass, great medical
expert at Yale and founder of the True
Health Initiative. He's published Kelly
more than 200 research papers, 15 books
on nutrition, lifestyle, and health. So
I went to you the expert on this. Why
has this study had such an impact on our
field? Well, the impact, I think, is all
these headlines. And since people eat
every day, they're fascinated with every
study about diet. And the ones that make
the headlines aren't the best studies or
the most important ones. They're the
most shocking ones, the most surprising
ones, and in particular, the ones that
tell us what we want to hear. Like ice
cream is good for us today. Fat is good.
So, I think that's the impact is really
all about those issues. Let's talk about
what the studies actually showed. And
and there's two we're going to highlight
that. first looked at
a lot of folks and the effect of the
effect of dairy and on their weight and
diabetes. So go ahead. Right. Yeah. So,
so this study looked at an association
between fats from dairy in the blood and
the likelihood of developing diabetes
over time and is shown here 46% lesser
likelihood of developing diabetes in
over 3,000 people when there was dairy
fat in their blood. Now, importantly,
that's just a study of association.
There there were other things that might
have accounted for the lower rate of
diabetes. We'll come back to that. But
that's basically what this study showed.
But in theory, if you look at this, you
say, "Okay, if I if I have fats from
yogurt or milk in my blood, seems to I
that seems that I have a much lower risk
of getting diabetes on the surface." And
and if that were a strong consistent
finding and if it were consistent with
other research, I think we could be more
confident about it. But actually the
association with specific dairy fats was
pretty weak. It wasn't totally
consistent. In other words, there were
associations between certain fats from
dairy but not all fats from dairy. So I
don't think we have a definitive answer
there. Okay. And the other big study
looked at something people are always
asking me about which is will I lose
weight or gain weight if I eat whole fat
dairy. Yeah. And I think that's a really
important question because if there is a
defense against diabetes men as you know
the main driver of the risk for type two
diabetes is weight gain. So this study
actually a larger group of of women
there was an association between eating
full fat dairy and protection against
weight gain over time. Now does that
make sense? Well yeah it could for a
couple of reasons. First if the fat and
dairy fills us up and keeps us full
satiety. If we get satiety from the fat
and dairy then we might actually eat
less calories overall and that of course
protects against weight gain. The other
thing is that fat does not raise blood
sugar directly and it doesn't trigger an
insulin release and it's the rise in
blood sugar and the release of insulin
that causes fat to accumulate around the
middle and that's the fat that increases
the risk for diabetes in particular. So
there may be protection because of
satiety that that lasting feeling
feeling of fullness and there may be
some protection because you're pushing
out of your diet sugar and refined
starch calories that do have an effect
on blood sugar and insulin levels. Come
on over. Let's draw some some pictures
here for everybody. Maybe this might
help you understand how Dr. Katz is is
interpreting what we're seeing. So,
let's say you have skim milk. All right?
You put skim milk in your stomach and it
has about 90 calories a cup, right? So,
you actually don't feel like you're
completely full, but you had your milk,
but you don't quite feel like you got it
all in there, right? If you have whole
milk, well, it's got fat in it, and for
that reason, actually has extra
calories, 150 calories specifically.
Let's compare these. You got the whole
milk, 150 calories. That's more than the
90 calories from the skim milk. So in
theory, in theory, you should gain
weight with whole milk and lose weight
with skim milk. Don't you all think
that? Right? Makes perfect sense. Right?
What Dr. Catz is saying is this
difference of this, you know, 60 calorie
difference. You make up over the course
of the day because you get the
grumbling, the growl, the hunger. That
that looks like a lot of us, right?
You're still hungry after you have that
skim milk. And the things you go after
oftentimes will have sugar in them. Some
in America we eat a lot of sugar. So
that might penalize you either because
of the hormones or because the fat
directly has a benefit. Who knows why?
But that's been the big slippery slope
here because on the surface you'll see
why everyone in America thought skim
milk was better. Now some researchers
are saying that this type of fat you
touched on was vitally important. It
might be the reason for this. Yeah. So
so a couple issues here. So, you know,
given a choice between 90 calories from
skim milk plus a whole bunch of calories
from cookies cuz you're still hungry
versus the 150 from whole milk, you may
be better off with the whole milk. I
think this all comes down to association
and context. So, these are studies of
association. They don't prove cause and
effect. You know, maybe the people who
ate the full fat dairy were people who
were less concerned about their weight
in the first place. Maybe they didn't
gain weight because they weren't as
prone to gain weight and they said, "I
can afford the calories." only the
dieters drank the skim milk. We we just
don't know for sure. Um there are a lot
of other things that might have
accounted for the association both with
weight and with diabetes. There are some
fats in dairy that might be specifically
protective. And by the way, not all the
fat in dairy is saturated. Some of it is
conjugated lolinic acids and these are
thought to bump up metabolic rate just a
little bit but maybe enough to make a
difference over a span of years. So
there may be some healthy fats in dairy.
To me, context is key. Now you your your
heritage is Mediterranean. There are a
lot of healthy fats in the Mediterranean
diet. You get them from nuts and seeds,
olive, avocado, fish, seafood. I would
argue if you're getting satiety from
healthy, wholesome foods, fiber in in
vegetables and fruits and whole grains,
beans and lentils, healthy fats from
those sources, there's very like
unlikely to be much benefit from the the
fat in dairy. And and the healthiest
diets around the world, healthiest
populations, they don't eat much dairy.
the blue zones, they don't eat much
dairy and the dairy they eat is goat and
sheep, not cow. And and most of the
intervention studies that have produced
the best results, even preventing
diabetes, haven't relied very much on
dairy. So, what does David Katz do in
his family? What do you actually do
differently based on this research? So,
I I haven't changed anything based on
these studies because I think they're
interesting, but I don't think they
provide a definitive answer. So, the
average person trying to make a decision
right now, the mom's going to go to the
store today and buy a carton of milk.
Does it matter really whether it's skim
1% 2% or full fat three and a half%. You
know, I I think it matters in context.
If you're eating a typical American
diet, you might derive some benefit from
the higher fat varieties. And if you
wanted to split the difference, 2% is
right in the middle. It's had 50 what I
do. It's had 50% of the fat taken out.
It hasn't had 98% of the fat t is right
in the middle. Um so again, if you have
trouble controlling your appetite, your
hunger, and you're eating a typical
American diet, first of all, fix that.
But, you know, dairy fat may be your
friend. If you don't have trouble
staying full, if you're getting plenty
of healthy fat from nuts, seeds, olives,
avocado, fish, I don't think there's a
specific reason based on these studies
to add dairy fat to your diet. I'm going
shopping for 2%. David Catz, thank you
very much. My bottom line on dairy
approved options for both you and your
family. When we come back,
we've been talking about a new study on
dairy suggesting that whole fat is a
healthier choice over low fat to ward
off diabetes and weight gain. So, in
light of the study and all the
controversy around it, what are the best
dairy product recommendations for you
and your family? What are you going to
buy? Pediatrician Dr. Tanya Alman has
the answers because she's given them
every day in her office. So, first off,
there's been a lot of controversy about
whether adults should have any dairy at
all. So, what do you tell your patients
and their parents? So, I talk to the
parents as much about nutrition as I do
the kids. And dairy products are
important for all ages. They provide
protein, calcium, vitamin D. These are
nutrients that most people don't get
enough of. So, the recommendations are
still three servings a day of dairy
products for adults. Cup of milk, 3/4
cup of yogurt. I know you love Greek
yogurt like I do or a slice of cheese.
All right, let's talk about the milk
specifically. There's two rules that you
argue everyone should abide by when
they're buying milk for their family. So
organic milk is from cows raised
organically which means that their feed
doesn't contain chemical pesticides or
fertilizers. They're not given hormones
and they're not given antibiotics. So
that's less exposure to all of those
things for your family. All right. And
why do I have these cool little goggles
here? What's try it? These are fun. My
patients love these. It's a great way to
make drinking milk fun for kids.
Do I have it? Right. I'll let you try
it. Oh my goodness. This is ridiculous.
In your mouth. There's got to be an
easier way to drink milk than this.
Wouldn't all kids love drinking milk
through fun straws? They would. Uh, they
would. I I got to say I'd rather use
these with curly cue things though. This
is it's a fashion statement. What about
raw milk? What do you think about folks
who love that? So, you know, raw milk
has become trendy because some people
perceive it as being less processed, but
the process of pasteurization, the
heating milk to kill bacteria is
actually important, especially when you
have kids and pregnant women drinking
the milk because you want to make sure
there's no dangerous bacteria. Then
there's the other end of the spectrum,
these ultra pasteurized milks, they
never seem to go bad, right?
Ultraasteurized milk can last in the
refrigerator for a lot longer. And in my
house, I buy three types of milk. I
drink non-fat, same as my 10-year-old.
My 8-year-old likes 1% or 2% and my
one-year-old drinks whole milk. So, in
some ways, ultra pasteurization can help
keep the milk longer in the
refrigerator, but it does taste a little
different, and some people don't love
the fact that it's more pasteurized.
Yeah, it seems seems more natural that
it would go bad, but I get if you're
buying lots of different kinds for
different age groups, you got to be
careful. Okay, speaking of that, let's
talk about the fact that one size
doesn't fit all when it comes to kids.
So, explain to us and we'll start off
with kids that are under a year of age,
what do you tell your patients about
what makes sense for them? So, under one
year of age, kids cannot drink regular
cow's milk because they can't really
absorb it. It doesn't have all the
important nutrients they need at that
age specifically. So, you want to make
sure you're giving your baby breast
milk. Obviously, is the best thing from
birth. This is breast milk until one and
only one heck of a breast.
This mom did a great job here. And if
you're not giving breast milk, then you
want to use an approved infant formula.
All right. But you can give yogurt, and
I love Greek yogurt even for babies
starting at 6 months of age. Plain. You
don't want to get them used to the sweet
taste of anything with added sugar. And
also cheese is also acceptable in a form
that they can handle. All right. What
about ages 1 to two? So age 1 to two,
the brain is really 60% fat. So they do
need the fat for brain development at
that age. So over age one, whole milk is
recommended. Now if you have a family
history of high cholesterol, heart
disease, then your pediatrician may
recommend 2% milk, which still has
enough fat for brain development. And
all this also counts, right? Exactly. If
you got a mom this giving, by the way,
you know, you can breastfeed to an
adult. Ex. It would be nutritious for us
as well. You want to try it with the
straw? No, I'm not going to try it. I
stopped breastfeeding a long time ago.
All right, now let's talk about people
like us. Anyone over the age of two,
frankly, what do you recommend? Over age
two, you can come down on the fat in the
milk if you like the taste and instead
give your family healthy plant-based
fats. Avocado, nuts, nut butter. We're
even giving nut butter now at six months
of age to babies to help prevent
allergies. And salmon is great for all
ages. Omega-3s, really healthy fat. So,
you give young children fish fats. I do.
I recommend everything at six months of
age. gets them used to eating healthy.
Start young and their taste buds will
like healthy food as they get older.
Thanks for the wonderful advice. Alman's
new book is called What to Feed Your
Baby. Is out now. We'll be right back.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good