[Music]
Today on Oz, summer health myths busted.
Should you pee on a jellyfish thing?
You've actually had a little bit of
personal experience with this. It was so
painful, Dr. Oz. Will a base tan save
you from sunburn? Will a bunch of grapes
help keep mosquitoes away? I have some
beauty in your next barbecue. Plus, keep
your lips luscious this summer. A cure
for cracked dry lips that keeps your
pucker perfect. Coming up next on Dr.
Oz.
Hi everybody. Today we are busting the
biggest summer health myths. Now, first
I asked lifeguards from coast to coast
the biggest summer myths they hear
around the water. I've got a perfect
person to talk about it. Please welcome
first place winner, first place of the
National Lifeguard Surf Race, Tom
[Applause]
O'Neal straight from the competition.
Yeah. Right out of the water. How do you
How do you actually win? What do you
What are you racing? You save people's
lives. You Well, sort of. We simulate
saving people's lives. But the race that
I won is called the uh men's open surf
race. Uh it was the 2014 USLA National
Championships which were held in
Virginia Beach. And it's just a great
venue for lifeguards to showcase our
skills and fitness level. They don't
care about the audience cares about this
by the way. Oh, sorry. You can talk
about all those skill stuff. All right.
So, you know, let's go through this cuz
you guys know a lot about summer. The
number one myth that everyone is talking
about is the one you probably hear at
the beach or the pool, which is
absolutely. So, Dr. Oz, the biggest myth
is waiting 30 minutes after you eat to
go swimming. That's the number one
thing. Parents are yelling at their kids
all summer about this. So, who
perpetuates this myth? Where does it
come from? Moms and grandmoms. They're
the ones yelling at this at the kids all
summer long without stop. So, here's the
deal. Waiting 30 minutes after eating is
a myth. It's a myth. You can swim
afterwards. It's not a big deal to go
swimming. Explain, if you don't mind,
what you guys learn in lifeguard school
about this myth. Sure. So, in lifeguard
training, um, they told us that
nothing's going to happen. Uh, in my
experience, nothing has ever happened
from something like this. In all of my
colleagues experiences, nothing has ever
happened like this. So, moms, rest
assured, it's okay. Yeah, you might get
a leg cramp here and there, but it's not
taking you down. All right. Next thing
that a lot of swimmers believe has to do
with these guys. Look at these folks. Do
you recognize these things? Oo,
jellyfish. And here's the thought. Are
we better off peeing on a jellyfish?
Sounds crazy. Denise, please join us.
Denise, how are you? Hi, Dr. O.
I would love to hear your story. You've
actually had a little bit of personal
experience with this concept. I have. My
husband and I were vacationing in Mexico
and unbeknownst to me, I was stung by a
jellyfish. And then it was so painful,
Dr. Oz, right here on my shin. And my
husband saw an episode of Friends and
indicated that urinating on the sting
would obliterate the pain. Yeah. You all
remember that episode of Friends, right?
This it started a major movement. So, he
actually peed on your leg.
He did. And you let him pee on your leg.
And I let him pee on my leg. And it did
not work at all. It burned. It even
burned even more. It was It stung. It
raised. It was just very, very painful.
Have you gotten them back for this at
all? I have. I have. Many, many times.
So, here's the deal. Peeing on a
jellyfish, my friends, it's a myth. It's
a myth. You know, now you actually know
a little bit about this. You've been
stung. I understand. Yes. Absolutely.
So, would you like to see the jellyfish
sting? You want to see his sting? Here,
I'll hold your All right. Thank you. So,
while I knew this was going to happen,
uh, while competing in Japan on an
international trip, I was stung by a
jellyfish and it actually left a a burn
mark, a scar on my arm. That's Did you
pee on that? No, I didn't. No, I didn't.
So, what Denise and all the other Here
you use this on your husband this next
time you try. Absolutely. What did you
use instead of pee? So, fortunately, the
lifeguards there were equipped uh as we
are here at home. Uh the first thing you
want to do is you want to get out of the
water. Immediately get out of the water
and you want to wash the affected area
off with salt water, warm salt water. Um
that will uh alleviate the pain and
deactivate the stinging cells rather
than using urine or tap water or fresh
water that can reactivate the stinging
cells. So what do you think people are
saying to you right now about that? What
was she thinking? I'm getting sweaty
talking about it. Thank you for sharing
your story. Thank you very much, Tom.
Thank you so much. And well, listen, I
want you to pay attention. The inside
scoop of your favorite summer treat.
One thing we hear a lot from ice cream
lovers is that they get brain freeze.
Well, guess what? Brain freeze is not a
myth. It's not your imagination. Even
the brains of Harvard researched and
found that it's a real thing. What
happens is when the nerves of your top
touch the cold, your blood vessels
expand and it triggers a pain message in
your brain. One easy way to avoid this,
warm up the roof of your mouth with your
tongue and you keep eating ice cream all
day long.
I don't know about you, but I thought
that was a pretty cool explanation. You
didn't get it. Cool. Anyway, next hold
up the summer product that you pay for
every year. Let me see it all up there.
What do you guys pay for every single
year? Yes. Sunscreen. Sunscreen. What's
your first name? Christina. Christina,
come stand if you don't mind. So, here's
the big idea. How long should we keep
that sunscreen before we toss it? I tend
to toss it every year. Every year. Is
that what you guys sort of do yearly?
Makes sense, right? It's a cream. All
right, everybody. That, my friends, the
concept of throwing out sunscreen every
year is a myth. Stamp it myth. It's a
costly myth. So, I want to I want to
talk you out of it. Have a seat. You're
going to enjoy this. Going to save a lot
of money today. Dermatologist Deborah
Watenberg is here. So, why is this a
myth?
So, this is a myth because sunscreens
actually have an expiration date printed
on them and the shelf life of most
sunscreens is two to three years. Did
you hear that? Two to three years. That
make you mad? It could be yours. So,
sunscreens um are tasted for their
stability. You want to be sure that you
you store your sunscreen in a safe
environment, not in the back of your car
for the whole year. Then it's going to
be bad. You want to throw it away. If
you leave it next to the heater in your
bathroom, it's not going to be great.
But if you're storing it in a cool, dark
environment through the winter and then
it's still there over the summer, you
can use it. The bigger issue is though,
you need to use approximately the size
of a shot glass in order to cover your
body when you are applying an SPF. So
one bottle is around 4 ounces. Some of
them are a little bit bigger, but if
it's 4 ounces, you're only getting
approximately four applications worth of
sunscreen. And as you can see, that's a
lot of sunscreen to apply. So, the
bigger issue for people is to remember
you need to apply it, you want to apply
it onto your skin before you go
outdoors, at least 20 minutes before
heading outside and you want to apply it
thick so that you get the SPF that's
applied or recognized on the bottle. So,
if you don't get this much used in a
summer, we got a separate issue for you.
Thank you very much for the tip. All
right. Oh, one more question. I hear
about this, but people always say, "I'll
get a pre-tan. I'm just going to get a
little bit of sun, but I won't burn."
And then that smart base tan will
protect my skin. So there is no such
thing as a healthy base tan. So can we
stamp it with a myth? Is that right?
Absolutely not. Base tan myth. Not a
smart way. What does it really do? A
base tan gives you a false sense of
security. It makes you think that you
have a little bit of color and therefore
you can go out. You know, maybe it's the
equivalent of a sunscreen SPF of a two
or three, but that's nothing. And it's
not healthy for your skin. So it's
giving you a false sense of security.
You go outdoors, you burn when you have
a base tan. You also are destroying your
skin. And if you look at the picture
that's on the screen, you can see this
woman has a base tan, but the damage
that has been done on the right side of
that screen shows that she has
hyperpigmentation, discoloration, and
damage. The damage to those cells is DNA
damage, and the cells are being
destroyed, increased risk for skin
cancer, increased risk for wrinkling,
and aging. And everyone's wearing
sunscreen so that they look young and
they look beautiful. If you do that, you
get a base tan, you're going to look
terrible. Thank you very much. All
right, let me go to Ivory and her
husband Carrie. They believe the sweeter
your blood, the more bugs will bite you.
How are you, Ivory? I'm good, Dr. Ivy.
Are you wearing ivory? She She's wearing
ivory, too. Yes, I am. So, what gives
you this belief that it's a it's a
sweetness issue that attracts those
mosquitoes to you? Well, I'm always
getting bit by mosquitoes, Dr. Eyes.
Why? My husband, he's never getting bit.
He says it's because I'm sweet, which
he's a smart man. I a very, very smart
man. But it's very irritating. They bite
me. It's itchy. It's scratchy. and he
never gets bit. So, I'm going to share
something with you. There a lot of
people think what you're saying is true,
but the thought that you're sweeter and
therefore the mosquitoes like you is
actually a myth. That's not why they're
eating at you. There's another reason
they are. They actually are attracted to
your body odor. Really? Yeah. Think
about that. It's our odor they like.
Carrie, do you think your wife smells
all the time? All the time. No questions
asked. Does she smell good or bad? Good.
Good. She's making sure. Yeah,
absolutely. Of course, he's going to say
that. So, but it's interesting. it.
That's not the smell I'm talking about.
There's actually a smell that we can't
appreciate that mosquitoes sense. And
when they get that smell, oh, they just
go after it. So besides individual
odors, there are things for example like
mint. So you have a mint jeulip for
example here. This will attract
mosquitoes to you. They love perfume. So
if you have that might be the
difference. Do you wear perfume? No.
Yeah. Just asking. So perfume
unfortunately women think it's you know
best bad luck when you put perfume on
that smell good for everybody else in
the in the place. You're also smelling
better for the for the mosquitoes and
cheese. Interestingly, you're putting
cheese on something else and just, you
know, or just cook it and you get on
you. They're going to like that. Okay.
So, you're probably wondering, what am I
going to do about this? Exactly. So,
here's what you're going to do about it.
I have something for you to pack at your
next barbecue. It
is grapes. Grapes. Grapes. Oh, here's
why I love grapes so much. It turns out
that mosquitoes detest the smell of
grapes. really they can't stand it. They
run away. You could actually put this
like citronanella around the dinner
table and it'll help steer those little
things away. And you certainly can smear
it on you a little bit if you get it
wrong. And unfortunately, here's the
only catch. Wine doesn't count, right?
You would think wine will get you there,
but there's something about the sugar in
the wine or something's throwing you. I
don't know what it is, but they don't
like that. But grapes themselves, real
grapes will work because I can go
outside and keep track of everybody
else. You're very swab and debated.
You test your summer mythology with my
quiz on dr.com. I'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up, the annual examination that
every woman wants to avoid and doctors
are fighting over it. Some say it could
put your health at risk. Do you still
need a yearly pelvic exam? Find out
next. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz, daytime
darling Wendy Williams gets real. The
scale registered a lot. 193 lbs. Does it
affect your self-esteem at all?
Revealing. Has it been a lifelong issue
for you the way? Yes, I come from a
place of fat. My first diet was first
grade and always entertaining. You had a
little work done. Yes, I did. Can you
tell? How her health secrets help you.
That's coming up tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
Oz. Friday on Dr. Oz. Touted as safe.
Now, ecigarettes called into question.
Whether you use them or not, why the
smoke-free alternative could be more
dangerous than you think. Plus, how
clean is your hotel room? Dr. Oz
uncovers their dirty secrets. Before you
check in, check out Dr.
Oz. Oh, that's coming up on Friday.
Today's big conversation is an important
topic for all women, especially in their
30s and 40s, who've had kids and think
they no longer need to go to their
OB/GYN. There is news that says your
yearly pelvic exam is no longer needed.
This recommendation is creating a stir
among doctors and some say it could be
putting your health at risk. OBG Dr.
Lauren Striker is one of them. So, why
are so many OBGN's up in arms over this
report? Well, the American College of
Physicians, who's an organization of
internists, not gynecologists, has
stated that there's no value in an
annual exam unless someone has a very
specific complaint. But no complaint
doesn't mean no problem. So,
gynecologists are really worried that a
lot of very important conditions are
going to get overlooked. And the other
fact is that less than 20% of women
actually go to a gynecologist for an
annual exam. Which means if your family
doctor internist isn't looking in your
vagina, no one's looking in your vagina.
This is not good for women's health.
Pelvic exams, they're an enigma.
Everyone knows the outside part, but
explain why they're so important to you.
What what actually happens? Well, a lot
of women don't realize how much is
actually happening. And a and a pelvic
exam starts with a very careful
inspection of the outside of the vagina,
the vulva. There may be a vulvar cancer,
precancer. There might be genital warts.
There might be inflammation. There might
be a rash. And then we actually look
inside the vagina at the walls of the
vagina to make sure that there's no
infection, that they're not dried, that
they're not irritated. And then we
inspect the cervix, the opening to the
uterus at the back of the vagina. And
even if it's a non-papsmear year, we
want to know if something's growing
there that shouldn't be. And then, of
course, the last part of the exam is the
bimmanual exam. When your gynecologist
uses two hands, one inside the vagina
and one on the belly to feel all the
pelvic organs, the uterus, the ovaries,
but even if a woman's had a hyctomy and
doesn't have a uterus, there's other
things in the pelvis. There's bowel,
there's bladder. We get a lot of
information from this exam. So papsmears
is not the major reason you do a pelvic
exam. No, in fact, it's not the same
thing at all. And that leads to so much
confusion because a lot of women are
told you don't need a papsmear every
year. And in fact, you don't. But it
doesn't mean that you get a hall pass
because someone's got to look at your
cervix, someone's got to look in your
vagina, and someone has got to feel
those pelvic organs. So, Dr. Sar has
three big concerns with this new report.
The first is that the American College
of Physicians has recommended public
exams are no longer needed for women
without any symptoms who are not
pregnant. You think that is flawed? This
is really flawed. First of all, it puts
the onus on the woman to know what her
symptoms are or if she even has
symptoms. And very often women do have
symptoms but they're embarrassed. They
don't want to say I have an odor or my
vaginal walls feel a little dry. So they
don't bring it up. The second is is a
lot of women think their symptoms are
just a normal part of aging. It may be
that they're having painful sex or that
they're losing urine but they think well
I'm not going to mention that. That
happens to every woman. Or they may not
even know that a symptom is important
like heavy bleeding that's getting
progressively heavier. And then there
are the conditions that have no
symptoms. There are a lot of very
serious conditions, vulvar cancers. I
mean, the list is endless of things that
have no symptoms until they're at a very
late stage, and that's not when we want
to find these things. Next, the report
says that chances for identifying
ovarian cancer during a public exam is
low. Is there any evidence really that
you make a big impact on ovarian cancer?
We're in agreement on this one. This is
not what gynecologists are recommending
an annual exam. Unfortunately, we know
that even women that have an annual exam
do not have a lower rate of dying from
ovarian cancer than women who do have
that don't have the annual exam. So,
that's kind of gotten skewed and that
that everyone is saying, well, you're
not going to find ovarian cancer anyway.
Why why bother with the exam? But
there's so many other things we're
looking for. This report also cited that
public exams are painful and
embarrassing, which I'm sure the
audience can attest to. In fact, before
the show talking about pain, yeah, I
asked on dr eyes.com our audience what
they thought. 68%
the vast majority said that they are
painful. Are you surprised by this?
Well, yes and no. I mean, it it depends
on which part of it is painful. A lot of
women when they say the exam is painful,
they're specifically talking about the
speculum exam. And every woman here is
familiar with what this is a speculum.
And the thing to keep in mind is that
just like shoes, speculum comes in many
different sizes and many different
shapes. And just like every woman
doesn't wear a size seven shoe, every
woman doesn't use the same size
speculum. And too often, if they see a
doctor who might only own one size
speculum, it's going to hurt. Also, if
the exam is painful, it may be an
indication that there is a problem, that
there's dryness, that there's an
infection, that something is growing
that shouldn't be. I really highly doubt
that most patients who see a
gynecologist annually would report that
it's a painful thing. Here example, this
is, you know, these are two sizes that
are available in the same doctor's
office. The same Mine's much bigger than
yours. That's right. And I probably have
about 30 different sizes. Which one
would you pick? Yeah. You know, everyone
always says to me, I want the small
speculum. Well, why I mean, can they can
women ask for the small speculum? They
can ask for whatever they want. I'm
going to use the right size, and the
right size is the smallest speculum that
will enable me to do what I need to do.
So, the speculum that I use for a 22y
old who's coming in for birth control
pills and maybe needs an STD screen is
going to be very different than the size
speculum I'm going to use for a
50-year-old who's having heavy bleeding.
So, it really depends and that's why you
need to go to an expert. Then there's
the really big issue, I think, which is
that women are embarrassed. Yeah. Is
that a valid concern? Testicular exams
are embarrassing. Rectal exams are
embarrassing. Nobody would say that
there's no value in those exams. The
problem also from my point of view is
this is once again making these women's
topics taboo. This is humiliating. Don't
go down there. And so what happens is
that women feel even more ashamed when
the doctor says, "You don't need an
exam." And she's thinking, "Ooh, boy. I
guess I should be really kind of
embarrassed about down there. I'm not
going to bring it up." We need to
normalize, not marginalize a pelvic exam
and make women comfortable. So give me
the bottom line. What should everyone
hear from you right now? When you go to
your doctor, he or she doesn't ask if
you'd like your blood pressure checked.
They shouldn't be asking if you'd like a
pelvic exam. This is part of a
comprehensive exam which is better for
women and which women should insist
upon. Dr. Thank you very much. Thanks
for bringing the speculums with you.
Anytime. Right back.
Next, he's traveled the globe in search
of natural ingredients that improve your
health. Now, Dr. Andrew Wild sets a new
course, a map through the market. How to
find Andrew's healthy treasures in the
aisles of your grocery store. The best
foods for your health. Next, tomorrow on
Dr. Oz, daytime darling Wendy Williams
gets real. The scale registered a lot.
193 lbs. Does it affect your self-esteem
at all? Revealing. Has it been a
lifelong issue for you? The weight? Yes.
I come from a place of fat. My first
diet was first grade and always
entertaining. You had a little work
done. Yes, I did. Can you tell how her
health secrets help you? That's coming
up tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
[Applause]
Oz. Dr. Andrew Wallace traveled around
the world searching for the best natural
ingredients to heal you and improve your
health. But today, for the first time,
he's going aisle by aisle to give you
his ultimate grocery store guide. Please
welcome my friend, Dr. Andrew While.
So I want to be clear about this. You
say we can harvest the healing powers of
foods in a grocery store and on a
budget. You don't have to have tons of
money to do this. Absolutely. I mean the
most expensive things in the grocery
store are meats and animal foods and you
can reduce the percentage of those in
the diet. And then vegetables which are
terrific power nutritional powerhouses.
Most of them are quite cheap and there
ways to get even less expensive. Let's
start with the frozen aisle which is a
good example. We've talked a lot about
frozen foods, which I think are
fantastic option. Uh, and a lot of
people don't really believe us. I wanted
to bring the guru in to tell us about
this. What do we look for to make sure
we're buying the best things in a frozen
form? Well, first of all, you I would
stay away from vegetables that are
peeled, chopped, or crushed. Uh, look
for USDA certified organic vegetables,
which you can find. And, uh, some
vegetables, frozen corn for example,
actually have more nutrients than fresh
corn. They do. Yes. And there are some
new uh frozen super sweet varieties of
corn that I think are fantastic,
delicious. So frozen vegetables, you
know, if you choose them carefully, are
great. So let me all show you why what
Dr. Wild says is so provocative happens
to be true. And it's true for a lot of
produce actually. Normally your produce
is picked way before it's ripe for a
reason. They've got to get it to you. So
to prevent spoiling, it's picked early,
not quite ripe yet. It's put into the
bin. They never quite developed the full
spectrum of vitamins, minerals, and
enzymes that mature ripening would have
allowed. So, your produce is short
changed nutritionally even before it
gets onto the truck. And then once it's
on the truck, the produce typically
travels more than 1,500 miles, 1,500
miles from the farm to your store. And
the amount of nutrients in your produce
diminish even more because of exposure
to the sunlight, for example, the time.
And then, of course, once it's on your
shelf, well, the produce is already
about a week old. And then after it's on
the shelf, it can sit there for another
four or five days because you haven't
bought it yet. And that produce section
happens to be the next stop. But please
remember this is the reason that frozen
stuff might make a difference for you.
So there are some vegetables, Dr. Wild,
you argue actually are probably worth
buying fresh. Well, I think all salad
greens obviously things like celery uh
and greens. I'm a big fan of greens and
I think they're often missing in the in
the American diet. They are great
nutritional powerhouses. inexpensive. Is
there one vegetable in particular you
think we're really missing out on? Well,
you know, I love charred which is
sitting here, but you know, also
collards, kale, which is here, all of
these things. And I like them briefly
cooked. I don't know where this idea
came from that's popular in the South of
cooking greens for hours, you know,
usually in a lot of bacon fat as well.
But, you know, if they're flashcooked,
stir fried in a little olive oil,
garlic, red pepper flakes, greens are
delicious and really good for you. Yeah.
So you you 30 seconds a minute I'd say
couple of minutes. Couple minutes till
they're bright green and still crunchy.
All right. Fruits uh been maligned of
late. They have a fair amount of sugar
in them. What's the rule for shopping?
Well, you want to get low glycemic load
fruits and berries you can't beat. I
mean the pigments in berries are
antioxidants that are strongly disease
protective. They're relatively low on
the glycemic load scale as compared with
tropical fruits. I I would get USDA
certified organic burries when you can
and look for really dark colored ones.
All right, the next trick on your list
uh is a problem for a lot of us. The
bread bakery where we go in there, we
smell it. Close your lungs up. You guys
probably smell this bread over there in
the audience already. What is the secret
to picking the healthiest bread? Well,
look, here's a little test that I used
to do when I was a kid and had bread
like this. I remember sitting at the
table. I would pull the crust off and
then see uh how small a a thing I could
get it in. Even you did that. If you can
get bread down to something like that or
or smaller, that is not the kind of
magic.
You want breads that are dense and that
don't that don't crush up like that, you
know, that are firmer. Uh and preferably
ones where you can see some cracked
grains in that have real substance.
These fluffy breads are the ones that
really spike blood sugar and are not
good for us. of the firm bread, which
one you like is a spelt is that your I
like spelt bread. That's a an an old
variety of wheat that's uh got a higher
protein content and uh grown in
healthier ways. That's one to try. See
if you like it. Yeah. And again, these
are not big price differences. Probably
no price difference. Buy the stuff that
makes sense. The olive oil is if it's
not in the bread, it ought to be there
because we always eat it. Absolutely.
Right. How do you know if you're buying
the right olive oil and how do you get
on a on a bargain? Okay. You you want to
taste olive oil and chop around because
price of olive oil doesn't necessarily
correlate with quality. Uh first of all,
you want to look for for olive oil that
is certified to be really olive oil
because there's been a lot of
adulteration of olive oil. That's been
much in the news. I like I use a sniff
test. I like olive oil that that
smells rich and fruity. Uh I like olive
oils that have a deep green color. And
also an interesting taste test. When you
taste olive oil, at the end of the
taste, often there's a peppery bite or
catch at the back of the throat. That's
a good thing. That's a compound called
oolioanthol that has an
anti-inflammatory effect as powerful as
ibuprofen. And you want that in your
olive oil. So look for olive oils that
have a peppery finish. Find the canned
aisle. This is a place where you can
save a lot of money and get yourself a
lot of health. Absolutely. This is this
is high quality protein. Really good for
us. We have sak canned sakkeye salmon
here. a very nutritious food. We've got
canned sardines and I like kippers,
which are smoked herring fililelets. Uh
canning softens the bones of these and
that's a good calcium source. These fish
all have a lot of omega-3 fatty acids in
them. And they're cheap. You know, these
are cheap sources of very high quality
protein and fat you can get in any
supermarket. Listen, Dr. and I teamed up
to give you a complete guide. Looks like
this. It's they'll tell you exactly what
you can take with you when you go
shopping and what you come home with. To
print it out, go to our website, dr.com.
Take advantage of this. We'll be right
back. Thanks,
[Music]
B. Next. Bad weather preventing you from
puckering up. Find out the real reasons
why your lips are getting the raw deal.
Kiss those chap lips goodbye. Secret
beauty tips to keep them protected and
healthy all year round. Coming
up tomorrow on Dr.
daytime darling Wendy Williams gets
real. The scale registered a lot. 193
lbs. Does it affect your self-esteem at
all? Revealing. Has it been a lifelong
issue for you? The weight? Yes, I come
from a place of fat. My first diet was
first grade. And always entertaining.
You had a little work done. Yes, I did.
Can you tell? How her health secrets
help you? That's coming up tomorrow on
Dr. Oz.
[Music]
Friday on Dr. Oz. Touted as safe. Now,
ecigarettes called into question.
Whether you use them or not, why the
smoke-free alternative could be more
dangerous than you think. Plus, how
clean is your hotel room? Dr. Oz
uncovers their dirty secrets. Before you
check in, check out Dr.
Oz. Oh, that's coming up on Friday.
They're incredibly common. They are
thoroughly annoying and they hurt.
Talking about chapped lips and everyone
blames them on the cold weather. But
today, I'm going to reveal three sneaky
reasons that why your lips are so
chapped and what you can do to keep them
healthy. But I need my assistant to the
day to help out. So, how about seed 104?
Where's
104? Where's 104? Oh, we got a winner.
We have a winner.
I'm so happy you came.
How are you? Very good. Let's get you
dressed up here. Good. Thank you. What's
your name? Lisa. Lisa. Nice to meet you.
Hi. It's so nice to meet you. Is that a
Is that a wedding ring? Yes, it is. Is
that the proposer back there? Yes. Wave
your hands up there. You have very good
taste. Oh, thank you. Now, what's his
name? Aaron. Aaron. Aaron. Yeah. So,
when you're with Aaron, does he ever
comment on your lips? Yes, he does. Now,
as as a male, he probably only comment
on how beautiful they are, but does he
ever comment how chapped they might be?
Um, I think so. Maybe if he avoids a
kiss or something. Yes, that would be a
problem for him. So, what does it feel
like when you get chapped lips? Uh, like
burning and just very dry. It's the
worst. And it begins to crack sometimes
and you just don't know what to do about
it. Exactly. You came to the right show
today. Come on over here. I'm going to
show you why your lips are so vulnerable
and and what we can do to make sure it
doesn't happen again. Okay, so let's
first explain what's going on with your
lips. The lips and in fact the entire
body, the skin is made up of different
layers. Some parts of the body have
really thick amounts of skin. We have
to, right? These papers represent the
different amounts of skin we have in
different parts of our body. So let's
say the foot, you'll notice if you look
at a picture of the of the foot from the
side, it'll look like this. So you have
the sole of the foot with a normal skin
here. Then you have this big thick
layers of skin up there. So you can
dance around. Do you like to dance?
Yeah. What kind of dancing do you do?
Oh, anything. Anything. Is that true?
Good. Yes. He likes He likes everything
about you. All right. So So you have all
this skin here that's there to protect
you so you can walk around, do things
you need to do in life. But if you lose
a little bit, right? Go ahead. Help me a
little bit. Keep going. Keep going. Keep
going. No matter what you do to your
foot, there's always a lot left. Yes. So
you need that protection. So I'm glad
you're made with feet with lots of skin
on them. Okay. Your arms don't have as
much as your feet, but they still have
quite a bit. Okay. Okay. So again, if
you look at the picture here, you'll
notice that your arms have that same
base layer, but just a little bit on
top. So you, for example, if you go out
in the sun too much, you'll peel and you
don't lose that much. So out in the sun,
go ahead, throw a little bit of that
off, right? And even with a little bit
of sunburn, your your skin still has
plenty of redundancy on the arm. Okay?
But your lips, the precious lips, lips
he loves so much, the lips that you have
chapped, sometimes they look like this,
right? There's nothing on top of them at
all. It's barely what you need. And it's
like one single piece of precious paper.
Yes. You can't afford to waste it. It's
the only one you get. And because
they're so thin and because they also
don't have any oil glands in them, it's
like the Sahara Desert. Oh, the lips are
always problem having problems because
they can't replenish themselves. They
can't moisturize themselves like the
rest of our body. So that causes them
issues so many of us face. So when do
you normally get your chap lip issues?
Um winter and summer. Both. Yes. When
don't you get chap lips? Spring and
fall. Okay. So, come on. So, the winter
is actually pretty common because you
get cold, dry air. Yes. And summer
happens for different reasons. Often
because of the sun. But there are three
sneaky reasons, okay, for chafted lips.
I'm going to show them with you today.
Most people don't know about these, but
it's going to change you for the better.
The first is we forget putting SPF
protection on our lips. Okay? So, you
actually need to put some protection on
there. I pro I I think you ought to get
lip balms with at least 15 SPF on them.
Nothing less. It's easy to get that way.
And make sure every morning, all year
round, summer, winter, in including fall
and spring, I want you to put a little
bit on there. Simple to do. Okay. The
next sneaky reason that your lips are
chapped, that you breathe through your
mouth. Oh, really? Yes. Okay, that makes
There's a couple reasons for that. When
you breathe through your mouth instead
of through your nose, you end up taking
all the moisture off the lips. Oh.
Ventilating basically and evaporating
all the moisture off. And one of the
signs that we might be breathing through
our mouth and in fact the time when we
often will chap our lips when we're
sleeping if we're
snoring. Are you a snorer? Are you Is
she a snore? Am I a sto? She's a snore.
Yeah, we have double hands up. I got up
there. Oh gosh. Okay. So, okay. So, but
so when you wake up in the morning if
you feel parched, does that ever happen?
Always. So, you are a snorer. I am.
Yeah. You can store it any size. By the
way, it's not it's mostly men, but women
do it as well. So, I want you to keep on
your bedstand something that can allow
you to moisturize your lips. The key
ingredients to look for are coconut oil
and shea butter. Perfect. Okay. The
third one is my favorite one. The third
sneaky reason, and I built you a model
all for you, Lisa. Oh, nice. The third
surprising reason is that you're licking
your lips. Oh, let me see you lick.
Oh, you're out.
We all lick differently, by the way.
Notice your friends.
So, normally it gets dry after you
licked it. And then what do you do? I
lick it more. Lick it more. We all do
that. So, I built you a model to
demonstrate what happens. So, you get to
be the tongue. There's your tongue.
Okay. Put it in the saliva. That's the
saliva. And lick these lips. Okay. Lick
them up nicely. There we are. Put them
up. Yeah. Nice and moist. Now, what ends
up happening when you lick your lips is
the air begins to evaporate it, right?
So, all of a sudden, you get this stuff
going on, right? And as it evaporates,
watch what happens. It begins to chop
it. You see that? Yeah. You see that
happening? Yep. And you Well, you pull
your side off as well. You see it all
the whole thing begins to chap off and
you got these sort of raw surfaces here
which we don't want. All because of darn
tongue licking our lips. Now, instead of
doing this, you put that down. I want
you to do something very innovative.
I've never shown this on the show
before, but I want you all to do this
for me. And please, if you ever ever
thought you should trust me, trust me
this one time, okay? Cuz you're going to
it's going to change your life for the
better. So, you're going to take the
best source of oil you have. Okay.
What's the oilest part of your face? Um,
my nose. Yes. You take the oil for your
nose and one do this in the audience.
Take the oil from your nose like this.
Natural oils. Mother Nature gave it to
you and then apply it to your lips. Oh
my. It's not dirty. It's oil. It's
natural oil. Apply that. It's nature's
lip balm. Wow. It's free. It's all
yours.
Oh, come on now, people. That's what you
have me doing this. I'm doing it. I'm
doing it. And that's how you know that
you can protect your lips without having
to do anything hard. You have been
wonderful and congratulations. Take
care. We'll be right back.
Is there a natural remedy you use to
keep your lips from getting chapped? Dr.
Oz wants to hear from you. I actually
make my own lip balm. I use beeswax and
coconut oil. A little labor intensive,
but it works great. I love it. Share
your story with us on Facebook.
Next, it's the room where you make the
most important health decisions and the
one we most often clean. The kitchen.
Learn to wipe out your kitchen dilemmas
in just 10 seconds. Small solutions to
make big changes in your life. Stay
tuned. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz, daytime
darling Wendy Williams gets real. The
scale registered a lot. 193 lbs. Does it
affect your self-esteem at all?
Revealing. Has it been a lifelong issue
for you? The weight? Yes. I come from a
place of fat. My first diet was first
grade and always entertaining. You had a
little work done. Yes, I did. Can you
tell how her health secrets help you?
That's coming up tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
Oz. This year I am focusing on the small
steps make big changes in your life. And
it's in the one room you make your most
important health decisions, your
kitchen. Sue Perry's joining me. She's
the deputy editor for Shop Smart
Magazine. So, what do you do? How are
you? Thanks for being here. Good to see
you. I went to visit Sue's setup and I
was so intrigued by some of these
insights that I wanted to have you here
to share with everybody else. But let's
first talk about the kitchen. Why is it
so important for our health? Well, first
of all, it's where we prepare food. So,
it's got to be super clean. You don't
want to be cleaning, you know, preparing
food in the dirty dishes. Plus, it gets
a little challenging because it's the
hub of the house. Everybody hangs out.
Everybody drops the mail and backpacks.
It becomes homework central. It's more
of a challenge to keep clean. And lots
of craziness happens there, which is why
we're going to focus on it. And I asked
three viewers to send in their kitchen
dilemmas. And so the healthy 10-second
solution to each. Take a look at
Evelyn's kitchen dilemma. I'm sure you
will all relate to it. My dishwasher
gets so unorganized and it's always way
too full. And I end up having to do two
loads. I need some tips and tricks so
that I have more time to spend with my
girls and are not up all night cleaning.
So, Evelyn's here in the studio. That's
a big pile of dishes. How long does it
take to get through all that? I feel
like it takes me forever to get through
those dishes, and I end up having to do
multiple loads just to get them cleaned.
So, Sue, the 10-second solution for
dishwashing, which is not a major part
of our life anymore. Oh, first of all,
all dishwashers actually have a pattern
of how they should be loaded. And your
manual is going to tell you that. And if
you don't have your manual, don't worry.
There's actually a general tip. The
dirty side of the plate always faces in
toward the center. Now, this dishwasher,
we looked at the manual, and so we know
that all the dishes go in this way. But
look what happens if you did it
halfhazardly. Your the water jets are
not going to hit that. And what you want
to do is not block your water jets. You
want to have your dishes sitting
upright. So that's anybody at home who
doesn't know how to outload their
dishes. That's one little tip of how you
can have. Again, this is crazy, but in
this case, every one of the dishes will
be angled in that direction. That's how
it's supposed to be. That's how it's
supposed to be. Now, the silverware, it
seems like the easy thing to do to put
all the spoons together, all the forks
together, and all of that. But you know
what they do? They nest. They clump
together and they're not going to get
the water jets. Called spooning for a
reason. Spooning for a reason. So, you
want to mix it up. Okay, great. So,
we're all good here. Okay, perfect. Then
this plastic, if you can address that
for me, cuz this is one big issue.
Plastic never goes in the bottom. Never
in the bottom because the heating
element is there. It can melt the
plastic. So, your plastic goes up here.
Okay. Thank you so much. Arena sent me
her kitchen dilemma. It has to do with a
special kitchen odor.
Dr. Oz, I feel like I constantly have an
odor coming out of my microwave. Do you
have any tips and tricks on how I can
better keep it smelling fresh and clean?
So, Arena is joining us. What have you
tried to get rid of that odor in your
microwave? Well, I'm a working mother of
a one-year-old and I tend to use the
microwave to reheat food, to defrost.
So, I've been using harsh chemicals and
I wish I had another solution. Take it
away, Shu. Lemons. Lemons. There's
nothing harsh about it. And they're
they're cleaning. I mean, you think
about lemon scent is in all kinds of
cleaning solutions. It just smells so
good. What you can do is just we chopped
up some lemons here. It doesn't have to
be perfect. You can take half a lemon,
chop it up, put it in about a cup of
water in a microwave safe bowl. Put it
in the microwave on high for about a
minute and let it boil just about a
minute. And then 10 to 15 minutes. Let
it just sit there. Open up the door.
You're going to have some vapors. Wipe
it out. It's clean. Perfect. And that's
simple. I don't know why you didn't tell
me this before. I know. And it makes the
kitchen smell good, too. The citric acid
we think binds up the odor particles,
but I love the concept. All right. We
have Charlene. She has a problem with
grease buildup. Hi, Dr. Oz. I need your
help. I always have a problem getting
the greasy residue off of my
refrigerator and even in my cabinets. Is
there something that I should be doing?
I need to be a surgeon just like you
just to clean it. Can you help me?
Charlene's a surgeon like me. Thank you
for a compliment. So, how much time do
you spend trying to get the grease off
the top of refrigerators and other
places in your house? I'd say about a
good 20 25 minutes just trying to get
the gunky oil off the top as well as
also um the residue that's on that forms
on the cabinets and um I'd like to be
spending my time doing more things like
watching our show. Well, you're very
kind. 10 seconds to all I'm giving you.
What's the solution? Okay, the solution
is first of all, you have to clean off
the gunk. So, dish dishwashing liquid
and hot water is a great uh grease
buster to clean off the surfaces. But
once you clean it off and you get up
here, if you go up on there, I'm going
to tell you what we're going to do.
Whoops. This is a really cool idea.
Can't do this in heels. Here's the
trick. You take the You take the end of
this and I'm going to plastic wrap
plastic wrap on top of the fridge.
You'll never have to clean off the gunk
again. What we're going to do is we're
going to cover the surface. If you don't
have plastic wrap and you have wax
paper, does the same thing, craft paper,
anything like that. And we're just going
to cover this surface.
Overlap. Make sure the surface is all
covered. And then in a few weeks, ball
it all up, throw it out, and do the same
thing again. You will never have to
clean the gunk off your top of your
fridge. You can do it on hot cabinets.
Yes, I am. You can find a gallery of my
favorite 10-second gets at dr.com. We'll
be right back.
What's your favorite microwave hack?
With a young child, we're always looking
for ways to save money. When our sponges
get a little old, I moisten them and put
it in the microwave for a minute. Perks
it right up. Good as new. Share yours on
facebook.com/drz. Tomorrow on Dr. Oz,
daytime darling Wendy Williams gets
real. The scale registered a lot. 193
lbs. Does it affect your self-esteem at
all? Revealing. Has it been a lifelong
issue for you? The weight? Yes, I come
from a place of fat. My first diet was
first grade and always entertaining. You
had a little work done. Yes, I did. Can
you tell? How her health secrets help
you. That's coming up tomorrow on Dr.
[Music]
Oz. We've told you computer games are a
great way to exercise your memory. Take
a look at this dog. Violet the Italian
greyhound took that tip to a whole new
level. If you look careful, this is the
best part about this. This is actually a
game for cats. Those are goldfish. But
Violet doesn't care. She's pretending
she's a cat right now. We should all
take a note from Violet. She attacks
that iPad. Simple games are easy to
access and can be played quickly. They
improve the players moods. They promote
relaxation. They ward up anxiety. Violet
is a very happy dog today. Now, it's
time for, in case you missed it, a
couple of things I want you to remember
from today's show. We had a big
conversation about pelvic exams. There's
news that says your yearly pelvic exam
is no longer needed. Now, this is
especially important for all women in
their 20s, 30s, and 40s who've had their
kids and think they no longer need to go
to their OB/GYN, but top OBGYn still say
there is value in a pelvic exam. If your
doctor doesn't offer one, you probably
ought to make it an an opportunity to
suggest it to them. Next, good news for
anyone who's been caught without lip
balm. And here's what you can do.
Instead of licking your lips, it's going
to sound odd, but I want you to take
your fingers, rub it on the side of your
nose. That's where mother nature's
provided your skin with natural oils.
Remember, it's not dirty. It's just oil.
And then apply it as a balm to your lip.
I see you grimacing out there. I want
everyone to do this. Just try it once,
please. Just trust me just once. Take
the oil from the side of your nose and
put it on your lips. There we are. It
doesn't taste bad, does it? It's your
own oil. Thank you for trusting me. I
want to close with a warning. Please be
careful about what you buy online,
especially weight loss pills. There are
some dubious people online that prey on
folks like you who are trying to do the
right thing for your health. Sometimes
they even try to make it seem like I'm
endorsing their products, which I don't.
To see a full list of our trusted
sponsorship partners, you can go to
dr.com. And I'll see you all next time.
[Music]
[Applause]