Today, a story so tragic that it made me
take a second look. This man beat his
mother to death with a hammer. There's
no dispute about that. The question is
why? He says a fog of allergy medicine
made him do it. We're going inside your
medicine cabinet and we're asking, can
allergy medicine make you kill? And the
killer sister is here. What she says
about the case may surprise you. But
first, crime correspondent Melissa Moore
has the story. It was an attack so
brutal that prosecutors decided not to
show autopsy photos. The victim had a
crushed skull and crushed facial bones
in numerous places. 26-year-old David
McGee bludgeoned his mother to death.
Crime scene investigators looked at the
apartment and discovered a bloody hammer
next to the bed and blood spatter all
over the wall. At the trial, McGee's
lawyer said the killing happened in a
quote fog of benadryil. She claimed
David was completely under the influence
of the allergy medication when he
committed the horrific crime. But a jury
of his peers were not swayed. After less
than a day of deliberations, David was
found guilty of firstdegree murder. Now,
two questions remain. Why did he do it?
And is allergy medication to blame for a
crime that completely devastated a
family?
Melissa Moore joins us. So, what stood
out the most to you about this case?
Well, there's two things that stood out
to me. First, just watching the trial,
it was absolutely heartbreaking, but
also the fact that these common everyday
medications that we use could be used as
a defense for murder. Like, we we
covered, you know, cold medicine, that
was a defense. We covered eye drops,
that was a defense. And now it's
benadryil. David stories is is a strange
one. What's his relationship with his
mother like? Well, it's it's really
unique. This is a family that they live
together. The son was 26. He was living
in a one-bedroom apartment with his
mother. He he had a close relationship
with her, but it sound like there was
some contention from what we heard in
the courtroom is that the mother was
badgering him to get a job. And do you
know if he had any mental health issues,
anything prior to this murder that might
explain why he did it? Yeah, he was
living at home because he had an
unexpected stroke at the age of 14. He
at 14 at 14. And so this really hurt the
family, but also caused them to grow get
closer together because they thought
they were going to lose him, that he was
going to die. And so they they rallied
together to save his life. But this
ultimately impacted his life forever. He
was never the same ever since. He
suffered from depression. He he didn't
finish his high school. And so this
ultimately, you know, really caused him
to have a lesser quality of life. this
issue of the fog of benadryil, which is
what David's attorney uses a defense.
Had it ever been used before? Where did
the idea come from? Had you ever heard
of this? No, I've never I've never heard
of it in this sense and it's it's never
been the cause for murder. And I know
for myself when I take benadryil, like
it knocks me out. Like it's actually
more like a sleeping pill for me. But
for him, I think it had different
consequences. So David was ultimately
found guilty of firstdegree murder and
sentenced to 26 years to life. So the
scene in the courtroom was very unusual
after the case, after the verdict. What
did the judge allow that's so unusual?
What's unusual is that he allowed the
family members to come in. The maternal
grandmother came and hugged him. The
sister came in and was with him. And
this is not a normal procedure. That's
right. So So the mother of the dead
woman Mhm. and the daughter of a dead
woman both hugged the murderer. Correct.
And that's unusual for a judge to allow
that. But also, he actually wrote a
suicide note. Oh, he did. He did. He
wrote a suicide note and saying that the
reason he killed his mother first was
that she wouldn't witness or live with
his death. So, he argued that I'll kill
you first, then I'll kill myself.
Correct. So, up next, the science behind
whether allergy medicine can be used as
a deadly weapon. What really happened
that day?
We're back taking a forensic look at the
death of Rebecca Apodaka whose son was
convicted of bludgeoning her to death
with a hammer. Now he says he committed
the horrific crime because he was under
a fog of an allergy medicine. Uh team
forensic criminologist Dr. Laura Petler
is here in the crime lab. So the
toxicology report says that David
ingested between 80 and 100 of these
right allergy pills at 25 milligrams a a
pill. Now, just to give you an idea,
right, that's abuse of a
medication. That is a lot of pills to
take. And that's what he says he took
the night that he murdered his mother.
The label, by the way, if you look at
it, it says take one to two tablets
every 4 to 6 hours. If you take 80 or
more pills in a 24-hour period, you are
more likely to overdose than to kill
somebody else. So, we don't actually
know what caused David to kill his
mother with a hammer, but the autopsy
report does give us some clues, but at
least you know what's going on in David
when this all took place. So, Laura,
tell us about the where. So, the where,
we were going to use this dollhouse to
explain what happened in this case. The
victim appears to have been ambushed
from behind because the autopsy report
shows that she had some wounds to the
back of her leg, some bruises, and also
to the to the her arms. Then the victim
ends up somehow over here on the bed.
The hammer of course was found near her
body on the nightstand, but her her
injuries, Dr. Oz, are cranial facial. So
that means that most of the attack was
actually just face on head on right to
the top in in front of her head.
Typically with faceown victims, we find
those in angerbased crime scenes. Now
let's talk about how she was attacked.
This is important. The autopsy reports
say the small bits of bone and brain
fragments were found on the bed and the
floor along with blood spatter on the
walls and the ceilings. Yes. Can you
just show me how that would have
happened? So, as far as the small
fragments of bone, she has subacoid
hemorrhaging, which is about six layers
down into through past the skull, past
all of the other membranes there. So,
those those bones break into a million
pieces and just shatter. So, that's why
you have it on the floor. Yes. And then
we're going to do this demonstration.
It's going to kind of explain a little
bit. Now, you're going to have to be
careful because Oh, look at this. This
is service, isn't it? I was trying to be
your scrub nurse here. Yes, I appreciate
that. Okay, so we're going to
demonstrate that how blood spatters.
Blood has a specific viscosity and this
blood is viscosity that it's similar to
milk. So, here's what I'm going to
do. Going to put a little bit of blood.
And this is not real blood, by the way.
Fake. And then when force is applied to
blood, especially in a beating death or
in a stabbing death, this is kind of
what happens. I have to open this up
just a little
bit. I'm going to apply force to this
blood and it's going to spatter.
Or if I change the direction of my hand
this way, it spatters that way. So in
order to have spatter, you have to have
an injury. the blood pulls into the
injury first and then when the weapon
like this I'm gonna take this glove off
when the weapon specifically a hammer is
used in this particular
case when when it's applied to the same
area that it was that created the injury
first you get what we have here in the
demonstration in the box now David where
did they find him David so David the
convicted son he is found in the closet
so fascinating because he could have
gone anywhere in this house But what he
does, he stays in the closet. We know
that he had tried to commit suicide. He
slit his wrist and things. But so he
followed through in the letter that
Melissa mentioned. Yes, he did slit his
wrist and he did slit his throat and
then he did take pills after he murdered
his mother. So what? Put this all
together for us. We we know he took the
benadryil. Were his acts intentional or
were they under the fog of some allergy
medication? The the in this particular
case, we have all of the cranial facial
injuries. That's the listed cause of
death on the autopsy report. So, it's a
purposeful location. He's not beating
her big toe with a hammer. He's beating
her cranial facially. So, it's a
deliberate intentional act. All right.
We cannot ignore the fact that David
allegedly had an unexplained stroke as a
teenager. That's unusual. We try to get
the medical reports. We were unable to.
So, I can't confirm that, but it was
discussed at the at in the in the court
proceedings. There can be cognitive
changes after stroke. That's true. You
can have problems solving challenging
issues. You can have difficulty
understanding concepts. We know some of
the common side effects of allergy
medications. You mentioned Melissa
drowsiness. That's the most common one.
That's why people take them. Fatigue,
dizziness, constipation. Right. Yeah.
But not murder. Murder is not a side
effect of an allergy medication. So,
what prompted David to do this in your
opinion, Laura? You know, it's hard to
say exactly, but we know that he did
have some cognitive deficiencies due to
the stroke. Uh, typically with an
anger-based killing like what we see in
this situation, it it's some event that
triggers the offender to attack.
Remember, David claims he was going to
kill himself first, but then decided to
kill his mother so she wouldn't have to
live with his suicide. So, up next,
David's sister's here. She's going to
speak out about that and what she says
you don't know about this case and why
she forgives her brother for killing
their mother. We're back investigating
if over-the-counter allergy medicine
could have led a son to bludgeon his
mother to death. David McKe says he was
under the influence of allergy medicine.
His sister Ella joins us now. When did
you first realize there was a problem
with your mom? My mother was supposed to
go to dinner with my grandmother and um
one of her friends. So when my
grandmother called me and said, "Hey, I
can't get a hold of your mom." And so I
decided just to go over to her house.
So, you go into the house and what do
you see? I saw my mother laying on her
bed face
down and it literally looked as though
she was just sleeping.
But she wasn't. No. I went over to her
and I was like I I touched her shoulder
and I was like, "Hey, mom. You you
forgot to pick up grandma. Aren't you
going to dinner with Meline and Grandma?
And I the second I I touched her
shoulder, I realized that something was
not
okay cuz she was
uh she was not the right temperature
that a person should be.
I know this is hard and I and I'm sorry
that you had to go through that.
It's something that you um you always
think happens to other people until you
realize that to other people you are
other people and it anything can happen
to anyone
and it's just it's it's awful.
Your brother, was he quiet? Did you did
you hear him? How did you find him? I
didn't know that he was there at first
because I didn't see him. But um I found
my brother in the closet and the first
thing that I thought at that point was
that someone had come in and hurt my mom
and that my brother was hiding. Were you
scared at this point? Cuz you you didn't
know what had happened to your mom, the
the perpetrator could be anywhere. And
if it was your brother, did it ever
cross your mind that it could be your
brother? No, it
didn't. The like I said I thought he was
if he was hiding I the only thing that I
thought was that he was scared of
someone else. There was no point in
which I was afraid of my brother or
thought that he could have done
something. Had your brother ever
demonstrated signs of mental illness? My
brother had had a stroke when he was 14
years old. But um afterwards
he a lot of people I guess with life and
death experiences like that they either
go one way like where they embrace life
to the fullest or they get really
depressed and reclusive and my brother
was one of the people that got really
depressed and reclusive. Was there ever
a moment as he was suffering through the
depression and whatever damage happened
because of the stroke where you thought
he might be a danger to himself to you
to your mother?
Never a point. I mean, I I thought I
thought
maybe at a certain point that he was in
danger of hurting
himself, but that point passed and he
gained like he went back to school, he
gained friends outside of of that. He
got a job and everything. And so I I
didn't really worry about that as much,
but obviously I should have.
Well, should have is a very dangerous
combination of words. You're right. This
defense of being in the fog of an
allergy
medicine. Do you think as a sister that
was what happened that evening? I
do. I know
that benadryil is the same thing as a
sleeping pill. And my brother had taken
so many of them. Like I'm amazed that
I'm amazed that he could function even.
So the fact that something awful
happened, I absolutely believe
that if he had not been under that
influence that he would have been able
to control himself or not have had that
happen. It was preventable.
You forgiven him for killing your
mother. I have forgiven him. I love my
brother. He will always be my brother. I
feel very strongly that just because
someone does a bad thing does not make
them a bad
person. But I forgive my brother because
he will always be my brother.
I'm sorry. Don't be sorry. It's okay.
What has he told you about how he
feels about what happened?
He feels such immense
guilt and that
he he regrets absolutely everything that
led up to what
happened and that he wishes that he and
this hurts me so much, but he wishes
that he had just followed through with
killing himself
first so that I would still have my
mom
and he wishes that he could undo it. And
now he wishes that eventually he can get
out of prison to try and start doing
something to write some of the wrong
that that he did. How do you want all of
us to remember your mom?
My mom was the coolest person ever. She
was my best friend. She
um was immensely into music.
And when I was about 11 years old, we
started going to concerts together. She
was an amazing friend to me, to her best
friend, to my grandparents, to everyone
that she met. Everyone liked my mom. You
You hear people say that a lot, but
everyone did like my mom. And I want her
to be remembered as someone who cared so
deeply about other people and wanted to
make the world a better place. Well, I
want to remember her for raising a
wonderful young woman. Thank you.
I wish you the best of luck. Thank you.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good