From the time I was 7 years old, I knew
I wanted to be a doctor. It was my
calling to heal and save lives. So, I
had a hard time understanding how
someone who was supposed to be a healer
could be accused of murder. This is
2-year-old Benjamin. His parents, a
doctor and a nurse, were charged with
killing him. Today, in an exclusive
interview, Benjamin's parents are
speaking out. Did they have anything to
do with the death of their son? Crime
correspondent Melissa Moore is here with
the story. So Melissa, it gets everybody
interested. A doctor and a nurse accused
of murdering their defensees 2-year-old
child. What was the community's
reaction? Well, this became a
high-profile case right from the
beginning. The community was divided in
taking sides. Some wondered, were they
being treated differently because the
son was adopted from Taiwan? And then
also the medical community was divided
because of the science of child abuse,
which is really unclear. I thought it
was, but I've learned differently. And I
must say in my mind was the idea that
this man might be either be given a
break because he's a doctor, his wife as
well, cuz she's a nurse. Or maybe it's
the opposite. They're held to a higher
standard. Thank you very much, Melissa.
So, after a three-month investigation,
Dr. James and Edelyn Yip were charged
with child endangerment. The murder was
a was the charge in the death of their
son, Benjamin. But six years later, the
charges were dropped. The ifs now join
me. Thank you very much for being here,
Edeline.
Dr. Let's start with your son's medical
condition. Tell us a little bit about
the problems that you identified as you
were adopting him. Well, it appeared
that he had some minor medical problems
uh when he was in the orphanage. He had
a problem with something called tracho
malaysia which is a bit of a little
breathing problem. There was a question
of whether or not one of his kidneys was
a little misshapen but it didn't appear
that there were a large number of
problems or that they were very severe.
He has a twin Jonathan. Any problems
with Jonathan? Not nearly uh to the
level of Benjamin. uh he didn't have any
demonstrated problems of significance in
the orphanage. So the ifs allowed us to
look at Benjamin's medical records which
as you can see from my medical unit
carrying these papers is quite
extensive. That's for a 2-year-old.
Looking through these records the months
before Benjamin died, uh he was admitted
to the hospital for several health
issues. And I I've jotted these down.
There was malnourishment. There was
vomiting, dehydration, kidney failure,
vitamin deficiencies, staff infection,
several healing fractures in the hands
and feet. I mean, this is a remarkable
list of problems. You know, in medicine,
Dr. You know, since you're a physician,
you know, but when when you get a chart
that's this thick, you know, there's a
big problem. And that's for a
2-year-old. How do you explain all of
this?
Well, um, you know, I I don't think
there is a good explanation, and we
never got a good explanation from any of
the physicians that we saw. I
was investigating non u
anatomical, non-physiological
potential causes on my own. But, you
know, we we continue to be in this
process of trying to find an answer.
So, let's go back to the day that your
son, Edeline, if you can help me with
this, to say the day your son was found
unconscious. What happened? Um, I stayed
home that day because he wasn't feeling
well. Um, he had a feeding tube and um
the feeding tube alarm um went off. So,
I went into his room
and I found him unresponsive.
Unresponsive. You're he Yeah. You know
what that means? Not moving. He reacted.
Yeah.
He wasn't breathing right.
So, what did you do? I freaked out.
Um,
I called 911
and I
I forgot how to do CPR. I forgot the
rate of chest compressions to to
breaths.
Um I I turned him on his side
and he had some food
that came out of his mouth and I freaked
out.
There there are people watching who are
going to say you're a trained nurse. How
can you forget CPR when you need it
most?
I'm a mom,
first of all, and nothing could ever
prepare you in finding your child not
responsive and not breathing.
So, I couldn't remember.
When the EMS group came,
you were there with your son.
I gather he was relatively lifeless at
the time. When did you realize that he
had passed?
I didn't know what was happening when
they told us that it was a very terrible
thing and it was a grave situation. I
was in shock. I could not believe that
that they were thinking that that he was
dying because we did everything we can
for him.
I I think um you know the thing was is
that he he was on life support for
several days um before he actually um
passed. Can I show everybody what the
medical records have revealed? Sure.
So because you allow us to look through
the im the records, we don't have the
actual images, but we have a pretty good
idea of what the doctors were dealing
with. And I want everyone to understand
what issues were raised because then
you'll begin to appreciate why their
accusations made and we all have to look
at this and try to decide in our own
minds what we think happened. So in the
chart it says that Benjamin had a
subdural hematoma. That means that he
had somehow injured part of his head and
there was bleeding under the surface of
the skull. You notice it's supposed to
be completely symmetrical and this is
not symmetrical and that caused a shift.
You notice these white lines are not in
the middle. The white lines are pushed
over and this black circle is supposed
to be some space in your brain. It's
completely missing here. Right? So this
means there was some head trauma that
pushed the brain over may have caused a
lot of these injuries. There were also
bilateral retinal hemorrhages. So in the
back of the eye there was bleeding and
this is together with this this other
findings considered a classic for shaken
baby syndrome. Shaken baby syndrome is
now known as abusive head trauma.
Dr. Yip when you heard these findings
when they were shared with you what were
your first thoughts? Well you know I
went to medical school as well and this
is the classic triad of uh shaken baby
syndrome. So, um, I knew that we would
be accused.
Adeline, when did you realize that
doctors were thinking that you might be
responsible for your child's injuries
and subsequent death?
When he um
was flown to Sacramento
uh at a hospital there and the doctor
told us um about what they were thinking
about. I was I was horrified.
How could they after all
the things that we've done and after his
long history
of being ill
think that we would hurt our son?
Just to clear the air, I'm going to ask
the question, did you or your husband
ever abuse your son Benjamin? No.
And it's hurtful to hear those
accusations.
I've heard those accusations, but I know
I did not do anything to hurt my son.
Were you angry about the accusations?
Well, yes. I mean, you know, I I think
um I think I know why they happened and
but now I'm more upset knowing about the
science.
Up next, what caused Benjamin's injuries
and why was his brain swelling? The
answers when we come back. Benjamin Yip
was just two years old when his mother,
a nurse, found him unresponsive in his
room. In a panic, she says she forgot
how to do CPR for reasons still unclear.
Benjamin did not survive. We are back
with Benjamin's parents, Dr. James Yip
and his wife Edeline. Dr. Yip, as you
would take your son, Benjamin, who you
had adopted when how how old was he? He
was 15 months when he came. I'm sorry.
18. 18 months, sorry. When he came home.
So, uh, your adopted son comes into your
home. You're taking him to doctors
because things aren't right. What
diagnosis
that sort of unify the problem are you
hearing? What you must be doing research
on your own as well? Yes, absolutely.
And there was no diagnosis. We had a
number of people look at him from his
primary care doctor to specialists at uh
other institutions. And you know, we
they were focused on specific parts of
his diagnosis, but not really a unifying
diagnosis. What do you think was wrong
with him? Well, I'm unsure myself why he
was so ill um to start with. So, after
the paramedics rushed Benjamin to the ER
and examined him, doctors believe his
condition was consistent with something
called shaken baby syndrome, which many
of you have heard of. It's called by
physicians abusive head trauma. After a
three-month investigation, Dr. Yip and
his wife, nurse Edelyn, were arrested
and charged with murder, child abuse.
Dr. Yip is a doctor. What's it like to
be arrested and charged with the abuse
of your child and the death of your
child?
Well, obviously it perhaps not, but
obviously it it it
speaks to the core of what I am pledged
to do, which is to help people. And it
is against that core value.
And when it occurred, it was something
that made me very upset. Uh, you know, I
was arrested at my place of work um in
front of all of my patients.
Um, why wouldn't you just go turn
yourself in?
We actually agreed to cooperate with the
sheriff's office uh if they chose to do
that, but they chose to show up
unexpectedly and do so and arrest me
there. To make a statement in your
opinion? I I don't know. You know,
obviously they never actually made
specific accusations about who did what.
It's my belief that I was arrested in an
attempt to use the arrest as leverage to
either um turn against my wife or uh
somehow because of loss of income uh be
willing to make a deal.
Adeline, the theory is that you were the
last person with your son. You delivered
a fatal blow to his head. It led to that
bleeding and the swelling and the other
challenges and problems that we talked
about when I was showing those images.
How do you respond as a mother to that
accusation? I didn't do it. I took care
of my son
every day and
I didn't I did not hit him.
So after the arrest, authorities took
away your two other children. Yeah. It's
a compounding an accusation
actually before the arrest. Yeah. It
took the children away from you
beforehand. Yes. They took I'm sorry. Go
ahead. They took the children away the
day after Benjamin went to the hospital.
So he was in the hospital dying and
child protective services ripped our
children away from our friends. How do
you deal with that? grieving for the
loss of one son while seeing your other
two children taken from you. You can't
you can't grieve. We have not had
a time to fully grieve.
How long were they taking from you for?
They were gone almost a year. A year?
Yes. Yes.
Let me just touch on one other issue
because I'm still stunned by this.
You're both working folks like so many
couples in America. Yes. There were
other caregivers involved with your
three children, all adopted.
Is there a possibility that someone who
cared for Benjamin may have been
involved in these injuries? No. No, we
we don't believe so. We don't think so.
I was the one who was a primary
caregiver. So, if anything happened, you
would have known about it. Yes. Up next,
a surprising twist in the case. Shaken
baby syndrome may not have caused
Benjamin's death. So, what did and who
was to blame? We're back with a doctor
and nurse who were accused of murdering
their son. Benjamin was just 2 years old
when he died after arriving unresponsive
to the ER. Doctors found his condition
consistent with shaken baby syndrome.
Benjamin's parents, Dr. James Yip and
his wife Edund are back with us. From
the beginning, both of you vehemently
denied the charges, the accusations that
you were responsible for shaken baby
syndrome. So, if that's not why Benjamin
died, why do you think he died?
I think he um he aspirated, he swallowed
um
some of the the food that he ate that
evening, it got dislodged into his
lungs. that because when I remember when
I turned him over, there were pieces of
carrots and potatoes that were coming
out of his mouth.
So, I think he aspirated.
So, after more than six years of
fighting to prove their innocence,
prosecutors dropped the charges.
Big move. How does it feel to be out
from under those allegations?
It's freeing, but you know, there's
there's some not being able to believe
it's finally over.
Can I bring in an an expert in this area
because I want to get to this issue of
shaken baby syndrome. What is it really?
An attorney involved, Paige Kab from the
Innocence Project is joining us now.
Paige, thank you very much for being
with us. Thank you for having me, Dr. H.
I'm stunned here. I'm I'm I'm looking at
a couple of medical professionals who
are accused of murdering their child for
reasons that I completely understand. At
least I thought I did. You know, head
injuries, bleeding in the eye, things
that are consistent with this shaking
baby syndrome, which I thought I
understood. Why did the prosecutors drop
the charges? So, this is really a case
of guilty until proven innocent. And and
part of what happens in these cases is
when we when doctors see these injuries,
these findings, um there is this there's
they've been trained that this is shaken
baby syndrome or abusive head trauma.
And so they tell the the prosecutors
that and they of course believe the
experts. So we really had to prove that
the yips were innocent, that Benjamin
had had this lifelong serious illness,
that he was unable to shake these
infections. And that ultimately led to
the stroke which is one of the things we
had to show them was that strokes can
cause subdural hematomas which I know is
one of your questions. So this all
started with a British neurosurgeon who
was looking at a baby had a subdural
hematoma. Um and he was wondering how
does this baby have this internal trauma
and no external signs of trauma? No
bruises, no skull fracture, no swelling.
Um and he came up with shaking this idea
that maybe you shake a baby and that's
how you get this internal injury with no
external injury. And so he wrote a paper
to warn people about the dangers. It's
like taking an egg and shaking it really
hard, right? You'll scramble the egg on
the inside, but the shell will still be
intact. That's the basic concept.
Exactly. And that turned into this rash
of diagnosis. There are thousands of
potentially innocent people in prison or
who've had their families ripped apart
because of this diagnosis. And it got so
bad that that British neurosurgeon who
first came up with it came out in 2012
and said, "This is just a hypothesis."
And it's still an unproven hypothesis.
Emily, Emily, you're the the face of
this now. H how are you recovering?
Not knowing what the new normal is quite
yet. Um
it's it's been very difficult. Um
because now a lot of people know about
it and our children have questions and
it's it's
we've come to realize that we're not
alone in this battle. We were very
fortunate to have our community um stand
behind us and our faith. Um we were told
that if we wanted our kids back, we had
to get a divorce and we said no, we did
not do anything. We want our children
back. Um we stood firm on our belief and
knowing that we're innocent and we we
fought and to to get to where we are
today.
I would have thought you just put this
behind you, but you've agreed to come on
the show and tell your story. Yes. Why?
Well, I think um we want to encourage
people who may be accused to actually
to be honest with themselves and don't
let somebody convince you that you've
done something wrong. This is not
medical certainty, no matter what they
are told. And it seems that our
our attitude now is to believe an
accusation immediately as it is made.
And I hope that the public will
return to the true belief in innocence
until proven guilty.
I wish you the best with your two
children. Thank you. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good