[Applause]
You know our best for making you laugh
and cry in her Emmy nominated role as
Kate Pearson on NBC's it show this is
us. Now Christine Mets has taken on
another inspiring and emotional role in
the upcoming film Breakthrough. And in
her real life she has several
breakthroughs of her own. I'm excited to
welcome my next guest Chrissy Mets. Come
on out.
[Applause]
I finally finally How are you? How are
you? Oh my goodness. It's been like
years in the making, right? It has a lot
of effort. Yeah, I know. I'm so happy.
Thank you for your patience. No, I've
been a busy girl. Yeah, you have been
busy. Gratefully, actually, since
speaking of busy, everyone was stunned
watching the season finale of This Is
Us. I know, right? So, we see you, your
character Kate gives birth to a 28-week
old child, which is a a risky time to
give birth to a child. One of our
children was born early. So, I, you
know, lived it a little bit. And, uh,
then we have, you have to fast forward
in the show, and I see the baby's okay.
Yeah. I see Toby, your husband, in the
in the show is around, although he's not
wearing a wedding ring. That's what
people notice. Yes. And where you your
your character is not there. What
happened? Who she could be at the dry
cleaner. Who knows? When When did she
die? What
[Laughter]
are you a writer on the show? Do you
want to be a writer on the show? That's
the thing is what's so beautiful about
this is us and the writers is that
because it's not linear, we can sort of
take you everywhere and we want to go
everywhere, right? So, um, we'll find
we'll find answers in season 4, but and
I do know what's happening just in case
you want to know, but I'm not going to
tell you because you you don't want to
open up the present too soon, right? You
want to just you want to I would open
the present. I know. I You might want to
just give me the I'm a doctor. Give me
the diagnosis she has. Don't worry about
it. Don't Don't stress yourself. Just
enjoy it. So, I actually knew I was
going to love you because I did What's
Watch What's Happening Live with your
co-star Toby. His real name is Chris
Sullivan, as you know. He's the best. He
He adores you. Hilarious guy, by the
way. Beyond. And I He told me a lot
about the behind the set events, the
shenanigans that goes on that keeps you
guys so energized. Well, that's him. He
is Mr. Shenanigan. Like honestly I I you
know we're in these like really heavy
emotional scenes and then he's like
cracking jokes you know in between and
it helps like we need some levity of
course but yeah he's always doing humor
it works. So let me brag on Chrissy. She
just had her first live televised
performance at the ACMS alongside lots
of powerhouse singers including Carrie
Underwood. There she is. She was singing
her song from Breakthrough. What was it
like being on stage? All I mean all of
America is watching you. Yeah. Yeah. And
it's about a really beautiful song from
a movie we'll speak about in a second.
Yeah. I mean, it was so, you know, I'm a
little I'm a girl from a little small
town in Florida and you know, you sort
of dream about these things happening,
but you don't ever know if it's going to
really happen. And to be on the stage
with these incredible artists who I've
revered for quite some time and I love.
I was like, this this is a a moment and
a a moment for women uh women in country
music and it was Yeah, it was pretty
incredible. It was special. You were
wonderful. Thanks. I am curious how you
deal with all the emotions. This great
movie breakthrough it's it's riveting
but it is it's up and down emotionally
for you so so it can work for us. Yeah.
The the depth that you have to pull from
that well. Yeah. Uh has involved members
of your family. I know your mom had been
ill for a while. Yes. My mom had a
stroke um two years ago now. Um but
physically she's doing better than she's
ever done before. So it's wonderful. But
I understand the the fear. Yeah. when
she had the stroke. Oh yeah. Helped you
identify a bit more with the characters
in Breakthrough. Maybe catalyze your
decision to move forward with the
project. Absolutely. Um almost verbatim
were the words that I said to my
mother's doctors. I said, "You can give
a diagnosis and I know you're you
practice. You're a doctor. You don't
always know and you don't always have
the answers. You don't know my mom, but
we have to only speak positive thoughts
around her." And Joyce said those exact
same things to her son John's doctors.
And I thought, "This is no coincidence,
you know, at all." So, so this is me,
New York Times bestseller. I had the
paperback finally. Yeah. Hard to find a
hardback these days.
Famously, you comment that you had 81
cents in the bank when they told you to
audition for This Is Us. Yeah. Yeah. I
needed to borrow gas money to get to the
audition.
That's funny now. But um yeah uh you
know but uh yeah I mean 12 years in the
making of trying to aspire to be an
actress and you know uh it's pretty
incredible. I mean yeah. So have you
changed since you got the break because
there are lots of people who are still
running around with 81 cents in the
bank. Sure. Looking for your cab fair or
gas money but they're not getting the
role. Yeah. And I I have to just for me
it was never about oh I want fame and
fortune. It was like I want to relate to
people. I want people to relate to me.
And um I think that's so much about what
we do is intention and those were always
my intentions. So So have those
intentions stayed the same because there
temptations to alter? Sure. I mean as we
do and evolve sometimes for better or
worse sometimes. Uh and of course in
this industry it's it's challenging. You
know you're sort of treated a certain
way and I and I always have to remind
myself that like we're all the same.
Like I am the same as every single
person on watching and in this audience.
Like I just have a different job. So
Hallelujah. Yeah. So I understand you
are blessed to have or share a meal with
my mentor Oprah. I know
that. She's the best. And she apparently
said something to you that I I've heard
uh from her in the past which is you
should be proud of what you've done in
your life. Sure. Too often we sort of
distance ourselves. What what happened?
I mean, she she's not apologetic about
anything because she does exactly what
she needs to do. Also, because she works
so hard for it. So, I walked into her
home and of course I'm like, "What is
this place?" And I said, "Wow, your home
is so beautiful." And she said, "I know.
Thank you." And and people you you're
sort of like, "Uh, what?" Because we're
taught to sort of deflect and, oh, this
dress was on sale. Instead of just
saying thank you or just owning that
moment and saying, "Yeah, I worked
really hard for this." And that's what
she did. And it was like I was there for
two seconds.
Oprah Winfrey, folks. There she is.
There she is. I'm grateful to her and I
think about her a lot when I have
breakthroughs
sitting here on the show and talk to
guest because the ideas came from her.
Sure. Just say the wisdom of how to let
a guest tell their story, right? You
practice gratitude. Who do you look to?
What what what ideas come to your mind?
For me, I start gratitude the first
thing in the morning before I even put
my feet on the floor. When I get out of
bed, I at least 10 things that I'm
grateful for. You write them down?
I should just say them out loud. Um, you
know, I for me it just sort of centers
me and starts the day in a positive way.
So, what are you grateful this morning?
Oh my goodness. That I woke up, that I'm
mobile, that I'm healthy, you know, that
I have incredible people that love me
and support me and who are making all of
these these wonderful things in my life
happen. Like there's I mean, we could
spend an hour on gratitude. We could,
but we don't. But we don't. We don't. We
spend a lot of time on the
anti-gratitude issues. Speaking of
gratitude, Christy stars in this new
movie I've been alluding to called
Breakthrough, which is based on an
incredible true story with a big health
element to it. She plays a mother whose
son fell through a frozen lake, drowned.
When I say drowned, like literally
drowned. Yeah. Heart stopped beating for
45 minutes. And what happened next is
very difficult to explain with science.
As a doctor, I can tell you I have no
idea how this happened. But you might be
able to explain it with prayer.
Do you get the goosebumps we get when
you watch that? You know, I don't know
if it's goosebumps as much as it's like,
wow, that's what I have to remind myself
to do every day. Just surrender. And
it's tricky. It's really tricky to do,
but also because the story is so moving
that finally when she surrendered and
she trusted, that's when the miracle
happened, you know. So, when you were
with your mom and in the darkest
moments, is that what you were saying to
yourself? Oh, sure. you know, you pray,
you know, you storm the heavens with
your prayers and then you just you have
to let go and let God for me. Um I I
there's nothing else that you can do at
that point. Yeah. Absolutely. Yeah. When
we come back, Devon Franklin, our
friend, is here. He's a faith leader,
comes on the show a lot, and he happens
to be the producer of Chrissy's new
movie. The little clip you just saw of
the real life medical miracle that
inspired this film is next. So stay with
us. You know, I love I love how
emotional you guys are watching the
movie because, you know, this is a true
story, you know, that that we're
obviously invested in and it's still
unbelievable for me. Oh my goodness. And
it was I mean, seriously, Dennis and
Josh and Chrissy are so good in that
moment. Every time I watch it, I'm like,
he's not going to make it.
You don't know the ending. There's a
clip from Chrissy Mets in the new film
Breakthrough about a mother's belief in
the power of prayer to heal her son
against all odds. cuz he's back with the
film's producer, faith leader, a very
good friend of mine, Devon Franklin. So,
I appreciate the fact that you're
experiencing it with us. By the way, how
is making this movie breakthrough
different from making This Is Us. You
know, I think it's the turnaround time
was a little longer. We shot it in 32
days. You know, Kate, I've been
cultivating for 30 seasons, so it's a
little different. Um, you haven't been
public as at least I haven't seen you as
public about your faith as uh as has
become evident watching this movie and
hearing you speak about it. How how has
faith informed your life? Oh my
goodness. Faith has always been such a
cornerstone if not like the most
important thing in my life. I mean I as
I talk about in my book and we sort of
touched on is that I had a pretty
tumultuous childhood. I mean all of us
it's all relative but um I mean I would
go to church on my own you know because
I was seeking that connection and that
conscious contact with God and um always
looking for that and and luckily and and
gratefully I I have that and I found
that and that's how I navigated
Hollywood. But what kind of a problem as
a child would you have where you'd find
solace in church? Uh, you know, my my
parents divorced and my mom remarried
and then I became the middle child. And
so, like navigating that through puberty
with a stepfather. Oh god. You know, all
of those things were like, huh, what do
I do? And and just feeling inadequate,
you know, as we do, especially through
puberty, like my goodness. Um, so yeah,
you know, life, yeah, life comes in
handy. Have some faith. You're you're
one of the most powerful people in
Hollywood. are very uh you know polite
about and humble about it but you are
you attracted some superstars to this
movie but you had to get attracted to it
first. Why? Well, I was promoting
Miracles from Heaven um one of the films
I produced. And when I was promoting
that film, I met Pastor Jason John and
Joyce Smith. And when Joyce talked about
going in that emergency room and praying
her son John back to life, I said, "I've
got to tell this because it motivated me
then and it still motivates me now." And
I felt like this is the type of story
that people really want to hear more
about.
For years, we've watched this guy
inspire America, finding films to just
touch our chords, just play their play
our chords in a special way. How has he
inspired you? I Okay, first of all, I I
don't even know how he wakes up in the
gym for at 4:00 in the morning and he
and like before he even I I makes me mad
actually. Stop it. Angry. I was going to
say that, but I was like that's not
kind. Um but just the motivation and his
consistency. Um, and what's really
wonderful is that not only has he become
like a brother to me, but a friend and
like so much of the guidance I never
knew that I needed, but like I found in
in you and I'm just so grateful. I mean,
just the way that he lives his life is
so inspiring. Well, it's it's the
ethics. You true though. It's so true.
Speaking of the ethics of making a
movie, you you felt you felt you felt it
was very important to get the family on
board before you move forward. Yes. You
know, I mean, for Chrissy and I, no
matter how much we love Breakthrough,
this is a movie for us, but for the
family, this is their life, and it's so
important to get it right. And so, the
family was involved during the
development of the script. They came to
set, uh, you know, met Chrissy, met all
the other actors. We screened the film
for them. They love it. So, the family
saying that we got it right is so
important. It means everything to us.
Oh, yeah. Well, you got it right. When
we come back, you're going to get to
meet John. The film's real life medical
miracle. I still am curious. I don't
understand how he's able to walk and
talk, but can do much more. Stay with
us. As doctors, we believe in science,
of course, but science doesn't always
have the answer. Sometimes there are
things called medical miracles. John
Smith was just 14 years old when he
drowned in a frozen lake. Yeah, she
drowned. And according to attending
physicians, and they quote, I'm quoting
them, he was dead for 45 minutes, which
meant his heart had stopped. His story
is the inspiration for the new film
Breakthrough. Despite all that, John is
actually sitting next to me. He's here
along with pastor Jason Noble. Back also
is the film star Chrissy Mets who plays
John's mom and the film producer Devon
Franklin. I got to say I I I only saw
the movie version of it because there
was no one filming you when you actually
fell into the lake. But what happened?
What what
when the ice gave way under you, what
did you think? You know, you're just
fighting for your life at that point. Um
it's that fight orflight instinct that
everyone has. And at that point it was
it was very scary, don't get me wrong,
but we knew that we couldn't get back
because there was so much ice between us
and the dock. We were 25 to 50 ft out.
So there was no way we could get back.
So at that point we were just trying
doing the best we can, but we knew that
we were staring death in the face. Your
two friends fell in after you and they
were able to get pulled out. You went
under and what did you experience when
you were under the dark water with only
ice above you? You know, for me it was
just I could understand how dirty the
water was. It was a greenish brown just
disgusting moss and then after that I
really don't remember anything just it
being very cold and the hypothermia
setting in. Patients of mine I'm a heart
surgeon so sometimes during the cases
people have problems with their heart
and they'll have out-of- body
experiences. Did you you have any
recollection of what happened when you
lost consciousness? Did you feel like
you were leaving your body? No sir
because we believe that breakthrough is
about a family. I mean from Devon, from
Chrissy, from Jason, all of us.
Breakthrough is about a family event
more than a if because if that would
have happened to me, it would have been
it would have been about my own
experience. Breakthrough is about family
and community. So in the film, John lay
lifeless without a pulse. Doctors gave
no chance of survival, no chance. And
then his mother prayed to God to breathe
life into his body. And then moments
later, John somehow came back, somehow
woke up. Have you ever experienced
something like that, Chris, in your
life?
How have you seen prayer play a role in
your day-to-day life? Oh, through
everything everything you know I do and
before I either make a decision or
whilst something is happening I'm like
okay please just be with me. I mean
literally to the performance the other
night on Sunday um there were some
technical difficulties and I thought
okay it's going to be what it's going to
be. I'm just going to surrender and
trust and uh thy will not mine be done.
Cuz you were very calm during that.
That's what That's what they say. That's
what they say. Yeah. When your mom had
her stroke, did you did you did you have
a moment where you felt you needed to
pray like this? Oh, sure. I mean,
constantly. And um Yeah. I mean, yeah.
All the time. And we sort of just sat
around her her bedside. And that's what
I said, like only positive thoughts and
only positive prayers. And like if you
have nothing good to say, then you can
you can step out of the realm. Um and
yeah, I mean, I do that every day
though. It's just that conscious contact
that that positive, you know, collective
energy and prayer. John, any squali at
all? Any side effects? Any bad memories?
Uh, you know, of course, I would I
remember some things, but God really
saved that and keeping it minimal. But I
I have no issues. I was back to playing
basketball within the next month to two
months. This is a picture of her playing
basketball, by the way. I can't believe
this. But I was back to just being a kid
and having fun. And you know, there's no
lifelong issues. The doctors actually
call me back just to see what's going on
with me and they're in awe. It's not
because anything's wrong. It's just
because they want to see me. So these
are these are just some of the summary
notes. The actual packet of your medical
records is quite thick. And one possible
theory is that the cold water because
when you were very cold water, there was
obviously ice there changes how drowning
happens. May have decreased the amount
of oxygen that John's organs needed to
stay alive. But you know, when you look
at these records, there really isn't a
good reason why you were able to sit
here, make words with your mouth, and be
neurologically intact. I could imagine
your body having survived. I can't
imagine your mind coming back when I
read what these records are re revealing
to me, which is the thing that's most
stunning. Now, Pastor Jason, you were
there the whole time as you as you as
you witnessed what he was like, and now
sitting here on my stage, how do you
reconcile that? You know, it's the power
of prayer. I mean, there's no question
when we walked into his room, the doctor
said he was brain dead, even after his
pulse came back. Brain dead. Rudiment
rudimentary brain function. Um, if he
survived, he would be a vegetable for
the rest of his life. 1% survival rate.
We took a group of pastors in and we
prayed that night. And some incredible
miracles happened in the room. And I
walked back out to Joyce and I said, "He
is walking out of the hospital. I don't
know how. I don't know why." You knew
it. I knew it. So, Speaking of Joyce,
your mom, I know that she's going
through some medical issues. couldn't be
here today. So, since she's not here,
let me ask you in privacy cuz she'll
probably never see this. What do you
think about how Chrissy played her in
the movie? Well, they did a sizzle
before the trailer and me and mom are in
the living room watching the sizzle and
we're looking at each other like, "When
did mom do this this sizzle? When did
mom over when did she do this voice
over?" And we're sitting there in such
confusion like, "What's going on?" Well,
it was Chrissy and just we were floored.
Feels good, doesn't it? Yeah. I mean, I
had to get it right. This Yeah, it's
Joyce. Yeah, I I wanted Absolutely. I
mean, it's so important. Let me give you
the final word. What do you want the
audience to walk away from with seeing
this film? Um, you know, Chrissy as
Joyce has a speech at the very end of
the film. And in that final speech,
Chrissy says as Joyce, that love is the
most powerful force in the universe. I
want everyone to walk out of the theater
knowing that love wins. And when we love
each other, we can have a breakthrough.
God bless you all. Thanks for being
here. Break Crew is in theaters this
weekend. Go check it out. And you're all
going home with a copy of Christy's
book, This Is Me. It's now in paperback.
Take the time. Read about love. We'll be
right back. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good