[Applause]
All right, I want to take a look at this
package of powder. Just simple old
powder. It's a new product. It's called
Palcohol that promises to turn
water into wine. Well, actually, not
wine. It's in vodka and rum, lots of
other fun things like that. It's
approved for sale starting the summer,
but Palcohol is causing a media frenzy.
Palcohol, a cocktail in a powder. It's
creating quite a buzz and everybody's
got an opinion. But not everyone agrees.
Critics call the powdered booze risky
and an accident waiting to happen. And
that's the concern. Although created for
adults, could palcohol attract kids and
lead to binge drinking or worse,
snorting or injecting it? It's dangerous
stuff and it shouldn't be allowed to be
sold. And what about sneaking it into
movie theater, stadiums, and schools?
Some states have already banned Palcohol
and others are considering it. With
liquid alcohol the most abused drug in
the US, could powdered alcohol be next.
Today, everything you need to know about
Palcohol. So today, your top questions
about Palcohol. And here to answer, Mark
Phillips. He's the creator of Palcohol
and physician Dr. Yale Varnado, who's
been researching the product. So what's
the point of powdered alcohol? Why did
you create it in the first place? Well,
I did it because I moved to Arizona and
I was doing outdoor activities that uh I
thought it would be nice to bring some
alcohol along when I finished with the
activity to relax like biking,
backpacking, hiking, stuff like that.
And so that's why I came up with it. But
what the real issue about Palcohol is
not just using for recreational
activities. It's all the innovative uses
that can be done in other businesses.
Once the public found out about the
product, a medical professionals called
me and said, "We'd love to use this
product for antiseptic, powdered
antiseptic." So when doctors go into
remote locations or disaster relief,
they have to lug in liquid antiseptic,
which is very heavy. Now they can bring
powdered antiseptic in, much lighter,
and can treat more patients. I see the
potential side benefits, but at its very
core, it's a way of allowing people to
carry alcohol around, whether for
drinking or other purposes uh
effortlessly. if you don't mind, show me
what it is and how it works so people
get a better idea. Again, it's not
available until the summer, but when it
comes available, it's going to be a big
big deal. So, this is like obviously a
sample packet. The labels aren't there
yet and everything else, but this is
about the size of the packet, 4 in x 6
in the powdered and there's this
powdered vodka in here right now. So,
now you pour the water in there. Now,
this is vodka. You wouldn't be mixing
water with vodka and you're going to get
water vodka right now. This will be
unpleasant tasting. You would typically
mi mix orange juice or a soda with the
vodka or if you do add water, you'd add
some kind of flavored powder to make it
any flavor you want. So, it's a mixed
drink when you're done. Yes, it's a
mixed drink. So, you zip it shut and you
shake it and generally about 30 seconds,
but we'll just take it about 15. Then,
you open it up and I gave you a straw
here so you can uh try it and put it in
there.
vodka
water. But but it does taste like vodka.
But it's vodka. There's no question
about it's vodka. That's right. I'll
keep sipping this while you talk. Okay,
that's right.
Yeah, it is remarkable. I wonder why
it's never done before. What? Give me
the the the broader background. How many
flavors does it come in? So, there's
four approved uh versions right now.
Powdered rum, powdered vodka, and then
two cocktail flavors. Cosmopolitan and
powderita. Our word for margarita. Lemon
drop should be coming along soon. With
the cocktail versions, you just add
water and you have a drink. And the
calorie count about 80 calories a
package. So far so good. Most people
they say, you know, maybe I'll see
what's that's why I think there's been
so much of an attention on this. But Dr.
Bernardo, some states have already
banned this product, banned it. And
there are many others that are
following. Here's a map of the ones that
have actually gotten rid of them. What's
the concern? Why is everyone worried? So
the concern really is, and you'd
mentioned, why hasn't this been done
before? People have actually been
looking at ways to make powdered or
crystallized alcohol since the 70s. So,
you know, when I first thought about
this or heard about this, I said, well,
you know, we always say in medicine, if
someone's attempted it before and you
know, it fell to the wayside, what was
the reason for it? Is it not safe? Are
there risks and that we just don't know
about? So, from the medical perspective,
being an advocate for the consumer, I am
concerned about what are the ways that
people might abuse it or misuse it. you
know, when people are coming into the
hospital, how could they pro perhaps be
intoxicated in a way that I don't know
how to fix because I don't actually know
what's in this product. There's more
than just dehydrated alcohol in this.
You know, the FDA has actually even said
themselves when they reviewed it, they
didn't do any testing on it. Um, they do
know that there are other compounds in
it that we would find in processed
foods. And if you want to live clean and
you want to uh live a healthy lifestyle,
you might be worried about some of those
additives because we just don't know
what the long terms effect. Mark, what's
your reaction? I'm sure these are not
new concerns for you. Why is it that all
these states are banning your product?
Well, they're banning it because they're
ignorant about the product. Really? Uh
the FDA did look at it. The TTB has
reviewed it. It that's very safe.
There's nothing nothing unnatural in the
product. Uh the reason they're banning
is because they just don't understand
the situation. Liquid alcohol has been
abused. Still is. It's a terrible thing
in United States. Binge drinking,
underage drinking, alcoholism. But the
solution is not to ban liquid alcohol.
No one's calling for that. And nor
should the calling for a ban of powdered
alcohol. Once you ban powdered alcohol,
one, it creates a demand for it. A
heightened demand. We want what we can't
have. More people drank in prohibition
they did before prohibition. More people
abused alcohol in prohibition than
before. A concerned mother came to me
last week and said, "I'm for the banning
of your product and because I don't want
my 15-year-old daughter to get a hold of
it." And I asked her, "Which should be
easier for your daughter to buy,
marijuana or a bottle of vodka in a
liquor store?" Well, you know, she can't
buy a bottle of vodka in the liquor
store. They ask her for ID and that
won't happen. But she can walk right out
that door on the street and buy
marijuana easily because it's not
regulated. So to protect the underage
drinkers from getting hold of alcohol,
we regulate it. By banning it, we lose
all regulation. They'll be able to buy
it anywhere. There a lot of folks who
have questions about this. People are
here in our audience who believe this
might be good, might be bad. Let's hear
from these are questions about Paul that
I think make a lot of sense. We're going
to start off with a member of law
enforcement. Uh how are you? Officer
Officer Roberts is joining us. So, have
you seen this yet? I have. All right.
So, you you It smells like alcohol. You
can, you know, sort of interesting. This
been doable. What What's your question?
My question, I've been a police officer
for 15 years. I'm a DARE instructor with
the kids. I've seen the worst of the
worst when it came to both abusing drugs
and drinking of alcohol. Can this be
snorted as a powder form or can it be
broken down and injected into the blood
with as other drugs can be? as well as
can I, as a police officer, if that
happens, detect the odor of the alcohol
on someone's breath? Well, of course it
could be snorted. Anything can be
snorted. Any powder can. Even liquids
can be snorted. It would take you about
one hour to snort this of pain and
misery to get this up your nose to equal
one drink. Or someone could just do
this.
Whoa.
I think that we know. Wow. That wasn't
water. There was no vodka.
But the the concern that I have
less it's going to become less of a
debate in a moment. The concern that I
have as a physician is I know that you
say no one would want to invest the time
in snorting this, but we're seeing kids
like on YouTube dousing themselves with
alcohol, setting themselves on fire,
doing doing the cinnamon challenge. Why
wouldn't someone want to put themselves
on YouTube snorting this? I mean, it's
absolutely possible, you know, and we
don't know what's in it. So, I mean, you
said it's all natural, but the FDA
hasn't done actual research and studies.
Have you guys actually conducted any
clinical trials on it? I mean, I'd like
to know what it is that you have mixed
in with this so that I know what I'm
ingesting. The FDA knows exactly what's
in this. Okay, we have to know. It's
proprietary. But we they have to know
that I I'm required to present to the
government and to the FDA. They know
exactly what's in it, and there's
nothing dangerous. And they've said
that. So, we don't know of yet. Well,
it's it's uh I'm going to move it
forward only because I I'm sure there's
going to be questions around that, but
the fundamental question the officer is
asking is whether or not kids will store
it. I'm I'm getting the idea they won't,
but they're probably going to misuse it
in other ways. Thank you. Thank you. At
least is a mother of two two teenage
daughters. Correct. Go ahead. So, I have
a lot of concerns about your product
being a mom of teens. Um I think it has
a tremendous amount of kid appeal, the
name, the packaging, the form. It looks
like a package of Fun Dip or a juice
pouch. Um,
first question is, do you have kids? And
my other question is, don't you feel
that a new, more convenient form of
alcohol will make it easier for them to
sneak it into schools, movies, and other
places? I don't have kids, but I was a
first grade teacher. My degree is in
elementary ed, and I have a passion for
kids, so I'm very concerned about that.
As far as sneaking it in, this
is one shot of vodka. And you can see
compared to that package, this is about
1/4 the size of that package. That's one
shot of vodka in that package. It's much
easier to sneak in liquid alcohol
anywhere than powdered alcohol. So the
idea that powdered alcohol is easier to
conceal is a falsehood. That's not true.
So how is it more appealing to kids?
It's not. The flavors are not sweet. It
costs four times more than liquid
alcohol. Typically, kids want cheap
alcohol to get drunk. They're not going
to pay for top shelf stuff. This is four
times more expensive. It's harder to
conceal. There's really nothing
appealing about it to kids, but parents
should still be keep alcohol away from
the kids' hands. Why are they, you know,
it won't be readily available to
underage drinkers? Thank you very much.
Let me finish with Aaron. He's a a
teacher, right? You're a assistant
principal. Assistant principal.
Assistant principal at the in New
Brunswick. Uh North Brunswick rather
North Brunswick High in New Jersey.
Right. That's big big rivalry. Go ahead.
Um I've been an educator as Dr. said for
about 20 years. I've seen a lot of
things and I know we're going to have to
do as educators. We're going to have to
get in front of this and start educating
the students. Um, we've been successful
doing that with PSAs, public service
announcements that deal with texting
while driving, driving under the
influence, and most recently bullying.
Um, my concern is, is this really going
to be the same potency as regular
alcohol? And secondly, is won't this
lead to more binge drinking or binge use
because it's a new portal for teenagers?
We don't legislate behavior. We educate
to change that. No matter what kind of
legislation we do, it will not stop
binge drinking, alcohol abuse, alcohol
misuse. We have to educate people. Uh I
don't think that this product is any
different than liquid alcohol. Certainly
not any any more dangerous or attractive
to people. It costs more than liquid
alcohol. So I don't think it will be
will be used by anyone for binge
drinking. It's much cheaper, much easier
to get drunk with liquid alcohol than it
is with powdered alcohol. So, I don't
see that appeal right there. Thanks for
being an educator. We do appreciate it.
There'll be lots more questions,
everyone. When this comes into play over
the summer and powdered alcohol hits
your shelves, we'll be following it
along with you. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good