Dr. Oz reveals the one anti-aging
product you're not using. You're wasting
your time and you're wasting your money.
>> Look younger overnight.
>> It works immediately. That's the nice
thing about it.
>> Today, I've asked everyone to circle
their worst wrinkle, the area they wish
looked smoother and younger. I did it to
help us answer one big question. What's
the most important product you can use
to target that spot that you circled? Is
it a moisturizer? Is it a lotion? Is it
something else? Well, the powerful
anti-aging secret I want you all to use
is, are you ready?
>> Yes.
>> Alpha hydroxy acids. They're making a
big comeback and we're now learning that
they can fight the signs of aging deep
under your skin, deep inside of you.
Now, they're cheap. They're easy to use.
And by the end of today, you're going to
know what type of alpha hydroxy acid is
best for you. So, we find out why you
circled yourselves and where you went.
Narin, you want to join us first?
>> Sure.
>> Then, if you don't mind.
>> So, you circled under your eyes.
>> Yes.
>> Why there? Because as I age, I look in
the mirror and I want to cry. I want to
walk out with my sunglasses because when
I look at pictures when I was younger,
it looks smooth. And I used to get
carded up until I was 30. I swear I hit
35 and they're like, "Go ahead, get out
of here."
>> So, you want to get carded going
forward?
>> Yeah, that would be great.
>> Is that an aspiration many of you have?
Getting carded.
>> What do you do for your under eye
wrinkles?
>> I've tried every cream imaginable. So, I
do a nightly cream um and I don't know
if it works or not. I definitely feel a
difference when I don't use it, but I've
even done like for allergies, I think
it's from rubbing my eyes, so I've used
eye drops and you know,
>> you're going to like our suggestions
today. Thank you very much. I also have
Tara. Tara, how are you?
>> Hi, good. How are you?
>> Where did you circle?
>> I circled around my laugh lines.
>> Yeah, I should point. Some people circle
their whole face. It doesn't count.
Doesn't count at all. I'm glad you
specified there. And why there?
>> Well, put um when I look in the mirror
now, I see the dimples I always dreamed
of.
>> All right. And when you when you see
those wrinkles that make you feel
>> a little older,
>> you want to get carded also.
>> Yes, I do.
>> All right. Thank you for sharing those
those stories. So, I'm going to show you
how alpha hydroxy acids can help you
smooth out the fine lines that you all
hate the most. So, I'm going to bring in
dermatologist Dr. Janette Graph. Thanks
for joining us, Dr. Graph.
>> Thank you. It's great to be here.
>> So, you just got some good insights
about the wrinkles and how they bother
folks. Why is it that alpha hydroxy
acids are making such a big comeback?
>> Well, there's a lot of new research
about alpha hydroxy acids. They are
natural acids that are found in fruits,
in milk. And what they do is they take
this dead skin cell layer which collects
as we get older, making our lines and
wrinkles look deeper and it removes them
and renews the skin. And nothing works
as effectively as an alpha hydroxy acid.
>> Now, they are found these are, you know,
these are weak acids, right? They're
gentle ones. If they're found in foods
like sugar cane, they're found in milk.
They're found in fruits like apples and
lemons and oranges. And they're the
ingredients in a lot of different
products, right? They're in
moisturizers. They're in cleansers.
They're in masks. And because they're so
widely used, it makes sense. They
probably were used a long time ago as
well. In fact, Cleopatra's anti-aging
rituals a couple thousand years ago
included a milk bath, which was
basically to help exfoliate and to
smooth her skin. It was a type of alpha
hydroxy acid. So you're arguing, if I
understand correctly, there's not a
single woman in this audience who are
watching us right now on television who
should not be using alpha hydroxy acids.
>> Absolutely correct.
>> So does alpha hydroxy acid work better
in some age women than others?
>> Actually, alpha hydroxy acids work well
in all ages in all age groups, but if
you're older when you try it for the
first time and you have a greater
collection of dead skin, you will see a
bigger difference.
>> That might be good news for a lot of
folks.
>> That's right.
>> Right. All right. The other thing I
don't understand is is why do we stop
using it because it was there at the
very beginning. So Norin, if I can ask
you a question. Yes.
>> Have you ever tried alpha hydroxy acid?
>> Um I tried it a long time ago thinking I
could avoid this but it made my skin
very dry and a little bit red and I
didn't think I could use it under my
eyes to be honest. So
>> And did did you have a reaction to it?
>> Yeah, I felt like I got um red dry skin
from it. So then I stopped using it.
>> Oh. So you thought it was from the alpha
hydroxy?
>> I thought it was from that. So I don't
know. And Tara, have you ever used it?
>> No.
>> Never tried it.
>> That I know of.
>> That that you know of? I love that. Had
you ever heard of it before?
>> I've heard of it, but I hear of a lot of
things and I'm busy and when I have that
moment to write something down, I run to
the store to get it and I'm not sure if
that's in it.
>> Right.
>> So, Dr. Graph, I mean, since it was
there and probably, you know, certainly
at the beginning of our careers, why do
you think it changed? Why did it drop
out of favor? Well, for exactly the
reason that we heard because initially
when they first came out, many of the
alpha hydroxy products were irritating.
So, there were a lot of complaints and
then they fell out of favor with a
number of people. Many people still use
them, but I have to say there's two
reasons. One is the formulations today
are completely different. So, they're
pretty safe to use and they've kind of
perfected them. So, all skin types can
use them. And depending on where you use
them, you can use them around the eye
area in eye creams. You can use them on
the face in serum form. You can use them
on the body on different areas. But the
other thing is there we're bombarded by
so many skin care products today that
it's hard for consumers to know what
they should be using. So it's great that
we're revisiting this topic because it
is so important. Oh, well, once I
understood the research on alpha hydroxy
acid, I felt really passionate about
getting this up because so many folks
ask questions around skincare and we've
got sometimes you think we have the
basics, but I think a lot of it is
marketing, right? Let me show you all
why I think it's the most important
thing for you to have in your skinincare
collection. So, here's an animation of
what your skin looks like. Many of you
have complained that you sort of have a
dullness to your face. The reason for
that is the old skin cells lie there and
they sort of hang out and they cause
these little valleys and and crevices
and that reflects the light weirdly. So
you look dull when you look in the
mirror. Now if you put on alpha hydroxy
acids, they coat the entire surface of
the skin, but they also go deep under
the skin. Does that make sense? When it
goes through the skin, it creates a new
environment for the cells lying under
there. Now that envir environment makes
these cells vulnerable and it makes
these cells more likely to die quickly.
That's a good thing because that means
that those older cells leave faster.
They allow new vibrant young uh cells to
come to the surface. They don't have
those nooks and crannies and valleys.
So, they don't reflect the light in
weird fashions. And because of that,
you'll have that more youthful looking
skin. And if I'm hearing correctly, you
may even see this benefit more in folks
who are a bit older. So, it's a smart
thing to revisit. So, Nar and Terra,
since you know, you've got huge
aspirations getting carded again. Uh
what I'm going to do when we come back
is talk about why alpha hydroxy acids
are the most valuable tool to help those
wrinkles. So, up next, the mistake
you're making every day that's aging
you. You're going to be surprised to
find out what you are doing wrong.
>> Dr. Oz Adah here for your wrinkle
report. About 5 years ago, I started
noticing the deep wrinkles under my
eyes. They just keep coming. I think
it's stress and lack of sleep. Whatever
it is, Dr. Oz, is there a way we can
slow the process on this? Can you help
me, please?
>> We're talking about your aging skin.
Let's bring in Julie, who says her daily
anti-aging skincare routine is a very
involved process. So, you took some
video of your typical nighttime routine.
>> I did. As you all watch it, how many
steps do you go through? Describe this
for us.
>> Uh, there's about seven, eight,
sometimes nine. It could go on forever.
>> Nine steps.
>> Why so many things?
>> Uh, you know, I'm trying to get rid of
these wrinkles. I have a young young
daughter, so I just I feel like I've got
to do something with these things.
>> It is dizzying.
>> It really is.
>> So, how long you been doing this for?
You know what? Over 20s something years.
>> 20 years. Nine steps a night.
>> Yes.
>> And anyone can bow for me if they look
in my my bathroom cabinet. I have every
product out there you can imagine.
>> Keep in your life must be your
>> They don't know what I do themselves.
Exactly.
>> They have no idea what I do.
>> When when you are trying to buy an
anti-aging beauty product, what do you
look for?
>> You know, I look for anything that says
uh anti-rinkle smoothing cream. Anything
that has to do with wrinkles, I buy it.
So,
>> Dr. Graph, seems like she's got
everything covered. Is she missing
anything?
>> Well, I think that we could actually
save you some time because we could
probably cut out three of those steps
and just by adding an alpha hydroxy
acid, we could take care of several of
those steps.
>> Okay.
>> Do you exfoliate, Julie?
>> I do. I use a little brush. I use
scrubs. I use microbubbles. I use
everything.
>> So, a lot of different ways of
exfoliating.
>> Yes. This is a part of the story that I
only learned recently. I'm fascinated by
alpha hydroxy acid. How would you
compare that to other exfoliants that
that Julie's using?
>> I would say that alpha hydroxy acids are
smart. So when you put them on your
skin, there's a reaction that happens
because of how they interact with your
skin. Whereas a physical abrasive or
something that's mechanical, you
control. So, it can sometimes be to the
point of too much of a good thing or not
enough. So, that's where I like alpha
hydroxy acids.
>> Now, you hear so much though about
different acids. I mean, glycolic acid,
um, salicylic acid. What I mean, are
they all the same thing?
>> No, they're different. Salicylic acid is
a different type of acid, but glycolic
acid is one type of alpha hydroxy acid,
as is lactic acid, citric acid.
I'm going to cover that in a moment, but
I want to show you first why it's so
important to use products that can strip
away that dead level of skin because
otherwise you're wasting your money. A
lot of those chemicals you're putting on
your face aren't actually getting to the
skin where they need to be in order to
help you, you know, achieve that young,
youthful skin that you desire. So, come
on over here. So, I I built you a little
flower garden.
>> Thank you.
>> You like flowers?
>> I love flowers.
>> All right. So, this is actually a
metaphor for your skin. And these
youthful, beautiful flowers down below
here are the young skin cells that need
to fuel the nutrients that you give
them. When you try to put creams,
serums, chemicals on your face to allow
you to age more gracefully, you need the
chemicals, the plant food, so to speak,
to get to the plants. But on our face,
we naturally have old dead skin cells.
And there's a covering with those dead
skin cells that makes it really hard for
the plant food to get to where it needs
to go. You see, those plants aren't
getting any of this at all. Nothing's
happening. Nothing's going through
whatsoever. You're starving your skin
cells that need the nutrients and you're
wasting your time and you're wasting
your money. This is true for all of you
who've circled parts of your face.
That's why the first thing you need to
do when you're going to put something
that might be beneficial on you is to
get rid of these other skin cells, the
old stuff you don't want there. So,
alpha hydroxy acid wipes all this away.
And by doing that, you now have an
environment where you can take
nutrients, whatever those serums and
creams and, you know, potions you're
using, and you can get that material to
these young skin cells that desperately
need it. So now you can water
the the skin just where it needs to be.
Right? That's why exfoliation is so
important. So Dr. Graph, how much more
valuable would Julie's anti-aging
solutions be if she was able to do this?
Well, just from your excellent
demonstration, you can see dramatically
different. It will be dramatically
improved because it's like removing a
barrier to your house. It's opening a
door so you can enter. Think of all the
ingredients that are just sitting on
your skin, not getting in because that
layer of dead skin is blocking.
>> Now, the key question here is if you
want to get these flowers nutrients that
they want, you have to be able to find
the right kind of alpha hydroxy acid,
don't you?
>> Yes, absolutely. That, my friends, is a
pretty critical decision. So, coming up
next, the best anti-aging match for
every skin type. Find out what's right
for you.
>> Hi, Dr. Oz. It's Deborah here with my
wrinkle report. I have these annoying
wrinkles under my eyes that started in
my 40s. I've tried creams. I've tried
concealers. Nothing works. I guess it's
just a normal aging process. Or maybe
I'm dehydrated. What can I do about
this, Dr. Oz?
So, what's the best type of alpha
hydroxy acid for dry, for oily, or for
combination skin? Let's bring in sisters
Sharon and Alicia. Now, Sharon says her
skin is very dry. Is that correct?
>> It is very dry.
>> And have you ever used alpha hydroxy
acid before?
>> I used alpha hydroxy probably 15 years
ago, but as soon as I put it on my face,
it just burned
>> and I had to wipe it off immediately.
>> So, Dr. Graph, common complaint. Should
Sharon give it the alpha hydroxy acid
another shot? Definitely. Also, 15 years
ago, they were more irritating. But for
someone like you, Sharon, whose skin is
dry or for darker skin tone patients or
patients with sensitive skin conditions
like rosacea, I recommend the
polyhydroxy acids. Now, I'm going to put
some on your hand. This is in a serum
form. You can get them in serums. You
can get them in cleansers. You can get
them as moisturizers. And you dab this
around your face and just blend it in.
and all my wrinkle spots.
>> I I would put it everywhere because what
it's also what it does is it helps to
even out your skin tone, too. So, just
think what's in that dead skin cell
layer. Age spots, wrinkles, everything
looks accentuated. So, when you
exfoliate that top layer, the skin looks
brighter and more even toned and you can
just blend it in.
>> Yeah, it feels very smooth.
>> So, it's a new generation of an
anti-aging serum. And And how often
should Sharon be using it? Sharon could
use this every night and at this is a
serum. So you could put your moisturizer
on right over it or if this is fine, you
can just leave it and sleep like this.
>> So is this sufficient just to use this
by itself?
>> If it's moisturizing enough for you if
you have dry skin, you may want to put a
moisturizer over it, but I also like it
on the neck, on the chest. These are a
areas that have aging skin. You can put
it on the back of your hands,
>> but in theory, you could just use the
alpha hydroxy acid. Use nothing else
besides that. If if your skin doesn't
feel dry, then you're good to go.
>> You're good to go. Most of the time, if
you're using a serum, you may want to
put a moisturizer over it because the
serums are very concentrated, so they
may be a little bit tight or they may
make your skin feel a little tight. So,
you may want to put a moisturizer over
it.
>> How's it feel, Sharon?
>> It feels smooth.
>> She got a dab in her nose. You should
clean that off. Otherwise, people
complain about it. It's
>> got to smooth it out a little bit. Okay.
>> I love sisters.
>> Let's take a look.
Yeah. Very good. You did a good job.
>> Does it burn?
>> Not a bit. Not a bit.
>> No, I could keep it on now. Okay.
>> I'm not I'm not like grabbing the raw
shagg and trying to get it off as
quickly as possible.
>> So, your sister Lysa has a very
different kind of skin. You argue your
skin is is oily.
>> My skin is very oily. Yes. It's um shiny
all the time. Shiny. And I'm usually
always blotting or, you know, trying to
put more powder on to cover up the
shine. It just it's just a mess. It's
>> like an oil slick.
>> Oh, huge oil slick. You know, it's like,
you know, bright shiny light when I walk
out in the sun. Ah. Dr. Graph, what do
you recommend for oily skin? So, we
already covered dry skin.
>> For oily skin, I recommend glycolic
acid. Glycolic acid is the strongest of
the alpha hydroxy acids. It penetrates
quickly. So, if you have oily or acne
prone skin, glycolic acid is great to
use. You can use it in a light lotion or
in a cream. And you would put it on much
the same way as Yeah. Just a little bit
on your face. Just rubbing a small
amount. You could also
>> you you spot it, distribute it, and put
it everywhere. I would also recommend
that you could use a cleanser that
contains glycolic acid also.
>> No. How about that spot there?
>> She's trying to help you.
>> Thanks, sis.
>> I know. I'm just making you beautiful,
you know. Oh,
>> it's priceless. Never changes. Now,
while they're while they're bickering
over here, what about the in between
skin types? So, if you're not dry,
you're not oily, what do you recommend?
>> Combination, normal skin types, I like
lactic acid, which as we know comes from
sour milk. Lactic acid is great because
it moisturizes. It It exfoliates. It
exfoliates. It's found pretty widely,
and you can use it. You find it in a lot
of body moisturizers also because it's
great for the body. So, it's a really
good moisturizer for oily and
combination skin.
>> And just to make it clear for everybody,
what is the most effective way to use
alpha hydroxy acid? Once you find the
right kind for your skin type, what's
what's the formula for that?
>> The best the most effective form is
either a serum, a lotion, or a cream
because they are leave-on products. So,
when you put them on your skin, the
alpha hydroxy is able to stay there. If
you use, you can add a cleanser for
added benefits, but if you use just a
cleanser, you're rinsing it off, so
you're not going to get as lasting
benefits.
>> And what about sun exposure? Because I
know once you've taken that superficial
layer of skin off, you've taken
protection off as well.
>> That's right. The alpha hydroxy acids
will make the skin more sensitive to the
sun. So, absolutely every single day of
the year, you should use a
broadspectctrum sunblock, UVA and UVB
with an SPF of 30.
>> Otherwise, you're wasting all the
benefit of what we're trying to do here.
>> Thank you very much. You guys can keep
equivalent over here if you want.
>> Oh, yeah. I'll win that battle.
>> Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good