[Applause]
Thinning hair and hair loss is the
medical condition I hear about the most
from women. And when it starts to thin
and fall out, panic sets in and it can
take an emotional toll. That's what
Shawn is going through. I know a lot of
you can relate.
My name is Shawn, 35 years old. I feel
so much older because I'm losing my
hair. I have incredibly thin
parts. I have bald patches in the back.
No matter where I part that part, I have
the hair
horizon. 10 years ago or so, I had much
thicker hair. Um, I felt more confident
going out with my friends. When I look
in the mirror, I see more scalp every
time. When I brush my hair, I see clumps
of my hair. I freak out quite a bit. I
wonder how I am going to cover these
bald spots in the back of my head. For a
living, I am a pub trivia host. Welcome
to team trivia. So, I'm in front of a
lot of people at a time. I'm gonna go
ahead and play a song. I do feel more
confident when I'm wearing a hat. When
I'm hiding my hair inside, I do feel
very insecure. If I take off my hat
while I'm there, are they going to think
I'm sick? Are they going to think
something's wrong with
me? This is my buffet of hair loss
camouflage. I have 50 some odd baseball
caps. I would never really go out
without a hat or something to cover my
hair up
with. From start to finish, it takes me
a good 45 minutes to style my hair in
the morning. This is my collection of
volumizing shampoos, conditioners, dry
shampoos. Pretty much anything you can
put in your hair, I've put in my hair.
I wonder a lot what I've done that's
caused my hair to fall out so early in
my life. I can't even make the hat work
on my head right now. Um, kind of want
to
cry. It really hurts me emotionally to
see my hair just falling out.
Thanks for being here, Sean. So, how
does a hair loss affect you emotionally?
My mom had this gorgeous, thick, full of
hair. Um, oh, I'm sorry. I'm already
crying. Um, I lost her in 1997. Sorry.
So now every time I see these clumps of
hair, I've got these bald patches and
I'm like, it's just another way. I'm
disconnected. I'm disconnected from her.
Um, to the point where I won't go out
with my friends without wearing a hat. I
won't be in
pictures. What kind of person doesn't
want to be in pictures with their
friends? What kind of person goes out
and says, "You know what? I have to hide
myself from here instead of being out
there and being in it with all my
friends. Does it make you feel helpless?
I feel like there's nothing I can do
anymore. I've put so many different
things in my hair. I'm ready to give up.
I'm just ready to give up. I want to go
home and cry and never leave my house
ever.
I don't want any of those things to be
true for you. I'm going to change all
that today. Okay. I've got to start by
put you in the truth tube because I want
to show you some numbers. Okay. I don't
want you to see this as a fearful
experience. I want you to see this
uplifting because it's going to give you
control back. Okay? What we fear most
really is what we don't understand.
Okay? So, I'm going to give you that
today. Let's take care of it. Come out
here. I did a battery of tests. Okay?
Stand right there. That way you'll be
able to see your numbers. So, let me
first give you the good news. Okay?
These are the numbers that we checked
that actually I was surprised were were
so good. You're not anemic. Okay? You're
not low on iron. Okay? You're not low on
selenium. Okay? These are the the things
we look for first. Okay? But there were
some numbers that weren't good. Okay.
And if it's okay, I'm going to share
those with you. Let's do it. All right.
So, the first thing we looked at were
your hormone levels, which really should
be the first place you look with hair
issues. Okay? And they were abnormal,
significantly abnormal, and they point
to problems with your thyroid. Okay?
It's not working well. Second thing we
looked at was the amount of inflammation
in your body. Okay? Your inflammation
numbers were again very, very high.
Okay? Your glucose. All right? you know,
it's a sign of diabetes or pre-diabetes.
Okay, your numbers were not in the
diabetes range, but they weren't normal
either. So, we put you sort of in the
pre-diabetes range. Okay, again, an area
where I think we can make improvement.
We can work with that. And finally, I'm
going to point out something that
everyone right now can start addressing
and you will also, which vitamin D, and
your levels were low. Okay, they weren't
just low, they were really low. In fact,
you want your your vitamin D level to be
at least 30. That's like the minimum 30.
Okay. Your number was one of the lowest
we've had on the show. It was 13.
I don't even know how to process that.
Well, let me put it in this way because
I'm going to go through these numbers
with you very slowly and very carefully.
But you came here for answers today.
Yeah. I just gave you a bunch of answers
and I have no idea how to process them.
No. I'm going to I'm going to walk
That's why you're here. That's why
everyone's here because you're not
alone. Okay. I'm going to take you
through this and you're going to feel
when you're done that all these are
addressable. Every single one of them.
Hair loss is a fixable problem if you
know what to aim at. So, what we're
going to do today is get you involved
with a program that's going to allow you
one by one to change those numbers. I
don't want you running into muticians or
more hair products anymore. I want you
running into doctors. That's a message
for all of us. Would you hear me with
that? Let's do it. All right. I've got
this right person to induce you to.
We're going to go through the whole
thing. how to deal with inflammation and
get everyone confident that we can work
to grow our hair back. When we come
back, a plan for everybody struggling
with thinning hair and hair loss. Stay
here. Today, we have the plan to reverse
hair loss and regrow your hair. Sean is
only 35, but she has developed bald
spots and her hair comes out in large
clumps. So, I wanted to find a doctor
that work not just on treating hair loss
issues, but the underlying medical
imbalances that cause it. That's really
why you're here to see this as a symptom
of a bigger issue. Dr. Elizabeth Boowm
is joining us. She's a functional
medicine physician who works with Dr.
Mark Heyman at the Ultra Wellness
Center. So, we just saw Dr. that Sean
has some, you know, significant
imbalances. We went through her hormone
levels, her inflammation numbers, her
glucose, vitamin D. These all sort of
fit together. How common is it for women
who have hair loss? Almost half the
population to have one or more of these
problems. You know, it's so common. I
see this all the time in my practice.
And you know, Sean, as a woman, I really
relate to you because I know how
important the way my hair looks means to
how I feel about myself. And and women
come in all the time to my practice
saying, "I'm losing hair. What can I
do?" And and this is really important
that you came and had this blood work
done because we found so many things we
can work on that's going to help your
hair look better. Okay. Walk me through
the thyroid. So, what what should Sean
be doing? Yeah. You know, I think Sean,
we've got to start there because we saw
some major imbalances in your thyroid.
many things we can do in terms of diet
and lifestyle for the thyroid, but your
TSH was a little out of range. So much
out of range that I think we want to
also add in some medication to help your
thyroid. Okay. Simple to take, very safe
to take, not expensive to take. Okay.
Second big issue was the amount of
inflammation in the blood sugar. You
mentioned those as well. These sort of
middle two items. What do we do there?
Absolutely. So, you know, we know food
is medicine, right? And we're always
thinking about a low glycemic diet to
help with diabetes and to help with our
blood sugar balance and to help prevent
heart disease. But what we often don't
realize is that when we manage our blood
sugar and go on a low glycemic diet that
we're going to talk about, then all of
our hormones in our b body rebalance
themselves and then our we get hair
regrowth. Okay. And if we work to with a
good diet, we can get that under better
balance. What you're talking about with
the low glycemic diet for hair loss.
Okay. Got a little demonstration here.
Go ahead. The first thing we want to do,
I guess, is change what the foods that
they're that we're putting in our body.
Absolutely. We've got to work to lower
inflammation in the body because
inflammation comes with a with a
specific diet. And we saw your
inflammatory markers were kind of high
or definitely high. And so, we've got to
work to lower that inflammation. Okay.
So, the first thing is we're going to be
taking out foods that are high in
inflammation. The simple noodles. The
simple carbs. Yeah. The ones you like. I
know. I love noodles. Well, do you love
your hair more than noodles is the
question. I definitely want more hair
than noodles. We can deal with that. The
sugar and alcohol. Okay. They're simp
they're simple carbohydrates, too. They
get they spike that blood sugar up.
We're going to pull those out of the
diet. Dairy is an inflammatory food for
a lot of people. So, we're going to pull
that out. Okay. Okay. We're going to
rebuild you with foods that actually
help the hair. They include fiber.
Absolutely. All of these things. So,
yeah. you know, so we can we can help
with balancing your blood sugar by
giving you the right foods. So, a diet
that's high in fiber. Okay. Okay. In
addition, we want to give you good
healthy fats, things like that are found
in salmon and avocado. They're good for
our hair. And the other thing that fat
and protein does is it slows the
digestion and absorption of your food.
So, you want to have some protein and
fat at every meal. So, your blood sugar
doesn't increase as quickly with your
food. So, it's really important to
balance your protein, your fats, and
your high fiber foods each meal of your
day. Okay. Okay. So, except for the
noodles, the rest seems pretty easy for
you. Yeah, we can deal with that. Next
thing you want to do is increase your
daily dose of two important vitamins.
Okay. One is biotin. Okay. Which is the
building block for your hair and the
other one is vitamin D that I mentioned
over there. Okay. So, please walk us
through how these vitamins are important
for hair growth. Absolutely. So, biotin
is really the hair vitamin. It's great
for building strong hair. And you know,
you can get enough biotin with two eggs
a day. And in addition, these eggs are
going to help also with balancing your
blood sugar. So, they're a great thing
to add in. I can do eggs. Yeah. And
vitamin D. Again, you could get it from
the sun. But in America, we just don't
do that, especially in the winter
months. You're going to take 1,000 units
of vitamin D. We're going to start with
that. There's a pretty good chance we
might need a little bit more. Okay.
Okay. And the last big issue, and I have
no idea why we don't do this more with
so many people suffering from hair loss,
is minoxidil drops daily. Dr. Bow, why
is this forgotten and why is it so
valuable? Well, you know, it's over the
counter. It's easy to use. You can apply
it to your hair couple times a day and
it helps right at the hair follicle with
hair regrowth. So, while we're looking
to get to these underlying root issues
with the hair loss, while we're working
to rebalance things in your body, we can
be using the minoxidil and that can that
can be really helpful. Okay. Yeah, we
can do that. Sean, we gave you some
answers today. Yes. Dr. Bow has agreed
kindly to make you her patient.
So, she's going to help you.
Thank you so much. Oh,
and all I want to know is now that you
have a bit more of an understanding and
hopefully a little less helpless in this
approach, do you still feel like hiding?
It's going to take a little bit to get
there so I can like start throwing out
those baseball
caps. But I actually kind of feel good
about this. I I feel pretty good about
this. All right, so we're going to
follow your story. We'll be with you.
You can all follow Sean's story as well.
For the entire plan to reverse hair loss
and regrow your hair, you go to
dotterage.com. Join the tour with us as
we fix hair all across America. Thank
you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good