[Applause]
She's been a celebrity OBGYn for over 20
years. Stars in Bravo's hit series
Married to Medicine. And her clientele
includes stars like Tony Braxton and the
families of TI and Usher. She recently
released the book The Queen V:
Everything you need to know about sex,
intimacy, and down their healthcare.
Please welcome Dr. Jackie Walkers.
>> Thanks for being here.
>> Thank you. Thank you for having me. So
T, before we get into the the Queen V
insights, uh TI's uh took his daughter,
accompanied his daughter for virginity
testing. You have a good relationship
with TI, so I don't want to put you in
awkward spot, but what do you feel about
accompanying your child for virginity
testing?
>> Let's clarify. I don't think he meant
that in a serious way. I think he
started out joking and of course it
blossomed into something else, but I
don't think we should be doing that. You
know, I don't think I want my dad to go
with me to the doctor to see if I'm a
virgin, especially if I'm not.
>> You're not.
>> I don't take Is there really such a
thing as virginity testing?
>> It isn't. There's no test cuz some women
aren't even born with a highman. You can
destroy the himman in sports.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. And then surgeries, of course, you
know, we could disrupt the highman
there. So, no.
>> Okay. Just got past that. Now, one of
the reasons you wrote the book was
because you feel so passionately about
the need for us to understand our own
bodies. Absolutely. Absolutely. I think
we're in an era where women are
disempowered. And I wrote the book
because I want to empower women to one
speak up about feminine health and two
to protect that vital part of their body
and treat it like royalty.
>> It does.
>> It is royalty. It is. And we're ashamed
about it. We hear about it from our mom
at age five and maybe she had it wrong.
Maybe we don't remember it right or
maybe the science changes. But here you
all these years later believing
oftenimes myths well-intentioned as they
may be that can take you in the exact
wrong direction.
>> We can't even say the word when we're
born. You know, in some shows you can't
even say the word. And so kids are
raised not saying the real word. We give
it names.
>> Oprah told me when I was doing the Opra
show years ago, she would say, "Call it
vaji."
>> VJ.
>> VJ. Yes. I got it wrong. a ja
>> and one thing you you comment on that I
adored because it's so true is this
concept of a door knob question.
>> Yes.
>> So doctors know this but most of you
don't. Please explain this.
>> So most of the time for women and I see
all women they come in the room and
they'll talk around the real situation
and a lot of times with physicians we
have only a limited amount of time. When
you stand up and your hand hits the door
>> knob it's like okay I need to say this
>> one last thing. Just one last thing.
>> One last thing. And that's what they
really want to talk about. And women are
embarrassed to talk about and they may
want to tell you something they did or
somebody and
and so that doororknob question comes
out and they really talk about what they
want to tell you.
>> And one of the biggest doorup questions
has to do with infertility.
>> Absolutely.
>> You have been very open which I applaud
you for about your own struggles with
infertility.
>> Yes.
>> Why is that so why is it so difficult to
talk about?
>> Women somehow take on ownership for
infertility. Now, I'm not sure why we do
that, but we there's a stigma around
infertility as if it's the woman's
fault, and we don't like to talk about
it because we feel like either we did
something wrong or we didn't do
something right. And I want to dispel
that myth that infertility is a woman's
fault, and it's not.
>> So,
to speak honestly, you got to get
comfortable being uncomfortable. You're
a big proponent of that.
>> Yes. Yes. I mean, go back to
infertility. I'm okay sharing my story.
That makes a lot of people uncomfortable
saying, "I'm infertile as an OBGYn and I
never had a baby and I'm comfortable
with it."
>> It's hard to get around that though.
>> Oh, it it takes work. It takes work, but
you can get around it. Just start doing
it. A journey of a million miles starts
with one step. Just start doing it.
>> All right. So, are you okay with
answering some uncomfortable questions
from around the country?
>> Let's do it.
>> Right. These were viewers who were so
embarrassed they didn't want to put
their names on the questions. We're
going to protect them, but these are
common questions I know many of you
have. We're going to start with your
hometown of Atlanta.
>> All right.
>> Where Share Carare is based.
>> Yes.
>> All right. So, I've douched for many
years, but recently a friend told me I
should stop. Is there anything wrong
with douching?
>> Listen to your friend on this. And there
is a lot wrong with douching. You're w
There's a bacteria that should be in the
vagina, Lactobacillus. And douching
washes away that lactobacillus, changes
the pH of the vagina, and sets you up
for a ton of infections, bacteria,
vaginosis, and yeast. So, no douching.
>> So, is down there is really a
self-cleing oven.
>> It's a selfcle. That's exactly what I
said in the book. It's a selfcleing
oven.
>> Making sure you got it in there. Up
next, even more of what you wanted to
know, but we're too afraid to ask of
your gyn. We're going to take all your
awkward questions. Stick around.
>> We're back with celebrity OBGYn, Dr.
Jackie Walters, who's here with
everything you need to know about down
there, but you're too afraid to ask. So,
we reached out to our Dr. draws viewers
across the country and ask them to send
us the questions they've been too
embarrassed and afraid to ask their own
OB/GYN. Next question is from Dallas.
Here's a question. I have bad reactions
to taking the pill. My doctor suggests
trying the ring for birth control. I'm
nervous about the procedure. How does
the ring work?
>> So, the ring is really a birth control
pill in a plastic form.
>> I brought you a little demo. You like
demo?
>> Yeah, let's do it. Let's do it.
So, of course, this
>> just orient everybody here.
>> Of course, I know everybody in the room
knows what this is, right?
>> But this is for the men.
>> Okay. For the men. All right. So, this
is the female body in a sense. Vagina,
cervix, uterus, bladder, rectum. And so,
the ring works with medicine embedded
estrogen, progesterone, just like in a
birth control pill. It's embedded in
this plastic.
>> And once it's down around the cervix, it
secretes its hormones like that.
>> Absolutely. The body absorbs that just
like it would if you were taking a peel
>> and it would secrete it for three weeks
and then the fourth week it comes out.
>> Right. Exactly. You take it out and then
that's the week you would probably have
a period.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. And so the ring is inserted by
almost like you could do a tampon. Put
your foot up if you're comfortable doing
that.
>> I've never personally done this but
>> never. Okay.
>> I'm trust
>> as a doctor you've seen it. I've
>> seen it.
>> Right. And so the ring is compressed,
slid into the vagina, and there's no
absolute place to put it in the vagina
as long as it's in there. And it
typically kind of fits here in the back
of the vagina. It doesn't slide out like
this in most cases,
>> but it's there. It's kind of
>> Well, I mean, can I ask a guy question
here? I mean, doesn't it get in the way?
>> No, not at all.
>> I mean, it looks like it would get in
the way. I'm just looking.
>> No, no, it becomes very It becomes very
soft and gelatinous. Most men, not all,
but most men won't even know it's there.
So,
>> all right.
>> And so, it just kind of says right there
in the body, like you showed it, and it
keeps you from getting pregnant.
>> And in the fourth week, you just lick
it.
>> Take your finger.
>> Yes.
>> Slide it right out.
>> I'm impressed.
>> Yes.
>> The OBGYn use that. Is it popular?
>> Oh, yes. Oh, yes. I mean, think about
it. You don't have to think about it for
3 weeks. It's there. You're not having
to remember to take a peel. I love this
segment. This is fantastic. I never knew
about these things. There you go.
>> I got all kinds of advice I can give on
this now. All right. Final question is
from Philly. It's my hometown, by the
way. Here it is. If someone has tested
positive for HPV, can it be transmitted
orally via saliva or sharing utensils or
kissing a child? What do you think? So
HPV, human papilloma virus, we do
believe and the answer really is maybe,
but we think it is definitely
transmitted orally, but not from a
utensil or kissing your child on the
forehead. It has to be typically real
oral. So the answer is yes to the oral,
but no to utensils and your child.
>> God bless you for being here with us
sharing the wisdom you've got. For
everything you want to know about sex,
intimacy, and down there health, you can
check out Dr. Dr. Jackie Walter's new
book, The Queen V. Now, this audience is
really curious about this topic.
>> Yes.
>> You think we have a couple copies for
them?
>> Oh, certainly. Let's do it.
>> All right. You're all going home with a
copy. Everyone will give the audience.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good