[Music]
Bruce Jenner has everyone buzzing about
transgender. I know this is a a
difficult conversation to have
sometimes. But first, meet a woman who
spent most of her life trapped in a
man's body. It started when I was around
four and something was was wrong. I
understanding transgender. You got five
kids, a wife. Did you worry you were
going to lose them? Coming up next on
Dr. Oz.
Welcome everybody. Bruce Jenner, no
stranger to the spotlight, an Olympic
gold medalist, star of Keeping Up with
the Kardashians, and now speculated to
be the new face of the transgender
community.
As Bruce's rumored transition moves from
the tabloid gossip columns to headline
news, the Olympian and one-time
heartthrob could end up becoming the
most high-profile celebrity to
transition in the public eye. Jenner's
journey has been drawing attention for
the last few months, capped off by
Jenner's mom, Esther, telling the world
she's more proud of Bruce now than for
winning Olympic gold. But Jenner is not
the only transgender newsmaker in the
public eye. Actress Leverne Cox became
the first openly transgender person to
be nominated for an Emmy for her role in
Orange is the New Black. And the
critically acclaimed show Transparent,
starring actor Jeffrey Tambber as a
father transitioning to a woman, won two
Golden Globe Awards this year. My whole
life, I've been dressing up
like a man.
This is me.
People who are lesbian, gay, bisexual,
or transgender. Transgender history was
also made when President Obama became
the first American president to
acknowledge the transgender community in
his State of the Union address. A
message sending a clear signal that
transgender Americans are finally
stepping into the spotlight and coming
into their own.
With all this attention focused on
transgender people, we want to help
answer some of your questions about what
transgender really means and especially
why some people transition later in
life. And there's no better way to do
that than to meet a family who is living
it.
16 years ago, surrounded by friends,
family, and their children from previous
marriages, Tom and Mary took vows to
spend the rest of their lives together.
They created a home, blended their
family. They considered themselves
soulmates.
Yet Tom struggled in secret with inner
conflict. From earliest childhood, Tom
felt confused about gender and felt like
a female born in a male body. Through
the years, those feelings intensified,
as did Tom's confusion.
Tom internalized those emotions,
excelling in sports, academics, and
later at his career. All while feeling
secretly isolated and depressed.
But 5 years ago, despondent and
increasingly suicidal, Tom decided to
face the truth and live openly as a
woman.
3 years ago, Tom transitioned to Tina to
friends and family. A year later, she
came out at work and in public. Today,
Tina and Mary are still married. And
look at this one. Look at those
sideburns.
And along with their children are
navigating the waters of their new lives
together. I love you. I love you, too.
Please welcome Tina to the show. Tina's
daughter, Evelyn, and wife, Mary, will
join us shortly. I want to thank you
first off for coming on. I know this is
a a difficult conversation to have
sometimes. Well, thank you for having
me. It I I enjoy having the
conversation. So, the big question that
comes up a lot is you had these gender
identity issues early in your life. Yet,
it took you a good part of your life to
finally come to grips with it. What was
that like? It started when I was around
four, I think, is when I first became
aware that just something was was wrong.
I had no idea what it was. Um, and just
over the next 40 years, I really
struggled with a sense that I'm supposed
to be a man, but I just felt I was or
wanted to be a woman. And that just felt
very difficult. You you're living a
life, you mentioned some of the
attributes, but trying to be more of a
man, marrying, having kids, doing things
to try to fit in, yet deep inside
earnestly struggling because you realize
it wasn't real. So, how do you find the
side that you've struggled enough as a
man and you want to live your authentic
self? Was there a moment that it finally
became alive to you? Yeah, I and I I
think this is common. You you you try
every other explanation. Uh therapy, it
was something my parents did. Oh, maybe
it's supplements if I take supplements.
Um I mean, I can't think you prayer. You
try a lot of prayer. you you just try
everything and and every year you
eliminate one of those and then finally
you're left with the one thing you
didn't want it to be at the time and um
we I had a night like that where I was
just very close to suicide and um I
didn't attempt it but I just it was very
despondent and I realized
I needed to redefine victory from
conquering my gender and manning up to
just accepting my gender. um even if I
didn't understand it and it was a weight
just lifted almost instantly. But at the
same time, you must have felt relieved
to be able to to get past that. You got
five kids, a wife. Did you worry you
were going to lose them with this
decision?
Yes. And I probably would have held it
off if I thought I had a choice. But I
and and I think my wife Mary agreed that
they were going to lose me one way or
the other and she'd rather keep me
around this way. And it really came down
to that. I I did not feel
I once you realize that you're being
inauthentic, it's impossible to fake it
anymore.
So this word transition, this is the
word that I I think most people are
comfortable enough. We haven't talked
about it much, but let me if I can
explain what transitioning really means.
And when I do it with the help of Dr.
Christine McInn is a surgeon who works
extensively with the transgender
community. Dr. McInn is actually a
Tina's doctor. She too is transgender.
Dr. Mcin, please join us.
Thank you very much for coming on again.
So, so if you can, the first question I
think we have to break through is what
causes someone to be transgender? Do we
really know the answer? Well, most
experts feel that is biologic in origin
and there's a lot of research that
points towards biologic causes. Like
there are some brain studies and and
there's more research every day. Um I
would almost bet my reputation as a as a
surgeon, having seen so many people
transition from different countries and
different cultures, the process is
always the same no matter where they
come from. And that to me speaks to a
biologic uh cause. walk us through the
transition process. What actually
happens when someone begins once they've
made the insight clear to themselves and
people around them what actually happens
medically? Well, you heard the story
leading up to that. And then uh usually
if they are lucky enough, they get the
idea that to go seek help from somebody
else and and hopefully they'll find a
therapist that uh knows what they're
talking about and the therapist will um
make the diagnosis of gender dysphoria,
but more importantly um give them the
support system to take this journey and
and give them the tools. A lot of times
when people think about transgender
folks making a a change in their lives,
it's it's often thought around surgical
issues, right? You take the penis off,
you make a vagina or vice versa. But
that's actually apparently not always
done, right? Or not frequently done.
What holds people back from making that
final decision? What else besides
surgery is part of the transition? Well,
since gender is a self ascribed uh
entity, uh people have different um
ideas about what that means to them. So,
some people they need that uh genital
surgery or maybe sometimes it's removal
of an Adam's apple to to look in the
mirror and say, "This is how I feel
inside," which is really what gender is
a p private thing. It's not a public
thing. So, Tina, you had the operation
about a year ago. What was it like
immediately afterwards?
It was wonderful. Um, the surgery itself
just felt like surgery. Uh, but
afterwards
I just felt complete. I felt I didn't
have to avert my eyes or or kind of
squint when I looked at myself. I was
just me. It it confirmed I love the word
gender confirmation surgery because it
really I felt confirmed physically. So,
we've heard how Tina's handled her
transition to live as her authentic
self, but what about her family? It's a
question I've touched on with you. How
are they handling it? Evelyn is here.
She's Tina's oldest child. And Evelyn,
would you mind joining us? And thank you
for being here as well.
Thank you again for coming.
So, Evelyn, for most of your life, the
person next to you was your cool dad. By
the way, she described you as cool.
That's those are her words, right?
athletic, preppy, cool guy, and it's
different now. And what's that
transition been like for you? Uh, it's
been a huge transition for me. I think I
found out about uh the fact that my dad
crossdressed a very long time ago. And
that was pretty easy to accept, but once
I found out uh almost 5 years ago that
that was it, my dad was not going to be
with us anymore. Uh it was it was
incredibly painful. Um the first two
years uh were just filled with a lot of
tears and a lot of conversations. We
talked all the time. Um
and uh and then seeing the transition to
then you know making the date for the
surgery everything was was very very
difficult. And then uh once it was all
over I actually felt a weight lifted
for Tina. Um, so it and our our our
relationship has gone through a
transition, too, and so we've gotten
closer. Tina, what does Evelyn's love
mean to you to have her express it like
that? Oh, everything. Um,
I it just when you're
when you're in the closet, it's it's
like living your entire life behind a
plexiglass. And you because you're
speaking through someone else and people
are speaking to someone else.
And so when they say I love you, you you
don't feel it because they're saying it
to this other person. And it's the first
time in my entire life I get to feel
that. And that's what for me transition
is about is being connected to the human
race in a way that I never was before.
You have four other children.
Do you ever feel that you left them as a
father and maybe they want that part of
you back?
Oh, yeah. And and there are pieces.
Look, he got me here. Uh, and wonderful.
I I used to tease that he was a man as a
woman would design him. He was pretty
cool.
Um, and and so I miss that at times. I
don't miss at ever. I've not had a
moment where I've missed that. I now
feel me. Uh, and so that was more for me
a stage. You're married to Mary for 16
years. It's a long relationship. How's
her journey been through all this?
It's been very tough. Uh, I would tell
people don't try this at home. But, uh,
the irony, right? You can only do it at
home. It's fantastic. But uh but she
stood by me even in her most tearful
moments. There was never any doubt that
she was there for me. But it was a real
struggle for her. It's very painful.
We're very we still are very in love,
but it's it's changed fundamentally.
We're take a break. When we come back,
the woman who married Tom 16 years ago
joins us to talk about her relationship
with Tina today. We'll be right back.
Coming up next, you heard from Tina.
Now, meet her wife, Mary. How she
discovered Tina's true feelings about
being transgendered, why she chose to
stay married, and what they do together
to make their life and marriage work.
Coming up next, tomorrow on Dr. Oz,
Jennifer Lopez is here. She's revealing
her health and beauty tips for the new
year, her morning ritual, and the big
thing she's into now. That's coming up
tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
Tom and Mary White married 16 years ago.
5 years ago, Tom confronted the lifelong
struggle of feeling like a woman trapped
in a man's body, transitioning to Tina 3
years ago. Today, Tina and Mary are
still married and facing the challenges
and complications of their relationship
together.
Talking today about transgender people
and why some transition later in life,
Tina's wife, Mary, is now joining us.
When did you first have an inkling that
your husband at the time, Tom, might
have a gender identity issue? Well, I
didn't know what it was. when we were
dating, he told me that he liked to wear
women's clothes once in a while, but I'd
never have to see it. So, I thought,
well, maybe that's a fetish. And he was
so wonderful that I could probably deal
with that. So, but then that and that
was that was fine for a while. And then
um probably I don't know how long ago it
was cuz it seems like it just happened.
Um, I would see women's shoes much
bigger size than mine, women's clothes
around, um, that were obviously not
mine. And I said, "What what is this
about?" And he said, "Oh, I'm sorry. I
didn't mean for you to see that, but um,
I have to dress once in a while like I I
had told you." Well, this went on for a
while, eb and flow.
He'd fight it. he'd come back, dress as
a woman, fight it, be a man. And then
there was one point that really I
realized this was going to be not going
to last. And she was uh she had come
home from work. Mhm. She was he at the
time and uh was in the bathroom and the
door was locked, was in there for quite
a long time. And I did not know what was
going on cuz I knew how depressed he
was. So I almost knocked down the door
to see what was going on
and I
he was crying and said, "I'm so sorry."
I sat inside the tub with him and he
said, "I'm sorry. I just can't live like
this anymore.
I've been fighting it. I'm trying to
fight it and sorry. And I just can't do
it. I have to be
who I am."
And um
I didn't know what I was going to do,
but I did know one thing for sure. I
love I loved him so much. And I cared
about what was going to happen to him
that I'm not going to just run away. I'm
going to see what happens and deal with
it dayto day. And
when she told me
finally, I guess uh 3 years ago when you
said or two years ago that she's going
to go through the transition.
It was not I cried. I cried a lot. I was
very depressed for a long time. But then
I thought if if he doesn't do this, I
might lose him as completely and at
least
if he goes through this transition and
becomes who he really is as this
beautiful woman she is.
At least I get to have her here and
she's my best friend. We are soulmates.
It's beautiful.
When you when you broke through the the
bathroom door to get to Tom, obviously,
you know, the thought of suicide we
discussed earlier had come across his
mind. You must have been fearful that he
would act on that. Absolutely. And I saw
how depressed he was and I was worried
that he was going to commit suicide. And
I I don't know for sure, but I feel like
if he wouldn't have done this, he would
have committed suicide and he wouldn't
be here with us.
He's never said that. But well, what do
you I mean you you may not have said in
private, but I am curious. Is was that a
real possibility? What would you have
done if you hadn't been able to
transition?
People tell me I'm brave. I I I think I
do brave things, but I did this because
I felt back to a wall where I had no
other alternative. And when that is the
alternative, then wearing a dress
suddenly seems very attractive.
Um, but seriously, people people tend to
focus on the dress. And I I can
understand it really is there's nothing
more depressing than having no self that
you can relate to. And in fact, to feel
that you're the one I was doing, the
violence to myself by repressing that.
And I realized I I can never
I I think that's why so many transgender
people commit suicide because they're
just going to the logical conclusion of
what they're doing to themselves
psychologically.
Um what's your marriage like now? It's
wonderful. Uh it's different. Uh we're I
would say we're very intimate but not in
a sexual sense. We're um but we've lost
one vocabulary for love and we've come
up with a thousand others. So, in the
way you make coffee for each other, the
way we listen to each other, uh the way
we talk to each other, um we are just a
very loving couple. We are. She's we're
best friends. And I would have never my
my philosophy on being with somebody is,
you know, in marriage or in a
relationship, if you think you're going
to leave that relationship to find
somebody else, that's not a reason to
leave. If you're leaving that
relationship because you cannot stand
being with that person, that's why you
would leave. I tell you, I love her. We
enjoy our life together. We have so much
fun. Didn't your friends, maybe even
your family say, "Leave, Tom. You don't
want to be with Tina?" Absolutely. I had
friends constantly tell me, "Why aren't
you leaving him? Divorce him. You know,
get on with your life." I'm like,
"Divorce him and go where? And why would
I? I love I love being with her. But I
would say our family was pretty
remarkable. They had difficulty with it.
But what was beautiful for me to see, we
have a very diverse family. She has a
daughter from a previous marriage who
belongs to a very devout um Christian
church, very about as conservative as
you can get. They translate the Bible,
interpret the Bible literally. This was
a real struggle for them. And I worried
that she might lose them for supporting
me. But they really had figured out a
way to honor their faith and you and and
me and me. And you and me for sticking
with her. Sure. Yeah. Uh
there's so many questions that come to
mind about how this all plays out. For
example, do you feel an attraction to
men or to women? It's a great question.
Uh, and it usually takes us, frankly, a
few years to work out the change in our
own heads.
I find men attractive in a way that I
never had before, but I far prefer the
company of women. So, I'd rather be at
the bar with her talking about how cute
you look.
You got me. You got me.
[Laughter]
[Applause]
Well, you know what? what's going on in
a man's head. It's, you know, it's not a
not a happy place sometimes. That's why
I don't think I
uh I while I find men attractive, I
can't I could never see myself if I even
if I weren't married going that far. I
just know too much of men's secrets.
I would love if you would just give the
audience some insights of what you think
is going on in Bruce Jenner's family
right now.
I
I just I I I have a hard time imagining.
Your mind just explodes with all of the
change. And I felt it hard enough. We
felt it hard enough in our neighborhood
and our family managing
a hundred conversations. Um
for for them facing this level of
publicity, I hope what they're doing is
I hope that Bruce is spending time
thinking about himself, herself. wait
for him to say her, right? Uh and and
their family. Yeah. And it must be so
fearful for his family because, you
know, when we found out what was going
on with her, I had no idea what
transgender meant. It was never in my
vocabulary. And we had to bring so many
people along with us to teach them what
it was about. And here they are in the
spotlight trying to deal with this and
losing their father and who's if that is
the case. It's hard. It's not easy. But
I've learned today that maybe you're
going to lose the father either way.
Exactly. And this is a much happier
ending to the story. I agree 100%. So if
I can speak to the audience on this and
I think people are often fearful and
judgmental of what they don't know or
understand. And I wanted to share Tina's
story today so everyone can see that
she's just a person trying to live her
authentic life. And I've truly adored
making her acquaintance and and having
this story on our show. I appreciate you
making the effort. Evelyn Beckin, thank
you as well very much. We'll be right
back.
[Applause]
Next. Do you want to live a pain-free
life? Before you turn to prescription
drugs, learn from other pain sufferers
who share their best do-it-yourself
remedies, simple solutions to get rid of
your chronic back and neck pain, plus
health shortcuts to simplify your life.
Next,
[Applause]
one of my biggest missions on this show
is to help you live a pain-free life.
And the good news, it's working because
thousands of formerly chronic bang back
pain sufferers have come forward.
They're saying, "Dr. Oz, I am now
painfree." So, I asked a lot of them to
share how they kicked their back pain to
the curb. And Tanya sent me this
provocative Facebook message. She says,
"Dr. Oz, after so much trial and error,
I finally found something so simple to
get rid of my pain." So, I wanted to
hear about it. So, what is your DIY
solution for back pain that you love so
much? So, have you ever had um like an
ice pack when you went to like a nurse's
office when you're in school or a child?
It's very similar to that. Oh, but it's
sort of free cuz you have all the stuff
at home. Oh, show me. Pray tell. So,
actually here we have two parts water.
There's two cups of water here. And one
cup of rubbing alcohol. Yep. Yep. It's
alcohol. It's alcohol. So, can you pour
that in here for me? So, water goes in
first. Yeah. And then the alcohol. The
alcohol goes in there. And you're going
to want to try to squeeze out as much of
the air as possible.
And how long does it take to freeze? So
you can put it in for like an hour and
it'll be cold enough and maybe not as
solid as this within an hour, but you
can use it after an hour. That's not too
solid. That's pretty good. No, it's not.
It's actually more like a gel. And when
it melts, can you refreeze it? I always
refreeze mine. I always have one in the
freezer. What a great money saver.
Fantastic idea. Thank you very, very It
works really well for a bunch of good
reasons. Keeping it in cold helps. Thank
you very much. Thank you so much. All
right. Next, I got Denise. How are you,
Denise? Good. Nice to meet you back.
Denise says that she learned this next
fix for her back pain actually on this
show and it's something called the
pretzel stretch. Pretzel stretch. Yes,
it is. So, how'd you hear about it?
Well, I watch a show quite often and I
go to yoga a lot and I just do it all
the time. You remind me what it is?
Sure. I like the name pretzel stretch.
Pretzel stretch. So, how do we sit? So,
straight up. Straight. Put your both
legs straight out. One's going to cross
over the little right over left. All
right. You're going to take your right
hand. Hold. No. No. Take your left hand.
Got it backwards. You're confusing me. I
am confused myself. And stretch around.
And you got to go as as far back as you
can. Oh, feels good. You'll feel it on
your back. How long do you hold it for?
I hold it for a few seconds. Probably
about 30 seconds. And then I'll doverse.
And then you do the reverse. It's And
when's your back pain usually worse?
When I wake up in the morning. I love
the fact you're not using prescription
medication. Thank you very much. Thank
you very much, Dr. Appreciate it. Now, I
wanted to share with you some other
DIYs. As I saw, these are three best
health hacks that I saw on Pinterest
this week. And actually, interestingly,
one of the best things to do for your
back pain has to do with one of these
little tips. It helps you lose weight.
You lose the weight, the back pain gets
better in a lot of people. Great health
hack for is very simple. All you've got
to do, and by the way, health hacks, you
all know these are simple shortcuts to
make life simpler. They're hopefully
inexpensive and easy to incorporate into
your life. The first health hack is this
marble scale. Look carefully at this.
You put a marble from the one bottle
that's that said pounds to go into the
other one that says pounds lost. Move it
from one jar to the next. And of course,
if you gain weight, you take it back.
Pounds lost, go back in the pounds to
go. It's a great visual motivator so you
can watch your progress. The next health
hack that I found on Pinterest. Really
enjoy this. Aluminum foil dryer balls.
Great DIY solution for doing laundry
because guess what? Dryer sheets can be
expensive. They've got lots of chemicals
in them. A ball of aluminum foil can
prevent static cling and they last for
months. You keep throwing the darn thing
in there and they really work. But this
last one is probably one of my favorites
because I use it myself. I'm going to
show you how to ripen an avocado. I
don't know how many of you had this
experience. You go to the store, you buy
an avocado and it's going to be ripe in
about a week, right? But you want to
make the, you know, the dish that you
want to make that day or the next day.
So, what you do is you take this avocado
and you take a banana and you put it in
a brown bag overnight. If you do that,
the avocado ripens. You can make a
guacamole. And how does this happen? I'm
going to do a little test right here.
This one I did myself. I've got these
were bought the same time, same place,
right? And I want to take a Who wants to
judge these for me? Who judges us? You
want to judge her? Squeeze the Charmin
here. Squeeze these and tell me, is
there a difference? Yes, definitely. We
could use this one right now. You could.
Isn't that amazing? Bought the same
time. All the frustration, angst of your
life gone with a simple paper. Really?
Thank Thank you very much. Listen, I've
added my top tips on backbolutions to my
Clipix. That's one of my favorite tools
on the web. And you can head to
clipix.com/draws
to see it right now. I'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up next. You've always heard that
drinking water is good for you, but can
too much be a bad thing? We may becoming
aquaholics and getting sick from
drinking more than we need. How much
water is really the right amount for
your body? Coming up next
tomorrow on Dr. Oz. Jennifer Lopez is
here. She's revealing her health and
beauty tips for the new year, her
morning ritual, and the big thing she's
into now. That's coming up tomorrow on
Dr. Oz.
[Applause]
As we all do things to better our
health, there's growing concern we could
be doing too much of a good thing. Some
experts are now saying drinking too much
water could be making us sick. And it's
leading to a whole new term. You may
have heard it, aquaholics.
Adding more water to our diets has
become increasingly popular. As a
nation, we drink over 1 billion glasses
of water a day, 38% more than we did in
the 1990s. With more and more diet and
fitness experts stressing the importance
of water for health, sales of bottled
water has skyrocketed to an astonishing
12 billion dollars annually with some
people taking their H2O intake to
extremes. But I wanted to show you the
5Q container that I fill up every day
with water and sometimes I find myself
actually filling it up again at night.
This is my 24 oz jug and we're going to
do some workout. Fill this up three
times and chug chug chug. Yet, some
experts now worry that drinking extreme
amounts of water can create its own
health hazards, contributing to
everything from bloating and nausea to
frequent urination and poor sleep. Could
you be putting yourself at risk for
these health problems by drinking too
much water?
Joanna Lenell are joining me. So, Joan,
let's go back to the very beginning of
all this thing. When when did you start
drinking this much water? About four
years ago, I decided I needed to lose
weight. So, I was told drinking water
would help me. So, I drank water and I
just continued and it worked. So, I just
kept drinking more and more water and
now I'm addicted. Addicted to water. I
really am. My water goes with me
wherever I go. Elena, how about you?
Well, about 5 years ago, Dr. Oz, I had a
cancer scare. Uh, fortunately, it was
benign. Good. And so that's when I
started drinking a lot of water, getting
on a more healthy regimen, and um now I
just chug chug chug. So I I just I saw
the jugs you all brought with you. And
Lenel, you brought a couple of the the
pictures you use. You drink two of these
before a workout. Is that really I think
I drink the 24 ounce. Two of these
before workout and then two after a
workout. That can't feel good. It's a
lot of water in your belly. Yeah. And um
Yeah. And it does kind of lead to a
little nausea, but I don't stop. So, I'm
definitely, I guess, addicted. Okay.
Okay. And Joanne, you you brought this.
This is gargantuous. A five quart
container. Is that right? I love my
container. It's very attractive. How
does all that water affect you?
Negatively. Um, unfortunately, I don't
sleep much. I have to wake up at least
two, three times in the middle of the
night. Yeah. I can only sleep about two
and a half hours um straight at once.
I'm tired when I wake up, of course,
because I'm not getting straight sleep.
Sure. And also, um I need to find the
ladies room wherever I go. Wherever. I
mean, I find myself crossing my legs,
which I'm sure so many women can
empathize with me just to hold it in.
And I've even had a bad incident once
where Yes. I What kind of a bad
incident? That doesn't sound good. I
did. I did. I um I could not hold it in.
I was out shopping
and I actually broke the hand dryer in
the ladies room of a store trying to dry
my pants.
That's a bad embarrassing. All right.
So, let's talk about this word
aquaholic. Okay. It's being used a fair
amount. It's not a clinical diagnosis.
Uh it's more like a disordered behavior,
but something that obviously has some
side effects. We want to deal with it.
And you both have said you sort of feel
addicted to the stuff. You have to have
it with you. Yes. Is that true, Joan?
Yes. Bring those goodies. Come on over,
Lynel, as well. I'm going to show you
with those trusty water containers
everything that you're doing. So, first
off, if you don't mind, pick the table
with your name on it. You'll see why in
a second. And we've been saying for
years, everybody, you want to get eight
glasses of water a day, right? Eight
glasses of water looks like this. And
you know even this we can talk about in
a second but in comparison Lenel this is
you with about 20 glasses of water. It's
a big difference between the two tables.
Definitely. If I can move one a little
further look at the 25 Joan that you
have in comparison a day. Does that
frighten you to see the difference
between what we generally think is the
right amount of water and what you guys
are taking in? Definitely. I I mean
because now it's so visual that I can
see I'm probably overdoing it. But then
how do I stop because I I take this like
everywhere? Well, I give you one little
tip. Do you want to take a little
dispenser of yours and put put some in a
cup there? I think one of the smartest
things to do is to drink your water from
a cup so you actually know what you're
getting. Like anything else, listen,
water is great for you. I want you to
drink water. Please don't take us the
wrong way, America. Keep getting your
water. I want you to visualize the right
amount of intake so you feel your best.
You can live your best life and still
get the benefit of the water because a
lot of people don't drink enough. So
using that cup and eight of those in a
day is a way of thinking it through.
Frankly, carting around that five C
container is like carting around a a
gallon a ton of ice cream. I don't cart
this around with me, Dr. This goes in my
refrigerator. Oh, good. I feel better
now. Oh, no, no, no. Jeez. The subway
with the I fill this up every morning. I
put lemons in it. It goes in my
refrigerator and I actually fill up.
Yes, I fill up my water. Okay. Be
pushing people away from you with that
cart. All right. So, I'm going to toast
to you.
I'll grab one of these, too. To the
right amount of water. And now, let me
explain to you and everybody at home
what the right amount of water is
because it's not eight glasses of water
either. That was an old idea. We've got
better ways of thinking about this. So,
let's get into those details. So instead
of the eight glasses a day, which is
what we used to say based on information
from literally Second World War, that we
don't think that's the best way of
taking your water from now on. It's not
a one-sizefits-all game. We all use
different amounts of water. So I'm going
to give you rules of thumb unless you're
sick that you can use. And it starts off
with trusting your body because when
you're thirsty, you should get a glass
of water. Then look at the color of your
urine. And we've talked a little bit
about this, but I'll make it really
vivid. It should be the color of pale
straw,
light yellow color like that. I don't
want it any darker than that. That means
you got plenty of stuff to wash out any
toxins that are in your body. One last
little tip, especially for the Jo-Ann's
of the world who aren't sleeping, I want
you to limit your water within two to
three hours of your bedtime. Does not
affect your sleep. Make sure you train
yourself like you do your pets. Go to
the bathroom right before you get in bed
so you can get uninterrupted sleep
throughout the night. We'll be right
back.
Coming up next, love a good
old-fashioned pancake but hate all the
carbs? Give these breakfast favorites a
healthy makeover. Tasty and creative
recipes that you will flip for the best
high protein pancakes to keep you full
for hours. Coming up,
whoever said a doctor's visit isn't fun
has obviously never been to the Dr. Oz
show. Is that right? Make your
appointment today. Go to dr.com/tick
and sign up for free tickets.
There's a new trend a lot of you in the
Oz Nation are flipping for high protein
pancakes. A typical pancake, believe it
or not, has as much as Whoa.
One more time.
I I've been working on this that many
grams of carbs. 28 g of carbs. But now,
home cooks are cutting the bad with
ingredients like protein powder and
peanut butter and egg whites and small
changes can cut the carb amount by a
whopping
67%.
So, today we have home cooks from the Oz
Nation here to compete for the best high
protein pancake to keep you full for
hours. Now, my med unit has been working
hard through the night calculating which
pancake is lowest in carbs and highest
in protein and flavor. And our finalists
are eagerly awaiting the results. Are
you ready? There they are. Very. Are you
guys all nervous? Yes. Baited. They're
all desirous of the coveted Golden
Spatula Award. In third place is
Valerie. Come on down, Valerie.
Welcome to the show. Bal. You can put
your pancakes down there and I'll adorn
you with your bronze medal, so to speak.
So, what do you got in here? Tell me
about it. I made strawberries and cream
protein pancakes. Now, how do you make
them? It's real simple. It's just four
ingredients. Uh 3/4 scoop of protein
powder, four egg whites,
raw oats, and um unsweetened almond
milk. You just mix it all together and
top it with some fresh strawberries or
you can even put the strawberries
inside. You know, first of all, kudos to
you for realizing that protein powder is
not just about shakes. So, you can use
it in a lot of different foods. And
we're also proud of the fact we have 10
g of protein in this pancake, which cuts
the carbs about 64%. Good for you.
Congratulations. All right, second place
is Denise. Come on down, Denise.
Oh, look at the joy on your face. Look
at that. I love you. I love you, too. I
love you, too. Oh my goodness. I just
love that. What a pretty smile. Ain't
that great? All right. So, what you put
in your protein pancakes? Um, today, um,
I made banana cinnamon protein pancakes,
and it has a half a scoop of protein
powder, eggs, egg whites, banana, and
Greek yogurt because our daughter
Jackie, she's 12 years old, but she
loves Greek yogurt. So, I love to add
that. I'm going to taste it and see what
it tastes like. Can't wait. Here. Was
the recipe yours? You make it up? Uh, I
have a large Italian family and we like
to eat and trade recipes. So, that's one
of the recipes that was traded. Tell you
what, I like it because it's got a
little bit of a punch to it. It's nice.
They're also little thinner and I like
that as well. So, 12 grams of protein on
this one, which is why you did so well
in the ranking and reducing carbo
carbohydrates by 59%.
And the cinnamon is a great idea because
it helps your body deal with the sugar
that's all going to be in the syrup more
effectively. So, congratulations. Oh,
thank you so much. Are we all ready? The
moment has arrived, everybody. It is
time to award the best protein pancake
maker. And the winner of the Golden
Spatula Award, are you ready? It is
Dawn. Come on down, Don.
Oh, I'll hold that up. That put this on
first so I can hear you. And there's
your golden spatula. I made this myself,
by the way. It's It's actually not
really golden. I mean, it's golden, but
not gold. Beautiful. But it will it will
So, tell me about your pancake. How'd
you make it? Well, I made peanut butter
protein pancakes. Um, peanut butter
protein. So, extra protein with the
peanut butter. Yes, exactly. Um, I put
in a half a scoop of peanut of protein
powder, cottage cheese, um, raw oats,
and egg whites. Cottage cheese. Cottage
cheese. We always have cottage cheese at
home. So, I figured I'd throw that in
one day and it came out delicious. Yeah,
I taste a little bit of just the right
amount. I mean, it's a crazy concept.
Cottage cheese and pancakes, right? But
it's innovative. It's incredibly tasty.
They were all tasty, by the way. So,
yours had 12 grams of protein. Wow. And
a whopping 67% reduction in
carbohydrates.
A little bit. I can say this. You have a
few more calories in yours than the
other ones, but you traded out basically
simple carbohydrates with no benefit for
a little extra fat. I'll take that
trade-off any day. Congratulations to
you to all my competitors. You can find
these protein pancake recipes at dr.com
and on my Pinterest board so you can
repin the recipes and make them for your
family. I'll be right back.
[Applause]
Tomorrow on Dr. Oz. Superstar Jennifer
Lopez is here. I'm excited to be on Dr.
Oz. Her beauty, that body. Jayla reveals
how she keeps it all together. You ever
look at your urine?
That's the first time in 10,000
interviews that I've done in my life
that anybody asked me the color of my
teeth.
That's coming up tomorrow on Dr. Oz.
[Applause]
So, do you know there's actually a
scientific fact that you actually do
look better in sunglasses? Don't you
like that? Sunglasses help make your
face look very even on both sides. And
that's one of the most important factors
we rank when we try and figure out
what's a beautiful face and not, which
is pure symmetry. So, there are lots of
surgeons now who wear sunglasses in the
operating room, not to be cool, but
actually to protect their eyes from
lasers. So, I was intrigued when I came
across these high-tech sheets. These
aren't just any sunglasses. They
originally created for laser surgeons,
but they were accidentally found to
correct color blindness. So, that same
vision technology is making its way into
sunglasses. It may help as many as 80%
of people who are color blind. What do
you guys think?
Looking good and feeling good. Last time
for in case you missed it. First, one of
the most provocative conversations I've
ever had in the show is a middle-aged
person like Tina. There are lots of
folks who have been making the decision
to undergo a gender transition. But what
seems like one person's choice is in
fact farreaching as families recreated
themselves in the process. Next, there's
a new trend that a lot of you in the Oz
Nation are flipping for. High protein
pancakes. We had our very own protein
pancake cookoff to crown the winner of
the coveted golden spatula. Today, our
winner swapped out protein uh powder and
and put it in place of the flour that's
usually there. But in addition, she also
added cottage cheese for flavor and a
little bit of peanut butter. Her pancake
cake, 12 grams of protein, and she
managed to cut out 60 for 7% of carbs.
You can find all the protein pancake
recipes at dr.com. It's also my
Pinterest board. Check it out. Make it
for your family. Finally, please be
careful about what you buy online,
especially weight loss pills. Dubious
people online make it seem that I
endorse their products. I don't. To see
a full list of our trusted sponsorship
partners, please go to dr.com. And I'll
see you next time.
[Music]