Today on Oz, think fast. Someone
collapses. Oh my god. You have seconds
to act. It's cardiac arrest. I wouldn't
have a clue what to do. What you do next
could save a life. Plus, caught on
camera. Our core worker is a 24/7
snacker. We catch viewers unhealthy
habits in the act.
See the plan to break bad eating habits.
Coming up next on Dr. Oz.
I'd like you to meet Karen. Her
11-year-old daughter Janet suffered a
cardiac arrest one afternoon in August
while at cheerleading
practice. Janet was a typical seemingly
healthy 11-year-old out for an afternoon
of cheerleading practice. But when Janet
went out for a slow jog with the other
cheerleaders, she never came back.
Janet collapsed on the field with a
sudden cardiac arrest. One of her
coaches, a pediatric trauma nurse,
immediately began CPR, but there was no
AED. Even after undergoing 45 minutes of
CPR, Janet died at the hospital less
than an hour after
collapsing. Janet's survival depended
upon a device that you've probably all
seen, but very few of you know how to
use. So Karen, if you can take us back
to that afternoon, what happened? Uh, I
had gone to cheerleading practice with
my daughter Janet, and uh, a couple
minutes later, two girls who were
cheerleaders with her ran up to me and
told me that Janet was laying on the
field and she wasn't moving. We had a
lot of calls go out to 911.
EMS arrived on the scene about 22
minutes later and uh from there we
started to transport her to the
hospital. Paramedics met us uh about 20
minutes after that and they took over
from EMS.
Um we arrived at the hospital close to
45 minutes. She had been in cardiac
arrest already. Uh the paramedics were
able to revive her uh at the hospital.
She went into cardiac arrest again and
she couldn't be saved. I'm so sorry. I
know this is difficult to talk about.
Thank you. I asked you to go through
that story as painful as is to retell
because I'm curious what we could have
done differently because what happened
to your daughter is not uncommon.
Everyone, this is called an AED device.
You've probably seen it. It's in
hallways and public areas all over this
country. It checks the heart's rhythm
and then it can send an electrical shock
to restart it. Did anyone have any idea
that this AED device could have helped
her? Did anyone know her heart had
stopped beating? Uh, the pediatric
trauma nurse knew. Um, she knew her
heart had stopped beating and she had um
already started CPR. I myself when I
came upon the scene, it was just I was
horrified and um I did not know um that
we needed an AD. And it wasn't until uh
after everything had happened that my
husband and I started researching like
how could this have ended differently
and uh and AED is a critical part to the
chain of survival when someone is in
cardiac arrest. Do you believe if this
AED device had been available for you,
your daughter would be alive now? My
husband and I um feel that had we had
one, she could very well be here with us
today. Thank you for sharing your story.
Thank you. Appreciate it. So 70% of
Americans feel helpless to act when
someone is having a cardiac emergency.
That's twothirds of us. That back
worries me. So I conducted a social
experiment to find out if the chance to
save a life from cardiac arrest comes
up. Will you be prepared?
I wouldn't have a clue what to do with
the AED. I'm not even sure what AED
stands for.
[Music]
We wanted to try our experiment on the
Dr. for Oz audience because no one is
better informed about health. But could
they pass this life and death test? Mom,
I don't take any available in the first
few rows. Okay. What our audience
doesn't know. Earlier that day, we
installed an AED on a fake wall in our
audience holding area. Then we rigged
hidden
cameras. To make this as real as
possible, we hired an experienced actor
to reenact sudden cardiac arrest.
Then we brought in an expert from the
American Red Cross, Lika Shaw, to play
the role of a helpful bystander. Our
audience has no idea what's about to
happen.
Oh my god. Oh, are you Andrew? Hello.
Uh, I don't think he's breathing. Fool's
people were terrified and sat
motionless. Can you get me an AED,
please? Just get me an an AED. An AED.
Give me an AD. How long was an AED? What
is AED?
Um, what is I took a class once. Are you
Oh, can you But fortunately, Shannon
knew what to do.
Seven. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Put up
here. As it turns out, Shannon was
trained to work in AED for her job.
I am a nurse anesthetist uh in
Baltimore, so I'm very familiar with
AEDs. Shannon knew what to do, but 99%
of the audience didn't. This is actually
okay. This is an actor. This is someone
from the American and you did a great
job.
I was just like, what am I supposed to
do? I panicked. I didn't know what to
do. She kept asking for an AED. I had no
idea what it was. Never heard of it.
Then we ran the experiment again with a
new audience.
Oh my god. Oh my god. Someone get an
AED, please. Please not. I don't. Again,
most were frozen in their tracks, but
not this woman. Turns out she's a nurse
and even trains people on CPR and AEDs.
Everyone needs to be trained because you
never know what's going to happen. Can
you grab the AED? In her next run
through, Camille didn't know how to work
an AED, but that didn't stop her. She
still helped by fetching the
defibrillator and bravely assisting. I
didn't know what to do, so I just
grabbed it and listened to what she was
saying. Kim told us her heart was
pounding, but you'd never know it. She
remained calm throughout. Oh, definitely
going to look into how to use an AED now
after this. Definitely.
[Applause]
Well, we say I have the smartest
audience in television. Camille is
joining us. When the actor fell on the
floor and you thought he was dying from
a heart problem, what was your first
reaction? Oh my gosh, I was so scared
and so nervous. I didn't know what to
do. But I heard someone yell, "Get an
AED. I just turned around, saw one on
the wall, grabbed it, and went over
there. I didn't even think." Do you have
any idea what this device does? No, I
know it's good, and you need to, you
know, need to have and know what to do
with it. You heard Karen's story about
losing her daughter. Yes. 80% more than
80% frankly of the time we drop dead in
front of the people who love us the
most, right? We die at home, folks. We
die with our pe friends in the cars. So
we can save each other's lives. 5% of
the time we actually do save their life.
There are hundreds of thousands of
lives. We can save this year if we pay
attention just for the next few minutes.
Yes. Can all do that together? Yes. All
right. Leica Sha is joining us from the
American Red Cross. Beacon, what is it
that is hurting us? Why isn't America
responding when we see folks dropping
down? It been loved ones. And clearly
they haven't taken my class. No, they
haven't. Um, I think that AEDs are a
medical device. It's got this big old
lightning bolt symbol on it. Maybe it's
a little intimidating. It may be a
little scary if you've never taken a
class. You don't really know what to do
beyond what you've seen on TV. Let's
demystify it. What do these devices do?
The purpose of an AED is to analyze a
victim's heart rhythm, and if it finds
something wrong with it, it prompts you
to deliver an electrical shock to the
heart. That shock interrupts the heart
rhythm and allows it to reset itself
back to normal, which is a pretty great
thing if someone's in cardiac arrest.
Now, remember, minutes are critically
important here. You dramatically change
the outcome just by acting a minute or
two earlier. So, there are three things
you got to do, Brett, when you see
someone go down right away. First and
foremost, call 911. If you can have
somebody else do it, even better.
Second, if your victim's unconscious and
not breathing, start CPR. It's the best
thing that we can do. You can take a
class to learn how to do it. And third,
as soon as it becomes available to you,
you use that AED because when in
combination with CPR, it does so much to
help victims in cardiac arrest. Wow.
Camille, you want to learn how to use an
AED? Yes, I do. Maybe you can take it
away. Come on over. I've got a little
friend down here. You're going to sit
right over there and I'll sit down right
next to you. Okay. Okay. The brilliant
thing about AEDs is they're super easy
to use because once you turn it on, it
tells you what to do. Okay. So, why
don't we turn on this AED here. Go ahead
and hit that on
button and let's see what it tells us.
Apply pads to patients bare chest. Okay.
Okay. Plug in pads connector next to
flashing light. Beautiful. So, we have
two steps. You're going to bear the
chest. Beautiful. And then wipe it down.
We want to make sure it's dry. It'll
keep repeating itself until we do
something.
You're going to apply these pads.
They've got pictures. So, one pad goes
up here, upper right side of the chest.
Beautiful. Yep. And that one goes down
there. Exactly. Well done, Camille.
Beautiful. If it's a child or an infant
that we're helping, you can actually
still use the pads. They might touch
those. So, one goes in the front and the
other goes in the back between the
shoulder blades. Super easy. Okay,
great. So, pads are on. Now, we're going
to plug in this connector. Love it.
Isn't that unbelievable how
straightforward that is? Analyzing heart
rhythm. Remember, it won't shock. Do not
touch the patient unless there's a
problem. Right. So, the problem wants
you off and it's going to shock the the
heart back. Shock advised. Okay.
Charging.
Stay clear of patient. So, we're going
to stay clear. Everybody else is too.
Deliver shock now. Press the orange
button now. Shock delivered. And that's
it. Paused. Wow. That's how you save
lives.
So, where can folks get trained to do
this other than watching the show? I
think that it's super important to take
a class. We offer classes all over the
country through the Red Cross. Visit our
website, redcross.org. Type in your zip
code, find a class near you. The more
training you have, the more confidence
you have. You build that muscle memory
and then the more lives we can save.
Let's do this together. For more
details, the Red Cross training programs
and to receive a 20% off discount so you
can save even more lives, go to dr.com.
I'll be right back.
[Applause]
Next. Confused by all the anti-aging
products on the market, all promising to
tone, tighten, and rejuvenate your skin,
we're cutting through the clutter and
putting some of the most talked about
products to the test, unveiling the best
anti-aging secrets of the year. Next,
Real Housewife Claudia Jordan gets real.
The embarrassing condition she's lived
with for years. Celebrity toes on a
jack. You've become the corn queen. I've
got a little home remedy for you that
could help you out. All new odds. That's
coming up on
[Music]
[Applause]
Monday. There are so many anti-aging
products in the market that promise to
tone, tighten, and rejuvenate. How do
you know which one is best? Today, I've
got some of the best new anti-aging
products, and I've asked you, the Dr.
Ash Show audience, led by Tanisha Thomas
from TV's Bad Girls Club, to test them
out. So, what do you look for when
you're trying to find the best
anti-aging product? Well, I know that um
SPF is important. Also, price because
honey, I'm not trying to break the piggy
bank. So, there's so many to choose
from. So, uh definitely SPF and
hydration. Yeah. And I might got to ask
cuz I know you do some crazy things out
there. What's the weirdest thing you've
done to get beautiful, to look a little
younger? Oh my gosh. Well, definitely
cross state lines for a weave, honey.
Yes, it's worth it. Oh, it's definitely
worth it. That's right. Hello, hair
popping. Hey, it is popping. Thank you.
All right, so we're going to get to
that. My team and I have been searching
for the best new anti-aging products and
we saw these. They are popping up
everywhere. Actress Mindy Kaling and
supermodel Heidi Clume have recently
posted these pictures on Instagram. I
actually tried it this morning myself.
You'll notice me there getting my
psyched up look. There I am. See how
comfortable I look? I look like
Jason. Maybe Hannibal Lecter.
But you guys are doing it yourselves. I
got to ask, do you do you feel a little
ridiculous doing this? Um, a little bit,
but it feels really nice. Describe it.
Um, it feels really cold and wet, but
really smooth. Cold in a good way. Yes.
What do you think? It feels soothing. Is
it worth it? Yes. Not sure yet, though.
Are you? Well, hopefully it'll be more
worth it. What do you think? Very
soothing. Very soothing. Is soothing the
best word that describes us, everybody?
Soothing. Who doesn't like it? Oh, maybe
one person.
Um, I think it's a little too close to
my eyes. And then move it
up. It's It's on your eyes. It's not too
close to your eyes. It's on your eyes.
There. Now, how's it now?
Gosh. Think about it. You're supposed to
be able to see through it. All right.
Kisha, have you tried this as well? I
have. I have tried it. Yes. And I love
it. You do? I mean, except, you know,
despite the fact I look like a Michael
Myers. I mean, honey, my face felt just
soft, hydrated. It was just it was
amazing. I could instantly feel a
difference. All right, so explain why
these sheet masks are one of the best
anti-aging products of the year. Here's
dermatologist Dr. Dorsay.
Sheet masks. These are one-time use and
mess-free, and they come with different
ingredients based on your particular
skin complaint. But the key point is
that they're made of biocelulose
material that recreates the natural skin
barrier and helps hydrate the skin and
lock in that moisture. You can do it at
home two to three times a week or
anytime you need a healthy glow. So, can
you see through it now? Yes. Better?
Much better. Yeah. How about you with
the glasses on? It's also okay. It's
soothing. That's a word. Now, how can
you get yours on with the glasses and
your friend back there couldn't do it? I
do everything with my glasses. I've been
wearing them since first grade. Well,
you look wonderful now. It's a great new
look. All right, so the mask is supposed
to stay on 15 to 20 minutes. We're going
to have everyone take them off at the
end of the segment for a full honest
reaction and hopefully you can all see
yourselves then at that point. All
right, the next new anti-aging product
comes from my beauty director at the
Good Life magazine, newest issue has
this Myeller water. This is a European
trend, very popular, just come to
America. It's basically makeup remover,
but it's soap free, alcohol free, and
it's a cleanser. So, you don't have to
scrub or rinse and it's meant to leave
the skin very soft and nourished and
hydrated. You know, I check all these
things out myself. I'm the beauty tester
and I like the way it feels on my skin.
But I actually wanted to hear about your
experience cuz you sent us a little
footage using my water. I did. So, walk
us through this. Well, you know, I wear
a ton of makeup for, you know, for
television and it was really, really
great because I love the fact that I
didn't have to wash it off and as you
see, I'm really enjoying myself there. I
mean, you know, the fact that just with
one swipe, it was so gentle on the skin.
Yeah. And I like the fact you don't have
to take it off at the end of the day,
right? Which is a huge event. Okay. We
got Lauren, Renee, and Mandy here from
the audience. They are bravely removing
their makeup with my water. So ladies,
what do you think? I think that is has a
good feel to it. It allows you
opportunity to take all of it off. And
look how much it took off in just a
little bit. I didn't have to use a lot
of product at all. So show the camera.
That is a lot. That's a lot. Yes. And it
was a clean feeling. My face feels
refreshed. And I feel like I'm glowing.
It's nice and smooth. Yeah. And it feels
like it's like this u nice water feel.
It's not a heavy chemical thick goopy
stuff. And it it does work. I sense that
too. My face usually feels a little
slippery afterwards. Like I have to wash
it again after I've taken off stuff. But
this doesn't have that feeling. I like
that it's not greasy. It's very light.
Very light. We have happy customers. I
think I think so, too. Get in there.
Come
on. Yeah. Get that soft tea going, girl.
I want to thank the beauty editors of
the good life for that tip. All right.
The final anti-aging product comes from
my daughter Daphne. She just tweeted
this. She said, "New skin saver find for
you. Anything with amla in it. It's
loaded with vitamin C. Amazingly gentle
and exfoliation that gets her the daily
glow that she wants." Let me explain
what amla is. You all know what this is.
It comes from Indian gooseberry. It does
have a lot of vitamin C and that content
helps form collagen which is good for
the skin. It helps smooth out the fine
wrinkles and the lines. That they
actually bought a product from a store.
It's a cleanser. They have amla but you
don't have to get that. You can actually
just buy the juice itself in a pure form
and you just apply it with a cotton pad
like this um after cleansing and or you
can get amla oil and this this is
actually frequently used Indian secret
for thick soft healthy hair. So Daphne
tried the amla oil on her face. Why
don't you walk us through because we
actually had a experiment done on
Tanisha's hair. The ama oil. Yes, I did.
I actually used it um before washing um
and then after washing. I loved it so
much. I used it as a treatment because I
have very dry scalp. You know, this
weather has not been kind, honey. Uh
okay. Looks good. Yes, it looks good,
right? Soft and just got rid of the
dryness in I'm in love with this. Would
you cross state lines for that? I would
cross a country. The definitive
endorsement. I will cross a country for
that one. Yes. Let's go back over here.
I want to check out our We got our our
mask audience here. What do you guys
think so far? Are you going to take it
off this robe? Take them all off
again. I want an honest opinion here.
What do you think? It's very refreshing.
I feel very clean. Good. Generally,
thumbs it up. Thumbs up. Yeah. Everyone
happy? Everyone can see. Can you Can you
see now? Yes. Happy customers. Thank you
very much. I want to thank all the
guests that all the experts today. We'll
be right back.
[Music]
What's your favorite at home anti-aging
tip? I dab a little bit of olive oil on
the sides of my eyes and my forehead
before bed each night. It's completely
natural and is a fantastic way to
moisturize. Plus, it smells great. Share
yours on
facebook.com/dr. Next. Are you a snack
food junkie? Vending machines by day,
refrigerator raids by night. We're
setting up a health stick to catch
unsuspecting snackers on tape and bust
them on our shelf. The plan for anyone
who has trouble snacking. Coming up
next. The woman you're about to meet
loves to snack and her co-workers say
she can't stay away from the office
vending machine. So, we set up a sting
to see if we could catch her on camera.
You want to see what happened?
Let's look. Our coworker Nicole is a 247
snacker. If it's not to the vending
machine and get a bag of chips or a
soda, she's snacking on some in
someone's office. We're going to try to
get some shot of her going to the
vending machine and eating it. We know
she wants to get healthy. That's why
we're going undercover so you can see
what we've been talking about. Time for
a health thing. Mission day one, baby.
Let's go.
Oh my god.
[Music]
I heard she's coming upstairs. I'm going
to go put a camera in the kitchen.
[Music]
[Applause]
I
need Oh my
god. Okay. Selfie time. Selfie time.
Selfie time. Ready?
in a second.
We're about to go with Buster. She has
no idea what she's in for. I'm busted.
Busted. Busted. Yeah, we got you. Good.
Been leaving you all week ago on healthy
skinny. Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Hi, Nicole. If you're listening to
this, you've been a victim of my health
state. My loveies. Your friends told me
that you can't help but snack on the
temperament foods around the office. So,
I'd love to invite you to my studio to
talk about the sting. I'll see you here.
What?
What's Nicole is here along with her
co-workers Janice, Andre, and Kenya. Oh,
Nicole. Poor Nicole. Uh, no. Can we
switch seats? No. You want a second? So,
were you surprised your friends turned
their cell phones on you? Very, very
surprised. Yeah, I'm I'm plotting
revenge right now. You are? Yes, I am.
How hard was it to set up the sting? It
was actually pretty easy cuz she wears a
lot of bracelets. So, when she's walking
down the hall, we can hear them. So, we
were like, "Go get the camera. She's
going. She's going."
And now, this Kenya was behind the
cameras helping plat out this whole
thing. And now, I heard the call got a
little revenge on you. What did you do?
Yeah. Um, we stepped out the office for
a second. We returned. Uh, Janice had to
search for her chair. Hm. Uh, once she
found it, I got to my office and candy
was all over my desk. I can't believe
she would do that. And then Janice tried
to call me. So I go to reach for the
phone and I'm like, "Where's my
receiver? Don't have a receiver.
Couldn't put it on speaker." Yeah. Where
was the video camera now?
Yeah. See what a good sport you are.
What gives you the urge to go up and
snack like you do? Well, you know, in
the afternoon I just need a little
pickme up to get me through the rest of
the day. So, a little Jolly Ranchu, a
little Pepsi, and I'm good. You're good.
Yeah. But does it last you through the
rest of the afternoon? Yep. Just Just
the perfect touch. Just the perfect
touch. We're going to see what we can do
about that. Before that, Nicole, you
weren't the only one to get set up with
a hell sting today. There's someone else
who has no idea. There's a man in this
audience, a man who set up a sting on
his wife. Now, how dangerous is that?
She's here and she has no idea until
right now. Take a look. Dr. Oz, I need
your help. My wife is snacking
constantly. She wakes up in the middle
of the night almost every night. Comes
down and raids the pantry. She eats the
kids snacks for school. The next morning
I wake up, it's like a small crime scene
around here. I'm going to set a video
up. I'm going to send it to you. I need
you, Dr. Oz. I think it's time for a
house thing.
I woke up before her and she's still
sleeping. And this is what uh what she'd
had last
night. Her
cookies and
chocolates. And there she was
sleeping. She's in the bathroom. She
doesn't know I'm here. This is
everything she's been eating.
[Music]
That's the That's new candy
wrappers. Aaron just made popcorn and
sat down on the couch
downstairs. That's
her. There's Aaron at 3:30 in the
morning eating popcorn and chocolates
and watching TV by
herself. We caught her red-handed.
Very very clever. Erin,
are those tears of joy? I I I'm shocked.
I am so shocked. I Any idea he could set
this up at all? No, I had no idea. We
We've been together for ever. So, I had
no idea he could set this up. I thought
this was my idea cuz I wanted to meet
you and be it was energetic couple. So,
I was like, "Woo, yay." But yeah. Oh,
now we got to meet now. It's nice to
meet you. Oh, nice to meet you. Thank
you. You think you could throw in the
dog house now, Erin? No. No. I I
actually I watch your show and I I want
to be healthy and my brother's getting
married in October and I've been trying
to do everything, but I at night I have
no willpower. I I sleepy, sleepy,
sleepy. So, what goes on specific? I see
that I just I love the shot looking over
the banister at three in the morning at
the TV set. And what is going on when
you start to get those those urges?
Well, I'll do Oh, I'm sorry. I do great
all day and eat healthy, try to do the
diet I'm supposed to do, but then I get
the I'm watching TV and I get the u the
cravings. Uh right now it's Easter, so
there's those peanut butter.
And then I I my willpower just just
leaves. So if you can help me with that,
that would be great. I I am going to
help you. That's what today's about. But
I got to go to Joe. Joe, tell the mic.
Why would you do this to the wife uh and
that who loves you so much and what
makes you brave enough to risk
everything? Well, it's it's a funny
thing, Doc. Uh you know, we've been
together 19 years and married for 16 and
she's always been the uh the midnight
pantry bandit and uh you know, the kids
are getting a little older now and Aaron
likes to not take the blame for some of
the stuff missing. So, there's been a
little bit of chaos in the house with me
and the kids over snacks in the morning
missing. And uh finally, you know, I
woke up a couple times and caught her,
but she denies it and you know, she gets
away with it with her little smile and
and and I buy it. But it this has been a
long time coming. Well, you have a
beautiful smile. You very good taste of
women and wonderful camera work. All
right. When we come back, how to break
the habit for anyone who has trouble
with stacking like Aaron here at any
time of day. Stay here. Thank you.
[Applause]
Coming up next. Do you eat when you're
bored, sad, stressed, or anxious? Want
to get healthy but can't stop the
snacking? Help is on the way with
healthy swaps for all your favorite
snacks. The plan to get you past
mindless and emotional eating. Coming
up. Real housewife Claudia Jordan gets
real. The embarrassing condition she's
lived with for years. Celebrity toes on
a jack. You've become the corn queen.
I've got a little home remedy for you
that could help you out. All new odds.
That's coming up on Monday.
Busted. Busted. Busted. Yeah. What?
There's Aaron at 3:30 in the morning and
popcorn and
chocolates watching TV by
herself. We caught her
red-handed. So, I'm here with Nicole and
Aaron and their friends and family
members who actually helped me catch
them in a Dr. Oz health sting. I love
doing these. Oh, question of the entire
group. How many of you only snack
because you're hungry? When you're
hungry? Hands up. Oh, please. Aaron,
come on. 3 in the morning. No one's
hungry. Nicole, you think you're only
doing it when you're hungry? Yeah. Yeah,
maybe. Maybe. We'll think about it. I
love you. All right, bigger question.
How many of you snack because you're
bored or anxious, stressed? Oh, I put my
hands up, too, right? That's a big deal
for all of us. Okay, so the question is,
how do we help you get past this
mindless and emotional eating? and I've
enlisted psychologist Dr. Romani
Dvasula.
Here are some tips to help you avoid
mindless
eating. First, instead of reaching for a
snack, try reaching for a warm drink
like warm tea or warm water. That's
because warm liquids soothe us. And we
often snack to soothe. Second, replace
the snacking with other activities that
you enjoy. things like reading, watching
TV, or talking on the phone with a
friend. And finally, remember the word
halt. Stop and think whether you're
snacking because you're actually hungry,
or if you're angry, lonely, or tired.
Only snack if you're hungry. Don't snack
to manage these other emotions. It's
better to work on other skills and other
ways of coping with difficult emotions.
Great advice. And Nicole was stung by
her co-workers for being unable to avoid
the office vending machine and that
candy bowl, the dreaded candy bowl. But
sometimes it's not just mindless eating.
Sometimes you just want a snack. And
actually, you were pretty honest about
this. Sometimes you just want that
little pickme up. So here's the deal. If
your co-workers have tricked you, they
actually want you to control your
snacking a little bit. So we have a plan
for you. Is that true? Kenya, you want
to take it away? We want you to embrace
embrace the snack size baggie. Why is
that, Kenya? Because it's portion
control. Just enough to get you through
your little break.
Doesn't this sound like a big deal? This
is actually my bag. It's perfect. I fill
this up in the morning. I happen to like
cashews. They're just what I need when I
need that afternoon pickme up, which is
what I do. I have this little bag. I
can't put too much in here. I pretty
much fill it as much as I can. And then
in the afternoon, I take it. Now, I put
a bunch of things up there. You could
have carrots and celery and popcorn and
nuts and other kinds of nuts, frankly.
Even chips, maybe things that aren't
ideal. Veggie chips, of course. Which of
those would you pick to put in your
half-sized baggie if you had the choice?
H not too excited. I can
tell. Don't hold back now. I want to see
the enthusiasm dripping from your pores.
Is that popcorn? Is that popcorn? Yes.
Okay. Popcorn. Popcorn is the best we
can do, huh? You don't seem too excited
about this tip. Although, Ken, you
worked on it all week. I try. I have a
health corner. You know what? I get it.
You want a decadent snack, don't you?
Yeah. You want something real? Yes. That
you're going to crave. And so, my Forget
this idea. It's a bad idea. All right. I
like it, but some of you may go, "Joe,
you like my idea?" I absolutely like
your idea. Joe, you have poor judgment.
Look what you did to Aaron. So, here's
the thing. Chef and self-proclaimed
snacker Candace Kamay is joining us with
healthy swaps for all of your favorite
snacks. These things will taste good.
You will like them. Okay. So, what are
your favorite things to snack on before
we talk about your healthy stuff, right?
Believe it or not, I am a total snacker.
I loved eating pita chips and bagel
chips and then I found out I may as well
be eating potato chips at the same time.
So now I snack on things like avocados,
raw nuts, popcorn, and I absolutely love
kind of changing it up to make things
more enticing at home and that's kind of
where the chef role comes into play. But
I know that you guys want something a
bit tastier. So chemist has created
swaps for the most common unhealthy
snacks. So what are they? I'll put them
in a list for you. They are the candies,
the chips, the cookies, the sodas, the
ice creams, all those bad things that
you I know you all want. I see you
nodding your heads up and down. We have
options for you. Take it away. By the
way, the entire audience, we're giving
you samples of these snacks cuz I'm
going ask you to vote on the ones that
you would actually crave so much you
replace that junk food with these
Candice approved snacks. Take it away.
Right. So, cookies. We all know we like
sweets and candies. So, I created a
cinnamon coconut popcorn for you. These
are ingredients you already have at
home. It's simple to make and cinnamon
actually just a little sprinkle on top.
You can actually use some coconut oil
spray. It's really simple, light, and
filling. Yeah. And you keep going. But
what does that replace? That's for this
replaces the candy and the cookies. Yes.
Cuz we all know we love sweets and we
want something to crave, you know, with
our sweet tooth. So these are rosemary,
garlic, almonds. So if you love chips
and you like salt, cuz a lot of us do,
these are actually a great alternative.
You can roast them at home in your oven.
You're going to get nutrients and you're
going to really feel good about what
you're snacking on. Then we have frozen
berries and grapes. Okay, so a lot of us
like to get, you know, frozen yogurt,
dessert, and ice cream at night. So, I'm
also to blame on this. Go to the
freezer. You reach in there and you just
get the half pint. Instead, put all of
these frozen berries and grapes into a
bag and then you can reach in and grab a
handful at night and they're so cold and
delicious and they kind of melt in your
mouth. It feels like you're eating ice
cream, but you're actually getting
something that's good for you. All
right. And finally, water, which we, you
know, I think is an option, but people
find it very bland. Instead of soda pop,
what do you offer? Absolutely. Infused
waters are kind of all over the place
right now. are very trendy and I'm sure
you've seen mason jars all over the
place. So you just add your favorites
like mint and cucumbers here. You can
add some honeydew melon as well or in
this case we have rosemary infused with
some berries. So you're going to get a
rosemary berry feel. These are really
great with coconut, pineapple, whatever
you like. Infuse, take it to work and
you can really hydrate and stay full at
work too. So we're going to take this
steak and we're going to learn from it.
Now I want you to take these ideas.
There are four of them. They're laid in
front of you that are savory, wonderful,
sometimes sweet treats. audience. You
all have them in front of you. You have
those little voting devices. You go
ahead and vote. In the meantime, I want
to ask Aaron which of these you think
you might like. I like them all. You
like them all. Especially in the middle
of the night, right? But I really like
the frozen fruit. That was because
almost replaces the ice cream. The
coldness I like. So I I like the fruit.
And Nicole, how about you? I like the
popcorn. Great. All right. The nuts
and the frozen fruit.
Now, now I see a smile on your face.
There's a smile over there. That's
amazing. I I unlike what happened
earlier when you couldn't pick the
celery or the carrots, which is your
favorite. Okay, here's the deal. You're
going to vote. A is cinnamon, coconut,
popcorn. B is garlic, rosemary, almonds.
C is frozen grapes and berries. D is
infused water. Log them in there, guys.
Vote which oneever you want. Again,
these things are fantastically tasty for
you. And the winner is Oh, frozen grapes
and berries won by a large margin. I
would have gone with the rosemary nuts.
I thought so too, actually. You guys
could probably enjoy all of them,
couldn't you? So, thank you all for
being part of this. Candace, thanks for
making these wonderful snacks. You can
find these recipes, all the other snack
ideas we got at dr.com. I want to thank
all my guests. It means good sports. I
love you all. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up, are you constantly dreading
dinner time? Has cooking become more of
a job? Celebrity chef Curtis Stone is
here to teach you how to make your
supper super again. Simple ways to make
cooking a joy and a chore no more. Next,
whoever said a doctor's visit isn't fun
has obviously never been to the Dr. Oz
show. Is that right? Make your
appointment today. Go to
dr.com/tick and sign up for free
tickets.
I want you all to live a good life. I
mean, after all, I named a magazine for
that reason, the good life. But let's
face it, a good life is filled with
good, healthy food. And a lot of you say
cooking has become more of a chore than
a joy. Sorry is in that group. Why is it
you dread dinner time? I get so
overwhelmed by the cooking experience in
general, just making sure I have the
right ingredients, the right utensils,
measuring out all the spices and getting
the flavor right. And then after work,
coming home and cooking, and then
cleaning after that, it just I get
anxiety just from the thought of cooking
alone. It's just another it feels like a
chore. Like a chore like homework. Yes.
We're lucky day because I invited
someone to join us. He's brought some
simple ways to get the joy back in your
cooking. He's the author of Good Food,
Good Life, celebrity chef Curtis Stone,
[Applause]
[Music]
welcome. This show segment is all yours.
Take it away. I want you to go when
we're done. I want you to help us all
appreciate how we make it a joy, not a
chore to make our meals. Now, Sar, I
think good food and good life are so
interconnected. And I'm going to give
you a few little tips that make it super
easy. Okay. The first one, I'm going to
show you how to do a Baja chicken salad.
Right now, over here, you think to
yourself, well, that's not enough to
make a salad. And that's cuz I did a
little bit of preparation ahead of time.
So, that's the first secret. Just get a
little bit organized. So, Doc, if you
don't mind having a quick look in the
fridge, I've got some carrots and some
radishes and some cabbage that I've
already sliced up. So, all of that stuff
comes together to um to quickly uh
That's it. Beautiful. Beautiful.
Beautiful. And we just toss that
straight on in here. Should I open that
up a bit on my Sure. I've made a quick
dressing which is really simple. It's
made from cilantro, a little bit of oil,
a little bit of vinegar. Toss it in. So,
you know, I I cut some of this stuff on
a Japanese mandolin. So, you can just
literally stand there and slice away,
right? So, it's really quick and simple.
Grab a couple forks. Don't be shy. Go
on. Use your hands. Use your hands.
Um, that's a good thing about having a
doctor in the kitchen. We know that
you've got nice clean hands.
Um, and then the avocados, which I've
kept to put on last because they're a
little bit softer, of course. Some of
those uh pumpkin seeds, you can go ahead
and throw a little bit of that feta in
and then drizzle drizzle your uh
dressing over. So, in literally 60
seconds or so, you can put together a
beautiful, healthy salad. So, yes,
there's a few minutes of chopping
earlier in the day. A little bit more.
But put a little bit more. So stingy
with that dressing. Don't be making sure
it's not too fat. Good girl. And then a
few corn chips. And look at this. Like
you know, I know that corn chips uh have
a little bit more fat in them. So I've
just got literally four or five corn
chips and you'll get that little bit of
crunch that you're looking for without
all the calories and fat. So that's tip
number one. Let me taste it.
I want to taste the chicken. Get in
there. Get in here. It's good. Yeah.
While I'm eating. So good. Part of the
issue sorry has and so many of you
viewers write about is the amount of
time it takes and the mess that that you
make me do it. So deal with the cleanup
as well. Mhm. So the cleanup is a
nightmare for all of us. Don't worry. I
have to clean up at my house too and I I
don't like it either. So the one pot
cooking thing I think is a is going to
be your best friend. Definitely. So you
think of a casserole or a stew that all
happens in one pot. But I thought I'd
show you something a little different.
I've got a big filt of salmon here and
I've roasted it on one tray. So it's one
tray cooking. Thinly sliced the beets
and I've just put that around with a
little oil. And then the salmon I've put
an herb crust on it and again a really
simple dressing or vinegarette that you
can just go ahead and spoon over the top
there. And you've got all the flavors in
the same pan which is really really
delicious. You literally have no dishes
then. You throw this the aluminum foil
away and you're done. That's right.
That's it. It's so simple. So get a fork
and dive in there. and tell me what you
think. I want to taste one of these
things. Mhm. Look how how long you cook
it for. So, the the salmon's only in the
in the oven for about 12 15 minutes,
depending on how thick the fililet of
salmon is. But it's a beautiful big
piece. It's, you know, if you're cooking
for a family of four or so, it's it's
really easy. It's delicious. Would the
family like, there's a bigger I love the
beets. Oh, yeah. My son, I think, would
love the beets and they're healthy
because I'm always trying to figure out
what's something for him to eat that's
healthy. Surprise your family with this.
If this is 12 minutes of work, this is a
good investment of time. Yeah,
definitely. Right. You know what? Take
this home for the kids tonight. Tell me
you made it for them on the way home.
They'll be so impressed. We'll wrap it
up for you. What do you think? I'm going
to be impressed. Absolutely. You got it.
I hope it's make everyone's chores a
little less painful. You can find all
these recipes on dr.com. First, I want
to thank you very much. Show us how to
put the joy back in the day in a very
fast, efficient way with no dishes.
Everybody in the audience, you're all
going home. We're talking Curtis's new
book, Good Food, Good Life. Plus, you
can watch Curtis on the Food Network's
new show, Allstar Academy, Sundays at
9:00 p.m. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
What's your favorite Oz approved fish
recipe? I absolutely love this recipe
for white fish tacos from dr.com. My
kids really enjoy the flavor. It's easy
to make, and best of all, it's healthy.
For this recipe and more, visit
draz.com.
All new Oz. Is there a problem with
pain? Real housewife Claudia Jordan gets
real. The embarrassing condition she's
lived with for years. Celebrity toes
that are jacked up. You become the corn
queen. I've got a little home remedy for
you that could help you out. Plus, a
reality star checks into rehab. A late
night host's painful surgery. And the
fashion duo under fire for their IVF
baby comments. The biggest health
headlines straight out of Hollywood.
We've got the inside scoop. That's
coming up on Monday on Dr.
[Music]
[Applause]
Oz. Remember, I always disagreeing over
the color of that dress. You know, was
it white and gold or was it blue and
black? You all remember that. Well, it's
too bad butterflies can't talk because
they would have added a few more colors
to the debate. See, eyes see colors
thanks called cones. And humans have
three types of cones. We can see green,
blue, and red. And you combine these
colors. you remember from art class when
you were a kid. Butterflies, well, they
have five types of cones. They have the
green, blue, and red, too. And then
there are two more mystery colors that
our brains can't even process. Plus, I'm
not a butterfly, so I can't imagine it.
But imagine that much more complex a
world. So, they can see all kinds of
beautiful things. The audience, when it
comes to color and color vision in
particular, can you guess what animal
that takes the prize? What do you think?
You'd never guess this one. It's called
the mantis shrimp. It's the butterfly of
the sea. He's got not three, not five,
16 color cones. So, they can see all
kinds of wacky things. Imagine what can
be seen with that much. Well, that's
maybe perhaps how beautiful he can see.
It reflects how beautiful he actually
is. Now, it's time for in case you
missed it. First, if you ever have the
chance to save a life from a cardiac
arrest, I want you to be ready for it
because odds are it's going to be
someone that you know, someone that you
love. For every minute that passes
without someone starting CPR, the chance
of surviving by cardiac arrest goes down
10%. So, when minutes are all you have,
there are three things you got to do.
You're going to call 911. You all know
that. Get people to come help you. Begin
CPR. The chest compressions. Super easy
to do. Then use an AED. Looks like this.
You're going to see them all over the
place now. And if you don't know how to
do CPR or use an AED, all you got to do
is learn, which is super simple because
you're going to save the life of someone
you know. Now, there are Red Cross
training classes all over the country.
For more details on those training
programs and to receive a 20% off
discount to do them, go to dr.com.
Frankly, folks, it's just a matter of
putting two pads in the chest and
getting away. The thing is automatic and
it's safe. Finally, please be careful of
dubious people online make it seem like
I'm endorsing their products because I
don't. To see a full list of our trusted
sponsorship partners, you go to dr.com.
And I will see you next time.
[Music]
[Applause]