The cauliflower craze continues, but are
the pre-made alternatives all a
cauliflower con? It's not just
cauliflower that you're getting. And
Wednesday, ready for this? It's the dish
on Oz, our brand new food series.
Perfect. Perfect. Daphne Oz and friends
are dishing on the hottest food trends.
I always like to heat things up a little
bit. Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you,
[Music]
Da
Cauliflower. Oh, I love it. Just a few
years ago, it exploded into notoriety as
a low carb craze gained full
steam. Pinterest pages taught us how to
pulverize us into this faux fried rice.
We can make homemade pizza crust. You
can mash it up like potatoes, even turn
it into buffalo wings. And now we've
entered another boom. Cauliflower
convenience. Our supermarket shelves are
bursting with every possible incarnation
of this this cruciferous veggie under
the sun. But are these pre-made
cauliflower products really low carb,
low calorie comfort food, or are you
being conned? Today we investigate. My
go-to nutritionist and author of Think
Yourself Thin, JJ Smith, is in our
cauliflower product testing lab. We
asked the Collie lovers in our audience
to bring in their favorite cauliflower
products and JJ's scientifically
evaluating them right now. And I'm also
joined by America's test kitchens Julia
Colin Davidson who's been following this
cauliflower boom very close. Hello. So,
first of all, why has cauliflower gotten
so popular and how has it shaped what
we're beginning to see in supermarkets?
Yeah, it's a downright craze these days
and it's due to a few reasons. First
off, the recession, which really
encouraged people to step away from
expensive meat-based recipes and really
take another look at vegetable-based
recipes because they're less expensive.
But what really takes cauliflower over
the top compared to all the other
vegetables is that you can throw it into
any recipe. It really just takes on
whatever flavor you give it. It's very
versatile. It's like a a vegetable
chameleon, right? It just adapts to its
environment and that's gotten everyone
on board. Yeah. Yeah. And of course, all
the big brands have taken notice and so
they're really putting out some really
interesting and creative new cauliflower
based products. So, we're going to
evaluate those today. We're going to
start with cauliflower pizza. So,
Sheena's backstage with JJ in our
cauliflower product testing lab with her
favorite pizza crust. So, Sheena, please
describe your first impression of the
product. I mean, it looks good to me.
It's made with real cauliflower,
gluten-free. I would assume that that
would mean it's low carb because
cauliflower is traditionally low carb.
All right, JJ, you took a little deeper
look at this pizza crust and others like
it. Give us a reality check. What did
you find? Okay, so what I did was
compare the cauliflower pizza crust with
a traditional pizza crust. And what I
found was that in a traditional pizza
crust, it's about 125 to 150 calories
per serving and about maybe 23 to 35 net
carbs. Now, cauliflower pizza crust had
a wide range. it was really all over
anywhere from 80 to 170 calories and
then net carbs was anywhere from 2 to
23. So what that means is you're going
to have to really really look at the
nutritional label because it's not
necessarily lower in calories or carbs.
That was hard to find. You know, if you
just show me this, I was surprised to
find that some of these cauliflower
crusts actually have more calories and
carbs than just getting a regular old
pizza crust, which is shocking to me.
Yeah. So I think a lot of folks think
that this is really just cauliflower,
right? Maybe with a binder thrown in
like egg. Yeah, this this looks like
this, right? Mash that up, pulverize it,
get this. Yeah, but the reality is most
uh crusts include a lot more ingredients
than that. Yeah, that's a lot. And so,
first I want to focus on these flowers
and starches like tapioca, cornstarch,
brown rice. They add that allimportant
chew to the pizza crust cuz without
chew, it's not a pizza, right? But this,
of course, boosts all those net carbs.
And then look at the fats. You have egg,
you have olive oils that add richness
and all these flavorings, some of which
are natural, but look at this zanthan
gum. That's a processed food. So, it's
not just cauliflower that you're
getting. So, Sheena, are you a little
surprised by what's in your cauliflower
pizza? Uh, very surprised. I had no idea
it had all that. And Jenny, what else
did you find about the cauliflower crust
that surprised you? Well, this was so
surprising to me. Cauliflower pizza
crust has two to three times more fat.
This is no bueno. No good. All right. So
what where is the fat from? You showed
us some oils over here. That's it. And
so the oils in the eggs do account for
some of the fat, especially for crusts
that have those starches in it, but some
of the crusts consider themselves low
carb. So they swap the starches and the
fat for cheese and a lot of cheese. Oh
my goodness. Yeah. And so, okay, these
are this is low carb, but all this
cheese, it adds flavor. It adds texture,
which is important, but now you've
jacked up the saturated fat. And of
course, at the end of the day, it's
still pizza, right? It's still a treat.
This shouldn't be a daily thing. And
they stuff on top of it also cuz the
cauliflower pizza crusts are easy to
make at home and you can control all the
ingredients that go into it if you do it
that way. Take a look at this video
showing you you how to make one. It's
super simple. I'm also going to put it
on my Facebook
[Music]
page.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
I got hungry watching that video. So
simple. And again, this uses this raw
material. Cauliflower we all
acknowledge. But when we're talking
about pre-made cauliflower foods, the
search continues. Yes, it does. So, what
about cauliflower tots and fries? They
almost seem too good to be true. Yeah.
You know, I tried these. They're pretty
good. They're crisp on the outside.
They've got decent flavor. They're
creamy on the inside. They're not bad.
Yeah. Tastes like potatoes. Yeah. But
let's be real. This isn't these aren't
vegetables. This is a vegetable product,
right? And so, at the end of the day,
how good or bad these are for you really
depends on the product itself. So, you
have to read the label. All right. So
Margie's backstage with JJ in the
cauliflower product testing lab with her
favorite cauliflower tots. So Margie,
what do you like about the tots? It's a
good way definitely to sneak in the
vegetable into my kid that's pretends
she's allergic to vegetables. So, but
whatever works if you're a mom. But
let's get into the nutrition side of
these things. JJ, what did you find?
Well, this is a good news story. I found
that the traditional tater tots are high
in both calories and carbs.
But if you look, you'll see that the
cauliflower t cauliflower tots are a lot
lower. See, they have less calories and
less carbs. However,
however, sometimes there's this hidden
ingredient. It won't always be in bowl,
but it'll be there. And it's a hybrid
where they have cauliflower and the
potato combined. And when you add in
that the potato, now you can see it's
virtually almost as high in calories as
the regular tater tots. So, you're going
to really have to be a detective and
look at these nutritional labels. But
straight up, cauliflower tater tots.
They are good to go. All right. Up next,
it's the new cauliflower past that
everyone is obsessed with. Stick around.
[Music]
[Applause]
We're taking on fakers,
frauds, and foes. I'm burning this. It's
smoking, but there's no melting. and
investigating how one man faked a
disability. Changing his diaper, it's
just gross. For his own twisted
pleasure.
That's coming up
[Applause]
tomorrow. They're selling out
nationwide. Customers fighting over bags
at the grocery stores. That's right.
There's a rush on the latest cauliflower
pasta on the market. Cauliflower noki.
Now today we're revealing the surprising
ingredient that makes these fluffy
comforting pasta pillows so good.
Nutritionist JJ Smith is backstage
manning our cauliflower product test
lab. So what kinds of cauliflower pastas
are you seeing back there JJ? They are
bringing me so many different
cauliflower pasta, cauliflower
spaghetti, cauliflower pin, and my
favorite cauliflower noki. This is this
is my beloved cauliflower noki. Well, I
want to get into this noki issue because
frozen cauliflower noki really has taken
over Instagram. People are dressing it
up like gourmet pastas. Look at those
pictures. Oh, dectable. So, to see how
cauliflower pasta stands up to the real
deal, I decided to bring in my good
friend Pasqual. He hails from Italy,
teaches Americans how to cook pasta the
Italian way on YouTube. But could he
taste the difference between a
cauliflower noki and a potato noki? But
folks love watching you, don't they?
Yeah. They're calling you from the old
country.
Everybody, the people in my sidor in
Italy, everybody said, "Pasqual, we see
you that
her was in Italy working a farm. We was
eat cauliflower in the
morning, 12:00 lunch, had dinner." Yep.
Cauliflower in the morning.
I like it too. I like it too. But here's
the question. This question most people
don't really know what a noki is. We
can't even pronounce it right over here.
So educate folks what's a noki and let's
get into whether you can make a noki
with cauliflower. Does it have to be
potatoal? Flour. It's really good and
with a potato too, but you taste this
with the noki with a cauliflower. Y it's
a good taste. All right. So JJ, while
I'm learning about Noki here, compare it
to the real deal nutritionally. Well, we
just learned that noki has a potato in
it. So you can see that it's higher in
calories and carbs. However, if you look
at cauliflower noki, you'll see that
it's 140 calories, 18 net carbs, a lot
lower than the traditional noki. So,
it's definitely a better option,
but there's always a there's always a
butt. There's always a butt. We did find
that cauliflower noki was two times
that's double the fat, and that is not
ideal. Now, this isn't a deal breaker,
but it is something I wanted everyone to
be aware of. All right, give it a taste
now. See if you're happy with it. Even
with a little extra fat.
Yes, there's been a happy Italian man.
All right, so America's test kitchen
Julia Colin Davidson is back. We looked
at the the ingredients. We're going to
put them up here for cauliflower noki.
And please help us understand about this
extra fat as well. Yeah. So there you
go. So majority of the ingredient is
cauliflower. That's good news. And here
are the rest of the ingredients. You
have some cassava and you have some
potato. Potato is obviously the
traditional ingredient in this classic
dumpling. a little bit of olive oil,
sometimes some egg, and this is where
the fats coming from. So, but if you
look at this on the whole, we know what
these ingredients are. They're very
simples. You know, you can pronounce
them all. They're from real food. So,
I'm a fan of these. I like it, too. And
it tastes good according to Pasal. So,
don't be afraid of the potato. A spot of
the spud is not a bad thing. Cauliflower
noki is a good tool if you're on paleo
because a lot of potatoes. And if you're
on just starting the keto where I know
they don't want potatoes, you got to
skip it for a little while, but after
you get on the program, you can try it
there, too. So, up next, the cauliflower
product that has started it all.
Pre-made cauliflower rice. Or is it just
cauliflower or a
[Music]
[Applause]
conan? Where do we go when we die? We're
unraveling this medical mystery and
examining the last moments of life. All
new Oz. That's coming up Friday.
[Music]
[Applause]
Cauliflower has been conquering nearly
every carb in the market, but the one
that started it all, rice. It has become
so popular that the rice industry itself
feels threatened. Rice lobbying groups
are even asking the FDA to consider
banning the word rice from cauliflower
products. What do you guys think about
that? A big battle going on. So, Julia
Colin Davidson is here from America's
Test Kitchen. What is your take on
cauliflower rice? It's delicious. I love
cauliflower rice. I make it a lot at
home. And the good thing is it's just
cauliflower. There's no other
ingredients hiding or lurking in
cauliflower rice. Easy to make. You just
take a head of cauliflower, you core it,
you cut it into pieces, put it in your
food processor, and you want to, you
know, chop it up, pulse it up until it
has the texture, you know, finely
chopped like rice. And this is the
packaged version. Yeah. So, this takes a
little bit of work. You can buy it
already done. You can see it's very
similar. Yeah. Now, the benefit of doing
it yourself is you get finer bits. The
benefit of buying it is it's no work,
but also these pieces are a bit more
dried out. So, it actually has a more
rice-like texture when you cook it. I
like this, but it's there's nothing
added like some of the other products we
saw. No, it's just cauliflower. All
right. So, everyone associates
cauliflower rice with stir fry, but
there are many new innovative ways to do
it. So, I brought in a few experts, new
ways to cook cauliflower rice beyond
stir fry. Tina's going to start us off.
Sure. I have my uh saffron risoto.
Cauliflower risoto. Thank you. You be
the expert. Oh, nice. Oh, I was hoping
it's uh a family favorite. It's
wonderful. Yeah, it's um I I make it
just like a traditional risoto except I
use the cauliflower rice. I love that
it's low carb. Uh the creamy texture. My
kids love that. Still has that cream.
You buy a pre-made bag. You make it
yourself. I love the pre-made bag. I'm a
busy mom, so I don't always have time to
shred and chop, so the pre-made is
perfect. It tastes just like risotto.
Yeah. Thank you. Delicious. Thank you so
much. Congratulations, Tina. Thank you.
All right. Next up, I want to go visit
Robera who's visiting us from Skype. She
at home in her kitchen where she's
whipping up her favorite recipe using
cauliflower rice. What do you got for
us, Robera?
So, I have some amazing low carb tacos.
You will think of Taco Tuesday
differently, let me tell you. So, what
we're going to do is we're going to
start out with our lettuce cups, right?
Which you can get. You can also use
romaine lettuce. You take your meat,
which is this little guy, which is the
cauliflower, which look at that. It
looks exactly like ground meat. You're
going to top it off with some tomatoes
and avocados. And then you're going to
take a big bite and enjoy it. Oh my
goodness. Before you Before you bite,
would you ever go back to regular rice?
Yes or no? No. She's
in. All in. It's accurate. But what I
love about bag cauliflower rice is
you're starting with clean, pure base.
You can control the ingredients. It's
what we want out of avocado for a
product. And to your point, it's so easy
to mold it into so many recipes because
it can take on whatever flavor you
desire. That's it. Nicely done. As
always, you can check out the America's
Test Kitchen's latest, the new
Essentials Cookbook. We put all the
recipes, by the way, on dr.com. We'll be
right back. Thanks,
Robera. And we're here at my favorite
foodies of the dish. What are we making
guys? We are putting a new spin on a
retro classic, turning the TV dinner
into a new sensation, skillet pot pie.
[Applause]
Today I'm introducing a brand new series
about everyone's favorite obsession,
food. You're talking about it all the
time. And I'm calling it the dish
because we are dishing on everything
from the hottest food trends, breaking
the internet to the coolest new recipes
and hacks that you're going to want to
try tonight. And the best part is is
with my daughter Dafty. So what are we
dishing on today? Ah, good stuff. Today
we've got a new spin on retro recipes
from your childhood. From your
childhood, from all of our childhoods. A
modern twist on chicken pot pie that's
better than any TV dinner you've ever
had. We've got a 10 can chili that will
take you right back. And we are
reinventing fondue with spinach and
artichokes. A little health nod for you.
Now, to do it right, you've got your
foodie friends, Stella Chefs. Who's
here? Okay, ready for this?
We've got TV legend and host of
Valerie's Home Cooking and bestselling
cookbook, author of One Dish at a Time,
Valerie Bernelli. Lot to live up to But
you can do it. I have no doubt. Food
Network star and chef and caterer to the
stars with southern and Caribbean roots,
Jamaica P.
Janet. Janet. And of course, singer,
songwriter, New York Times bestselling
author, and Southern food trends setter
Jesse James.
Welcome, ladies. I'm having the audience
do quality control by taste testing your
food. Yeah. Get you to weigh in, though.
Okay. Hi, guys.
Looks so beautiful.
So, today we're going retro, right?
Taking right back to childhood. So, tell
me first off, what was your favorite
childhood meal? What takes you right
back? Oh, capi emro scoop. Come again.
It was my non capleti ombroso and she
would put them in in h chicken broth and
it was the best chicken soup I've ever
had to this day. Sounds good. Love it.
Good job. Good.
All right. So, my mom was a terrible
cook. Sorry, mom.
What? And you're like a navy. No, she
knows she's a bad cook. She knows. All
of my childhood food memories, it's like
that looks delicious, mom. Maybe that
made you a chef. when she burned the
dinner, then we ordered pizza. So, it
was like pizza family fun night. So,
that's what I remember everybody having
just good pizza and laugh and good time.
I love it.
That's fun. What about you, Jeff? Um,
mine my mama would make she called it
American spaghetti. So, it was very sim.
We didn't have a lot of money growing
up, so it was it was a a can of just
tomato sauce, which it's the way that
she put the love into it, the ground
meat. It was really really good, and it
warms my heart. A Yes. Ours was red
sauce with spaghetti. Also, my
grandfather's from Staten Island, so we
had this family red sauce recipe that
would be on the pot Sundays for like 6
hours just swirling and swirling. You go
in there with that crusty bread. To this
day, the smell of garlic and oil cooking
in the kitchen is like it's the best.
That
feels It is the Italian. So good. I love
it. It's I love it, too. It makes And
it's also It brings everyone in.
Everyone's coming through the kitchen
then. And we've got I'm some from such a
big family. I love that feeling of the
party in the kitchen, which is this.
Yes. Yeah. That's what we do. You ready
for? Well, you guys, I have some some
some treats for you here in front of
you. But this is part of our hot dish,
okay? This is where we break down the
biggest food trends from the from around
Hollywood and the stories blowing up
your newsfeed, making you feel like
you're in the know about the whole world
of food. And since today is the retro
show, we're starting with a tweet from
Valerie. Uhoh. What I do now? She did
this about the new reboot of the movie A
Star Is Born. Yes. And then I realized
as I'm like uh gagaing over Lady Gaga,
I'm like I could be old enough to um be
Lady Gaga's mom. And I'm okay with that,
by the way.
Well, ironically, the movie A Star is
Born with Gaga in it may not have
happened if it wasn't for a bowl of
pasta. Are you ready for this? So, Lady
Gaga was auditioning for this role, you
guys. And Bradley Cooper came over to
her home and was, you know, just
chatting with her, seeing if there was
chemistry. And apparently, she sent him
to the fridge to help himself to some
leftover pasta. And it was so good. He
said it may have actually helped her get
the gig.
The way to a man's tummy. I want to know
because I don't think anyone's actually
figured out what kind of pasta it was. I
agree. I'd love to know. Lady Gaga, if
you are watching, which I know you are.
Please let us know what you made, girl.
Was it a bowl of naysay? Like what was
it? We got to know. I agree. I want to
know. I want to know. Oh, I also want to
know. Is there have there ever been a
dish you've made that has like helped
you get your man to come around to your
side of things? I bet you I bet you know
the way to Eric's heart. Oh, I did. So,
we you know, we we started talking over
the phone. Someone set us up and after,
you know, four weeks of talking. He
invited himself to come meet me in
Nashville. So, I figured I needed a way
to win him over. So, I made him some
jumbolaya. And after that, we had a
bottle of wine. We had some jumbolaya.
And after the weekend, on the way to the
airport, he asked me to be his
girlfriend.
How spicy was that jumbolaya? I mean, I
mean, there's other parts to the story,
but I'm not going to tell you all
everything. Family show. No, not like
that.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I love it. Well,
let's get Eric's side of the story,
don't you think? Okay, let's do let's
get him on FaceTime. Eric, verify that
the Jambalaya got you into it. Oh, wait.
Here we go. All right, we're going to
ask him what he thinks about this.
Y'all, this is crazy. Let's We're
actually going to
FaceTime. I get it. I want to
see. Let's see his face here.
Hey.
[Laughter]
Look where I'm at, babe.
Wow. Beautiful girls. You're all so
young and pretty. Yeah. Yeah. So, I'm
telling him the story about the first
weekend we ever spent together.
What' you tell
the jumbo part only? Wait a minute. Just
the food. Stick to the mood. Eric, you
tell us your side. How'd it go down? Um,
well, as I recall it, she whined and
dined me. She had me stay
over. We had a little little veno. She
cooked me
jumbolaya. She had her apron on in the
kitchen. I can remember it vividly. And
um, being a northern boy, she sealed my
heart with some Cajun food.
That's how you do it. Yes.
I love it. Are the babies good? They're
just waking up, so it's a little chaotic
right now. Okay. I don't know. I love
you, baby. Thank you. So cute. Oh my
gosh. Sweetheart. For those of you who
don't know, Jesse's married to Eric
Decker, football legend, hottie, great
dad, drama fan. My love for you. And and
you've trained him so well. Hey,
beautiful girl. Tells you just the story
you want. Perfect. He's a good man. Good
one. Well, if anybody needs some help
convincing their husband and or
boyfriend or anybody, it might just
happen in the form of these donuts. Are
you ready for these? What is this? What
have you got in front of us, Dafany?
Ready for this? Drunken donuts. What?
Because you know what's better than
donuts? Food donuts. Donuts. I think
I've got procco. One of you has bourbon.
One has like an Irish side car. No, we
both have bourbon. Rosé, Irish cream,
bourbon. And these are all from the
doughnut project. Okay. I love their
stuff inside them. I think they taste
Oh. Oh, you got a Boston cream. Oh, you
lucky lady. Okay. I love how Dafany
always tries to get me drunk. I love it.
Thank you. You know what I want us to
Okay. Yes, I do. It's true. No, I have
to laugh cuz I'm like, if you're going
to bring boozy donuts like to the
office, you may want to warn people and
let them know. No, don't tell them
anything.
really fun because like Barb in
accounting is going to be like twerking
on the copy machine and she's she might
add an extra zero to your paycheck. Get
Barb actually this is so I love you so
much for setting this up so perfectly
because the way that just the way that
you might want to send these donuts to
your office could just be with this
brand new service you guys that I've
been dying to tell you about which is
what Oh my god. You can now have scary
clowns deliver your donuts if you would
like to. Look at this picture.
A new company allows you to send scary
clowns to deliver donuts to anyone that
you might like so that you can be both
if you're sending these boozy ones, you
can be fat, drunk, and scared all of the
time. No. No. So, is there anyone in
your life who would receive a scary
clown with donuts? Um, like a friend of
me accounting. I would never send it to
a friend.
Jesus. Oh my god.
No, don't do that. Wow. Donut.
Wow. You're crazy. No, I don't. Hi. Hi.
That's not some donuts. Oh, thank you.
All right. Don't do that. And don't
scare people. Is she going to get beat
with a box of donut? Don't do that.
Scared. We're going to go to break for a
second. Valerie Bur and Nelly's's brand
new twist on the chicken pot pie that
will make your taste buds go back to the
disco times. Okay, stay tuned. Where'd
he go? When he got that was so
[Music]
scary, we're back and we're asked in the
critical question. Are TV dinners a
thing again? Valerie was on the
everyone's favorite TV show of the 70s,
One Day at a Time. Thank you. Do Do you
remember these? I do. I love them. Love
them. It was so exciting. Did you get to
have those as a kid? We did. Not very
often, but this is before microwaves.
You had to actually put these in the
oven. 45 minutes later, it came out. So,
this is a little present from you. It's
the absolute least I could do. So, now
you got a new take on these TV TV
dinners. What do you got for us? I got a
chicken pot pie. Chicken pot pie all in
one pan. All right. While you make that,
while you make that audience, guess what
I've got? What are you doing with that?
I have Daphne's high school yearbook.
How did you get that? And childhood
photos. I'm going to holler if I find
anything interesting to share. And also
notes from all my Yes. It's full of
notes. Full of notes. Oh my gosh. Don't
read them. Valerie, enjoy yourself. I
will. Make it tasty. Do it good. I will.
All for you, Dr. Oz.
Okay. So, we're starting with basically,
you all know what is in a chicken pot
pie. I mean, you got, you know, your
veggies, usually peas, corn, everything,
but I've just played up a little bit
with it. I got some uh potatoes, and you
can use all frozen veggies if you want
to, and just heat them through. So, I
got potatoes, and there are some red
peppers in here, and some carrots, and
some mushrooms, and we got some eric
vert, or green beans, really. They're
just green beans. Green beans. And we
got some peas. And we got some garlic.
So, all that goes in. Little chili
flake. A little chili flake. I always
like to heat things up a little bit.
Yeah, cuz you're so spicy, though. You a
lot. So, we just get those all blended
together. Chicken in. Chicken in,
please. Chicken in. Okay. So, then we
got a little basically some bashameal
sauce here, which is flour and oil and
um there's some cream in here. And
again, I like things spicy, so I got a
little hot sauce in here. Love it. So,
that goes on top of this. Get it all
mixed together. It smells so And then it
ends up looking like this, right? Yep.
And again, I want your life to be easy.
So, we have some pie dough that you get
get right in the fridge. One of the best
tricks ever. That's the best. Don't make
your
own. I agree. We never do. Just roll it
right over. So easy.
And this is where all the homemade
happens. So, you know, and it looks not
in. But here's the deal. If you want to
get all fancy and crimp it, you can get
all fancy and crimp it. And then that's
going to go in the oven. And then
what comes out? Oh, let's see. All in
one. Moment of truth. All right. Yes.
Look at that. Oh, that's gorgeous. Oh my
goodness. And it looks so beautiful and
homemade. And you use a lot of
ingredients just from the grocery store.
I love that. So good. All right, we got
to dive in on this. Let's talk about it.
We've made Wait, wait, wait. Oh, okay.
Can you see me for a second? Look at
this flaky crust. Ready? Are you
watching this? Watch it flake apart.
Look at that. Okay, we can't tease the
audience without giving them some. Oh,
please do. Yes, they do. You want some?
Little chicken pot pie. I only have
three for now. Watch flake in there.
That is Dr. Oz. Help me here.
Save me cuz I only brought three pies
over. I've got You're in trouble. The
first lesson of audience. All right.
Well, well, Valerie's over there feeding
the audience. You guys, it's delicious.
It's really good. Do either one of you
want to be brave and show us some of
your uh retro pics. Uh oh. We have some
for Let's see Valerie's going to be
really over there. Let's see Valerie's
throwback pick.
How much you having a day? You look like
All right. Oh my god.
Hey, cheerleader. We've got spirit. Of
course, you were cheer captain. Oh my
gosh. So good. Oh wow. Oh
my gosh. And I have I have no idea why
my mother decided me to put it in a
cowgirl outfit. So it's amazing I'm not
in therapy. I don't know why she dressed
me like that. I don't have no idea that
I've got I've got Daffh's retro photo
here, which the audience has been
adoring. There it is. Look at that.
There's a clown. She's with a clown. She
She didn't like that food. You didn't
like the clown back then either. There
she is.
Now, now I need to go to therapy. You
just want to know if Valerie still has
the bell bottoms from back in the day.
Oh, come on. I'd love to borrow those. I
don't think I do. You You got rid of No,
but I have new ones. Bell Bottoms are
always in as far as I'm concerned. Oh,
yes, they are. Valerie, uh, you know
what I do have, though? You know what I
do have is I still have the Elton John
boots. I wore in the Elton John episode
of One Day at a Time where we sang. Oh
wow, that was fun. You're going to have
to bring those in sometime. I still have
the boots. We're going to wear those.
And of course, you got to act with
everyone's childhood crush. Someone like
Sean Cassidy says, "Yes, in Hearty
Boys." Who was the best kisser? I want
to know. Oh, kiss and tell. A girl never
tells. Oh, you got to tell. But a woman
does. I don't remember. I kissed a lot
of boys.
But not no not like Valerie, but as
characters. As of course I I'm a serial
monogamist. A so that's fun. Yeah,
that's the right way to go. Yeah, seem
to work out pretty well. This pot pie
also seem to work out really well. This
is delicious. And of course, you guys
can find these recipes on
dr.com/thedish. And all of our sharable
pics and step by steps are on Instagram
at The Dish on Oz. And when we come
back, Jesse James Decker is taking us
for a walk down memory lane with a
southern classic using ingredients you
already have in your pants. Don't go
away.
[Music]
[Applause]
Why do you think he would fake having
Down syndrome? How one man faked a
disability. You're doing a job to help
someone and you're taking advantage of
for his own twisted pleasure. Changing
his diaper. It's just gross. That's
coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
We are back with a new spin on another
retro food. This one is a little bit of
southern charm. Jesse, what are you
making for us? We are making my 10 can
chili. Yes. 10 cans. It's fabulous. 10.
10 like 10 cans. Yes. So, we've started
out with ground beef. We've got our
onion. We've got carrots. And now we're
going to add the cans. So, Daffany, I'm
going to need you to grab the tomato and
green chilies. Go, go, go, go, go. We're
going to do this quickly. Quickly,
quickly. Yes. Yes. Yes. Okay. So, now
we're going to add this. Yes. Dump it in
there for me. Tomato and green.
Absolutely. Yes. We're going to see how
quickly we can do this. Cuz when you got
hungry babies, you got to go. Yes. Okay.
Next, I need you to work. Yes. Go, girl.
We're I need you to grab Let's see. We
got the kidney beans. Okay. Got two cans
of I need more than that. More than
that. Keep it going. Keep it going. Keep
it going. We got corn and we've got the
vegetable vegetarian chili. All right.
Okay. Perfect. Oh, that's more veggie
chili. Veggie. I do. Absolutely. Got the
corn. This is veggie chili. Yes, it is.
All right. What do I do? Tell me what to
do. Okay, girl. I need you to grab the
green beans. Okay. Yep. And then uh
we've got let's see what else. A little
bit of tomato sauce. And that's Wait,
that's one, two, three, four, five, six.
That's the clumsy one. Bring in the
rest. Can the sea ladies got cans from
the back? There we go. Got the green
beans. Green beans. Got some Yep. tomato
sauce. Good, good, good. So, this is
just stuff in your pantry. You just
throw it in there. So, here's the thing.
My mama always says, "Have tons of cans
of vegetables in your pantry and have
frozen meat. That way you can always
whip something up last minute. I've got
three kids under four and a husband that
works. Sometimes sometimes your mom is
very smart. My mama is smart. So
sometimes you just need something you
can whip up like that to feed your
family. All right. And we got to add a
little spice in that mix. Yes, we are
adding some spice. Add some spice. But I
want to learn more about all of it. How
much? Just a little pinch. Just a little
pinch. Little dab will do. I want to
know a little bit more about your Yeah.
What is this? Oh, sorry. So this is
chili. We've got cumin. We've got a
little garlic powder. And we got a
little Cajun seasoning cuz I put Cajun
seasoning on everything. So, two
questions. Seriously, you said 10 cans.
Nine and 10 aren't used. So, not just
really 10 cans, not 10 cans. Well,
here's the thing. Two were not used
because sometimes you might want to
double up your corn and sometimes you
might want to double up your green
beans. Whatever you want. All right. So,
we got some retro home video, Daffy,
don't we? Oh, let me see. We do. We do.
I was going to say your mama learned
this from her mama. She did. And your
your grandma. We got a little retro
video of you cooking with her. Take a
look at this. Oh yeah.
Work great.
You're working hard. Working hard. Let's
turn it right around. Let's turn it
around now. Work. Hurry up.
[Applause]
Oh god. I love it. Love it. It's just
it's sweet cuz that's my my mama Mary M
Mary Baglio and she passed but she
taught my mama how to cook and she
taught her daughter and my mama and so
that was me making homemade Italian
bread when we were in Louisiana
together. So it's just I haven't seen
that in a really long time. She would be
so proud of you what you're doing like
you're making her proud. But that's the
beauty of recipes that does it it gives
you your family heritage. Oh, it totally
it totally does.
All right. Will you all stop crying?
We're making There's no crying
while we're making. Oh, yeah. Pull
yourself together. Make your mama cry.
Chili. I know. So,
[Laughter]
well, while she's adding tears to her
chili. Um, what's going to sweeten this
up for us? Yes, cuz we've got super
spicy over there. So, I'm bringing the
southern sweet cuz I'm southern and
Caribbean. So, I bring the southern
sweet and Caribbean heat on any given
day. You don't know what you're going to
get with it. Oh, I like that. That's
your tag. Yes. Caribbean heat and
southern sweet. I love that. Yes. So, I
am making some sweet honey butter
cornbread. And if you say it with a
southern accent, it just makes it even
better. So, we're doing sweet honey
butter cornbread. All right. So, we have
the basic cornbread mix. We're doing the
dry mix first. So, it's allpurpose
flour. We have baking powder, salt,
sugar, of course, cuz I love sweet
cornbread. You guys love sweet
cornbread. I like it anyway. I'll take
it. And we got a little baking powder.
Okay. So, we have our dry going.
Daffhany has beat our our eggs. And then
we will add in I love your eggs. Oh yes,
she is just going to town on these eggs.
We have some milk going in. Vegetable
oil
and melted butter if you don't have
that. Yes, melted butter. We got to have
butter with a All right. Who stole my
butter? Did we knock our butter out?
Valerie, did you steal my Dr. Oz? You
stole my butter. I thought you had
enough butter already in there. What?
It's really good. All right. Well, if
Dr. Oz doesn't steal your butter, you'll
add in some melted butter. And then I
add in, you got to have the honey for
the sweetness, extra sweetness in there.
So we'll mix that all together. We have
wet going and then we have our dry mix.
We put the two together. And then I like
to pour it into a cast iron skillet cuz
when we were doing the best cast iron
skillet, it doesn't have to be hot. You
want to spray the inside first or you
can add a little butter around the edge
there. Not if he's around though. He
takes your butter if you will. All
right. So we will bake that off in the
oven at 350°. And you can see it already
looks delicious cuz he's eating it. Come
on over. We got Jesse's chili here.
Cornbread. Come join us. I tell you, you
don't need that butter. This stuff is so
good today. It's sweet and sour all
together with little tears inside. It's
It's special. Oh, this is so good. You
name it after your mom. Is that right?
My mama is the one that taught me how to
cook. And so chili and um jumbolaya,
those are some of the few things she
taught me in right in the beginning cuz
my mom is an amazing cook. So I wanted
to be just like her. Well, guess what?
We got it. Guess what? We got her here.
We got her here today. Come on up with
Parker.
Are they
twins? I'm so proud of you.
Crying. Crying out there. You brought
your body double.
We're like sisters. I am here to tell
you this girl has been cooking since she
was in diapers. She was born to
Kd for
mama. We're going to hang out with Mama
Parker. You guys can find these recipes
on
dr.com/theish and all of our sharable
picss and step by steps or on Instagram
at the dish on Oz. When we come back,
I'm making fun fondue fun again with a
healthy spin. Don't go away.
I'm so glad you
were. You came. This isn't me.
Why do you think he would fake having
Down syndrome? How one man faked a
disability. You're doing a job to help
someone and you're taking advantage of
for his own twisted pleasure. Changing
his diaper. It's just gross. That's
coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
We are back with the dish crew and
another retro food. So, what is it? So,
here's the deal. Daffhne actually thinks
her dad is really cheesy, so this is
perfect. Perfect.
He sets me up sometimes. Um, yeah, I do
think you're a little cheesy every once
in a while, but informative and and
really lovable, but still cheesy. A
little well only as cheesy as this
fondue which is mostly cheese. Um so
this is made a really basic cheese
sauce. Okay this is garlic cooked with a
little bit of butter or oil a little bit
of flour adding a whole bunch of cheese
and of course the wine wine or beer is
what makes fond do gives it that
delicious you know sort of acid flavor
too and of course it's really just a
delicious pot of cheese and then I make
it a little bit healthier is
patronizing me. I'm going to put a whole
like Popeye's whole serving of If I
wasn't here, would you do that? Probably
not. No. You know what? I like this. I'm
sort of doing a fondue spin on on art um
a spinach artich choke dip. And
actually, my favorite brilliant. That's
that's what I get at the That's what I
get at the restaurant when I'm like, you
know, let's be a little healthy. Let's
let's And then if you're intimidated by
artichokes or you haven't made them a
lot at home, we actually have a really
fun little video Instagram story here to
show you. Here's how you're going to
steam your artich chokes. Okay, you take
off the uh the utmost stems and leaves.
So you take off that top pointy stem
right there. Top pointy leaves right
there. And then you're going to flip it
around and take off the end of the stem
also because that's a really woody part.
Leaving just a bit at the end. You take
a spoon and scoop out the choke. Okay,
that's the hairy part in the middle of
it. This is a really easy technique um
just to make sure you don't have to
worry about it after it cooks. You
sprinkle a little water in a little
lemon into your water and then steam
these artichokes up. Okay. And the
lemon's going to keep them from turning
brown, which is great. And voila, you
have these great artichokes. And what I
did was I actually cut the stems up. I
love I do this in my stuffed in my
stuffed artich chokes, too. I throw
these in with the breadcrumbs. So,
chopped up stems of the artichokes. No
waste. That's right. And then I cubed up
the steamed artich chokes and put them
on this little platter. Get in there.
Little hunks of bread, some boiled
tomato, some boiled potatoes. So, it's
kind of like a reclet there. Okay. So,
Valerie, why is it called the choke? You
heard that word? Because those little
the things inside the middle, all the
purple parts, you can choke on them. You
choke on them. Is that true? It's true.
It's absolutely true.
I like that.
What's going on down there, Jamaica? All
right. So, uh, we're going to play a fun
game. You guys up for a game? Yes. Yes.
It's a retro throwback. It's called
Never Have I Ever. Have you played that?
I would love this game. All right. So,
if you haven't played it, All right. So,
I'm going to pull out a question. And
we're playing it foodie style. So, it's
food questions. And if you've done it
before, you're going to take a little
sip. Okay. All right. So, I'm gonna call
you out. Kind of weird to play this game
with my dad. I'm not going to lie. All
right. No, it's I'm watching carefully.
All right. So, never have I ever eaten
something out of the trash.
I have. And it was a donut I threw away.
Like, I want to be skinny and then I was
like, "Give me my donut back." So, yes,
I did do it. We've all been there. I did
it. We've all been there. Don't judge
me. All right. Don't you hate when you
accidentally throw the cookie out with
the tin foil or you're like, "No, no,
you got a fish back for that cookie."
Okay. No shame in my game. Okay. Never
have I ever tried breast milk. Oh, no. I
haven't done that. Isn't that why you
try breast milk first? You know, you
want to make sure it tastes good for
your baby obviously before. Have you
never tried it? And it's just kind of
interesting. It's a novelty. Hey,
listen. We're going to put all these
This is a great game. You should play
it. Reminds you back. We're going to put
a lot more of these clues on our
website. Play with your friends. You'll
be interesting what you learn. We'll be
dishing again next Wednesday. So, tune
in together everybody. Change is
happening. Our journey is just
beginning.
[Applause]
[Music]