[Music]
season 11 starts now.
Imagine you get into a car accident. You
look around at the wreckage and realize
your nightmare isn't over. While you
were able to walk away from the crash,
the person in the other car does not.
They died at the hands of your mistake.
Today, you'll meet two women who are
speaking about their secret shame after
they accidentally killed someone. What
happened when they realized another
person's life was taken at their hands?
And could they ever forgive themselves?
On a dark country road in Midland, Texas
at the wheel of her father's Chevy
Impala, Laura Bush was only 17 years old
when she ran a stop sign, crashed, and
accidentally killed her friend. That
moment, she says, has haunted her for
most of her adult life. Many other
celebrities have opened up about the
tremendous guilt and pain they've
suffered after accidentally taking a
life. For Venus Williams, it was the
death of a 78-year-old man after a car
crash that left her heartbroken. Rebecca
Gayhart says she didn't want to live
following her tragic car accident that
killed a 9-year-old boy.
An accidental killing is defined as a
death resulting from a perfectly lawful
act that one wouldn't expect to cause
harm. It's estimated that over 1 million
people a year cause an accidental death
or injury. And headline after headline
reveals how quickly our fragile
realities can crumble through a fatal
mishap.
>> I hit and killed a young man. He was
just 18.
That night, the first responders
couldn't come for a while. And that was
the loneliest and saddest half hour of
my life. Then they told me that two men
had died in the accident. The accident
that I was at fault for. I didn't think
that I deserve to be on this earth. I
felt like it was a mistake that I was
alive. How can you go on after you've
taken two lives?
>> On September 23rd, 2018 in the Utah
Mountains, Caen Richen's life was
changed forever. That day, she and her
family were out target shooting. What
they didn't realize was that behind the
target they set up was a road. On that
road, another family was driving by.
Caen fired three shots, removed her ear
protectors, and heard screaming.
Her bullets had struck a 14-year-old boy
in the head, killing him instantly.
Today, Kaen has come to speak about the
tragic day that will haunt her forever.
Kaen joins me now in studio. What gives
you the strength to speak up today about
your story?
>> Um
the desire and the hope that I can
prevent future tragedies
and
just the support system that I have, my
husband, my children, you know, the
people around me. Um
I never want something like this to
happen to anybody else. And so whatever
I can do to prevent that,
you know, I'll do.
>> Can you take me back to that day? What
happened after you realized you pulled
the trigger and that something had
happened?
>> Well, when we first took our hearing
protection off, we heard the screaming.
And my initial thought was it was just
some teenagers out goofing around. And
then the jeep came flying up onto the
top of the hill and stopped and we could
hear what they were screaming and
realized what had happened.
Um, my four children were with us and so
we had them stay where they were at as
me and my husband ran up the hill to see
if there was anything we could do.
It was very obvious
that nothing could be done. Um, my
husband called 911
and I went back down the hill to my
children and took them around up to
where our campsite was, where we'd been
sitting, so that they didn't have to be
witness to to what had happened.
>> What went through your mind as you began
to process that this little boy had had
passed?
It's like living in a nightmare that you
can't wake up from.
Never never thought I would be in this
position.
Thank you.
I just I couldn't believe it had
happened. You know, we've always been
very careful.
Um, we've worked really hard at teaching
our kids gun safety
and uh, it just
I was in shock. I just
unbelievable.
>> So, in the days, weeks after the
incident, the community was in mourning
and obviously the story made headlines.
How did people respond to you?
Those who personally knew me, most of
them were very supportive. Um, there are
a few people that no longer associate
with me.
Um, but there is a lot of
anger. You know, there are times where I
was out that you could hear that I could
hear people talking about me.
>> Mhm. Some of them knew who I was and
didn't realize
that I was there.
Um, I learned to quit answering my
phone. I got a lot of blocked phone
calls. Um, I shut off all my social
media because I would get messages from
people and then they would block me from
them. Um,
so you just
you have to learn to just ignore people.
you know,
they are allowed to feel however they
want. You know, they don't know the
story. They don't know me. Um, and if if
it makes them feel better to be angry at
me, then, you know, that's okay. Cuz
there's nothing that they can say to me
that I haven't said to myself.
>> That's tough.
With your guilt, you pleaded guilty
>> to negligent homicide.
>> Yes.
and you've said that you thought you
might spend the rest of your life in
prison. Did Did you believe that that
would be the right penalty for you, that
you deserve that?
Um,
it wasn't necessarily that I believed
it, but I remember sitting up on the
mountain while we were waiting for the
police to arrive, thinking that whatever
came my way, I was willing to accept
because I killed somebody's kid.
As painful is for you to say that,
investigators, as you know, went out to
the site. They determined that there's
no way you could have seen the road, nor
would have expected it to turn the way
it did from where you were standing. Did
that alleviate some of the pain to know
that at least officially people weren't
blaming you
>> a little bit?
>> So, Kayleen was sentenced to community
service and educating the public on gun
safety, although I understand the judge
was originally going to sentence you to
one day in jail for every year of the
child's life.
What have you said to the family?
>> I don't feel like I have the right to
impose on them until they're until
they're ready. Um, the only contact
we've really had is to ask them if we
could dedicate the presentation that I
do to the hunter safety groups on gun
safety in the video that I made in their
son's memory.
Um, but we've tried very hard to be very
respectful of their feelings. Um,
>> I'm glad you came here today.
>> Thank you.
>> So, we're going to keep talking about
this. Coming up, a car accident that
took the life of an 8-year-old boy. And
what the woman behind the wheel says
still haunts her today.
>> I live with the memory of that small,
broken body, and I live with the memory
of his mother's screams.
And I'll always wonder if there's
something I could have done differently
to avoid hitting him.
>> Today, we asked the heart-wrenching
question. What happens after you
accidentally kill someone? We're back
with Kaen who was practicing target
shooting and one of her stray bullets
hit and killed a teen boy. You just saw
a clip of Maryanne. She says she will
never forget the boy whose life she took
that fateful day. It's a horrifying
reality she's had to face for more than
40 years.
>> Yes.
>> Marian, thank you for being here. What
what happened that day that changed your
life forever?
>> At the time, I was a student living in a
small town in Ohio on a beautiful spring
day. I was driving along a country road
back to my student apartment when an
8-year-old boy named Brian darted into
the road. I tried to swerve, but I hit
him and he died before he reached the
hospital.
You were 22 years old when this
happened.
>> Yes, I was.
>> Did you ever wonder why did this have to
happen to me?
>> I I think I wondered that from the very
beginning and I concluded that I must be
a terrible person. I blamed myself.
Uh although I was not charged with any
offenses, I was convinced that this
child's death was my fault. It happened
in front of my car. I collided with him.
>> Um
I also struggled with pretty severe
trauma symptoms for quite some time.
horrible images that would I'd be making
breakfast or brushing my teeth and all
of a sudden a terrible image would pop
into my mind.
>> Um I was overcome with guilt and grief
and fear. Uh it was very difficult to
concentrate. Uh so it was a very very
difficult time and uh I definitely
held myself responsible.
It took a while, but years later you
wrote a a letter to the boy's mother.
>> Yes, I did.
>> Did you ever get a response?
>> I did. I I received a response from his
brother. His mother had passed away.
>> And the brother and I have had a number
of conversations
which I believe have been very healing
and helpful for both of us. And I'm
pretty awed by his generosity of spirit.
It's it's a gift and a bit of grace. Um
I I will say people ask me all the time
about contacting the family of the
victim that they unintentionally killed.
And what I tell them is if they are
hoping for forgiveness or some
understanding or some reconciliation,
they're probably not ready to make that
approach because they don't really, in
my opinion, have the right to ask for
that from their victim. But when their
healing has progressed to a point that
they could just speak from the heart and
say, "Your son, your partner, your
spouse lives with me, is in my heart,
and I just want you to know that um
because I know he's in your heart, too."
That can be very beautiful and powerful.
>> So, there are about 20,000 people in
this country who accidentally kill
someone else. It's not that rare,
>> right? And I've taken care of lots of
folks in my life who felt responsible
for the deaths of others.
>> Sure.
>> Sometimes it's people who are in a car
accident. Sometimes police officers
taking
>> trying to keep the place safe.
Healthcare providers, right?
>> When patients don't do well,
>> right?
>> And what I've noticed, I don't know if
if your research has shown this, that is
there's a deep sense of quiet of
solemnness that happens
>> and and you know, you've been listening
to Kaen's story. What's your message of
hope for her? Because I I I feel a deep
sense of darkness in you, Kaen. And I'd
probably feel it's been how many days or
months since that child died?
>> 16 months in one day.
>> And you have children that are similar
age.
>> I have four children between the ages of
11 and 18.
>> Okay. Kayen,
this tragic shooting
will change you, but it doesn't need to
define you. You're so much more than
that. And I don't think anybody could
have watched and listened to your
interview with Dr. Oz and not recognized
that you're a very caring and thoughtful
person and also very brave for coming
out here and telling your story.
I want to invite you to
honor
that young boy who died too young in the
choices you make going forward. You've
already started to do that with your gun
safety activism and that's very
beautiful. What I find is that when
unintentional killers reach out to other
people, they actually heal themselves
even as they're helping others because
we regain our self-respect, a sense of
ourselves as good people that we've
lost. We regain trust in ourselves in
the world. and we regain a sense of
acceptance. We're no longer disconnected
from the people around us. We're part of
a community and we're helping to make
that community a safer, kinder, more
compassionate place. So, that's my
invitation to you. I think you're
already on that journey. I have every
confidence in your ability to succeed
and um I wish you peace.
>> Thank you. You're welcome.
>> Sen, what will it take for you to
forgive yourself and find some bit of
peace?
>> Right now,
I don't know that it's
I don't know that the forgiveness will
ever truly come. I think it's more
acceptance
and
moving forward, you know, so that it's
not defining me, so that I'm making a
difference
>> in other people's lives.
My whole purpose now is to make sure
that nobody else goes through this.
>> I wish you the best going forward. I
know it's a long road. Thank you very
much.
>> Thank you.
>> We'll be right back.
Coming up, medical mysteries that will
shock you. What would you do if your
skin looked like fish scales all over
your body? Or could you be allergic to
something so vital to life as water?
Medical cases that will baffle you.
That's next.
[Music]
We're back. Investigating medical
mysteries. Imagine your skin feels and
looks like this. scales that look like
they're from a fish all over your body.
You're covered with thick, dry scales
that peel off to become painful cracks
on your body's biggest organ. Today, we
investigate the medical mystery of what
could cause skin to blister, peel, and
shed so visibly and so intensely. For
one woman, she says her skin gets so dry
that her eyelids flip out. Take a look
at what she goes through every day just
to get out of the house.
I am totally not a morning person, but
this is the most important part of my
day because it sets the tone for my
skin. So, I always start with eye drops.
Um, just keep my eyes hydrated so they
don't close all the way. How would I
describe my skin? Rough, dry,
flaky, and peely. Broken because it
doesn't do what it's supposed to do. One
of the things with my condition is I
always have to carry lotion around and
my skin also sheds so I have to be
constantly sweeping.
Growing up different was definitely a
challenge emotionally. I felt most
people saw my skin first instead of
getting to know who I am. I began to
feel worthless and less than all because
of my skin.
>> I'm so happy that you're here. May I
touch your hand? Yes, absolutely. Thank
you for having me.
>> Thank you for being here. So, please
share with everybody the name of your
condition.
>> Yes, it's called lamelariosis
and basically my body sheds old skin
cells off too slow and that's what
causes the dry flaky scales.
>> Lamelichthosis.
>> So, you can tell when your skin is
starting to dry out. What does that mean
you have to do? What does it feel like?
It basically it starts out feeling more
itchy than normal and it'll start
actually feeling tight and maybe a
little tender and that's how I know I
need to reapply the lotion.
>> So I notice your skin and you you point
out in that piece it's the first thing
people see and one does notice. I
noticed your eyes first by the way which
are beautiful.
>> Thank you.
>> But may I may I examine your hands?
>> Absolutely.
>> So this is pretty typical the scaling.
>> Mhm.
>> And it doesn't hurt when I touch it.
>> No, not at all.
I actually don't mind when people aren't
afraid to touch me because so much of my
life people wouldn't touch things I
touched. So,
>> well, I'll keep holding your hands then.
>> Sure.
>> What What was that like as a child
having people I'm sure they had
nicknames for you and they unfounded
fears and they judge you based on what
you look like. Something you couldn't
change.
>> Oh, absolutely. When I was little, it
was a huge challenge because you just
want to fit in. You want to belong. And
when I started school, parents actually
called the principal and wanted their
kids taken out of my class.
>> The parents called?
>> Yes. I think they were afraid it was
contagious, which it is not.
>> And as a result, um, it the kids, I
think, were afraid of it then because
their parents were.
>> Sure.
>> And when I actually started school, they
wouldn't touch things I touched. I was
bullied by exclusion. always kind of
left out on the outside looking in is
how I often felt. I get stared at
everywhere, too. And I know it's just
something that people aren't used to
seeing. So, it's their natural reaction,
but that's hard, too, when you're
constantly being stared at.
>> Well, it's it's your largest organ. Just
to put in context, I know you know, but
for everybody else, we probably have 20
square feet of skin. That's like a a
small bathroom worth on the floor of
skin. It's a lot of skin, right?
Protects us from germs. Is vitally
important to how we feel things and
touch things. how we perceived by
others. And so the emotional side's one
part of it, and I want to come back to
that in a second, but the physical part
is really important. And for example,
regulating your body temperature is
probably a challenge because I don't
know, do you sweat normally through the
skin?
>> I actually cannot sweat.
>> You can't sweat at all.
>> No.
>> So, how do you deal? That's dangerous.
>> It is. It's actually life-threatening.
Something as simple as a fever, I could
actually die from.
So, thankfully, I haven't had one in
many, many years. But I basically carry
around a spray bottle that I fill with
water and I call it my fake sweat.
>> Do I see it there? Yeah.
>> And what it does is it acts as my body's
way of sweating.
>> So this is a it's dangerous actually.
You're brave that you grow up as with a
problem that you probably were aware at
young age could be lethal to you.
>> Mhm.
>> One of the things that's get that's
amazing to me is some of these this is a
genetic abnormality. Correct.
>> So not something you could have done or
changed. We don't have a cure for it. It
can happen to any skin tone,
>> right? And the condition is something
that most folks don't understand. So, if
you want to spend two seconds explaining
it, let me give a little background.
When children are born with this
condition, uh they have this little
translucent uh film almost. This is what
you look like as a baby. Yes.
>> Which I think is really cute.
>> My grandma said I almost looked like uh
when I was born with a collodian
membrane, I was almost like I was a
sausage link cuz you have like that
thing around you.
>> Exactly. The casing. Yeah.
>> Right. And then the membrane is replaced
by the thicker scaly skin as you get
older and emotionally
from the first moment you can remember
life all the things that you mentioned
which are processing so beautifully now
>> is you know was still was there and it's
hard to do that. How did you cope
emotionally? How did you get to this
point as as a as I don't know I I'll use
the word healthy as you appear balanced
as you appear. It's definitely been a
huge transformation and people who know
me now, they find it hard to believe
that I used to be shy and insecure, but
it was kind of three-fold. One is
definitely my faith because I believe
God creates everyone in his image and
the very things that we often see as
flaws are the things he's going to use
to impact the world in a big way.
>> Beautifully said.
>> Thank you.
And secondly is the performing arts. I
remember my first dance show. I was far
enough away from the audience that for
the first time in my life, people saw me
as Bailey the dancer instead of Bailey
the girl with the weird skin. And then
the third, and everyone struggles with
insecurities. I'm sure you have them as
well.
>> Absolutely.
>> And when you look in the mirror every
day, you have a choice.
And you could choose to believe all the
things that the world tends to say is
beautiful and you have to fit into the
certain mold. Or you could choose that
you're beautifully unique just the way
you are. And life is so much better when
you choose the second route.
>> So you you redefine beauty.
>> Yes.
>> Bailey's beautiful now.
>> Yes. Well, I always have been beautiful.
>> Yes. You always Exactly. Now you realize
you're beautiful.
>> Now I realize it. I'm owning it. for you
have the power of one which we've been
talking about on the show a lot. You
have a strong voice. You use it. You
speak the truth and you're going to
change a lot of lives by doing that.
>> Thank you.
>> Bless you for coming to our show.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Up next, a medical mystery that is
baffling. Can you be allergic to
something that all of life depends on?
Water.
>> We'll be right back.
>> It was a relationship that ended very
poorly. Tried to ruin my life. revenge
porn.
>> Not only were there topless photos of
me, but they had added a Google map to
my location.
>> Oh my. That's coming up on Thursday.
>> We're back investigating medical
mysteries. Water, it's vital for
survival. But what if every time you
took a sip
of water or showered or got caught in
the rain, your skin became red, itchy,
and felt like it was on fire? My next
guest says her body rejects water, and
even a drop of water can put her at
risk.
>> I see water as an obstacle in my life.
I'm literally allergic to water.
So, if I'm externally exposed to it,
there will be hives and rashes. And
internally, I will have abdominal
cramping and migraines and fevers.
Foods with high water content, like
fruits and vegetables, can be pretty
painful for me to eat. I've even
recorded the sound of my stomach when
it's cramping.
Things as simple as washing my hands is
painful. Brushing my teeth really hurts.
I honestly only shower about one to two
times a month now.
Dehydration is a pretty constant symptom
of mine. I've even been admitted to the
ER on multiple occasions.
Having a chronic condition with
invisible symptoms can be really
challenging because there's a lot of
discrimination. I've even had a woman
accuse me of faking my disability.
There's so much that I can't do because
of my condition. My body is just
fighting a battle with itself and it
environment.
Tessa joins us via Zoom. Tessa, thanks
for being with us. Let's go back to the
very beginning. This started when you
were about eight years old, pretty
young. What kinds of symptoms did you
first notice?
>> Um, I first started noticing I had
really big rashes all over my body when
I would step out of the shower. So, at
first we thought maybe I could be
allergic to my shampoos or my soap or
body wash, but it just kept coming back
to water. It was in lake water, oceans,
rain water, even just my own sweat and
tears.
>> So, how did the doctors pinpoint that
your body was reacting in fact to the
water that you mentioned? I mean, it's
so essential to life. I I'd never heard
of it before I heard, but your story.
>> Yeah, most people have not heard of it.
It was pretty hard to diagnose. It took
us a few years. It started with just
eliminating food allergies and
eliminating allergies to anything else
I'd be coming into contact with. But a
water allergy test is super simple. You
just get a towel, soak it in room
temperature water, and lay it over your
upper limb, and within about 20 minutes,
you'll see a reaction.
>> So, what was your reaction when they
actually made this diagnosis of a water
allergy? It's so so jarring.
>> Yeah, I was I was a kid. I was only 8 to
10 years old when this was happening.
And I was kind of in denial of it. I
didn't really know what was going on, so
I didn't really know how to accept it.
And I would lie about my condition to
people, to friends. I would say it was
my asthma. It wasn't something
underlying from that. So, I really
didn't accept it until I was older.
>> It does sound unbelievable. And just for
everyone listening, since I've read up
on it, it appears around puberty. We're
not sure why it happens. One theory, by
the way, is that the water actually
activates something on your skin or in
your body. And Tessa gave us you thank
you for sharing your medical records and
medical records actually
>> demonstrate this. It's a rare case
what's called aquagenic erdicaria.
Aquagenic is water and herdicaria is
hives. So basically, you're allergic to
water. It's real. Yeah.
>> And in your case, you say that you're
allergic both externally and internally.
So which means you can't even drink
water. So how do you stay hydrated?
>> I I try to stay hydrated using whole
milk. Um the fats and proteins and sugar
found in whole milk actually help kind
of like sneak the water molecules into
my system. But even my level of
hydration is probably everybody else's
level of dehydration.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's hard to avoid water,
right? It makes up 60% of our bodies as
well.
>> So they can ask of a personal question
here.
>> Many are probably thinking how do you
shower, right? Because that that must
affect your body adversely. How often do
you shower?
>> I only shower about one to two times a
month right now.
>> And and what happens when you do shower?
>> I even in cold water, I will get a fever
within about 5 minutes of stepping into
it. I will exit the shower with hives
pretty much all over my body and I have
to rest for about an hour or two
afterwards.
>> I would only shower once a month or less
too personally.
>> All right. So, what what about if you're
outside playing and it starts to rain.
>> If it starts to rain, I will do anything
I can to get inside. Whenever I'm in
rain, I will get a fever and a migraine
and it's really awful. But if I have to
go out in the rain, I have an umbrella
built for like four people that I will
hunker down underneath to try to stay
dry.
>> Well, I I I tell you I commend your
resilience and for being able to smile
about it, then keep hanging in there.
This is what I think we'll find a cure
for. You just got to figure out exactly
what's going down.
>> Yeah, I hope so.
>> Stay out of the rain. Thanks for sharing
your story. We'll be right back.
>> Coming up, children who say they've
lived past lives. Could this boy have
lived a past life of baseball legend Lou
Garrick?
[Applause]
Today we investigate the phenomenon of
past lives and the children who say
they've lived them. Like a toddler who
told his parents he once lived a past
life as a Civil War soldier. or a
10-year-old who says he had a past life
as a Hollywood agent in the 1950s with
lots of details. And you're about to
meet a boy who says he lived a past life
as someone who died nearly 70 years
before he was born. Baseball legend Lou
Garrick. Please welcome Christian and
his mother Kathy. Thank you both for
being here.
>> Thank you.
>> So Ky, take me back when this all
started. Christian was 2 years old. So I
don't know if you even know this.
Probably most kids don't remember when
they're two. What was so unique about
your son that also caught your
attention?
>> Well, we're not baseball people and he
saw some neighborhood kids playing
baseball in the neighborhood and became
so obsessed with baseball that he had us
playing baseball with him like 8 to 10
hours a day. Um, we put some videos on
YouTube and they got like 10 million
views and still these videos of him when
he was 2, three, four years old get
millions of views like every year still
10 years later.
>> It's a good throw. You're a lefty which
is an advantage. Yeah.
>> So, Christian started making comments at
the same time that he started playing.
And Kathy, this is probably something
you'll remember more than he would. And
I gather you were in a plane one day and
he said something that stopped you in
your tracks.
>> Right. In the very beginning, I didn't
think much of it. He would say strange
things like, "I was a tall baseball
player."
>> He'd say in the past tense.
>> He would say past tense, but I would
correct him. So, when he was 2 years
old, Adam Sandler saw him on YouTube and
flew us to Boston to be in a movie. And
while we were on the plane, I was trying
to put his seatelts on, and he was
struggling with me. and he said, "I
didn't wear seat belts when I was big
and and I drank alcohol and even then I
didn't think much of it. It was a little
embarrassing. People were laughing."
>> Yeah.
>> Um but it really when he turned three is
when the floodgates really opened and he
began sharing very specific details,
things that he hadn't had any access to
that information.
>> One I know is happened when he saw a
picture of this gentleman. I'll put it
up there if you don't mind. This is
baseball legend Babe Ruth. So Christian,
how did you react when you saw that
picture? When I saw it, I got very
furious and I wo my bat up in the air
and I told my mom, "I don't like him. He
was mean to me."
>> We were at Finway Park when he saw that.
He was too Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's That's a weird thing. Babe
Ruth had played in Boston initially.
>> Yeah.
>> So, had you ever talked to mentioned
Babe Ruth? You talk about baseball
history at all with your son?
>> Not at all. We weren't baseball people.
His dad's from Germany, so not at all.
>> And so, you just thought this is a wild
imagination of a young child growing,
>> right? I really did in the beginning,
but then as time went on, he got so
specific and shared just very specific
things about playing baseball in the
1920s and 30s. Um, he was able to
recognize people in photographs and name
some people. Um, so it just the more
that these details came out, I realized
there was no possible way that he could
just be making it up.
>> So you started asking around for advice
about what might be going on with your
son. What did you learn?
>> Right. Well, reincarnation is not part
of my belief system being a Christian.
Um I went to my pastor and the first
thing he said was maybe he's you know
possessed by an unwelcome spirit like a
spirit of a dead person
>> which as a mother that's very
disconcerting
>> scary right so then I took a very
scientific approach which you'll
appreciate I went to the University of
Virginia School of Medicine and got in
contact with researchers there who've
been researching children's past lives
um for the last 50 years they've
documented o almost um 3,000 cases and
what they told me to do is show them
photographs from Babe Ruth's era because
we knew he was upset by Babe Ruth. We
knew some things he had said that would
be cons consistent with that era like
when he grew up he said there was fire
in the lights like gaslighting. Um so I
showed him some pictures and
>> the gas lighting from the 20s.
>> Yeah. Well this was early Yeah. early
1900s. Yeah. Well in the house too.
>> So Kathy showed this picture of Turan.
This is a 1927 Yankees. Maybe the best
team to ever play baseball. And Babe
Ruth is in this picture. He's top row
third from the left. Christian, what did
your mom What did you say to your mom
when you saw this picture? Were you
surprised by it? Could you find yourself
in it?
>> Yeah. I I immediately pointed to a guy
with dimples and I said, "That was me."
>> It's a guy in the top left. We circle
him. That's That's Lou Garri.
>> Yeah.
>> And at the time, we didn't even know who
it was. But
>> what was that like actually hearing your
son at least be able to put some
language behind what he was trying to
tell you?
>> Yeah. I was grateful at the time that I
had Dr. Tucker and Carol Bowman who's
another expert in the field because they
said continue to show him photos. So I
showed him photos of of L Garri's
parents. He was able to pick out the
names from a list of names. Um it was
strange. It was definitely um strange as
a mother, but I really wanted to listen
to him and be there for him.
>> Do do you remember that picture being
taken or details about what was going on
then?
>> No, not too much.
>> But you felt pretty comfortable picking
out that person, Lou Garry.
>> Yeah.
>> In the image. So, there probably some
folks out there thinking, Kathy, you
know, you you're you're feeding your son
this information. There's just no way.
What do you say to those skeptics?
>> Well, I was the most skeptical of all.
And um you know, the only reason we're
really sharing the story now is not to
convince people of reincarnation, but
really just to share that message that
our souls survive death. Um that love
can surpass one lifetime. And I really
feel like if we can start to see people
as souls within a body rather than, you
know, this physical body representation
of who we are, we can have a lot more
compassion. Um, a lot be a lot just less
judgmental. And, um, I think really the
world needs that right now. So,
>> for sure it needs that. But I'm really
curious what's going on with you
Christians. So, when we come back, the
chilling memory Christian says he
remembers from his past life as Lou
Garry. Plus, could you have a past life
and not know it? Stick around.
[Applause]
It was a relationship that ended very
poorly. Tried to ruin my life.
>> Revenge porn.
>> Not only were there topless photos of
me, but they had added a Google map to
my location.
>> Oh my. That's coming up on Thursday.
>> Yeah.
>> Made the cast. We've been talking about
children who say they lived past lives.
Christian says he once lived a past life
is Lou Garri. He's back along with his
mother Kathy. Also joining us is medium
Anna Ramandi who trained past life
regression therapists. So you know a lot
about this. So Christian, you started
having memories when you were two. Yeah.
>> What is the first memory you have
personally of the past life?
>> Well, when I was little, I used to tell
my parents like things. I was a tall
baseball player and that I stayed in
hotels almost every night and stuff like
that. What did it feel like to have
those sensations, those visions, those
memories? Did it ever frighten you?
>> No, not really. But it was strange
because
>> you'd never seen those really. You just
sort of felt that they were part of you.
>> Mhm.
>> And you're 11 now.
>> Yeah.
>> Are you still having those memories?
>> No. As when I turned six, they started
slowly fading away. And that's what
usually happens with past life memories.
>> And your mom is taking you to hospitals
to talk to doctors about this.
>> Yeah.
>> And so you've learned a fair amount
about it. Does it bother you you don't
have those memories anymore or you're
okay moving on?
>> I'm okay moving on.
>> And what makes Christian's story so
unique?
>> A couple of things. First of all, he
remembers so vividly and specifics. You
know, often kids will talk about past
lives, but it's they kind of the drop in
memories and then they're out. He lived
with this. He felt it. This was me.
Also, Lou Garriig is not gone very long,
you know, and to have a soul that is
shared with someone famous who hasn't
been gone very long is also quite
unique.
>> Yeah. It's not Caesar or Cleopatra.
Someone who's, you know, people remember
being alive with with
>> Lou Gary. So, if you can give us a quick
insight about what reincarnation really
is.
>> Well, you know, our bodies die and it
goes to dust, but the soul goes on
forever. And so when we die, the energy
of the soul, the soul has vibration, you
know, goes on and the soul has an
opportunity to write some of the wrongs
it did in a past life. And so the to the
soul will come back and, you know,
occupy another body.
>> And is it common that a child will lose
this ability to experience a past life
as they get older?
>> Yeah, there's an open window between
birth and sex. Um, you know, usually
around six, kids are becoming
socialized. they, you know, they're and
they're becoming their own selves, okay?
And they tend to forget about, you know,
what their past life was. I mean, you
can see like, well, babies will point
and talk and they can't communicate, but
um they're seeing and feeling and then
it goes.
>> Are you picking up anything? I'm not
putting pressure on you, but I'm just
sitting here.
>> A couple of things. Um, first of all,
there's a man here named Richard.
Richard,
>> it's my dad.
>> Um, who says
>> he goes to all the games. All the games.
and he's with a younger female um uh
Chris. Um he's with her. They go to your
games.
>> My stepsister who passed away is named
Kristen.
>> Okay.
>> And my dad's named Richard Bird. Richard
Bird is my father. And he passed away
passed from Alzheimer's.
>> They go to all your games.
>> And he played baseball with him before.
>> But he loves that you have become your
own. Like you're not it's it's your
Christian now. But I'm also feeling Babe
Ruth. Okay. Not Lou Garri. Babe Ruth
because he wants to set the record
straight. He's sorry and he wants you to
let that go. I'm
>> gonna cry. And and I'm the reason I'm
emotional is because he still has issues
with Babe Ruth at this age. He still
doesn't really like him because of a
past thing. So it really touches me that
you
>> Yeah, you got to let it go. Don't hold
it anymore.
>> Boy, he's a he's a complex character.
>> He's beautiful.
>> May not let it go with Babe Ruth or you
may not remember L Garri, but I
understand you're a lefty, which L Garri
was also.
>> Yep.
>> Yes, he batted lefty. So can you throw
left-handed?
>> Yeah. Well,
>> yeah.
>> I'm taking my ring off because I've
learned long ago, don't wear any rings.
You guys throw it over here. Let's see
what you got.
>> Gonna have you throw it a break.
Literally. All right. Hit the glove.
>> I got the children's glove, by the way.
Here.
>> I'm not moving it.
>> All right. Let's see what you got,
Tiger.
Jeez.
All right. Throw us one more time. Put
it down here, coach.
There we are. Well, it's the best I can
do with this glove. Christian, thank you
very much. Thank you.
>> You can hear more of Christian's story
in the book, The Boy Who Knew Too Much,
an astounding true story of a young
boy's past life memories. We'll be right
back. Best shot.
[Applause]
[Music]
>> This next story is going to give you all
the feels guaranteed. This mama
Chihuahua Rosa gave birth to a premature
litter. And tragically, none of them
survived.
But that's not the end of the story. I
wouldn't have told it because Rosa was
in the process of being rescued and
that's when an amazing thing happened.
It's a little bit of serendipity.
Joining us now via Zoom to tell us more
about it is Rachel Merro, the executive
director from Secondhand Hounds. So
Rachel, why while Mama Rosa, who lost
her pops, was in transit on the way to
your rescue, your phone rang again. What
was that call about?
It was a call from an Indian reservation
and they had two five two week old baby
puppies who had just lost their mom and
had nowhere to go. So, Secondhand Hound
said yes and uh we thought maybe we
could make a love match.
>> All right. So, you get one dog mama,
five dog babies. Sort of serendipity.
You're thinking about maybe a match. So,
what what happened next, Rachel?
>> It was crazy. It was like fate. Um we
introduced them. Mama dog, Rosa, when
she heard them yipping, she immediately
started wagging her tail, cleaning them,
nursing them, and they've been together
ever since.
>> Oh my goodness. So, what can we all
learn from this story, Rachel?
>> I think it's just great um that Rosa
adopted these puppies, and I know some
of your viewers might be looking to
adopt a dog themselves. And it's just we
want people to know that you don't need
to go to a breeder to get a purebred
like Rosa or to get little puppies like
these guys. Gosh,
>> you can go to your local shelter or
rescue and it saves a life as well.
>> Liza, thank you for all the wonderful
work you and others do. Second Hang
House, fantastic story. Appreciate you
sharing it. Remember everyone, the power
of one lies in the power you make a
difference. One person with one voice.
Speak the truth. Goodbye everybody.
[Music]