[Applause]
Everyone is talking about system 20. In
fact, on our digital platform, system 20
has been the most engaged with New
Year's plan we've ever rolled out. And
if you haven't started system 20, it is
not too late. Super simple. Go to dr.com
to print the system 20 checklist. It's a
shopping list. It's a one sheet. Become
part of the system today. We did all the
homework for you. Now, today we're going
to reveal system 20 sleep hacks and
stress busters. Because a good night's
sleep and the way we handle our stress
are cornerstones to good health and
weight loss. We have finally cracked the
code to finally get the rest you need to
have your body feel better in 2020.
First off, we want you to wake up at the
same time every single day. Right? This
establishes your circadian rhythm or
your internal body clock. Wake up the
same time every day and your body will
start to learn when to fall asleep, too.
You're building a memory. Next, you want
caffeine at 300 PM, right? And no more
after that. Caffeine takes a while to
wear off and can cause sleeping problems
even if you don't feel it. So, if you
don't want coffee, it's fine, but
certainly if you're a drinker, not after
3 p.m. And finally, put your phone down
1 hour before bedtime. Couple reasons.
The phones emit something called blue
light, which suppresses melatonin
production. So, when you're looking at
it, it'll turn off your brain's ability
to shut down. And friends, there's never
any good news after 10 p.m., right? So,
anything that comes in over your phone
after 10 is going to keep you up at
night. Now, Oz Team investigative
reporter Mars Avoc along with our system
20 test group have been documenting
their journey for the past four weeks.
Take a look.
>> System 20 is more than a plan about what
you eat. It also includes how to handle
stress and sleep.
>> It's 11:00.
Time to turn off my phone. Our system 20
testers have been monitoring their sleep
and stress for the past month,
documenting their success and struggles.
[Music]
>> I've been meditating 2 minutes every
morning.
>> Just gives me a supercharge.
>> Life seems to be getting easier.
I just looked at the clock and it is
306,
which means I have missed my deadline
for coffee.
It took a little bit of getting used to,
maybe a week or so. I'm feeling calmer
and I'm sleeping better.
Putting my phone away an hour before bed
is really hard. I'm trying to figure out
what I'm going to do for the next hour.
Like, I guess I could read a book.
>> Yikes. I did not realize how hard that
would be.
It's 4 weeks and getting up at 700 a.m.
I'm feeling much better because if I
snooze I lose.
>> So I told myself I get up every day at
6:00 a.m. And this is probably the
hardest thing I've ever done.
>> This waking up at 6:00 a.m. thing is
actually not that bad after all. To be
honest, I have way more energy now.
>> Marie, you look very well rested.
>> Oh, thank you, Dr. How is system 20 help
with your sleep?
>> You know, it's amazing how you can
program your body because at first it's
difficult, but now I want to fall asleep
at the same time and I naturally wake up
at the same time even on weekends. So,
that's been great. And I feel like, you
know, there's a saying, there's no
problem that can't be solved with a good
night's sleep. It helps me manage my
stress so much better. Things just don't
upset me as much. It's
>> the best feeling just lying down know
you got a couple hours of peace and
quiet, but you got to set up. It doesn't
happen by accident. So, Chris Tracy is
here. She has been tracking her sleep
with the sleep score app. So, what
changes has your sleep score uh actually
revealed to you that you might not have
appreciated?
>> Well, before system 20, my sleep was all
over the place. I was lucky if I got
five, six hours of sleep a night, tossed
and turned all night.
>> So, we actually you got you were kind
enough to get us your sleep score data.
Yes.
>> So, in that setting, your actual grade
was a 60,
>> which is, as you know, not quite good
enough, like barely passing. So, you got
started taking some of the advice
>> and what happened?
>> And then when I started using the sleep
app, I became more mindful of my sleep
and I'm happy to say I'm almost at that
eight hour mark.
>> You are? Yes.
>> And you feel it?
>> Yeah, I definitely feel better during
the day
>> because your sleep score number is The
last one we got was 86. So,
>> that's a huge difference, guys. Now,
Mar, you were struggling with the 3M
caffeine cut off.
>> That was hard. I'm an Italian girl. I
need my espresso. I drink it from when I
wake up till about 7 or 8 at night. It's
my fuel for the day. So, I really really
struggled with that. But I found that
with good nutrition, you're getting your
energy from other places. I was relying
on caffeine for my energy.
>> Come on. Let's meet because Mary Lee had
the same issue, same struggle and she
came up with a system 20 snack because
you use the list that we gave you. We
have all this helpful data, this
information we can share with you guys.
You just print them out. But the the
best part is this one pager that has 10
snacks on it. So, you put them together
into what? So, I made a system approved
a system 20 approved snack that is uh
uses all the ingredients and is also
healthy and tasty at the same time. I
used uh ingredients like uh flax seed
crackers and chopped walnuts for crunch.
I used u chickpeas, believe it or not.
That's why I call them is that what that
is?
>> Yeah, it is. And that's
>> This is brilliant,
>> isn't it? That's why they're called
fierce chick bites. Fierce chick bites.
>> Chick bites. These are chick bites.
>> Thank you. Yeah. And I also used 70% uh
chocolate chopped in there as well for
the sweetness because we don't add any
sugar. And I use blueberries in this one
too for the vitamin C. And I also uh use
coconut for
>> There's no sugar in this.
>> No, there isn't.
>> Wow.
>> And it um the coconut is good along with
the chocolate for brain and heart
health. So it's healthy and still tasty.
>> You are something else. You came up with
this idea.
>> Yes, I did.
>> I'm so proud of you. Really? You know
why it's good for you? But it the taste.
Forget about why it's good for you. You
would eat these. I'd have to pull them
away from you. Maybe we Maybe we can
share this with the audience. What do
you think?
>> Oh, we should. We should. Absolutely.
>> You want to taste some of these?
>> All right. Soon as we're done this,
we're bringing them over. All right.
Now, finally got Carolyn here. She's had
trouble putting her phone down an hour
before bed, which is actually my hardest
thing to do. I really struggle. So, you
actually found an app that I did not
know about that helps us do it.
>> Yes. You know what, Dr. Eyes? There is
an app. You get your iPhone. I'm going
to show you exactly. Please take us
through it. So, you get to your iPhone,
you go to your settings,
>> and then you go to screen time.
>> Well, there's there's actually a screen
time uh icon.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Then you go to downtime. Of course, you
got to turn it on. And then for the sake
of time, let's just say I'm going to go
to bed right now for the sake of time.
So, I'm going to change the time. You
have to set it for the time that you
actually want your phone to be shut down
or your apps to be shut down. So, it's
and I'm going to now
>> Oh, you it all shut down. Tik Tok,
Instagram, Facebook.
>> So, let's watch this. So, okay. Oh, I
want to go check Facebook because I'm
always on Facebook. Nope. Can't go.
>> I love this.
>> And then, okay, now let's try Instagram.
Nope. Can't do it.
>> This is brilliant. Yeah, obviously it's
important the manufacturers of these
products realize it's good for us to be
able to do this. Thank you, Carolyn.
Next, if meditation just isn't your
thing, well, it could be because you're
doing the wrong one. When we come back,
a quiz to find out your system 20
meditation type. Stick around. If you're
checking your New Year's resolution
stressless boxes but are having trouble
shutting off your thoughts for the
morning meditation, it might be because
you're doing the wrong one. So, we
developed a system 20. What's your
meditation type quiz? And it all starts
with everyone just stop what you're
doing, close your eyes, and picture
yourself at the beach. All right, we
want you to focus on your senses. What
do you see? What do you hear? What do
you feel? In fact, is already at the
beach. She's practicing. So again, which
one stands out most? Is it the colors?
Right. Right. The bright blue sky and
binding sun, right? Is it the sound of
the waves crashing? That's what's
attracting your attention. Or is it the
feeling of the sand beneath your toes
wiggling around because you're a tactile
person? So, which sense is speaking to
you?
The the sound of the waves crashing
definitely is speaking to me right now.
>> I knew you'd be auditory.
>> Yes, absolutely.
>> Come on up here. I'm going to show you.
This is fascinating. Actually, we don't
all resonate to the same thing. So,
you're going to use whatever you were
paying attention to in that little
meditation we're doing as your guide.
So, if you're someone who likes to focus
on a scene, for example, this beautiful
ocean or any visualization, then it's
fine. Then you're a visual person,
right? Focus on an image that you find
relaxing. Fills you with that warm and
fuzzy feeling. For me, it's the
grandkids.
>> Okay?
>> Yeah. Put them up there. If I have this
in front of me, it just relaxes me. You
know, they don't usually lie like this
peacefully, but when they do, capture it
and it makes you happy. Now, if you're a
listener like Renatha, you want to try a
mantra meditation. This type of
meditation uses a repetitive sound to
clear the mind. You want to do one with
me? Yeah. Okay. How about
>> three, two, one? Um,
>> get my note. Oh,
>> you're all good at that. And that'll get
you in that place you want to be.
>> Sometimes though, you're a tactile
person. You prove you like this movement
meditation approach. So, a simple
stretch or a light jog will often free
you so your mind can do what it needs to
do, which is to relax.
>> Stretch. All right. I I do it during
yoga. Actually, it works for me. So, all
the resources you need to get started on
system 20, including a link to my
favorite meditation app, ShareCare. It's
on dr.comsystem20.
Take advantage of it. Stuff's all free.
Remember, the power of change lies in
the power of you. One person, one voice
speaking the truth. Goodbye, everybody.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good