Today on Dr. Oz, I'm being rigged with a
hidden camera to investigate the food in
dollar stores. That's right, you guys.
People more than ever, thank you, are
shopping for the groceries at dollar
stores. So, I'm going in to see what's
what and see if it's even safe to eat.
Come join.
Boom. Today, there
are You love this. You know why they
care? Because there are more dollar
stores in the United States than all the
Walmarts and all the Starbucks combined
and more and more people are relying on
them for their groceries. But are you
making a healthy choice? That was health
guru Jed Weedstrom from The Biggest
Loser who sent her undercover to a local
dollar store to investigate. Let's see
what else she found. We all know that
dollar stores are great for party
supplies, but what about the food? I'm
going to check it out.
[Music]
And I did not expect to find you here.
Apple cider vinegar. This is amazing. I
literally have this part of like my
daily uh regiment. What else we have
going on here? And quick oats. I
literally just ran out of these.
Perfect. Every day I have these as well.
I'm getting some good things here.
Actually, I'm going to check out the
freezer section, too. See what they
have. Oh, wow.
I'm kind of pleasantly surprised here.
Look at all these great vegetables.
Green beans, spinach, you've got
asparagus. I mean, most time at the
grocery store, it's $3 a bag, so this is
a good steal. Oh, even got frozen corn.
Dr. Oz, aren't you proud of me? I'm
getting my vegetables
in. And steak. Literally steak at the
dollar
store. Have Have you tried the ribeye
before? You tried the ribeye steak?
Yeah. Is it any good? Yeah. Okay, it's
going in my
cart. Why
not? Last but not least, the staples for
anyone's kitchen. Eggs and milk. A buck
a piece.
Perfect. That wraps it up for me. I'm
going to go home now and see if my picks
pass here at the dollar store.
[Music]
You look good in glasses, don't you
think? Oh, thank you. It's like a spy
movie. But but you were surprised by
some of the healthy items you found in
the dollar store. Yeah, it was actually
fascinating and I was as I kind of said
in the video, I was impressed that
they've uh these dollar store chains are
they're rolling out this better for you
kind of grocery item list because
they're realizing that families want to
provide uh better items for their
households and from refrigerators to
other produce. It was like I said, I was
very impressed. All right, you're going
to walk us through it. Yeah. All right,
so let's take you through some of the
dollar store grocery finds. We're going
to reveal if they are a pick or a pass.
First up, one of my favorite things,
apple cider vinegar, but purchased in
the dollar store. I saw you grab it off
the shelf in the very beginning. What do
you look for? So, one thing you want to
look for is that know that it's between
four and 5% acidity, which it has here,
which is great. Again, if it's not
working for you, it's not going to work
in your body. Uh, the other component
here that was really important was
expiration date. So, if you have those
two things, then you get a pick for me,
which this one did. A dollar store pick.
She got it. A little more excited. She
picked it. Okay. Next up, dollar store
milk. We have William here who always
buys milk at the dollar store cuz it's
only a dollar, but his wife Vivian is
very savvy and she doesn't always agree
with that. So, Vivian, what worries you
about the dollar store milk? Well, um I
worry about the expiration date. It's I
I don't think it's healthy for us. For
me, as long as it's not expired, it's
good to go. I I'll drink it. Right. So,
we got a little argument here. The the
expiration, you wouldn't buy it if it
was already expired. No, not if it's
expired. because it's not expired. I
definitely would pick it up. Okay. Okay.
It's a smart man and this smart woman.
So, we got already great things. I can
see why you're married. Okay. But here's
the thing. Um I had the same uh
curiosity around that as well because I
think of these items that have been
living there for a while that's at the
end of their life kind of and what I
found is there weren't any expiration
with the milk. So, you kind of get a
point. But I did kind of find something
else. What's that? Do you all want to
know? Yes. Great. Okay. So, what we have
here is a dollar's worth of milk at a
dollar store. However, when we're
shopping at bigger grocery stores, this
is what we usually buy. Look familiar to
anybody? Yeah. Yeah. I see a lot of
people. Okay, good. So, the differences
is what you're getting for your dollar.
Do you want to see what you're getting
for a dollar store dollar? Sure. Yeah.
Follow me. Come on. We're going to get
some help on here. Okay. So, here's a
little list I have you. I'm going to
stand right here. I want to know how
much you think it would cost for a
gallon of dollar store milk. I've got
this awesome little thing here and I
want you to go through and how much do
you think for one gallon of dollar store
milk would it cost? That's tough. Uh you
can help out if you want, guys. Price is
right. Right. Come on. Um
four. Three.
Four. Three. There's a six. I'm going.
All right. Four. Four. It is. Okay.
Whoever was yelling for four, he heard
you. Okay. Um Well, it's a very smart
audience. It's not a bad way to go. But
yeah, but that would mean, guys, that
would mean four of these would be into
here. Does that make sense? No. Who's on
my side? Yep. So, let's bring it
through. How much higher?
Eight.
Nine. Six. Who said eight? Yeah. Look at
them up there. All the women. Oh, nice.
$8. So, although it's not expired and
it's okay to drink, it's not worth the
deal. You're not getting enough for
You're not getting the bang for your
buck. Right. So that's what we're doing.
Right. Exactly. Yeah. So dollar store
milk is a pass. So you both are right
and marriages are safe everywhere. She's
writer. She's right.
All right. Next up, dollar store steak.
Steak. So the best way to tell if it's
going to work for most of us is to let a
couple experts taste it. Oh yeah. Two
people who know a lot about steak. Matt
and George are two firefighters who
pride themselves in cooking some of the
best steak in their firehouse. So,
they're tasting the two kinds of steak.
You've got a little bit on the blue
plate, a little bit in the white plate
there from different kinds of stores.
One of them being a dollar store. So,
compare them. Contrast them for me,
Matt. Yeah. So, you have this guy. You
can immediately tell it's thinner. It's
probably a little But size isn't
everything. Yeah, exactly. But you bite
into it, you would think you would think
a thin steak like that, it would be
tough. it would be chewy, but it's
actually very watery and it's very chewy
and it it doesn't have that that steak
feel that you have in your mouth when
you bite into a nice juicy steak.
George, a couple adjectives to describe
the white versus the blue. So, if
something you look for in a steak is
like fat, good fat content, something
like that. Obviously, marbleization,
things like that. Um, and you look at
it, they obviously both have fat. Um,
but this one, it's like grease. It's
coming out greasy and almost
unappetizing like a sad little steak and
uh sad. Yeah. And then you have the
obviously the better steak which is
appetizing and something that you want
to eat where this is I had the more
choke back. Well, it wasn't hard for
either of you to identify that the blue
is actually the better quality steak.
Pennywise pound foolish in this case.
So, dollar store steak gets a pass when
it comes to meat. We don't we don't get
it from the dollar store. A pass. Yeah.
God bless you for what you do. Thank you
very much. All right, next up, let's get
some of Jen's favorite dollar store
picks. These are things that are
no-brainers. Walk us through them. So,
these are what I call my staple items in
my kitchen, and I was really excited to
see that these dollar stores had made
them a part of their uh grocery list. Uh
quick oats. There's literally one
ingredient in here, which are oats.
Thank you. You are so smart. Oats.
Exactly. The other thing I love were the
frozen vegetables. And this one should
be in everybody's kitchen. Okay. When it
comes down to it, eggs are an excellent
source of protein, of fat that I could
do eggs for breakfast, lunch, and
dinner. Uh, and for a dollar, especially
if you have a family, it it's it's kind
of the no-brainer for me. So, I was
pumped to see that on the on the
shelves. As we challenge natural food
chef and author of Meat on the Side,
Nikki Dinky, to come up with a healthy
meal using these dollar store grocery
picks. Let's see what she came up with.
Hey, Dr. Oz, I'm psyched about these
dollar store finds. These are really
good ones, especially the oatmeal. So,
I'm thinking we take all of this and
make a savory oatmeal bowl with spinach
and corn and pico de gallo and an egg on
top. It's going to be amazing in less
than 5 minutes. I've got some boiling
water for our oats. But before I put the
oats in, I'm going to put in some of
that frozen spinach and frozen corn. And
then our
oats. All right. So, some of this
salsa. Now, this is a little bit
optional, but I had some avocado on
hand. Last but not least, this crispy
fried egg, a little bit of black pepper,
and of course, a touch of hot sauce.
That salsa on top just does it for me.
And the pops of sweet corn, that crispy
egg. I'm telling you, this is the way
that I want to start every day. Cheers.
Coming up, the important thing to know
before buying dollar store pain
relievers. Plus, which of these health
and wellness products is the biggest
dollar store steel? Find out when we
come back. Dollar stores in with rock
bottom prices. But when it all comes to
our health, you know, can they really be
trusted with it? Jen Widers went
undercover to a local dollar store to
investigate the picks and passes for
dollar health and wellness items. Take a
look. I'm back at it and I'm headed to
the health and wellness aisle to look
for deals on ibuprofen. Let's go. Ah,
found it. Yes, it can be up to $8 at
normal drugstores. This is pretty great.
While I'm at
it, allergy medicine. I need it cuz
listen to me right now. And who doesn't
need vitamins this time of year? We're
all getting sick. We need to stay
healthy. Going to grab some for me. Grab
some for my
friends. Jackpot reading glasses. I
mean, I'm always on the lookout for new
pair of statement lenses, right? All
right. I'm trying some on here.
[Music]
I think these are my favorite. This is
it. You're going home with me. Last
thing on my list. I can't get through
the week without
coffee. Now I'm done.
You had a good time. I'm so silly. It
was so much fun. You look like a spy
undercover. Oh, big time. You actually
sort of were finding things out. Oh,
very much so. Yeah. So, the first thing
she wanted to look at today was dollar
store medications and vitamins. These
things come up a lot because they're
pricey. They Right. They cost a lot. We
think they're good for you. Is it worth
getting a little bit of a discount at a
dollar store? How do they stack up? You
know, to be honest, it was a little
tricky because I was actually excited to
see the variety that was in place, but
so many supplements, vitamins, they're
not regulated very well. So, are they a
pick or a pass? Sounds like pass. It's a
pass. All right. Next. dollar store
reading glasses, which you had a lot of
fun. Oh, you notice it should be illegal
what you just did in there. Now,
Michelle was curious about this because
Michelle's notorious amongst her circle
of friends for breaking her glasses. Are
these examples? Yes, Dr. Eyes. I break
all of my glasses. Yeah, I sit on them.
I step on them. I drive over them.
That's right. All right. So, you need to
buy glasses. You look around for them.
Glasses can also get pricey sometimes.
You're buying five, six, seven pairs at
a time and then they take a, you know, a
while for them to like make the glasses.
So, I don't want to wait. Well, that's
actually kind of where I saw a solution
in these dollar stores. I mean,
obviously, I was kind of being silly and
trying them on, but at a dollar a
repair, someone like Michelle could
actually find that as an asset and where
you don't have to be as worried about
what happens to them.
Oh, doctor. So, I have a little test.
He's very interested here. I had a test
that I wanted to perform with Michelle.
And what that is is I asked you previous
to the to my little experiment uh to my
little shopping spree um what
magnification of the glasses that you
normally wear and so I wanted to bring
them and actually take a test and see if
they work cuz if they don't work why are
we buying anything right I would love
that. Okay. Oh look at you're a good
sport. So any any 1.0's one and a
quarters. What are you? This looks fun.
Are you picking them cuz he picked them?
Well it matches my shirt too and because
he picked them. I was trying to match
her style. I wanted to match over here.
Now, the experiment to set it up, it's
it's a unorthodox experiment. We're
going to say that it works with Let's
dim the lights a little bit, everybody.
Oh. Um, welcome to Sha Eyes. Please zoom
in on this menu. Oh my god. Wow. Safe.
Oh, see, we're in. Yes, you. So, anybody
that has glasses, Michelle, I know
you're one of those people. It's dimly
lit. The writing is small. So, I'd like
to test if those cheaters are actually
worthy of the purchase. Doc, would you
like to have her read something off the
menu? Maybe the entree play. Okay.
There's a kale salad for an appetizer
with balsamic vinegrett. Massaged kale
with kale shavings. Shredded kale. Kale
salad with balsamic. This is all the
same thing. You're only getting kale at
this restaurant. This is a health show.
But you passed.
So, are they safe though? They So,
here's the here's the big uh kind of uh
small print. They are safe if you have
the same u magnification requirement in
both your eyes. So, making sense. So,
dollar store glasses, reading glasses.
They're a pick. They're a pick with the
same ramification.
Thank you. Thank you. We'll sign this
for you. Oh, what would the Next up,
dollar store coffee filters. You were so
excited when you saw these in your
store. Now, you actually love these.
Yeah. Well, ear muffs. But I coffee all
day for me. Okay. All day long. I I love
it. I like the way it tastes. I like
being social with it. So for me, coffee
filters are a staple in my household
that I kind of can't go through the day
without. So for all the work that you've
done, I want to gift these to you. It's
it's really the least I could do. It's
the absolute least. Just so generous and
thoughtful and what a good person.
Jerum, a star that you are. You want
more of Jen's motivations and workouts.
You can get them anytime, anywhere by
downloading her new app. It is called
NeoU. You can find the complete list of
what's safe to buy at dollar store.com.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good