The Coline shooter's mother. Many say
you're the mother of a killer. Is that
fair? Sue Clebald. Were you ever scared
of Dylan? Her biggest regret. Do you
think you're a good mother to Dylan?
Could she have prevented the Coline
tragedy? Something went wrong in his
thinking. Sue Clebald. What you haven't
heard? If Dylan was sitting in my seat,
what would you want him to hear? Coming
up next.
Today, a special edition of our show,
Coline. A word that is synonymous with a
tragic wave of school shootings that
continue to plague our nation. Coline
may still be the most notorious of them
all, thanks to the meticulous and
cold-blooded planning by Dylan Clebold
and Eric Harris. Imagine being the
parent of one of those shooters. It's
been 17 years since that infamous day in
April. And for the first time, Dillian
Clebolt's mother, Sue, is finally
breaking her
silence. This is a photograph of Dylan
Clebolt. At the time, he was 17 years
old. And this photo from the same year,
Dylan on his way to the prom. Can you
see any signs that just 3 days later he
would participate in one of the worst
school shootings in American
history? On April 20th,
1999, Dylan and his friend Eric Harris
entered Coline High School with
explosives and automatic
weapons. By the time it was over, 14
students and one teacher were dead. 24
more were wounded. Dylan and Eric took
their own
lives. Dylan and Eric's murder suicide
left their families, their community,
and the world with profound questions we
still struggle to answer. How could this
happen? What was going on in the minds
of these young men who killed? Could
anything have been done to stop it?
Dylan's mother, Sue Klebolt, has been on
a 17-year journey in search of answers.
A long, painful quest leading to the
publication of her book, A Mother's
Reckoning. Today, what Su Klebold
learned as she struggled to come to
terms with the actions of her
son. You've been quiet for 17 years.
Why' you decide to go public now?
Well, the tragedy was so horrendous. So
many lives were lost. So many people
were
hurt. And from the very beginning, I
didn't understand really what had
happened, what my son's role in it was.
It took a very long time to even
understand his role in the tragedy. It
took additional time for me to process
that to get through it to uh do a lot of
personal work around the loss.
And then I started doing a lot of
research to try to understand how he had
died and how what state of mind he might
have been in to harm so many people so
viciously. Um so I guess the one-word
answer to that is readiness. I just
wasn't ready until now.
So, it's a sensitive topic. Obviously,
you've lived it for all these years.
This is a book where it's remarkably
gripping. I stayed up literally most of
the evening trying to absorb the
information that was so important in it.
And I don't think I'll ever forget some
of the lessons you shared, many of which
we'll cover. But you're not making money
from the book. Correct. You're donating
all the proceeds to mental health work.
All my share. all your share after of
the profits. So, let's start on April
the 20th, 1999,
the day of the Coline shootings. How did
you find out that there was a problem?
That day began um very early in the
morning for me. I was getting ready to
go to
work and it was dark because I used to
go downtown. I had to get up very early.
It was not time for me to give Dylan his
wakeup call yet. Mhm. His bedroom was
upstairs and mine was down. And while I
was getting dressed for work, I heard
him thundering down the stairs with
heavy footsteps. He ran right past my
bedroom door. I was very surprised that
he was up early. I leaned out my bedroom
door and all I could see was darkness. I
couldn't see him. And I said, "Dill."
And then I heard his voice in the
darkness by the front door. and he said
bye and he slammed the front door and
left. So the last word he said to you
was by. Yes. How did you find out that
he was one of the shooters?
That process sort of evolved a little
bit slowly. The first inkling I had of
the tragedy was when I was at work. I
was getting ready to go to an afternoon
meeting. I had stepped away from my desk
and the red message light was flashing
on my phone. Mhm. When I came back to
answer and and listen to the message, it
was my husband's voice. And it sounded
ragged and breathless in a way that I
had never heard him speak before. And he
said, "This is an emergency. Call me
back immediately." Mhm. From the tone in
his voice, I knew something had happened
to one of my children. I just knew it.
Um, I called him back and he was in a a
state of great agitation and he said,
"Listen to the television." And he put
the phone down in front of the
television and I couldn't hear what was
happening. But I thought, "If something
is on television, that's huge. This is
not just simply there's been an
automobile accident." And I yelled,
"What's happening? What's happening?"
And uh my husband got back on the phone
and just started blurting out, you know,
there's been a shooting at the school.
People in trench coats are hurting
people. Uh Dylan's friends don't know
where he is. He wasn't in in his in his
first class this morning. And it was
sort of a cascade of terror and trying
to put these pieces
together. It took me the full day to
learn that my son had
died. Uh, and toward the end of the day,
I was able to listen to the news reports
and hear how some of the other victims
and their conditions, if they were in
hospitals, and their estimates of how
many were
wounded. And from that point until six
months
later, I believed that my son was
there, perhaps not under his own
valition, maybe accidentally, maybe he'd
been tricked or coerced.
Uh, I had a very strong amount of denial
about his role in this. And it wasn't
until we got the police report six
months later that I really had to
acknowledge what he had done. What goes
through your
mind when you realize your son killed 12
students, a teacher, wounded 24 more?
I don't think there's any way to
describe the agony that I feel, the
humiliation, the
sorrow. It's it's incomprehensible to
even try to explain it to someone.
The only and here's a very small analogy
and it's probably ineffective but
imagine that you're taking a beloved dog
for a walk and you're holding the leash
and while you're holding that leash that
dog attacks and kills others and you're
holding the leash and that's very much
the way it felt like how could this have
happened? He was my son. I was caring
for him. I was loving him. Just
bewilderment
um pain. so many horrible feelings. The
days leading up to the shooting, did you
notice anything that was changing in
him? Any acute issue that might have set
him off? No, not at all. Um, three days
before the shootings, he went to a prom
with his friends and 12 kids rented a
limo together and went out for dinner.
and he came back early the next morning
and we talked in the hallway and he told
me he'd had the best time he'd ever had
in his life and thanked me for sending
him. He talked with his friends about
his future and which one would come back
with a muscle car that he or she wanted
and um there was no indication that I
could see that he was deeply troubled or
dangerous.
What did you feel? What was going on
when you first learned your son had
died?
That he was actually gone.
We the day of the shootings, the uh
police, the sheriff's department and
actually it was different sheriff
sheriff's departments had come to our
house and they had sent a SWAT team and
we were asked to leave our
house. So we were all asked to remain
outside and I was sitting on the ground
for most of the day sitting outside on
our our front walk.
And all day long I kept asking, "Is
Dylan alive? Can you tell me what's
happening with my son?" I didn't know
what was happening in the school. I
heard through an open
window a fragment of a news report where
they said 25 people are believed to be
dead.
And I I was I just kept trying to find
out what had happened to my
son. Toward the end of the day in the
late afternoon, I think one of the
officers took pity on me and
said is I said is I asked is my son dead
and he said yes he is and I said how did
he die and he said I don't know.
Was part of the recovery learning to to
grieve for your son or was that
difficult knowing that he'd killed all
those other kids?
When a murder suicide occurs where you
love someone and they harm other people
and then take their own lives, it's a
very complicated grief
process. First, there is the horrible
sorrow of knowing that he hurt so many
people that their lives were devastated
and I had that burden of feeling somehow
I didn't know how but feeling somehow
responsible because he was my child.
On top of that comes the uh probing eye
of the media, the accusations and that
develops fear and paranoia. Uh you
become afraid. I was certainly fearful.
I I feared for our safety. I I know that
when I went back to work,
um my supervisor showing me the back
staircase so that if someone invaded my
personal space, if the media showed up
uh unexpectedly, I could have a way to
get out. Mhm. And on top of all that is
grief for your for your own lost loved
one and uh we were being sued. So I had
those kinds of issues where I was
worried about the lawsuits and what
would happen and if I would lose our
home and if we would be bankrupt. And it
was through
therapy. I had a wonderful therapist who
was a grief specialist.
and she helped me get through this by
emphasizing the importance of focusing
on grief. She said there's nothing you
could do about all these other things.
That the real thing I needed to work on
personally was to feel the grief of my
own loss and that these other things
would come in time and I would be able
to find answers. So I think early on I
was sort of pushing myself into allowing
myself to grieve. Were you able to
grieve for the victims, the kids who had
died that day?
I have grieved for them in so many ways
over the years.
Um to this day when I hear anything
about one of the victims or I see
children in a grocery store with one of
their parents and I think look the kids
this this child is just like you know
this beautiful relationship between a
parent and a child and Dylan took that
away from them. I will still cry when I
hear things about that.
Um I will never stop really grieving for
all these losses. I don't think
there was a stockpiling of guns
including semi-automatic weapons and
shotguns. Multiple rounds of ammunition,
homemade bombs. Yes. I'm sure I'm not
the first person to ask this, but how is
it possible that all this could take
place without you knowing about it?
Coming up next,
Michael Straan is back. Now, he gets
real about his dad's health scare that
was a wakeup call for him. I look back
now, it actually changed my life. Plus,
Shannon Dhy's cancer crisis. How she's
fighting back. All new
Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
Every piece of evidence from the Coline
High School shooting is in this
building.
[Music]
Let's talk about the evidence. About 6
months after the
shooting, you're able to see what the
police had gathered information about
what was happening with your son and
with Eric Harris. What did you and your
husband learn?
We had been believing that Dylan, as I
said, was
somehow not quite responsible for this,
that that he had been there, but he
couldn't have done the things that they
said he was doing. When we went to the
police um presentation six months later,
we learned that everything we had
believed was wrong, that he had planned
the attack, that they had planned the
attack together for some time, that
Dylan was actively shooting others with
the intent of killing them, that he was
sadistic and hateful and
cruel. And for me that introduced a
new a new situation to grieve for. And I
think that particular phase of this I it
started the grief process entirely all
over because I had to reframe who Dylan
was to me. So hard to acknowledge that.
Mhm. Yes. Let me go through some of the
evidence that was revealed. There was a
stockpiling of guns, including
semi-automatic weapons, and shotguns,
multiple rounds of ammunition, homemade
bombs. Yes.
I'm sure I'm not the first person to ask
this, but how is it possible that all
this could take place without your
knowing about it?
I wish I knew. Um, I was in and out of
Dylan's room.
I think the answer to that is I believed
in the goodness and wellness of my son
and I was parenting a child that I
believed to be healthy and not at risk.
If I had believed he was at risk, I
would have been searching more for
things that were a threat. But um and
certainly I was the kind of mother who
did search. Uh he and his friend Eric
had gotten arrested for theft 14 months
before they died. And I searched his
room regularly, but at the time of
Dylan's death, he was a graduating
senior. He was a few weeks away from
ending his senior year. He'd been
accepted at four colleges. He had
demonstrated to us that he was um doing
everything that was expected of him and
that he was looking forward to his
future. He'd been accepted at four
colleges. he was going to a prom. I
didn't see any indications that anything
was wrong. And whatever he was doing was
very well hidden. And I did not think to
look for it. I did not know it existed.
We had always been an anti-gun family.
We didn't own any. We never thought that
someone in our family could own a gun.
The idea that a 17-year-old boy could
have purchased a gun without our
knowledge was appalling to us. So, we
didn't even know such a thing was
possible. Let's pursue that because
there are these so-called basement
tapes, videos that you learned about 6
months after the Coline shooting. What
did you feel when you saw your son on
those videotapes with guns? I felt ill.
I remember um standing
up right after or during the
presentation because I thought I was
going to be sick and I want I almost
left the room. It was a terrible,
terrible shock to see that and to learn
that he not only was capable of doing
what he did, but but they had the
wherewithal and the means and were able
to obtain all these
materials. It was astounding and
baffling and horrifying. Did you
recognize your son in those videos? Was
that your boy?
It certainly didn't appear to be to me.
this was not the child that I
recognized. I think um in some of those
tapes it appeared to me that he was
posturing. He was doing theater. He was
trying to be dramatic and tough and kind
of performing in perhaps on Eric's
behalf and on on behalf of anybody who
would look at those tapes.
But it was not the child I recognized at
all. As you processed all this evidence
against your son, did it change how you
felt about him? For a brief time, it
did. And uh there was even a moment when
I felt that I hated him. I think I began
to feel over time that Dylan was a
victim of his own thinking and his own
malfunctioning mind. in in in thinking
that in believing that it was not
possible to maintain any level of anger.
Were you ever scared of Dylan?
And I remember pushing him against the
refrigerator, you know, shape up. Stop
thinking of yourself. Think of other
people in your family. And he took a
deep breath and he said,
"Mom, please stop pushing me. I don't
know if I'm going to be able to control
my anger." Coming up next.
Michael Strahan is back. Now he gets
real about his dad's health scare that
was a wakeup call for him. I look back
now and it actually changed my life.
Plus Shannon Dhy's cancer crisis. How
she's fighting back. All new
Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
Journal entry. April
1999. Dylan, wherever you are, I love
and miss you. I'm struggling in the
chaos you left behind. If there is any
way to absolve you of these actions,
please point the way. Help us find
answers that will give us peace and help
us live with this life we have been
thrust into. Help
us. Were you ever scared of Dylan?
You know, I was never afraid of Dylan.
There was one moment though where we
were having a confrontation and it was
the only time that I ever remember the
two of us having a
confrontation. Um it was a time when he
had forgotten to get me a Mother's Day
gift and everything was seemed to be
falling apart in my personal life. Uh my
husband was ill and our other son was
struggling to stand on his own two feet
and Dylan forgot to get me a Mother's
Day gift and he had forgotten to do some
things that were his
responsibility and I remember pushing
him against the refrigerator and really
giving him a mom lecture. I mean I was
just like you know shape up, stop
thinking of yourself, think of other
people in your
family. And Dylan was quite a bit taller
than me. And he stood up and he took a
deep breath and he said,
"Mom, please stop pushing me. I don't
know if I'm going to be able to control
my anger." And that did startle me. I
mean, it really took me a back for a
moment. But the fact that he had said
that and said it gently and said it
quietly dispelled any fear reaction. I
was a little bit a little bit for a
moment frightened slightly but I felt
that my uh pushing him and yelling at
him was really my error that I wasn't
parenting properly that I was saying to
myself what are you doing here you're
not handling this very well so we
immediately
separated I apologized to him he
apologized to me later that day he went
out and got me a gift and it was a day
where I thought we had sort of resolved
things
in the book. You blame Eric Harris for
at least getting your son involved
in a way that allowed Coline to happen.
I don't I don't like the word blame and
I don't believe that is what I
feel. I believe that
Eric was blatantly homicidal. what they
did was so terrible and so evil. I know
it's out of the bounds of somebody who
is troubled and I know that and that's
why I worked so hard to try to
understand it.
But I think that for whatever they were
experiencing, there was a kind of a um
almost a magnetic attraction that they
fulfilled each and the other
um something that the other needed to to
do whatever it was they felt they were
going to do. Do you forgive Dylan for
the shooting?
It is a very difficult question to
answer because I understand the
sensitivity of that
answer. By loving and forgiving my son,
I know that that aligns me with someone
who was a
killer. In my mind, Dylan, something
went wrong in his thinking. We could see
a full two years before this happened
that he was having suicidal thoughts and
feelings. They were not treated. They
got worse and
worse. And I feel that Dylan was a
victim of his own disorder of what was
going on in his mind. So forgiveness
isn't even really a piece of this.
Do you still love Dylan? Absolutely.
Every minute, every day, he's with me.
Every minute,
[Music]
you wanted to reach out to the families
that had lost loved ones at Coline. I
know the mother that I met first, the
first thing she asked me was, "Who was
Dylan?" And I thought that was the most
beautiful gift anybody could give
me to ask that
[Music]
question. Tom's words sound like a
jackhammer to me. Even those uttered
most
quietly. His thoughts are never aligned
with mine. They always come from far
away and they're totally foreign to my
thinking.
[Music]
There was so much anger and hostility
directed towards you after the Coline
shooting. What was it like to go to
Littleton, Colorado as a home and live
there? What were the sentiments to your
family after the massacre?
I thought a lot about that. I I gave it
serious
consideration. Um, but what I ultimately
decided was that I needed to be near my
support system. I couldn't imagine that
anything could happen in my life that
would instantly overnight make me hate
it. Uh, and it was very difficult and
very traumatic. Um, we would I would uh
go into a doctor's office and just pray
that they didn't call my name out loud
because I didn't want anyone to know who
I was.
Why' you stay? Why not leave? Why not
change your name, change your country? I
thought a lot about that. And then I
also realized that if I left, I would
still be the mother of a killer. I
wouldn't change anything. I can't hide
from this. And so I tried to embrace it
and um learn from it and accept it and
see where this journey took me.
Coping with Coline put tremendous stress
on all your relationships, but perhaps
most importantly on your marriage.
I'd love to understand how you and your
husband coped or didn't. We each coped
in our own way. We grieve differently.
Um my tendency is to be more um
extroverted to seek out other fellow
survivors of loss to sort of get
shoulder-to-shoulder with people who
want to do something and and make a
difference. My husband is much more
introverted and I think my activity
level, my reaching out
um was difficult for him and I think his
withdrawal and his tendency to want a
quiet and peaceful life, not dealing
with this constantly was difficult for
me. And the way I sort of summarized
this, it was is sort of he's perceiving
me to be grieving incorrectly because
I'm wallowing in it. And I sort of
viewed that what he was doing was
incorrect because he was in denial. And
that was sort of neither that wasn't
really true for either of us. But that's
the way I think it sort of felt for both
of us. You described yourselves as being
on roller coasters. It was a roller
coaster, but different ones. Yes. We
were on two different rides. Yes. And we
were never in the same place at the same
time. And that was one of the difficult
things. when you're having a down day
and you feel sad, you want someone to
appreciate that sadness, give you the
space for that sadness and feel it with
you. Or, you know, it always seemed that
one of us would be sad, the other would
be angry or vice versa. And it it was
stressful to always try to find a
balance in this relationship when we
were just wildly fluctuating through all
kinds of emotions. So, the marriage did
not survive. That is correct. What does
Tom think about what you're doing now
writing this book?
And I don't want to say what Tom is
thinking because I don't know what Tom
is thinking. I can only say that my
writing the book was difficult for him.
Early on, you and your husband differed
on how you wanted to address the
families that had lost loved ones at
Coline. You wanted to reach out and
write to them.
He felt the opposite.
How did you reconcile that? What what
did you want to say to them that was so
important?
I wanted to
acknowledge that to whatever degree it
was possible for me that I
recognized their agony and their sorrow
and to know let them know that I cared
about
that and to let them know that I am not
my son and to think of us both as two
beings with the same frame of mind, the
same personality, the same perceptions
was incorrect. direct um I wanted to do
whatever I could to connect with them. I
thought perhaps it might help certainly
you know when we look at victims and
victims advocacy sometimes it is helpful
for people to to come face to face with
with um perpetrators or their families
and I thought it might be helpful for
them. What kind of responses did you
get?
I got a very small response. Uh I did
get um over over time I I was um able to
meet two of the parents who did reach
out to me and wanted to
meet and I don't think I have ever felt
gratitude that deeply as I did to those
individuals who were brave enough and
kind enough to meet with me and quite a
few years later many years later I also
did re um meet another one of the
fathers but the meeting early on with
the with the two individuals who reached
out to me. It was a very tearful meeting
and um I know the mother that I met
first, the first thing she asked me was
who was Dylan? And I thought that was
the most beautiful gift anybody could
give
me to ask that question to not make the
assumption that he was just some evil
killer but that he was a boy and that he
was loved and that there was someone to
know
there and I will always be grateful to
her for for doing that.
Did you grieve for her child and the
others? Of
course. Of course I did. I didn't know
them, but I think of them always. I
still think of
them. They are always in my
mind. And to me, you know, the strongest
love that I can identify is the love
between a parent and a child.
and the thought that my son took that
away from
them. I felt so terrible and I continue
to feel terrible no matter what I do, no
matter how much I learn. That is
something that is very difficult to live
with.
Many say that you're the mother of a
killer. Yes.
Is that fair?
It is true. I don't know if it's fair or
not, but it's
true. It's something I've had to come to
grips
with. He was a killer.
Are you right not to have been involved
in his diary, not to have violated his
confidence? Cuz the answers were all
there right in front of you. I know.
Would you have to do it again? Would you
have read what Dylan was writing in
secret? Coming up next,
Michael Strahan gets real about his
dad's healthcare that was a wakeup call
for him. It actually changed my life.
Plus, Shannon Dy's cancer crisis. How
she's fighting back. All new Oz. That's
coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
[Applause]
Let's talk about Dylan's state of mind.
You make a note in the book that you
never wanted to read Dylan's
writings, his diary. He didn't feel it
was appropriate and you've seen it
written that we're not supposed to do
that, right? Were you right not to have
been involved in his diary, not to have
violated his confidence? Because the
answers were all there right in front of
you. I know if you could have just seen
what he was really thinking. Before this
happened to me, I would have said, "No,
that would be unethical to read a
child's diary." I would say to to a
parent
now, you search for anything you can,
but know the risks of doing that and be
prepared to discuss those risks and
discuss your concerns because the
message we're sending is I care about
you. I'm worried about you and I would
do anything I had to do to try to keep
you safe. If you have to do it again,
would you have read what Dylan was
writing in secret?
I certainly would have, but we have to
remember this was not a book. This were
pages stuck in school books or in a back
of a calendar. So it would it wasn't
just the simple fact of finding a book
somewhere and opening it. So you write
about your belief that that a brain
illness is not a hall pass. Yes. What do
you mean by that?
I don't want anyone to think that I'm
excusing what Dylan did like, oh, he
couldn't help it. he was sick. It's not
quite, you know, I understand that
that's kind of a ridiculous statement.
Um, that's what I meant by that. That
certainly whatever was in Dylan that
caused him to be violent, I'm sure there
were medical factors, but I'm sure there
were others as well. And as a mother, a
very important insight you offer is that
love is not enough. That is one of the
most important things I believe that I
learned from this entire
experience. that if someone does have a
brain illness, if someone is not well,
you can love them. You can tell them you
love them, you can believe that your
love is protective, but you can't always
you can't love away illness. If someone
is truly ill, they need help. They need
professional help. And I believed that
my love was protective. And I think
certainly when it comes to mental
illnesses especially, we tend to believe
that our loving them alone will fix
things and we'll make things right. And
it doesn't
[Music]
necessarily. It never occurred to me to
have any conversations about what's
going on in your head. I never had a
conversation like that with Dylan. I so
deeply regret that I did not. So, if
Dylan was sitting in my seat right
now, what would you want him to hear?
Coming up next.
[Music]
Can we talk about the legacy of Coline?
Mhm. Yeah. As you struggle to make sense
of this, do you feel any
responsibility for these copycat school
shootings?
As a survivor of a child who died by
suicide, I feel
responsible in many ways for not saving
his
life. But I don't feel responsible for
um intensifying the level of
violence. And that's a difficult thing
again for some people to hear. But you
know, I did not raise my son to be a
violent person. and I did everything I
knew how to do
to keep him safe and happy and make him
a good
citizen.
Um, and I certainly have not um tried to
make the Coline incident something that
would be copied. You you write in the
book about Tom forcing the kids to get
dressed for church, about making sure
that, you know, he kept his room clean
or, you know, he was a good boy.
And yet you argue you point out that you
never monitored his brain health which
you say is the single biggest regret of
your life.
Absolutely. And again 17 years ago this
had not happened and I don't think
anything about depression was widely
known and teen depression. But if you
had monitored his brain health could you
have prevented the Coline shooting? I
believe that yes, I could have if I had
had the knowledge and the information
and the ability to see to somehow
capture the level of Dylan's
despair. Um, I certainly I don't know if
I could have prevented a shooting in
which Eric was involved, but I certainly
believe that Dylan would not have been
there that day to take part in it. So,
if Dylan was sitting in my seat right
now, what would you want him to hear?
I think I'd want him to
hear how I've used these last 17
years to say, "I'm sorry, I didn't
know." and to try to find whatever
answers I can and to share
them and to encourage people to realize
that what goes on behind the face is
very different from what you think
you're seeing. It can be very different
and to be very mindful of that. We teach
our children and I certainly did every
way to keep themselves safe. I mean I
what do we teach them? How to cross the
street? you know, don't drink and drive,
use condoms. I mean, just all these
things. And it never occurred to me to
have any conversations about what's
going on in your head, how do you
perceive life? Do you feel sometimes
that you'd rather not be
here? I never had a conversation like
that with Dylan. And I so deeply regret
that I did not. Do you think Dylan had
any idea how much he would hurt you? I
think he had no idea whatsoever. Dylan
had no idea what this would do to to so
many of us. I don't think he did.
[Music]
Charlie is back. There were some reports
that you sent angry texts made some
comments that were a little alarming for
me to hear. Is he ready to face his
truth? According to Denise, you said,
"I'm going to kill you and I'm going to
kill your mom." I'm concerned as a
father and a husband. All new Oz.
That's coming up next
week. Sue has compiled a list of
resources about teen suicide prevention,
bullying, and many other topics. They're
all in her book, A Mother's Reckoning.
You can also find them on
dr.com. So, if you decide to never speak
about this tragedy ever again, what
would you want everyone in America to
know, to take away from this
conversation?
I think I'd want people to
understand the importance of not always
trusting what you see and the need
to always look behind the surface to
make the assumption that there is a need
to look behind the surface even when
there isn't. The chance that one's child
or family member would become a mass
shooter is very very small. It's
probably one in millions. But the
chances that someone you love might be
struggling with thoughts of suicide and
might be planning their own death,
there's a much much higher danger of
that. And I think I want to raise
awareness about that for people to know
that suicide is the uh second leading
cause of death for youth and we have to
open our eyes and do something about
this. Do you think you're a good mother
to Dylan?
I'm sure it sounds ridiculous for me to
say yes, but I did believe I was a good
mother. And I believe where I failed him
was in all the ways that we've discussed
today, of not knowing how to communicate
in a way that would draw him out, um, of
trusting in his goodness and his
healthiness.
But I believed I was the best mother I
knew how to
be. And I believe for the most part I
was a good mom. I sure tried hard to
[Music]
be Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
[Music]