Today, a true crime mystery. What
happened to Ada Shabbani? Just days
before her birthday, the 25-year-old
aspiring actress disappeared from her
Hollywood home, leaving behind very few
clues and sending her family and
community into panic. The full story has
never been told. Now, one team has set
out to uncover the truth behind this
mystery. And they're choosing to
publicize their investigation in real
time, even if it risks their lives.
Joining me now is journalist and podcast
host Neil Strauss and private
investigator Jaden Brandt. Jaden was
hired by the Shabbani family. Neil is a
well-known writer for the New York Times
and Rolling Stone. I thank you both for
being here. Neil, I mean, journalists
get threats, but you've had threats
against your life. Have you ever thought
this might not be the best move? Maybe
we should back up a tiny bit. Uh, I've
definitely been threatened before, and I
guess my first response was fear because
I have a four-year-old. Second response
was regret. But then you realize if
someone is threatening you, it's most
often coming from a position of
weakness. Yeah. So I realized that I was
probably close to the truth because
otherwise why would they be trying to
stop me? Jaden. Jaden, what were you and
the family facing as you tried to
uncover what had happened to their
daughter, especially because there
weren't a lot of clues at the beginning
of ADA's case. Right. So yeah, I think
as in all missing person's cases, you
know, one of the challenges initially is
u with a day of being an adult, um you
know, there's limited resources that the
local police departments um can expend
to handle these cases. So reports are
taken, but generally as an adult,
they're taken um you know, as a
voluntary missing and they're kind of
categorized that way. So a lot of times
the families look to us as private
investigators to um try to supplement
that investigation. And so we often try
to um try to determine whether or not
they were voluntary or involuntary. Um
if we start to see that there may be
foul play involved, we we try to develop
that evidence and and get that to the
local police department so that they can
move the case status to something where
they can get more resources. And what's
interesting because I learned it during
this this is really like I normally
write about entertainment for Rolling
Stone. Oh my goodness. So So I didn't
know till I did this that there 3,900
people. So, if you go to the LAPD, the
LA police website, it says 3,900 people
go missing every year. So, if you have a
loved one who goes missing, it says
they'll probably show up. If they don't
show up, a police officer will take a
report. But they can't take it that
seriously because it's not proven as a
homicide. They said if you still can't
find them, you should hire a private
investigator. Well, they tell you, they
tell you that on their website. This is
not like They literally say that on
their website. It's shocking. And then
they said if you can't afford a private
investigator, because guys like Jaden
are expensive probably. um that uh then
you should go to the Salvation Army. It
says that on their website. The
Salvation Army? Yeah, cuz I guess they
have some kind of service, volunteer
service. But that's the procedure cuz so
many people go missing and because
there's no body, they can't say it's a
homicide. I never knew the Salvation
Army deputized private investigators,
but you know, they I always supported
them. I thought they were great group,
but it just shows I get the the larger
point. Big cities, the police can't keep
up. Exactly. And I know we don't solve
probably half the murders. Right. Right.
So, it's probably worth hiring someone
early on. So, here you are. You're
hired. You're professional. Um, you
start to develop the case a little bit.
How are you able to uncover new leads?
Well, I think initially, um, what we do
is is try to get out and and and hit
everything as fast as we can because
it's very timesensitive. So, we start
talking to friends, family, um anyone
that's involved in their life to try and
figure out and and try to piece together
um kind of what their life looked like
at the time that they disappeared, try
to parse through that and and you know,
try to find that that clue or that
thread that we can pull to to give us a
direction to go because because people I
I I can't stress this enough because as
I'm doing more, I'm seeing the same
mistakes happen over and over as a
pattern, which is you want to wait for
them to show up and then you want to
wait for the police to do their
And maybe that by that time a week or
two weeks have passed and all the
security footage has started to expire.
So you miss maybe that crucial the bus
that was driving by because their
cameras roll over every 24 hours. That
maybe convenience store and maybe that
expires after a month and you start to
lose these pieces of information and you
may never know what happened if you
don't move fast. So you guys got on to
it pretty quickly. How did you begin to
tease out what was happening in Ada's
life right before she disappeared? Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, I think I think the first
the first steps were I mean you talk to
everybody in her her life, her friends,
her friends are friends, you go through
photo, you go through their your
computer, her phone, uh you know,
iCloud, all that data and you can start
to really piece together like an exact
series of steps until she goes off the
grid. So, at the beginning of this
investigation, Neil and Jaden had very
little to work with. They retrace Ada's
last steps and digital activity. I'm
going to walk you through what they
found. On February 23rd, 2018, she
actually leaves the apartment and she
goes to her local favorite coffee shop,
right? And these are all the little
pieces I put together. So, we'll start
off at the very beginning. First clue,
coffee shop. It's called Rise and Grind.
It was a pretty much of a habit. She
would go there. Yeah. I was at the
corner from her apartment and you knew
she was there. Yes. Okay. So, this is
again February 23rd. Now, let's go
forward a couple hours. It's now 12:21
that day. YouTube history data shows her
listening to music. So, now they can
place her. At least someone's using her
device if she's not. Right? Plays the
last song at around 12:48, which 20
minutes later, right? Typical for us to
do that. Listen for a couple minutes.
Right? Right after that, two minutes
later, was the last time her phone was
used that
afternoon. And then fast forward 12
hours later, right, the computer is
powered on from inside of her home. Now,
this is more than 12 hours after her
phone activity stopped. and she was a
pretty frequent social media user. So
Jaden, why is this significant? Well, I
mean that tells us that um you know
based on her phone usage, I mean she she
was always on her phone. That tells us
that it may not have been her that was
using the computer that night. That
coupled with the fact that when LAPD
first went to her apartment, her door
was left unlocked. It was unlocked.
Correct. All right. So let's go to that
ballpoint. Now you also again the police
are reporting this. So now we have
pretty good evidence. Again, later in
that same day, a few hours later, but
now it's daytime, front doors unlocked,
no signs of a struggle. And this is the
crazy thing. Can we have a seat here?
The last text was sent around that
period. And it's asking, "Where are the
red candles?" That's the clue. Where are
the red candles? So Neil, who was that
text sent to? Uh she was uh in an acting
school. She sent that text to a friend
from acting school saying, "Yeah, do you
know where I can get red candles?" And
at the time that was one of the first
kind of mysteries and clues. All right.
So keep that in your mind. Red candles.
You you did some homework on people
around here. A lot of personal
interviews. Who stands out? Who caught
your attention? Well, so after talking
to friends, family, uh other students at
the acting school. Um one name it just
kept coming up. Um and that was Chris
Spots. Um he was an on-again off-again
boyfriend, fellow student at the acting
school. Um, and you know, we were
getting a lot of lot of information
about him, a lot of misinformation about
him, and um, we knew that he was
somebody that we needed to talk to. All
right. Up next, the investigation proved
to be far from easy, and startling
discoveries would place Neil and Jaden
in a web of lies. Don't go away. Hey,
just wanted to give you an update. Just
got a call from Angel. He just got a
call that came in on his cell phone.
Basically, he got a call from a guy
anonymous, didn't leave a name, you
know, a block number, saying that he saw
a
DEA and she was being like put
into the bed of a pickup truck out in
front of her
apartment. She He said that she was like
out of it, like the implication was like
maybe drugged. And then this truck took
off and drove south down toward
Hollywood
Boulevard. He gives us a description of
the
truck and he even has the plate number.
We're back with journalist Neil Strauss
and private investigator Jaden Brandt
who have been on the hunt to figure out
what happened to 25-year-old aspiring
actress Ada Shabbani. After conducting
several interviews, they got tips like
the ones you just heard and they began
coming in these tips. So Neil, that's a
message that Jaden sent to you. What
were your thoughts as you began
processing? It's pretty It's a
blockbuster idea. Yeah. I mean, your
first thoughts when you hear this
message is there no leads, no real
suspects yet, and all of a sudden
there's the entire case and what
happened being delivered right there.
So, I thought we got it. This is it. But
that turned out not to be the case. So,
who owned that truck, Jaden? Well, so
yeah, that that that was a big tip. So,
uh we ran the license plate uh and we
actually Does law enforcement do that
for you? Can you do that outside of law
enforcement? Uh, no. Private
investigators have access to to that
type of information. Okay. licensed
investigators do. Yes. Okay. So, um we
ran the plate and we found that it came
back to Chris Spots who was again the on
and off again boyfriend, the acting
student. Um we got an address off of
that registration. Ended up not being
the address. Um and um we started
looking into some other possible
addresses where he may be and and really
the the hunt was on at that point. Can
you give us a little bit of background
on Ada? Who was he? What was she doing?
and and her relationship with Chris
spots. Yeah, I think I think it's really
important to mention because Ada is born
in Macedonia. She's Al Albanian and
really is one of those people who just
always had that special quality about
her. You can even find early videos of
her baby dancing on YouTube. Like she is
a star. She just radiates. She's on
stage. She always knew she was too big
for the town she was born in. So like so
many people with a dream, she wanted to
come to LA and be an actress and a star.
But unlike many of those people, she
really wanted to work at it, right? She
went to the Stella Adler Academy of
Acting, uh, which is one of the most
prestigious and serious acting schools,
and that's where she met Chris Spots.
He's a couple years older, a senior
student. Uh, and he's an actor, too.
He's an actor, too. Oh, yeah. Right. So,
they're dating. So, so yeah, they're do
a scene together. They're rehearsing
back at her apartment, and they start
dating. Got it. So, now this is, you
know, this intrigue gets a little
thicker. Yeah. So, the next tip that
came in that sort of got you moving in
the right direction. There's probably
one more piece of backtory I should give
you. Please. He has a fiance. He's a
fiance. He has a fiance. So, we
discovered that that he had a fiance.
All right. So, what's what's your next
move now? You've got a tip that his
license plate, his truck was in front of
her house. Someone just said that she
was carted out on it. You know that they
were dating, but he's got a fiance. So,
that complicates issues. Now, where do
you go? Um, well, at this point, at this
point, I wanted to investigate
everything I could about Chris Spots.
But at the same time, here's the thing
you learn from journalism and writing is
you can't trust anything you most things
you read and most things you hear unless
they're firsthand. So, this tip came
from an anonymous tipster to one of
Ada's friends who was running the tip
line to Jaden to me. So, before I just
take this at face value, I wanted to go
find this person. So, I found out who
they were. I waited outside their
apartment. They walked outside. I said I
told them what I was doing. I said,
"Could I talk to you?" They were a
little casy. They agreed to do
anonymously anonymously. They pulled me
into a parking garage, which I probably
shouldn't have done if I was smarter. Uh
they pulled me into the parking garage
and they said a completely different
story. They said that Ada wasn't
drugged. She wasn't forced into the
truck, but she was being taken out of
the apartment in the in the bed of a
truck hiding from somebody else. Oh. And
so that's when all of a sudden, and by
the way, every news report you read will
say was drugged and put in the back of
the truck. And that's not what happened.
It just reinforces how misleading much
of what we read is these days. But this
is actually legitimate journalists
writing the wrong thing. Right. So if I
can just talk a little I made about a
medical observation I made about a lot
of these true crime shows. This thing
called false memory syndrome and it's a
condition where a person centers a
memory on a significant experience an
emotional experience that could but the
experience happens to be false. It never
happened. Yeah. And I study I so I
studied this for the podcast because I
was fascinated because here's what
happened. The tipster's tip was also
wrong because Jaden got a hold of
footage. I'm sorry. What you just told
me was a clarification. It was wrong,
too. That was wrong, too. That's what's
crazy about this. That's why these
things are so hard to investigate. But
it's fascinating to just dig in and get
to the truth. So, he had false memory.
Yeah. And I'll tell you I'll tell you
how that I'll tell you how that worked
cuz I became fascinated by it because
this person was sure he saw a day in the
truck. What happened is that had
happened a few days earlier and he
conflated the two events. So I went to
this the University of Colona just to
kind of research this and they're doing
studies on false memory. So what I used
to think right is that I thought just
your memory is just a recording device
in your unconscious mind. That's what I
thought it was. I didn't know. I thought
they're all stored but that's not what
happens. You know it's it's like the
neuron every time you access a memory
the neurology kind of changes. So
they're doing a study. They're getting
people anyone who 17 people who college
students saying who were never arrested
never had problems with the police. They
were convincing them over the course of
three interviews, making them remember
something that wasn't true, which is
that they had been arrested by the
police and had a fight. They were
implanting false memories over the
course of three maybe hourlong
interviews and everybody was going for
it. Oh my goodness. It's it just changed
the way I think about everything. Well,
that of course because then now you do
these interviews and if you keep asking
enough questions the right way, you
could purposely convince people that
they're guilty or not. And it gets
locked in. And they did studies too.
They ask you ask somebody you know uh at
what uh speed was the car going during
the accident they'll say one speed. If
you say how fast was the car speeding
during the accident they'll say a faster
speed. Be careful guys now that you
understand how this works. People can
manipulate your mind and that'll save a
lot of relationships because your both
memories are true to you. It may not be
what happened. All right. So Chris was I
know not as easy to access Jaden early
in this investigation when police
finally did catch up to him. What was he
saying?
Well, uh, you know, yeah, Chris was
Chris was not easy to to get in contact
with, uh, at this time. You know, he
was, um, he was telling all kinds of
different stories. Um, he had told some
some friends that, um, him and Ada had
gotten in an argument. They had broken
up and he had left the apartment. Um, he
told, um, another group of friends that,
uh, he took her up to Magic Mountain and
dropped her off after an argument. He
actually told his attorney that as well.
That was a statement that was given to
us. And um Ada communicated to her
friends that he had told her that they
were going on a trip because uh his
uncle had died and they were going to a
funeral up in Northern California. So he
he he had proved to be pretty hard to
get in contact with. He was bouncing
between hotels in Los Angeles and
between a family home in Colorado as
well. So I'm just putting this together
my myself. First off, this issue about
the funeral, is that what the red
candles were about? Yes. So, good. Good
job, by the way. I was gonna point that
out. Yeah. The red candles were for the
funeral of uh Kristen's uncle. So, she
wanted them for the funeral. So, she
thought she was going to a to a funeral.
Exactly. And then this false memory show
caught up on this. So, we have one
person falsely saying that an eyewitness
saw her being pulled out when she was
drugged. The person who got to the
primary witness said, "No, no, that's
not what happened. She was put into the
back to hide." And then the videotape,
the videotape shows the truth. The
truth, which is she is leaving very
amically with her boyfriend, getting the
passenger seat of his car with a
suitcase. And you don't take a suitcase
to Magic Mountain because it's only an
hour away from LA, right? So, she
thought she was going somewhere, right?
And she was looking for red candles,
right? All right. Jane and Neil were
able to uncover deleted footage from
Ada's iCloud account. Take a look. I'm
not recording anymore beef out of my
truck. You have beat me up. Get out of
my truck. You have beat me up. You've
taken my Rolex. You took my Rolex. You
took my Rolex. You beat me up.
Everything hurt. Just get out of my
truck. I'm not getting out till I get my
Rolex. I'll go upstairs and get your
Rolex
in. I'll go upstairs and get your Rolex.
It's on the same place you left it.
Please get out of my truck. You have my
Rolex and my keys and my iPhone. No. My
second iPhone. Yes, you have it. Yes,
even my find my iPhone shows me the
address of your place. Do you think I
have it in my house? Show me it. Show
me. Open up your iPhone, please. Let's
look for your iPhone. Open up your
iPhone. Let's see what The battery is
dead. You just said when you open up
your phone, the battery is dead. I'm
going to call the police.
Up next, the search for Ada intensifies.
Investigators get a lead of where she
might be, but will she still be alive?
Plus, a high-speed chase with a twist
that no one saw coming. Stay with us.
We're back with journalist Neil Strauss
and private investigator Jaden Brandt.
So, less than a month into their
investigation of the missing 25-year-old
aspiring actress Ada Shabbani, they
finally find her boyfriend Chris Spots.
So, what happens when police finally
caught up with them? Um, so Chris was uh
returning to Los Angeles from Colorado.
Um, police uh located his uh Toyota
Tacoma truck. That was the truck we saw
Ada in the back of. Correct. same one
that had pulled out in front of the
house that everyone got wrong. But yes,
correct. It was his truck. She just was
in the back. Back truck. Same truck. All
right. Yeah. So, police located his
truck um and he led them on a on a
pursuit and uh at the end of that
pursuit um he pulled over and fatally
shot himself.
He committed suicide. Yes.
and and and not not only so this is
where the it's it's the it's the sad
it's a saddest story because you know he
he may I thought maybe this secret if
he's the one who's responsible was gone
with him. So I did some research and I
found out there was someone in the car
with him. This person hasn't been named.
I tracked them down. I talked to him. He
said that here's what here's what Chris
was planning. Chris was planning on
taking his own life. But before doing it
he wanted to go uh he was an actor. He
wanted to go to he had a part in LA. He
wanted to do an acting job and show the
world what he could do as an actor. And
then the pair of them, Chris and his
friend, had two guns in the car. I just
get the chills I'm saying this gets so
crazy. Had two guns. They had a rope and
a tape recorder. And they're going to go
confront Chris's father because Chris
said they were prepared to torture, tie
up, torture Chris's father because Chris
said his father had done it and his
father knows where Ada is and he was
prepared to even kill his own father.
And what had his father done? Well, what
Chris believed Chris believed and was
tell telling his friend Chance and uh
and uh that his father was the one who
who' done it. His father had a a bad
history and that his Chris believed his
father was responsible responsible for
Ada's disappearance. Okay. And what
happened to Ada? Did she turn up? Uh so
yeah, five days um after Chris committed
suicide, um Ada's body was located in a
shallow grave uh about 45 minutes
outside of Sacramento, California.
It's so I mean it's so it's just so it's
just I just it's again I'm new to this,
but it's like from everything there's
just there are two people who don't need
to be gone. There's even with motives we
have and what we know there's just no
there's no no good reason. Do we know if
there was a connection to between Chris
and a day's death?
Um, what we can't what we what we can
say is
that so here's what's wild is this is
still being investigated as what
happened, right? The podcast is
literally ongoing in real time. So
there's a lot of answers coming and I'm
trying to nail them all down before I
present them. And literally two nights
ago I was on the phone with Chris's
father for two hours. So I'm literally
like we're really in a process right
here. This isn't a cold case that we
went back to. This is literally ongoing.
So, we're we're wrapping this up and
we're nailing down the final things.
That's why it's so almost uncomfortable
to even be on here talking about it.
Well, I appreciate you coming. Yeah. On
the other hand, often times on this
show, we are doing autopsies of what
happened. Right. Right. It's looking
back at what went wrong. Being in the
middle of it, I understand all the
questions. I had no idea that so much of
the burden of solving the crimes in our
communities is up to us. Yeah. And I
appreciate that we don't know yet what
happened to Ada. Obviously, her death is
terribly unfortunate. Chris is most
likely is as well. And I try to put
these pieces together in my own mind.
And I I pay you tribute for keeping it
all straight and going one step beyond
where normal law enforcement goes
because it opens our eyes to it. It's
still an open uh case. You have hope
that we will one day know the answer of
what happened to Ada. Yeah. I I can tell
you because of the data we've recovered
and picked up that we're going to have a
very very clear idea of what happened.
These things never make sense. Both it's
interesting because both families are
are suffering, her family, Chris's
family, and they really just want
answers in the truth, whatever those may
be. So, it's really a there is a burden
on that. The police want to close it
close an investigation or close a case,
but a family wants just answers and and
closure, and that's what we're trying to
get. All right. Thank you very much for
being here. You can catch up on Neil and
Jaden's investigation by listening to
their podcast, To Live and Die in LA.
It's got new episodes on Thursdays, so
check it out. You can find it wherever
you find your podcast. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good