Working in hospitals, I've seen a lot of
things that will shock you. But I'm
always amazed at what can get stuck in
the human body. Today, the extreme
X-rays that you have to see to believe.
I'm about to show you the craziest
objects you'd never expect to see in the
human body. They're going to make you
wonder how did that get in there? For
example, see this little cartoon toy?
You recognize it, right? You can see the
exact outline, the eyes, little smile,
right? You can see it so clearly. So
lots more things like this are in your
body sometimes and here to break it down
for us is gastroenterenterologist Dr.
Rashini Raj. Thanks for being here. You
brought examples of the kinds of things
that you find and sometimes have to
remove from the human body. That's
right. And we're talking here about
things particularly children in general
tend to swallow. They they just get
their hands on everything. They love to
put things in their mouth. We see coins,
these button batteries. These can
actually be very dangerous if swallowed.
pen caps, doll heads, those little
action figures, little doll accessories.
I have I have soldiers like this at
home. Yeah, I know. I do, too. I have
two boys. So, you have to be very
careful with children. Really try to
monitor them and don't have loose things
like this around where they could put
them in their mouth. Not just kids as
adults, too. For example, these little
pain caps. How many of you guys are
always chewing on them like this? I
know. Chewing chewing like that. Bad
idea. Don't Don't do that cuz you can
swallow it. However, all that stated,
are they really a problem? Let's go
through our X-ray Hall of Fame to show
things that are more of a concern. First
off, this image you're I don't think
ever going to be able to forget. I know
it's a safety pin. I have no idea how it
got stuck up in someone's nose. Please
outline it for everybody. Okay. So,
right here you see the safety pin.
Here's the head. And here's the sharp
edge to it. Now, this was just a
10-year-old girl who was using a safety
pin to kind of clean her nose as kids
tend to do sometimes. And unfortunately,
she kind of lost control of it. It got
lodged in her sinuses and it took
several hours to get out. Oh my
goodness. That would have been a
challenge. Yes. Okay. Correct. Next
image. Check this out. This is a nail.
That's right. It's a nail. The kind you
put in wood. And it's not juxaposed.
That's literally through the pallet of
his mouth up into the be towards the
eyeball. Yeah. I mean, when it comes to
jarring x-rays, I think this one hits
the nail on the head, as we say. Sorry,
I couldn't resist. She'll be here all
week. Try the corn beef. Anyway, this
was a young man who was working in
construction and his nail gun actually
misfired. The crazy thing about it is he
did not realize this nail was lodged in
his mouth actually here in his hard
pallet. Didn't really put two and two
together until he had this nagging
toothache. Went to the doctor. This is
what the X-ray found. Can you imagine
the dentist getting the image? I know.
And how lucky was this young man that it
didn't go somewhere crucial in his brain
that this is where what happened? He was
actually fine after. They use a hammer
to pull it out to How do you do that? I
don't I'm not exact. I think it was more
of a tool to take it out. Yeah. All
right. In this image, look carefully
here. You all see the pen the pen in the
belly.
Yeah. So, this is pretty dramatic as
well. And this was a woman who was
examining her tonsils. Maybe she had a
sore throat using a pen as a kind of
tongue depressor. Lost control of it.
Accidentally swallowed it. She knew she
swallowed it, but she went to get an
X-ray the next day. Because the pen was
plastic, it didn't show up on a regular
X-ray. 25 years later, she ended up
getting a CAT scan. 25 years. And this
pen was still there in her intestine,
believe it or not. Now, I know what
you're all asking. You're all thinking,
"Does this still work?" Right? That's
the question on everyone's mind. So,
crazily, look at this. Not only did it
work, that's the actual lettering made
by that pen after 25 years in her belly.
Yeah, it was a felt pen. That's a
company you want to be involved with.
Next up, this shiny little object. I see
it on the X-ray. See it there? It's a
diamond earring. Right now, everyone's
lost an earring before, right? But check
out what happened when McKenzie realized
her lost earring was in her infant son.
So Bennett swallowed an
earring, but he was playing and I look
over and he has something in his mouth.
And I'm like, "Oh my gosh, what did you
just eat?" So I'm like trying to scoop
it out. Then I look over on the
nightstand to see what he could have
eaten. and saw one earring. There it is,
you guys. Here's my earring.
It sure is. McKenzie and her son Bennett
join us now. McKenzie, how did you get
the earring out? What did doctors tell
you?
They said to wait it out. Yeah. Um, and
I had the fun task of checking his
diapers and finally after two days
discovering the earring. Oh, he passed
it. Yes. Daddy. Yes. Yes. No, I'm not
daddy. That's that's that's that's not
right.
Mommy. Yes. Well, he's
obviously very active. So, where is that
earring now? Do you wear it to remember
the the the event?
Yes. The earring. As happy as I was to
see the earring, I was just as happy to
throw it away because it was disgusting.
Thank you for sharing your story. God
bless you both. Say thank you. Bye. Bye.
Bye. Oh, he's so cute. So cute.
Up next, just how long should it take
for a swallowed object like a diamond
earring to pass? The extreme experiment
scientists did to find out the answer
for
you. We're back with Dr. Raj taking a
look at some extreme X-rays. Now, we've
been investigating how the heck some
things get stuck in the human body, and
now we're going to find out how long it
takes for something to well come back
out. Now, as a grandfather, I'm always
afraid of my grandkids getting some of
these beautiful toys, right? Then they
swallow one of these like the head here,
right? And all of a sudden, you've got
to figure out what to do about it. So,
one of the questions we always ask is
how long will it take to come out? So,
Dr. Raj, there was an experiment that
pediatricians did. That's right. To try
to figure out exactly the answer. Yeah.
They were from the UK and Australia and
they actually swallowed these exact type
of toys and then they measured how long
it would take. They did X-rays to really
monitor how long it would pass through
their system. Right. So there's the
actual illust. Imagine doctors doing
this. By the way, the little pictures of
the head and the measurements and they
got all kinds of curves and results. So
let's just play it through and to reveal
what they were showing to us. So let's
say
you're looking inside of me. All right.
There I am. Got to muster today, don't
I? All right. And let's say I take this
little plastic toy head. Don't try this
at
home. All right. It's down. Now, first
off, you're going to see it. There it
is, right in the my esophagus. Now,
hopefully it doesn't stay in my
esophagus too long. This is actually a
very dangerous place cuz, for example,
those batteries, they can do some real
damage to the thin wall of the
esophagus. And things like chicken bones
can get stuck in here and really hurt
and that can cause problems. But if
you're lucky, and most people are, and
it goes through that swallowing tube,
which doesn't take very much time, boom,
it's in your stomach. Now, what do you
do? Talk this through. Okay. So, like
you said, it went through the esophagus.
Thank goodness it's now in the stomach.
You have the digestive enzymes there,
the acid of your stomach working on this
object, but it will eventually pass from
the stomach into here we are now in your
small intestine. Lots of feet to go
through here. It almost looks like a
video game, but as it's passing through,
usually if it's soft and it doesn't have
any like jagged edges, it won't do too
much damage. And finally, we get to the
end of the journey, your large
intestine, also known as your colon. And
here we are on our way out. That feels
good. That feels so good.
So
we accelerated that a little bit, but
they actually wanted to figure out the
answer to the question we started with.
So they created something called a fart
score. It's not what you think. These
are real doctors actually making this
up. It is the mind and retrieval time.
So how long does it take for these
objects to pass through? Yeah, I mean
it's a pretty clever idea, right? So
what was the fort score for one of those
tiny little toys that I just swallowed?
When When's it coming out of me? It's
coming out in 1 to two days. Not too
long, actually. Oh, that's good. And
what should we do if a child or loved
one swallows a toy head or something a
bit more concerning a foreign object?
Well, it's very important. You can't be
too careful in this situation. Call your
doctor. All right. So, like so many
things, like everybody, this too shall
pass. Dr. Raj, wonderful advice. The
other changes happening. Our journey is
just beginning. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good