[Music]
Today on Oz. It's a popular
over-the-counter painkiller found in
many products. But is it killing more
than the pain? What is it and how you
can overdose without ever knowing? Plus,
a glass of wine to help you unwind is
fine. But what happens when it becomes a
crutch? The plan to control drinking
before it controls you. Coming up next.
Instead of menopen, chances are this
popular over-the-counter painkiller used
to treat everything from headaches to
backachches is in your medicine cabinet
right now. But today, a startling new
headline. 80,000 people a year are
accidentally overdosing and ending up in
the emergency room with serious, even
fatal liver damage. Sadly, doesn't take
a lot to get you there. It's the most
commonly used pain reliever in America.
But now acetime is also the most common
cause of acute liver failure. That's the
shocking conclusion in a new consumer
reports expose of the dangers of
painkillers. Taking too much acetime can
cause problems for your kidneys, but it
can be especially toxic to your liver.
Every week, an estimated 50 million
Americans take medications containing
acetime to treat everything from joint
and muscle pain to headaches, allergies,
colds, and the flu. You got it without a
prescription. You've trusted it for
years. But should you think twice before
popping a pill with
acetime? This affects everybody watching
now. Joining us from Emory University
Hospital Emergency Department is Dr.
Daria Long Gillespie who sees acetime
overdoses all too often. Why has this
become such a widespread problem? Well,
Dr. Oz, acetaminophen is so widely used
and for good reason. Because at
recommended doses, it's safe. It gives
people good pain control without a
prescription with very rare side
effects. However, people become very
familiar with it and think that any dose
can be a safe dose. And that's where I,
as a physician, get concerned because
just because it's over- the-counter
doesn't mean it's candy. And on the
contrary, if you take much higher than
recommended doses, you can get liver
failure and even death. So, when people
come to you in the ER and you think they
may have this problem, what kinds of
symptoms are they having? Well, that's a
key lesson is that you cannot wait for
symptoms. They may not arise until 24 to
48 hours after you've taken the
medication and may not even be until you
have liver damage. Even when you do have
symptoms, they're non-specific. So, we
have nausea, vomiting, weakness,
generalized bodyaches, and eventually
leading to things like jaundice, dark
urine, confusion, and coma. Before I
tell everybody what the dangerous dose
is because I do want you to know that
number. Let me show everybody what
medications are out there that contain a
cetime because this is the reality. A
lot of you don't know how many different
places it is found. Look at this table.
I've got some of the biggest brands out
there. All again when taken as directed,
they are safe. But the danger lies that
in that you don't know how much
acetaphen is hiding in these bottles.
Again, we have Tylenol, extra Tylenol,
Alka-Seltzer, uh you know, Nyquil,
frankly, uh Dayquil, uh Theraplu, uh
there's all kinds of roptosin cold, uh
you you we've got things that I would
never I would never have expected my
doll. And when you look at this
different array of products used for
very different problems, you begin to
realize how you could take a lot more of
this stuff instead of menophen than you
realize. So how much what's the magic
number for us to keep in the back of our
minds is too much acetame? We as
physicians recommend no more than four
grams in a 24-hour period. So that can
be eight of the extra strength tablets
or as you can see each of these
medications may have a different
concentration. So people really have to
look at how much acetaminophen is in
each medication. And what if you do take
too much acetamophan, what can it do to
your liver? Well, actually what it does
is your liver processes acetaminophen.
So if you take too much of it, it can
overwhelm your body's ability to process
and start to cause liver damage. So I
couldn't let the show go without doing a
little demonstration for you. Uh so I
put my thinking cap on. And this is your
liver. And these are the chemicals the
liver has that that Daria was
describing. And they're there to protect
you and to protect the liver. So you
take blood that has a little too much
acetaminophen in it, the four grams he
spoke of, and it wipes away those
protective chemicals. They're not there.
Now remember, your liver is the big
detox organ of the body. It has to be
there for you. So when those chemicals
are all gone, toxins that aren't
supposed to be able to get to your liver
directly get right in there. And when
that happens, watch what occurs. You
literally begin to eat away and dissolve
the liver. Unfortunately, liver
literally can get soupy. It begins to to
fall apart inside your body. So, what's
the best way to protect yourself from
this happening without you realizing it?
Well, as we mentioned, you can't wait
for symptoms because you can already
cause liver damage before you have your
symptoms. So, I want everybody to know
your dose. Look at your medications and
know how much you're taking. Do the math
and add it up. And then there's a great
resource that everyone needs to know
about if you're ever concerned about
taking too much. It's the poison control
hotline. 1
8002221222. 24/7. We'll get you a
toxicologist that specializes in this
and can answer your questions. So before
you run off to the ER, call it's free.
Absolutely free. They can give you
advice about whether what you've done
may be causing a problem like this.
Let's go over the risk factors again. I
want everyone to be clear about this.
You can if you're taking the
acetammenophen dose this four grams for
example for 10 days in a row if you're
taking it while after you're drinking
alcohol because the alcohol does some
irritating as well or if you got a
history of liver problems to begin with.
Now I think the best way to sort of
bring this home to a lot of you is to
share the story of a 19-year-old woman
that I have not met Madeline Burn and we
are joined by her mother Evelyn who
knows firsthand about the dangers of
acid defend. Thank you for joining us.
So, could you share with the audience
what happened to your daughter?
First, I want to say that she was an
incredibly awesome human being. She was
an honor student. She was the drum major
in her high school band. So, she had
trouble with her back. She was in an
auto accident in 2001 and off and on had
back problems. And as most people know,
backpacks at school are very heavy. And
sometimes she would be we would take her
to the doctor and he would you know tell
her to take
acetaminophen and um she would take it
off and on and
um she'd been taking it for
approximately 7 days. We got a call
Sunday. She was fine Saturday, perfectly
fine Saturday. Sunday morning we got a
call that her roommate found her on her
sofa with vomit on her.
By that afternoon, she was on life
support. First thing Monday morning, she
was dead. It happens that fast. It
killed her liver that fast.
Why was it important for you to be here
with us today to share this terrible
story? Um there there are quite a few
reasons for my husband and I and and my
whole
family. We don't want this to happen to
anybody else. And we we know that she
would not want it to happen. And I can't
really give a lot of meaning to her
death. It to me it was very senseless.
And if you doing this show helps
anybody, then it'll give some meaning to
her life. And with only 19 years, I
mean, I don't get to be a grandmother. I
I don't get to see her get married. My
husband doesn't get to walk her down the
aisle. And
I know it took a lot to come here. And I
promise you, we will get the word out.
Thank you. Thanks for joining us. Now
that story should be a wakeup call for
all of us. I want to thank you for being
here. Thank you, Dr. Gillespie. I
appreciate it. We'll be right back.
Dr. Oz wants to know, "Have you cut
acetaminophen out of your life? Tell us
why. I took it almost every day for
aches and pains until I learned the
damage it was doing to my liver. Now I
rely on natural pain solutions." Share
your story on Dr. Oz's Facebook
page. Next, sharp tonged and always
funny actress Debbie Mazar. how she
handles the health problems no one has
time for. From quick beauty routines to
eating right, find out her simple tricks
to look and feel healthy in a flash.
Coming up next, Barbara Stryisan, her
fight against the number one killer in
women. One out of three of you will die
of it. And the moment she never
expected, oh my god. Next odds. That's
coming up tomorrow.
[Applause]
You know her as the fast talking actress
from Good Fellas and Entourage. But what
you might not know is Debbie Mazour is a
talented stylist. She worked with
Madonna. She also has a cooking show and
she's a mom of two. She's here to tell
us how to handle the health problems
that nobody has time for. Please welcome
Debbie Mazour.
[Music]
You're wonderful. Thank you for being
here. How do you do it all? How do you
juggle all these crazy things you're up
to? Oh, you you know the answer to that
question cuz you do a lot of stuff
yourself. I you know, as I have a wife.
She uh she does she makes all the
important decisions. And your beautiful
daughter Daffhne, who I adore and uh and
congratulations on your grandchild. Um
the best. Yes.
family, you know, uh for me, I basically
I'm a person who likes to have a very
full life. Um I'm a visual person and my
husband like was such a fantastic cook.
So we made a blog together which turned
into a TV show. So now like we're
cooking. We've written a cookbook and um
and you know I I have lots of projects
going. I love to write. Well, let me
talk about one of your important
projects. She's got a new role. She's
starring in a TV land show called
Younger. I love your character is
actually encouraging a friend to lie.
What's the biggest lie you've told? Um,
I probably have aged up because back in
the day, um, I wanted to, you know, be
able to go into clubs to work and to be
able to be like feel relevant and grown
up. So, I used to age up. What other
lies have I told? Oh, my resume. Because
before I before the internet happened,
we used to be able to say like, "Oh,
yeah. I was in this great movie or I did
this play. Oh, you haven't seen it, but
I was in this stuff." Now, you can't lie
anymore. So, that's the worst thing to
happen to us actors. So Debbie's a
working mom like most of you. She's got
no time to deal with health problems. So
she's come up with some easy solutions.
That's why I want you here. So come on
over. We're going to start with food
because you've talked about the food
love you have. Yes. Because the love of
your life makes food. So if you've got
no time for healthy meals, this is the
one I want you to make. Go ahead. Walk
us through the the number one solution
you found for healthy meals. Well, what
one thing I like to promote is far. Far
is an ancient grain. The truth. Far or
farro, but it's far with a double R. And
fau is like used by the atruskins, the
Romans used in the Mediterranean. So
it's kind of like a rice or like a
buckwheat. It's got incredible nice sort
of a nutty rounded flavor. And it's
really easy to use. Store in your
refrigerator. You basically make it. It
takes about 30 to 40 minutes to cook.
You rinse it. You dress it with olive
oil, salt, and pepper. And it can be
reused into soups, into as a side dish.
We have a soup here. We have a soup
here. So that if you want it to be a
little more hearty cuz soup is also nice
and dietetic. You have your proteins in
there. You add a little bit of far and
um boom. Like it's But this is the
salad, right? The foundation you're
going to make us. And you could just
like toss the far in. I'm going to use
all of it. Just dump it in there. And
then I have some uh nice cherry tomatoes
and some fresh burata or mozzarella. And
it's just nice in the summer time. Don't
dump all those in there because it might
be not not too many for this. Let's see.
How do you know what's the right amount?
It Well, you eyeball. It's a taste. So
here, just Okay. Put Put a couple in.
important decisions I don't get to make
anymore. All right. Half of it, you
think? Is that too much? Do half. And
then extra virgin olive oil. You take uh
some fresh um basil and uh and then like
toss it, you know, toss it. I'm a good
tosser. Great. You toss it up. Then when
you add the olives in there, I know. Oh,
the olives. Absolutely. So, this is like
a little bit of a capras. You add the
olives. And this is great cuz it's got
cheese and the fo is like is almost like
a rice. How many of you have heard of
farro before? Farro. Oh, a couple. How
many of you going to try it now? Because
you saw they've demonstrated more
people. Good. All right. Now, come on
over here. Got problem number two. I've
got a little props for you. You brought
this from home. Oh, yes. It's a little
gift you brought to show. The second
problem we don't have any time for is
these guys. Take a look at this picture.
You all know what that is.
Gross. They're lice. Yeah. Who has no
time for lice? Yep. There you go. You
know, lice is a clean problem because
lice like clean hair, by the way. No,
like my kids are in public school and
it's funny because like it's a problem
and like then the whole house has to get
checked and so I actually hired a
nitpicker. Nitpickers. I thought like I
thought you like are picking on me but
your spouse is usually a nitpicker. The
spouse is Well, it turns out nitpickers
are hired people. Then that's all they
do is pick out knits and like come on.
Are you serious? And they actually
brought this one to me. It's clean by
the way. Okay. Um these are super tiny
teeth. And what we do is we like you
know do your hair. I take a bunch of
conditioner or oil. You want to drown
them because they breathe lice. So, you
have to suffocate them and you have to
comb it out with the conditioner and
like you have to do it several times
during the week. This is garlic extract.
It turns out that they don't like
garlic. I've been told and you want to
put it around the hairline. Okay. Do a
demonstration. Please do. Take it away.
I cannot believe this works. I've never
heard of garlic. Actually, I've heard of
not wearing the same helmet. Someone
Earbuds, by the way. Earbuds can pass
lights along even simple things like
that. Sure. So, basically, you just want
to take a little drop on your hand and
you want to rub it behind the around the
hairline behind the ear. Now, this
garlic, not a lot. Turn. And you want to
go all the way around. That's right. She
was a stylist. I forgot. Turn. You smell
like a pizza now, by the way. Now, yes.
Now, the smell the smell does go away.
Like, trust me, I have two daughters and
they would like not be having it if they
smelled like garlic, even though they
are Italian. But, um, so now and you
want to just go around the hairline. You
want to keep the hair pulled back in a
braid when there's a lace outbreak at
school. Julie, thank you very much. Hope
it's helpful for your kids. Thanks for
being game. All right, there's one last
problem we're going to get, Phil.
Problem number three is none of us have
time for wrinkles. So, what do you do
about your wrinkles? One thing that I
like to do is I have an avocado that's
going bad. I squeeze some lemon in the
avocado cuz this is brightening. I take
a coffee beans. I grind them up and I
make a really nice mixture. What I do
with this is I take it and I rub it on
my skin. The avocado oil actually is
wonderful on the skin. You can put a
little bit of olive oil in there as
well. I like the lemon because it's got
like kind of like a bleaching component.
You could eat the leftovers. Probably
you could eat the leftovers. You could
put this in your hair minus a coffee
bean. Like does it help with the lice
too? Probably not. Probably not. They
might want to eat it or something. This
is a picture of Debbie with the mask on.
She's brave enough to
allow that. Are you not wearing
anything? Are we to show that picture?
Um, actually I have on a strapless
bikini cuz I was on camera. Now you want
you want me to put this on your face.
All right. Why not? Yeah, why not?
So, what I want to do is let's put this
here just a little bit so we don't get
We'll just do one side. And what you're
going to realize is that like see if I
go like this, you feel how the coffee.
So that's exfoliating. It's great. So,
between the olive oil and, you know, the
You can do both sides. I can. No, I'm
kidding. Can I get the worst show? It
feels really good though. Yeah. And so,
there you go. I'm going to just do a
little bit right here. I mean, I would
coat it more, but you know, then you're
going to be a mess. You have to go
backstage, but like, see, like this. And
then you leave it on. What I do is I sit
like in the bathtub and I have a nice
glass of wine, a book, and I cover my
entire body because I used to have an
avocado tree when I lived in LA. So, I
would give all the avocados away. what
was left over I would keep using in my
salad and then the excess I would make
like a full body thing and then you just
jump into the shower and you're it's
like you're like silky.
I shake your Well, I can't shake your
hand.
You can check out Debbiey's new show,
Younger. It premieres Tuesday, March
31st on TV Land. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up next, do you enjoy the
occasional glass of wine with friends?
But has it become a nightly habit? If
wine is a crutch to relieve stress,
something in your life may be broken.
The plan to control drinking that can
lead to a problem. Coming up
next, many of us enjoy a glass of wine
or two with friends. It's sociable. It's
relaxing. It's good, good thing to do.
But what happens when wine becomes your
crutch, your stress reliever, your
comfort device, and something you can't
go a night
without? Over the years, Melissa has
developed a ritual with wine. After a
hard day's work and dinner is done, she
settles in to relax with TV and a glass
of wine. But that one glass can become
two or three, even a whole bottle. And
that has Melissa's family and friends
worried about her
health. Melissa and I have been friends
for 5 years. We definitely bond and
enjoy a glass of wine together. She's a
great person. She's a great mother.
She's a great friend, but I have noticed
that Melissa's drinking has increased
over the years. I think her habit
started with her ex-husband and has
increased after the divorce. Just the
daily life of being a single mom and
raising three kids by herself. It's not
easy. I have told my mother that I think
she drinks too much. That can't be
healthy for anyone. One time I was
talking to her about her drinking and we
got into a really big argument about it
that lasted for a few hours. I think
Melissa relies too much on having a
glass of wine at the end of the day to
relax and relieve her stress.
You okay, Melissa? Yes.
It's on the surface, isn't it? When you
see your family talking about you. Yep,
it is.
So, people who love you think this is
becoming an issue. I understand that. If
you don't mind, I'd love you to describe
your relationship with wine and and what
was it like to hear them talking about
that relationship. Um, they're right.
It's a crutch, you know, and it's
probably not healthy for me.
Um, but I enjoy it, you know. That's my
way of at the end of the day taking, you
know, a breath and just breathing. And
it just makes me feel better for the
moment.
When did you start the drink? About 15
years ago after I gave birth to my
second child. Um me and my best friend,
we both had children together and we
were stay at home moms and we would
watch like General Hospital on a you
know together and she brought over a
bottle of white Dendel. So that's how I
got introduced to it and that's when I
started. I mean I didn't drink every day
back then you know that was just for fun
in the beginning but it progressed.
What's the trigger now? Get you to take
that first glass of wine. It's just
every day. It's just I feel like every
day is the same routine over and over
again. You know, you got to get up with
the kids. You got to take the kids to
school. Then I got to come home and I
got to get ready for my work, you know,
and then to pick the kids up to come
home, cook dinner. It's the same thing
every day and it's just stress. It's
stressful. So, is the is the wine a
reward or is it the crutch that your
friends think it is? Um, I believe
sometimes I look at it as it is my
reward. You know, it's me saying, "I
deserve this. I worked hard today. I'm
entitled to sit down and have a drink,
you know, and it makes me feel good."
And your friend commented on the role of
your your husband, your divorce. Mhm.
And the the way you were feeling back
then when that first separation became
apparent. I was scared. I was petrified.
And you know, I started to drink more
because it was helping me subside my
feelings for the moment. Subside the
feelings. Yeah. But I mean, you would
still get up every morning and they were
there, but it would help me to, you
know, not think about it for the moment.
How does it do that? How's how does it
help you subside the feeling? How does
it help you cope? It just relaxes me. I
don't think about anything. I just I veg
out. I do my thing and I just relax. It
just I just breathe, I guess. I don't
know.
Well, breathing simply you ought to be
able to do all the time the wine. Yeah.
See, I think the wine is putting a
blanket over your emotions.
That's not the same thing as dealing
with them
and they're so, you know, inside of you
percolating looking for a way to express
themselves. So, we heard from your
family and friends who obviously love
you and, you know, and they see your
nightly wine routine as concerning to
them. So, we followed that ritual from
their point of view. I wanted to follow
you with your perspective. So, you let
us kindly into your house. What we did
was visit Melissa with cameras and a
member of my medical team to see how the
wine was affecting her. Take a look. Hi.
Hey. How are you? Nice to meet you. Nice
to meet you, too.
So, I'm just here tonight to monitor
your drinking. Occasionally, I'll pull
you aside for some testing, but
otherwise, I'm just a fly on the wall.
It's the end of the night. I just put
the kids to bed. Now, it's time for me.
It's mommy time. I just want to sit back
and I just want to
[Music]
relax. I just finished my first glass of
wine and I'm feeling relaxed. So, right
now I'm going to give you a breathalyzer
test. Take a deep breath and blow out
for 2 seconds into this hole. It's
[Music]
04. What I'm going to do now is test
your coordination. Raise your right leg
and then count upward to a thousand. You
walk heel to toe and keep your hands by
your
[Music]
side. I just finished my third glass.
I'm tired.
07. I'm ready for
bed. Good night.
interventionist and former addict
herself, Christina Wanzel is joining
us. So Melissa, by the end of the night,
you had the three glasses of wine and
that breathalyzer test, you got a 07.
Yes. If you're driving in a car at a 08.
I wouldn't be driving in a car. You
wouldn't? No. Once I'm home and I know
I'm going to have a I don't drive even
if I have a glass of wine. I won't go
anywhere. Good for you. Good for you. I
only point that out to the audience
because at 08 it's a DUI, right? Uh but
it also to me is a point at which all of
us in medicine sort of say you're not
yourself anymore, right? So that sends a
signal to me that you're sort of living
on the edge. Do you think you're on the
edge of danger at the border? Probably.
And is that something that you are you
striving to stay on that edge? No.
That's almost a byproduct of all this.
So you're not harming others? I don't
think not yet. But I worry about you
harming yourself and the message that
you're sending out. So I think when you
go into these boundary areas, we just
need to have an open conversation about
what impact it could have. So if you
don't drink, if you didn't have that
first drink or the second or the third,
what would happen?
Well, first of all, it helps me to sleep
at night. So if I don't have a couple
glasses of wine, I can't sleep. I just
can't sleep. So I like to also have a
couple so I can sleep.
So, it's soothing you, right? Helping
you cope. You know, you're getting close
to a boundary, but you don't go out.
Christristie, let me go to you. How do
you can you tell the difference between
someone who's a social drinker and
someone who's an alcoholic? Well, first
of all, social drinking is actually
social uh when you're out or with
friends and you're sharing time with
people. So, so social drinking is a
social event. Habitual drinking is doing
something every day, maybe not knowing
why we do it or not. And then addiction
of course is moving into the the feeling
that I can't do without it. And of
course I think the hallmark is how your
relationship with alcohol when we look
at addiction how your relationship with
alcohol or any substance is affecting
other members in your family or in your
or you know in your social life. I do I
also want to say that you do not have to
get in a car to cause damage with
alcohol. Right? That's one piece of it.
And frankly, with all due respect, you
don't know if you're going to get in a
car or not. I mean, you don't plan on
it, but it's the unplanned events that
really change lives in catastrophic and
profound ways. So, if there was some
sort of event or some sort of emergency,
you actually are unfit to drive. And I
think more importantly, what happens
with a relationship with alcohol is it
becomes a relationship in your life. It
is what is between you and the rest of
your family members. It becomes a more
significant relationship in your life
than the people around you. It doesn't
mean you don't love the people in your
life. It just means that alcohol or that
relationship is first and that's how
children are affected.
Does that make sense to you? Yes. You
understand what I'm how that makes
sense? Yes, I do. Does it resonate with
you? Do you see yourself in any of those
three categories? So, as I heard you,
there's the social drinkers, which is
social with people. There's the habitual
drinkers, people who want to have their
glass of wine because it's part of their
routine. Then people who are alcoholics.
Which category would you put yourself
in? I don't want to put myself
in any of them. I don't know. Um,
probably an alcoholic.
Christine, let me go to you. I think
that if you feel that you're alcoholic,
it is something to pay attention to.
Alcoholism isn't generally something you
wake up in. It's something that you
slide into.
you kind of arrive into the disease like
all other great
diseases and that's what's happening to
you right it what I hear you saying is
that you're sliding toward a
very
significant profound and lifealtering
disorder I want you to know how
incredibly brave I think you are because
you are like so many women my practice
is filled with people just like you
beautiful articulate educated ated high
functioning moms running households,
working in businesses, raising children,
sometimes alone, sometimes with somebody
else. It's a busy life and we live in a
culture that is entitled to taking the
edge off. You are doing what we are
trained to do. It takes the exceptional
person to ask the hard questions. And I
love that you talk about being nervous
about the answer because what that tells
me is that you're on the precipice of a
great truth. Listen, you want to change?
Yes, I do. All right. So, when we come
back, we got a plan to cut back on
whatever drinking it is before it
becomes a problem. Stay with
[Music]
us next. There's nothing wrong with a
glass of wine to relax, but when it
becomes your crutch, it could get out of
control. Stop using wine to blanket your
emotions and identify what triggers you
to drink. The plan to replace your
nightly wine ritual with new ways to
de-stress. Coming up, Barbara Streryan,
her fight against the number one killer
in women. One out of three of you will
die of it. And the moment she never
expected, oh my god. Next, Oz. That's
coming up
tomorrow. There's nothing wrong with a
glass of wine to unwind, but when it
becomes your crutch and the only way to
de-stress, it could get out of control.
Today, the plan to cut back on social
drinking before it leads to a problem.
Interventionist and former addict
Christina Wanzel is back, as well as
Melissa, who's currently drinking three
to four glasses of wine a night to
unwind. So, Christina, how do you know
when the drinking of the wine has become
a bigger problem than you think than you
anticipated? I think the greatest thing
to do if anyone out there is questioning
their relationship with alcohol is to
cut it out for say 90 days. I know it
sounds like a long time, but it's the
best way to learn about your
relationship with alcohol. It's a great
social experiment. You get to see the
world that we live in. You know, we live
in this culture where alcohol is just
part of it. Honestly, I pick up my kids
from school and women are talking about
going home and having their wine. It's
acceptable. It's part of it. And it
takes the exception, right? I haven't
had a drink for 21 years. And it t it's
the ex Thank you.
I only share that because it's a gift,
you know, when when we when we learn how
to take care of ourselves without a
substance. And that's the culture we
live in. If you hurt or something's
happening, take something for it. So,
we're going to go into this plan and
just to focus on this issue. We're going
to get people to unwind without having
to use a substance. We're going to focus
on wine because it's one of the ones
we're using a lot more. Food we used to
be in this category. Wine's quickly
catching up. So, like a lot of folks, I
think you're drinking your feelings. You
think I'm accurate when I say that? Yes.
Right. So, when we drink our feelings,
we don't allow those feelings to become
a weapon for us to allow us to be who we
can be. So, the first step of this plan
for everybody out there is to keep a
drinking diary to uncover your trigger
emotions. So, please, Christina, walk us
through what this is and why it's so
important. You're not just writing down
that you're drinking, you're writing
down the emotions with it. So, this is a
great thing to do. It's about before you
take the drink or the second drink or
the third drink to sit down for a moment
and consider why you're drinking it,
what you're feeling, what you want to
not feel maybe more importantly. And
even if look, even if you have the drink
after you do the entry, fair enough. All
right, so we're going to put this very
easily downloadable drinking diary on
dr.com. I think it's a good first step
again to connect with why you're
drinking. Second big issue is to replace
one glass of wine every night with a
social interaction. If it's truly social
drinking, you should be able to make
that reality occur. So, Christina, walk
us through this. Send an email to a
friend or uh call your dad who I know
that you're close to. Or go visit a
neighbor. What would you do to replace
one glass of wine? What social
interaction?
Well, my favorite person to talk to is
my best friend in Pennsylvania. Fine.
Call call Pennsylvania. That becomes
Listen, these are small steps. Don't
cost anything that you can do every day
because you drink wine every day. So,
we're not looking for magical solutions
here. We're looking for practical
everyday solutions for you and everybody
at home. Whereas, again, whether you're
social or more of a drinker. All right.
Come on over here. I've got another step
for you. Okay. You can actually replace
the ritual completely. So, you actually
like to take the wine you say because
you like to get to sleep. Yes. It's a
big deal for you. Yes. To get you there.
Yeah. So instead of wine, I recommend
tart cherry juice. Let me explain. You
like the tannins of wine, the tartness
of it. Yes. Right. This has tannins in
it. This actually also has melatonin in
it, which is a natural substance that's
going to let your brain realize it's
night time, time to go to bed. These
type of replacements might get that
iconic feel of
this without the impact of the wine.
Yes. Okay. These are small things done,
right? And it'll get you to sleep. So,
you seem skeptical to me, which I'm
happy you are because a lot of folks
watching at home are probably thinking
it's too easy to do it this way. What do
you think will work for you? I got to
I'm going to take it slow. I want to
take it a step at a time. I, you know, I
want to adjust to changes. It's a change
for me cuz I'm used to doing this every
night, you know. Is this scary for you?
It's very scary because it's a change
again.
Is the change scaring you? the
possibility that you're slipping into a
darker place with the alcohol than you
thought.
I don't know. I don't know. I I think I
can do this. So maybe I'm not falling
into that darker place. I don't want to.
That's the whole thing. Yeah. I know you
can do this. I don't just think I know
you can. And there are millions of folks
just like you are wondering how they can
put their life together without all this
happening, whether it's food or alcohol
or anything else. This is why I do this
show. We'll be here for you. We'll make
this happen if you want it to happen for
you. But you've got to have confidence
in here that you can make this happen. I
do. All right. Thank you. Thanks for
being here. Thank you. Thanks for all
the advice. You get the full plan and
the information for all of our tutu back
first on dr.com. I'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up, whether you dream of dancing
or just playing on the floor with your
kids, back pain may be stopping you from
doing what you love. Find out how you
can get long-term relief. Three at home
solutions for all your back pains that
are drug-free. Coming up next, we are
bringing a healthy back this season and
want you to bring it too. Grab your
prescription pad for fun and sign up for
free tickets today. You can go to
dra.com/tick and sign up. Did I get it
[Applause]
right? Sometimes the first step towards
healing is to ask what if. So today I'm
asking all of you, what if, for example,
what if you didn't have back pain? How
would your life be different? What would
you be able to do? And that's exactly
what I asked our studio audience before
the show. They went out there and they
pinned their answers to the place where
it hurts the most. Notice the lower
back. A lot of little uh posters here.
These are a couple of them, by the way.
Kristen said that she would take dance
lessons or she actually start dancing
again. Kyifira over here said that she
wanted to play with her daughter with
her kids. And Tanya, look at that one.
sex with exclamation points. She says,
"You want have more sex." Today, I'm
gonna have all of you make all these
things happen. I'm gonna start with
Tanya because of that provocative post.
I want to help her get back in action
right away. Hi, how are you? Thank you
for putting up here what most people
don't. Some people, you know, present
marathons, walk the dogs, but sex was
Definitely. Definitely. I hear that
excuse a lot. The back pain. I can't
have sex. It's really not an excuse. My
back really does hurt, Dr. Well, I'm
sure your back hurts, but would it
change how intimate you are if you
didn't have the pain? Absolutely. I
think I could do a little more. And what
have you done for it? Well, rest, you
know, sit and try to just keep
everything, you know, lay down and
relax, but it's not working. All right.
So, the rule of thumb, everybody, when
you hurt your back, don't delay getting
back into action because it will delay
your recovery. Oh, okay. So, one day you
get to take off and of course, don't go
out and run marathons when you come
back. Just do things that are rational,
but get back to daily activities. is
more quickly you can do that your body
will compensate and take you through it
and help you cope. So just don't lie
there. Okay, you're right. I probably
should I probably shouldn't say just
don't lie there. I should use different
phrases, but yes,
maybe with your post. Thank you very
much. No problem. Thanks. All right,
let's go back to the what if wall. Let's
go back to Ky. She talked about wanting
to play with her kids. Where's Kyira?
Come on down.
[Music]
It's a great pleasure to How How old are
the kids? My daughter, she's eight years
old. You have an eight-year-old? Yes.
That's a good time to play. Very active.
You have to wrestle them down at that
age. Yes. The daughter's a little easier
in boys, by the way. Yes. All right. So,
what games would you play with them if
you didn't have the back pain? Oh, she's
on the track team. So, and I used to run
track. So, I would run track with her. I
would love to take her ice skating,
rollerblading, you know, just do those
active things with her. Come on over.
I'm going to show something with you.
It's called myofascial release. It's one
of the most effective ways to get rid of
the pain at home. See these little
rollers here? You've probably seen them
in stores. This is how you use them.
They cost almost nothing. By the way,
you have membranes around the muscles,
the casing around the sausage. Think of
it that way. That little plasticky kind
of thing. You need to loosen that up and
allow that restricted motion to
therefore open and it'll take care of
your discomfort. So, I'll show you how
to do it. So, sit down on top of this
with your buttocks. Okay. Okay. And then
you can use your feet to balance you and
you're going to slide this roll behind
your back.
there. And then depending on how much
discomfort you have, you're going to
roll like this with your elbows. Yep.
You keep your elbows on the roll and
move your back back and forth on there.
Now, as you get better at this, you can
actually stretch your legs out and put
more weight on your back. You do this
with your daughter, by the way. She'll
love it, too. She wants to do this all
the time. That's the problem.
Well, now you'll be able to keep up with
her. I love it. Thank you. Take it with
you. It's all yours. Thanks, guys.
And finally, let me get the one last one
we had over there in the wall. Kristen,
where's Kristen? She's here. Come, come
on over. How are you? Now, you wrote
that you wanted to take dance lessons.
Yes, I actually used to dance. Tap,
jazz, ballet, even have my undergraduate
degree in dance. Is that you dancing?
Uh, yes, that is me dancing. One heck of
a get up. Yes. What were you dancing in?
Uh, actually, I was competing for Miss
Ohio America. Congratulations. Thank
you. So, do you have a partner you dance
with? No. I was hoping you would be my
partner. Well, if we can deal with your
back pain, we'll dance away off the set.
How's that? All right, sounds good. All
right, so the solution number three, one
that I really like a lot, probably my
favorite, is called the TENS therapy.
So, can I do it with you? Sure. The TENS
stands for transcutaneous electrical
nerve stimulation. There's no quiz on
this. It's a very simple concept, but
it's incredibly powerful. It blocks the
pain with waves of relaxing pulses that
penetrate into your skin. So, our
trusted sponsorship partner, Icy Hot,
makes a smart relief TENS therapy
device, which I'm allowed to try on you
if you're up for it. Yes. All right. So,
get comfortable. Pretend you fell while
dancing. You're on your That's happened
before. So, get comfortable and just,
you know, you can sort of relax your
back a little bit there. Okay. So, I'm
going to expose your back if you don't
mind. So, you obviously we all have
spines. So, these are the pads you'll
place on one side of the spine or the
other. They they look like this when you
take them out of the package. And they
have a plastic that they're adhered to.
You pull them off. And they got on the
back of them have sticking material. You
can sort of feel my finger sticking to
it or see it. All right. And then in the
middle, it'll instruct you where to
place them. You don't want to place it
over the spine. You place it on one side
of the spine. So, for example, in your
case, I place it like
that. Do you feel it there? Mhm. Okay.
And then once it's on there, expose that
if you don't mind. Uh, I'm going to turn
this
on. As it turns on, you're going to
start feeling there's a little green
light that went on. Now, you can
actually turn it on and then increase or
decrease the amplitude. So, I'm going to
increase it a little bit. Do you feel
the little electricity going in there?
Yes, a little bit. So, this is
technology. Is it enough or you want
some more? You can do more. Okay. So,
doctors use this technology. Physical
therapists use it quite a bit. How's
that about right? Great. Okay. So, the
nice thing is you can just change the
intensity as you desire and they've done
all kinds of cool experiments looking at
how to randomize the pulses so your body
doesn't get used to it. You don't need a
prescription. It's 100% drug free. It's
portable. You can use it at home. You
can use it on the go. Describe it to
everybody what it feels like. Um, it's
just like a nice little tingly massage.
It doesn't hurt. It actually feels
pretty good. The interesting thing about
this technology is you should get pain
relief almost
instantaneously. And it can last hours
after you've used it. So, it's sort of a
nice little trick to try in the morning
before you go to work or if you're going
to go out in the evening and then you
don't have to wear it all night long.
You can if you want, but you don't have
to. Great. You want another one? Yes,
please. But that one that one will turn
off in half an hour and you can turn it
back on again, but that's for tomorrow.
Okay, great. Thank you. Thank you very
much. Now, let me give you a little some
good news, everybody. Thanks to Icy Hot.
Beginning tomorrow at 3 p.m. Eastern
time, you can go to dr.com to be one of
the first to receive one of 300 Icy Hot
Smart Relief TE 10 therapy devices.
These are available at Walmart as well.
An audience, I would never forget about
you guys. You know how much I love you.
You're all going home with an Icy Hot
Smart Relief T therapy device, too. We
will be right back.
[Applause]
Next, Dr. Oz, the one. We watch you
today. The only I'm still a work in
progress. Barbara Stryen. I want women
to be powerful. Her passion to fight the
number one killer in women. One out of
three of you will die of it. And the
moment she never expected. Have you ever
held a heart? No, but I'd like to. Oh my
god. Next, Dr. Oz. That's coming up
[Music]
[Applause]
tomorrow. I've been seeing this quote
show up on a lot of your Instagram and
Facebook pages. She believed she could,
so she did. Think about that. I really
love how you're embracing this
philosophy. Makes me think of my wife,
daughters, even my granddaughter Felo,
and how they're going to accomplish lots
of things in their lives. Thinking about
that mantra. Remember, whether you're
dealing with an extra 5 lbs or really
big obstacle, you have the power and
only you have the power to transform
thought into action. It all starts with
believing in yourself. And I'm putting
this inspirational code up on dr.com.
Log on and share what you believe you
could accomplish and what you have done
and plan to do in the future. Now, it's
time for in case you missed it. Today, a
big reality check for those of you who
lean on wine as a crutch. Many of us
drink the occasional glass with a nice
meal when socializing with friends. But
when you start to need it for stress
relief and comfort, then things could
get out of control. So today, we gave
you a plan to cut back on social
drinking before it becomes a problem.
This is unlike any other plan because
it's going to help you assess your
relationship with drinking. And a great
way to gauge that is to keep a drinking
diary. You can download it on dr.com
right now. And here's how you're going
to do it. You're going to write down the
number of drinks you have every day.
Next to each one, write down the feeling
you were having, experiencing. Were you
sad, happy, stressed? What were you
feeling when you had the wine? It's
going to help you identify why using
this as a crush. Remember, social
drinking is supposed to be social. So,
we also gave you the insight that you
should try to be more social instead of
drinking. Maybe you can replace one for
the other. Finally, please be careful of
dubious people online that make it seem
like I'm endorsing their products
because they don't. To see a full list
of our trusted sponsorship partners,
please go to dr.com and I'll see you
next time.
[Music]
[Applause]