Now with zero calories. Fun fruit
flavors. A healthy hydrator available
now. You've seen headlines. Flavored no
calorie water. Just how natural are the
natural flavors inside? And are these
hidden additives causing you to gain
weight? What's in your flavored water?
Our investigation uncovers startling new
information. Plus, the health guru who
eats 5,000 calories in just one meal.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you, Becca.
[Music]
Over the last 10 years, we've been
investigating artificial sweeteners and
weight gain. And you as the smartest
audience in television switch from sodas
and diet sodas to drinking more of these
clear flavored waters. They look so
pure. But could what's in them actually
be crashing your
diet? Today the truth about no calorie
flavored waters. Are the additives in
them making you gain weight? Plus the
biggest food mystery out there. What are
the natural flavors inside these drinks?
Now no calorie flavored waters. You know
these you've heard of them all right?
They come in all kinds of flavors.
There's lemon, there's limes, there's
mangoes. From carbonated distilled
versions. And we spend more than $2
billion on these drinks a year. That's
what we spent last year. So, who who
here is obsessed with these no calorie
flavored beverages? Well, you got some
hands up here. Why do you like them so
much? They taste good. I hate water.
Yeah, it's boring, isn't it? Yeah, that
one makes me feel good, too. Who thinks
water's
boring? Enough
people. You What do you love about them?
Yeah. So, I used to drink a lot of diet
soda. Like, diet soda was my crutch. So,
I decided to try flavored water thinking
it was a better alternative, not
knowing, you know, how unhealthy it
could possibly be. Is anyone here
worried about the issue of the flavor?
How do they make this thing taste like
passion fruit? I mean, without any
calories, because if I eat the passion
fruit, there'd be calories in it. Well,
I love water. So, I decided, let me try
some flavored water. My favorite is
watermelon flavored water. But I'm
thinking, how is watermelon flavored
water actually have zero calories? How
is that? That should be dawning on all
of us as a major concern cuz when it's
too good to be true, it often is. To
help me investigate these drinks,
Kellyanne Patruchi, that's a present for
you. And these drinks are zero calories,
but that doesn't mean they have zero
effect on your health. No, it doesn't.
Just because it says zero calories does
not give you a free pass. Now, I know
that we're using a lot of these drinks
and and consuming them because they're
healthier than some of the alternatives.
And in some cases, they are. But here's
what we have to watch for. There's a lot
of hidden additives in these. So, it's a
way of getting things in your diet that
you don't want and you don't even know
it. So, we have to be careful and watch
this. You all with me on this? As
anxious as you might be, as we're
learning about this, my med team and
Kellyanne scoured the market, analyzed
the no calorie flavored waters out
there. One of the surprising ingredients
we uncovered were artificial sweeteners.
Some of them were the same ones you find
in diet soda, which is the exact
opposite of why people are switching to
these. You know, the med team and I
expected to find things like aspartame,
maybe a little little of that. But what
we were blown away to find is there's
artificial sweeteners all over these
drinks. And that's just like, you know,
drinking diet soda or anything else that
we're really trying to switch to
healthier options. So, they're all
created equal. I like the move in
general, but artificial sweeteners like
sucralose, right, are hot topics in the
world of nutrition. And we ought to know
about this before we make our choices.
And if we don't like what we're hearing,
buy something else that doesn't have
that in there. So, what's the deal with
sucralose and weight gain and these
other artificial sweeteners? Yeah. So,
this is a really interesting and
evolving topic because you'd think,
okay, zero calories, we know it's going
to show a correlation to weight loss,
but not all the studies do. Some of them
show a correlation actually to weight
gain. And we have to think about this
really intelligently. And here's how.
Our bodies are really smart. It's very
hard to outsmart the body. So if we're
getting this intense hit of sweetness
and no calories to back it up, that
confuses the brain and it confuses the
body. And that's never a good thing. Let
me a little animation to see how this
plays out. Thank you very much. Y in
real life, this is what ends up
happening. All right. You're sitting
there, you're enjoying yourself and
normally, right, you see something
that's got sugar in it, right? Like for
example, the chocolates you love or the
donut you enjoy in the morning and your
brain knows when you've had enough of
this real sugar, right? And it shuts off
your sweet tooth. That's how it's
supposed to work. But when you consume
drinks with artificial sweeteners in
them, your brain doesn't seem to get the
right signal that you've had enough of
the sugar you want. Right? Your tongue
tastes the sweetness, but your brain
knows better. It's too smart. It knows
and can sense that it's a different
feeling, right? It's not the same
satiety that it gets with real sugar.
So, it sends you out there looking,
forging for more of these sweets, high
and low, and soon you're surrounded by
them. So, we love to test things out
here on the show. So, we did our own
little social experiment I think you'll
enjoy, right? Could the artificial
sweeteners in these drinks actually be
increasing your cravings? That was the
question. So, for two days, right, this
little social experiment on no calorie
flavored waters was conducted. And for
the first two days, we asked people to
drink plain water and they just added
their own lemon, right? simple, easy,
and pretty inexpensive. The following
two days, we asked them to drink a
nocalorie lemon flavored water like you
might go out and buy in a store, right?
Each day, they rated their cravings on a
scale from one to five, right? Five
being the most intense cravings and one,
I don't even care anymore, right? So, we
want to see if the number stayed low or
high with these two options. So, let's
bring in Alexis. How are you, Alexis?
Hi. You were one of our experimentes.
Yes.
So, you did you did it the way we asked
you to do it for four days. Okay. Are
you curious about this? Very right here
are the results. Again, we're just
looking to see whether we're getting a
good deal for this move. First off, when
people in the first two days just had
water with lemon, their craving
intensity, remember one means I don't
care. Five is I got to have something
was a two. All right. For the second two
days, when you switched to a lemon
flavored water, your craving intensity
went up to
3.5. Went all the way up to a number
that's much more concerning to me
because you probably were experiencing
more cravings. I don't know. Did did you
did you sense this in your own life?
100%. When I was doing just the water
with uh pure actual lemon, it was like
very satisfying the flavor itself. I
found myself not snacking as much,
sticking to, you know, three meals a
day. And then as soon as I went over and
did the like the lemon flavored water, I
was snacking everywhere. I was ravenous.
I was looking for sweet and salty and
all that different stuff. And in my own
personal life, I found this as well. And
you know, lemon water is an old
treatment in ayurveetic medicine,
thousands of years old. This is not
thousands of years old. And I'm not
against all these. I think there's some
probably reasonable products out there,
and I know it's convenient. But there's
one other little thing I got to get to.
When you do look at the ingredients, you
see carbonated water and then this
thing, natural
flavors. What does that mean to you,
Alexis? Well, I hope that it means that
everything in it is derived naturally.
We're going to find out cuz up next, the
biggest food mystery lighting up the
internet. What's in your flavored water
that makes it taste like a lemon or a
lime? Stick
[Applause]
[Music]
around. Eye drops. They seem harmless
enough, but did one woman use them as
the ultimate murder weapon? You won't
believe your eyes. A true crime
investigation. All new
Oz. That's coming up tomorrow.
We've been investigating the truth about
the no calorie flavored waters that are
all over the place. Now, no matter if
it's grapefruit or raspberry or lemon or
lime, you won't find fruit on the
ingredient label. But what you will find
is a mystery ingredient, natural
flavors. Now, I along with everyone else
online was curious to know what that
mean. So, we asked a food scientist to
uncover the science behind natural
flavors. But first, I've got some
audience members here. Come on in, guys.
I want them to talk about their favorite
lowc calorie waters. So, Melody, what do
you enjoy drinking? Grapefruit.
Absolutely. Isn't this cool? And
Shannon, what do you enjoy? My favorite
is passion fruit. So, grapefruit and
passion fruit. Right. Now, these have
calories in them. Right. So, Shannon, do
you ever wonder how this beautiful
passion fruit gets into that passion
fruit no calorie water without any
calories getting in there? I do. I
always think about that and I'm always
wondering what's the healthier options,
what's the more natural alternative. So,
I'm interested to find out. Yeah, I
always figure if you just squirt a
little bit in there, you might get five
calories. That's at least you know what
you're dealing with. But having this
pre-made for you with zero calories is
attractive. So, pay attention. You'll
enjoy this. Food scientists Taylor
Wallace and nutritionist Kelly and
Patruchi are here to tell us what they
uncovered about natural flavors. And
remember, these nocalorie drinks aren't
using fruit juice, right? There's no
fruit juice in the ingredients label.
So, how do they get the taste there? So,
when they say natural flavors, they
actually do come from a natural source,
but it's a process and it begins in a
lab. And so, here's what happens. The
food scientists will take a natural food
like this fruit, and they'll put it in a
big machine, and I have to tell you,
it's called a still, and this is a big
whopper, a huge machine. They'll put it
at a certain temperature, prescribed
temperature for a certain period of
time. And at the end of that, it comes
out like you see here. And this end
product is actually really concentrated
and all of the nutri all the nutrition
has been stripped away. So you can
clearly feel that this is probably not
going to taste good at this point. So
what they do is they add in some extra
flavor, maybe some, you know, herb or a
bark or another fruit essence. They add
that in here so you get the taste you
want. So the point being, if you are
drinking some kind of drink that's
supposed to be grapefruit flavored, it
may not actually come from a grapefruit.
Not fully. Not fully. Tell you
experimented with some of these natural
flavors in your food science lab. So
show them what you uncovered here. And
this is a pretty concrete example of how
this would be done in the laboratory.
Absolutely. So most companies aren't
going to tell you exactly what's in
their natural flavor because they have
their own recipes. So I took a flashback
to graduate school, Dr. draws and I put
on my food chemistry hat, went into the
lab and made us a couple of examples.
Now, the goal here is to really make the
flavors pop in your mouth, right? We
want to give you that experience of
biting into the orange, but we don't do
that with just one flavor. So, the first
drink that I'm going to show you, you
can take a sip, uh, just has that one
orange flavor in it. And as you'll see,
it's very subtle, right? I mean, the
word blend comes to mind, right? It's
like water with someone dripped a couple
droplets of orange juice in there.
Exactly. So, for the second drink, what
I did is I extracted some flavors from
the orange peel, the oils that are
naturally in the orange, and then I
added a little bit of phosphoric acid to
give it a little tang and really kick
those flavors up a notch. This is
fantastic. Yeah. Right. Really, really
good. See, you you invite me and
Kellyanne to your Christmas party and
I'll bring the eggnog. I'll bring the
alcohol. But but but so so back to the
issue about these natural flavors and
why it's this grabag term. Is it purely
because it's a secret recipe that they
don't publish it? Well, so there's a
number of reasons why we don't label it
on the food label. One, as food
scientists, we want to keep the label as
clean as possible. So like Kellyanne
said, we want you to focus on the amount
of calories or the amount of sugar
that's actually in products. Uh the
second reason is because uh flavorists
like my friend Stacy travel all over the
world to find the newest exciting exotic
flavor so that they can go back in the
lab and blend them and make the next
creative innovation of flavored waters
for you. They don't want somebody
stealing that and knocking it off. So
therefore, because it's all from natural
products, the FDA just requires that you
label it as natural flavor. So let me
cut to the chase. Are they safe?
Absolutely. In fact, they're used in
such small quantities, they don't make
an impact on any type of health outcome.
Now, here's what's interesting about
natural flavors. Natural really does
mean natural. So, they can come from a
fruit, a vegetable, an herb, or a spice.
My favorite vanilla natural extract
actually comes from uh beaver anal
glands.
Beaver anal glands. And it actually
tastes really great. What do you guys
think about that? Beaver Beaver anal
glands. even if it tastes great. And so
you you can actually mix that with other
flavors and actually get a raspberry
flavor out of that. Now, for most of you
all who are really grossed out with
that, we don't actually sell a lot of
those pro products on the grocery store
shelf because one, it's expensive to do
and two, we don't really have a lot of
beavers, you know, just kind of hanging
out around here. What a terrible job to
have. We harvest beaver anal glands,
right? Come on over here. So, Kill Hian.
Yeah. What do we pay attention to when
we're buying these these these flavored
waters that have no calories in them?
There's just one word we all have to
keep in mind. The big buzzword I want
this to be so prominent in everyone's
brain when they're looking for these
natural flavors. That's why we don't
want to get any of the artificial stuff.
It's simple. These are natural flavors.
It actually works for this. Now, Taylor,
if you prefer unflavored seltzer, you
got a little tool for us. Little hack
because I actually if I had my brothers
would only drink that. But I get that
you get bored of just a plain old water.
So, help me bump it up a little bit.
Hack it for me. Okay. Well, let's bring
a little food chemistry into your own
household. You can take those oranges,
uh maybe a little bit of mint or lime
and muddle those together because again,
you want to let those uh oils escape
from the food like a mojito. Yeah. And
you can even actually cook them on top
of the stove for, you know, one or two
minutes to help bring those flavors out
again. Uh then add more water, dilute it
out, let it set overnight. Uh the next
day you can filter it through a coffee
filter to get rid of all the solids and
voila, it's your first step to becoming
a food scientist. Who want to taste
this? Who's up for this? Here you go.
Why not give it a shot? This is my
little gift to you. This is how we ought
to be doing it if you want to avoid
anything. But at least you know what to
look for. You share it down the aisle.
Up next, can you really eat 5,000
calories of junk food in one meal?
Can you and lose weight? It's not about
whether you can do it. Can you actually
do it and lose weight? Think about that.
We'll be right
[Music]
back. Now, you know how much I love
yogurt. But did you know just how much
sugar oo could be added to just one cup?
All
new. That's coming up on Wednesday.
[Music]
This meal is super
filling. That was actually chicken gravy
mash. And that's not all. Imagine eating
all these epic meals. These are real
meals. Has eaten giant fries, onion ring
sandwich, right? a three-p pound pastry,
right? That's pretty large. And a
ginormous mac and cheese steak sort of
looks like this thing I got behind me. I
got closeup of it there. Look at that.
But yet, despite that, this Instagram
sensations gone viral for his health.
Secret to losing more than 60 pounds.
That's in before, and that's after. And
that's really his physique. Blake Horton
says he eats 5,000 calories in one meal
just once a day. It's not just a fitness
fanatics trick, guys. There are women
who are trying this as well, more and
more. Today we're investigating this new
extreme form of internet rather
intermittent fasting that's all over the
internet. Can you really eat all those
calories in one sitting and lose weight?
And here's the other question. Is it
even healthy? Please welcome Blake. I
got to say, you have captured the
nation's attention. Half a million
people watch you eat every night. I've
witnessed this myself. Why are you so
passionate about how you eat your food?
When I figured out how to eat what seems
like a cheat meal every night before bed
and lose weight and get all your daily
nutrients at the same time, there's no
reason not to be hooked and also no
longer get hungry. So, I just we're
going to get into all these bits because
it's it's it's so much so different from
any of us thought was possible. But how
did you learn about this? Who taught you
you could even try this? I was losing
weight um eating small meals spread out
throughout the day, which I was
miserable. You know, when you understand
your caloric budget and you're counting
calories and you try to spread it out
over three, four, five meals, shakes,
snacks, you have like you're calorically
broke. You have no budget, right? And
when you shrink that down, I read about
intermittent fasting and it said you can
eat fewer meals, same daily caloric
allowance,
reduce
hunger, go to bed happy and and full,
right, with a giant food baby and
continue to the same progress. So I
decided to test it out and I took it to
everything I do is like to an extreme. I
took it I'm sensing that. Yeah. So, I
got really creative with it and I
reduced it to one meal a day, which I
didn't know anybody at the time like who
was doing that. So, the longer you wait
to eat, once you get used to it, you
don't you no longer get hungry. If you
eat in like a 4hour time period, all
your calories, all your nutrients in a 4
hour time period, you're not going to be
hungry. Not nearly as much as if you did
three meals or four, five, six, like the
Let's Let's kick the tires on this.
We're going to investigate first of all
what Blake's eating to lose weight. So,
walk me through your meal plan and just
bring everyone up to speed of of why you
would eat this. And just to be clear,
okay, this is what it actually looks
like on the Instagram feed. But all of
these things went into this. So, take
your time. Explain what this is. And
this is about 5,000 calories we
calculated. This is this is a little bit
higher calorie. I believe mine was uh
was around 4,000 calories. But I see I
do see a lot of oil here, which I didn't
have on mine. Oh, okay. Here, I'll fix
that. If you could just Yeah. Yeah.
There we are. Okay. It's 4,000 calories.
So, this is all 4,000 calories in here.
All right. There you go. Yeah. I didn't
recognize that. So, what do we have? We
had some um salad and vegetables. Yeah,
we had about four pounds of vegetables.
Everybody asked if I eat fruits and
vegetables. Most of my meals have like
four pounds of vegetables or like three
pounds of fruit. But everyone sees the
cheese sauce, the dressing. Um, and this
it's some some low calorie uh cheese
sauce. What about the f French fries?
They're not the health food normally.
Fries. I mean, they are potatoes.
They're not like deep fried fried like
for hours. I mean, the fries I use are
probably between like two to three grams
of fat per 3 oz serving of. So, you're
very thoughtful about the cheat foods. I
count all my I count all my nutrients.
And what time do you normally eat? I
normally eat usually around like 1 to 2
am. Yeah, I thought that was the case. I
figured that's impossible. Why? Why at
that hour? Because I go live on
Instagram and everybody's like, "Why are
you live in the middle of the night?" My
schedule is just packed. Like I like
eating at the end of the day. Um because
I mean, biologically, we were meant to
to feast and fast. And when we when we
feast, we go to sleep. You digest while
resting. A lot of people have heartburn,
indigestion, acid reflux. Yes. I mean,
I'm sure plenty of people here have had
I've had it in the past, too. But when
we go out to eat a lunch and then we you
try to walk off your big lunch or you go
try to run it off or go to the gym after
eating and your body's trying to digest
all this food while moving. That can
cause a lot of those issues where I eat
all my food and yes, I look like I have
a huge baby, but I digest while resting.
See, I I honest if I ate at 1 in the
morning, I wouldn't be able to sleep all
night. That would keep you from
sleeping. Yeah, for sure. That would
throw me off. And you know, this this
doesn't look so healthy to me. And this
for sure is a little bit petrifying as a
doctor. That's right.
I'm surprised they recreated this.
We took a long time. We had to push
people up. So, let me go back through
this. This we come on over here for a
second. I'm going to walk you through
how I analyzed the food a little bit.
So, this is one meal you had, right?
Doesn't look as healthy as some other
meals that I could imagine you eating.
Is that a big hamburger? It looks like
Yeah, it's a giant cheeseburger.
Cheeseburg cheeseburger. It's a
cheeseburger, believe me. All right.
Look over here. calorie content for
that, right? Pretty significant.
3,385. So, it's less than the 5,000. I
said less than the 4,000 even that you
might have said. Fat was was almost 90
grams in carbs, 391 gram. Right. Here's
another one. This is this is a sort of
some pizza. This is a pretty big size of
pizza. It's bigger than your torso.
Yeah. Right here. Here we had uh
3,974 calories, sugar 123 grams, sodium
8,46.
Well, that was for two of these slices
of pizza, not just one. How many did you
eat? Two. Well, then what's the total
The total was for two slices. Yeah.
Sure. Sodium's a little bit high, but
8,000. Yeah. For me, I mean, it's almost
double the recommended amount or a
little bit over double the recommended
amount, but I keep my potassium in
check. I'm sure you've heard about the
sodium potassium balance. And I'm also
into fitness, so I mean, I flush out the
sodium. Can I get Can I see your abs?
This is the This is what I'm talking
about. This I want to know how he eats
that food, that pizza, and has this.
So, part of the reason I want you to
come on, if you don't mind, is I
actually know that women are following
you and are losing weight on the
program. So, because they're off on
social media and they're looking at what
you're doing and imitating it, getting
success, I got curious. So, I've got
Kathy here with us. How are you, Kathy?
I'm good. How are you? If I get it
correctly, Greg, come join us. that
Kathy's lost 50 pounds in six months. By
the way, before you even start to go, is
that unusual for people who are
following you? Do do you hear these
stories? I have my own diet. It's the
Blake diet. And uh plenty of people have
watched my how-to videos, my tutorials,
and I have over 1300 people now losing
weight because 1300 over. All right. So,
you're one of the over 1300 people. Yes.
Tell me your story. Okay. So, um we
found Blake on the internet, my fiance
and I, Jamie. He's here today. Um he
found him on YouTube and we decided to
watch him. He start decided to start the
diet. He's like, "Oh, I'll give it a
try." I saw his success. The first week
or two weeks, he lost like 15 pounds.
Did it make you mad a little bit? Yeah.
Yeah. And I was just like, you know
what? I'm going to give it a try. I
mean, I have nothing else to lose. I
mean, I've done the whole traditional
dieting. And it didn't really work for
me. And I was never a breakfast person.
I could never eat breakfast. So, this
diet was just perfect. Where Where is
he? Where's he hiding? We'll pull him
up. Jamie. So, Jamie looks skinny, too.
He is. He lost 85 lbs. He lost 85 lbs.
Yeah.
And are you eating the same kinds of
food as Blake is? Uh, for the most part,
yeah. And scaled down into my calorie
intake, my burn. And your fiance is also
Yes. Did I say fiance or boyfriend?
Fiance. Yes. Just making sure. Okay. All
right. And the same kind of food. And
you say that you lost the the weight,
but you had other benefits also. Uh,
yeah. I had more energy. Um, I didn't
feel so sluggish. I felt better. My skin
cleared up. My hair felt better. And at
what time of day are you eating? Um, I
eat at midnight. You also eat at
midnight. What is going on here? It's
go. It's flies in the face of everything
we're talking about here. Come on over
here. So, I'm going to take you to the
truth tube. Blake, get on over there.
I'm going to put you in the truth tube.
Now, you know what this is, right? We've
talked about intermittent fasting
before. And part of the challenge here,
and just to be honest, I've never seen
anyone eat the portion sizes that you're
speaking about, Blake, or that you're
enjoying or your your fiance is either
who looks so healthy on the outside, but
I'm actually more concerned about what's
going on inside of you. Mhm. So, you
allowed us to to to audit you, to put
you through a full examination, right?
We have all your blood tests. When we
come back, we got Blake's test results.
Is the diet that's blowing up on the
internet really healthy in the long
term? That's the real question I'm
asking. Is it something you ought to
try? Stick
[Music]
around. Eye drops. They seem harmless
enough, but did one woman use them as
the ultimate murder weapon? All new.
That's coming up
[Music]
[Applause]
tomorrow. We're back with the question.
Is the internet's new diet obsession of
fasting and feasting on junk food
something you ought to be trying? Now,
you may get to eat thousands of calories
and shed pounds, but what's it doing to
your insides? Blake Horton, who started
this new trend, is back. We tested his
cholesterol and his blood sugar before
the show, and I asked him to keep track
of his sleep patterns, and the results
are in. Are you ready, Blake? I am
ready. You're ready. All right. You
confident? I'm confident. Okay. Total
cholesterol should be under 200.
Blakes's 118.
I I'm not quite sure how this is all
working, but I got to say that number is
nice. The blood sugar ought to be less
than 100, between 70 and 99 ideally.
Yours 84. Smack dab in the middle. I I I
was surprised. These are just two of the
lab results. I I looked at all your lab
results. Literally every single one was
in the optimal range. So I'm I'm a
little trying to figure out get my
footing back. But I have to say at least
on the insides of you, you look as good
as you do on the outside. But then I did
one more thing. I wanted to know whether
eating that late at night was messing
with your sleep at all. Do you think of
yourself as a good sleeper? Um if I get
the time to sleep, I sleep like a rock.
But with my schedule, I'm like basically
like a long napper. All right. Well,
long napping is a good way to describe
it because on average you were getting 2
hours and 45 minutes of sleep, which is,
you know, as your sleep score, there's a
little scoring system we have. Your
sleep score was 46. Let me show you the
actual chart. There's the 46. And it
look, you know, you got, you fell asleep
immediately like a rock. Told you,
right? But you weren't asleep very long.
You didn't get deep sleep. Uh, you
didn't dream. Do you remember dreaming
at all? Um, depends. Very rarely. Yeah.
18 minutes you're not dreaming. So,
usually. So I this is not surprising I
guess because you're not giving yourself
time. If you gave yourself time, would
it be better than this? One of my goals
in 2019 is to set my schedule where I
can get a good night's sleep. All right.
So I have to acknowledge I I'm shocked.
I've never seen anyone look as good as
you look eating what you've been eating.
So I asked my medical unit to dive into
you a little bit. What makes you
different? What makes you special? And
one issue in the back of my mind is you
do work out. And I wanted to figure out
how many calories do you really burn a
day? So I had the med unit calculated
out. They think that your calories
burned in a day because you have a lean
muscle looking at your weight and
everything else, all the other
variables,
3,850 calories a day of burning of
calories. That's part of the answer. So,
if you're not burning 3,850 calories,
don't eat 4,000 calorie meals. It's not
going to work so well, right? Okay. So,
then that doesn't explain everything.
Let's get back to this intermittent
fasting issue because people are losing
a lot of weight who don't burn 3,850
calories and I want to understand what's
going down with them. Mhm. So, let's
just go through the average American and
how we all think about weight loss. The
average person starts eating their
breakfast at 7:00 a.m. and they're done
their dinner, whatever they're going to
eat by 10 p.m. That's about 15 hours. We
used to think calories in, calories out,
right? And when you eat like this, that
might be the case, right? Because if
you're going to have breakfast, lunch,
dinner, and snacks in between, you know,
it takes you a long time. It's a big
long eating window. Your metabolism is
going to want to deal with it as it can
in peace meal. What you're arguing is
eat it all at once. get up at seven, go
to bed at whenever you're gonna go to
bed, and eat one meal, wherever it
happens to be. Well, the data seems to
suggest that if we shorten the window
when we eat, you might be better off.
You can eat the same number of calories
in a short period of time as you would
over the whole day and you lose weight
compared to what you would be eating.
Now, think about that. And they did a
study actually shortening it down to
just a 4-hour window of eating and
demonstrated results like yours. So, I
don't know how many of you are thinking
about this, but that combined with the
idea that you're not hungry because
you're not thinking about food, not
tempting yourself all day long might
make it work. The one issue that I've
got Mhm. is what kind of food you're
eating. So, the one beef would be you're
eating junk food. You're arguing you're
having fruits and veggies, but what do
you have to say to folks at home who
think they want to copy you? To the
untrained human eye, if you just assume
what you are seeing on the screen,
you're wrong. any any of my meals that I
make personally, if you would go to
order it out at a restaurant, it would
be twice the calories, probably more.
So, I'm using healthier versions of
everything, lower calorie versions. Uh,
my foods are higher protein, lower fat.
Um, my my meals, I'm weighing all my
ingredients. My meals are like, it's
like I'm a scientist in a lab, a mad
scientist making my meal to fit my daily
needs. The macronutrients work for you.
Macro. So, I micro and micro, but
they're across the board. doing your
homework. If people want to jump start
their way towards doing what you're
doing, what's the best way to start for
on a very basic level to just skip your
first meal of the day? If that's
breakfast, some people go out, they eat
a 500 calorie breakfast. They don't
really know or eat one at home to start
their day. If they would just save those
500 calories, 500 calories times seven
days a week is 3500 calories. That's one
pound of body weight. Yeah. And if
you're looking to lose a pound a week
and you're maintaining and you cut out
that 500 calorie breakfast, you're going
to lose a pound a week just like that.
Blake, you're intriguing to me.
Congratulations. Appreciate it. We'll be
right back.
[Applause]
[Music]
Up next, constipation confessions. Could
you have a mega colon? Plus, top experts
reveal the surprising food to get things
moving along again.
[Applause]
All right, let's face it. Let's face it.
We have all struggled with constipation
before. Am I right? Right. Once in a
life at least, sometimes a lot more than
that. But a shocking new headline is
opening my eyes to a whole new level of
being well backed up. There are reports
of a man whose colon expanded to seven
ines and actually burst because he was
so constipated. So many of my friends
and family have been asking me about it
that even I've gotten curious. So today,
do you have a mega colon? And could your
constipation be deadly? For the first
time ever, I'm going to show you what a
real meggaolon looks like. Think about
the word mega colon. My first
sisters-in-law Kristen and Carrie are
here. They say they are obsessed with
talking about their bathroom
schedules. So I got to say first, you're
very brave to be here. Well, what kinds
of things do you talk about, Kristen?
Um, I'm pretty regular, so I don't have
much to say on the topic.
So Carrie, what do you complain about
when you get constipated? What to do to
fix it? Yeah. And it comes up a fair
amount. Fair enough. Are you worried
about mega colon? Now I am.
I've got to bring an expert. So pay
attention to this. Gastronurologist like
Dr. Rashini Raj has been investigating
this story which was ripped from the
headlines. So you got the details. So
just everyone's on the same page. What
actually happened with this case? So
this was a 24 year old young man who had
chronic constipation for about four
years but then for about two weeks it
was much more severe. He had severe
abdominal pain a lot of bloating and
distension of his abdomen. So he went to
the ER and this is what they found. So
this is a measure that I'm standing like
this and you cut at me in half this way
right? So you actually cut see half my
body and this is the line of his colon
way bigger than it's supposed to. That's
the spine by the way. Yeah. in the back.
So basically from his spine to his belly
button which is about here. He's got a
colon taking up the whole space. You go
to the bathroom down here, right? The
rectum's down here. It's your pelvic
bone. So that's a this is a long
distance, right? 7 in which is much much
larger than you want your colon to be.
And you're going to feel it. Now they
sent him home with some laxatives, some
enemas, but he showed up again two days
later, even worse pain. And this is what
they found. We call this free air in the
abdomen. This means the colon has burst.
There's a perforation, a tear in the
colon. This is actually a
life-threatening emergency because you
can get an overwhelming infection of
your entire body. So again, this is the
colon in here, the area that we had the,
you know, air in before. This is all air
that's now inside the belly but the
intestinal system. That is a surgical
catastrophe, emergency. It's a big
problem. So let's show everybody how
this actually happens. How a colon
becomes a mega colon. So we pulled
together a little animation and I'm
going to walk you through it so to
speak. So right here next to me is your
colon. And when you eat food we fecal
material waste traveling through starts
to move up the colon and then it travels
across the colon over here. Right? And
then I'll step over here. It comes down
the descending colon and then this is
pretty typical if you have constipation.
It'll get stuck here. You all see this?
This is regular constipation. But here's
the problem. When this colon starts to
dilate up, get really big and stretch
out. That's the the term we use in
medicine for a mega colon and it can
distend severely for a bunch of cases,
but chronic constipation is one of the
things if it's untreated for a long time
that worries us. And a mega colon can
lead to perforation because it gets so
big it pops. And that's surgical
emergency that we were showing you with
those X-rays earlier. And that can also
lead to sepsis and a bad infection. So,
Dr. You actually found a picture of a
mega colon. This is unique. It's
displayed in a museum. Yeah. I mean,
look at this. This is actually dates
back to 1892. And this is a a museum in
Philadelphia where a 29year-old man,
lifelong constipation, actually was
unfortunately and sadly found dead in
his bathroom. He died while trying to
have a bowel movement. Severely
distended mega colon. They call it the
giant mega colon. So So I've never seen
one in person.
But for the first time in 10 years, we
have a megolon to show the
audience. Carrie is back to She's been
whining to her sister-in-law about this.
Are you ready to see a mega colon?
I am. You are. She says with great
trepidation and not a lot of confidence.
Okay. So, first of all, a healthy colon
looks like this. All right. This colon
is not gargantuan. You I've shown you
colons before and this is about the
right size. But
this is what a mega colon looks like.
Compare these together. Do you see how
much larger that is? Compare this colon
to this
colon, right? I mean, it's a lot bigger.
And this is the difference between a
regular colon with constipation and a
colon that's gotten large from chronic
problems. It's, you know, less than half
the size of the mega colon. Thoughts on
this?
It's pretty gross and pretty big and I
never wanted that to happen to me. Does
this want you to get take your
constipation a bit more seriously?
Definitely. All right, that's a good
idea because Dr. A, it's not just about
drinking a little more water or tiny bit
more fiber. What What are the reasons
you get a mega colon? So, but getting a
meggaolon, it's a rare uh complication
of constipation, but there are also
people who are lacking the nerve cells
in the lining of their colon that help
move things along. So, they might
develop meggaolon. People with Crohn's
disease or colitis, if it's untreated,
they can get a severe distension which
leads to what we call toxic mega colon.
For most people with constipation, their
colon is still going to look like this.
It's going to have the normal diameter,
but you want to keep an eye on it. If
you feel after several weeks that you're
not moving your bowels, you're starting
to get pain or discomfort. You may be
down this road and you want to do things
not just drinking water but increasing
your exercise intake, your fiber intake
and speaking to your doctor about other
measures so you don't go from this
normal size to this mega colon. Stay
here and guard the mega colon. I will do
that. That many of them never had one
before. Let me ask Dr. Raj important
question. How do you know if your
chronic constipation? Yeah, which car
many others are suffering from has
become more of a medical emergency.
Whether it's become a mega colon. So a
mega colon is going to give you first of
all severe abdominal pain. You might
even get fever or what we call sepsis.
So other signs of real infection. But
the hallmark is that distended hard like
a drum abdomen. And to kind of diagnose
yourself, you can really tap on your
your abdomen when we do it with the two
fingers. And it's going to sound kind of
like it would if you did a drum or a
balloon. So you want to know, is this
full of air, a really distended colon
that at some point could actually
rupture. Just think about that. I mean,
literally, that's what it's going to
feel like a little bit. And that's how
we diagnose the problem just on physical
examinations. That's right. Yeah. Up
next, what can you do to prevent
constipation? We're revealing
constipation confessions. The top ways
health experts get rid of their own
[Music]
constipation. Here's your daily show.
[Applause]
We've been asked the question, do you
have a mega colon? And now it's time for
the biggest constipation confessions. My
go-to health experts are spilling the
beans and what they really do when they
get backed up. They're revealing the
most common constipation situations and
what you can do to get things moving
again. Joining us is nutritionist Tanya
Zuckerber. We're going to start with the
stress constipation. tell us about this
study. So I have found that when my
clients get stressed that they often
complain about constipation and I
believe it's due to two factors. When
people get stressed they don't drink
enough water. They don't stop to drink
and therefore the lack of fluid hardens
the stool. The other thing that happens
is when people are stressed we tend to
eat emotionally and we eat things such
as cookies and cakes and refined carbs
that lack fiber. So they don't have the
stool bulk that would normally be
present to increase the stool so they
could pass it. Yeah. Now personally when
I get stressed out I have the opposite
problem. But we'll get to that later.
Fiber and magnesium smoothie is your
solution. Yes. So, we have combined
these two nutrients using two foods.
We're going to get fiber by using a high
fiber cereal. We have them here. And we
have raspberries which contain fiber and
magnesium. And because we want this to
be addirect, put them in the smoothie.
And because we are recommending this at
breakfast, we want to make sure that the
meal is complete. So, we added some
Greek yogurt for protein and some almond
milk. But you can use traditional milk.
Any milk works. So you you want the
liquid there really for the smoothness
of it.
I have to go already.
It's that effective. It's perfect. So
treatise, come over here. So Trice, you
actually tried this out for a little bit
for your stress constipation.
The taste, I think you'll agree, is
pretty good. Very good. How did it work
for you? It really worked, Dr. Oz. For
some reason, I've been constipated from
working so much and the kids and so to
have something that tastes good and
that's affordable. It was like really
quick to make and I actually
incorporated into my diet cuz I want to
move on the regular. Come move on me
over here. We got another great idea.
This is the away from home. You can come
over here if you want. All right. Away
from home constipation. Dr. Raj, you
actually have confessed this is a
problem you sometimes experience. You're
not alone, by the way. Exactly. I get
it. Many of my patients get it, my
friends. Now, when you're traveling, a
lot of things can throw off your system.
When I do, my go-to trick is to bring
some golden raisins with me. This is
something I eat pretty much every day.
It's a great source of fiber. It gets
things moving. I just prefer the golden.
You can use regular raisins as well.
They're delicious and it's just like a
nice little treat that helps you move.
So, Tanya over there who made this
little smoothie, she's also called the
queen of fiber. Listen, I love Tanya.
So, give us some other fiber hacks. Um,
so women should aim for 35 grams of
fiber a day. and it's easier to get than
most people realize. Starting at
breakfast, you saw we use the cereal in
the smoothie, but just have a bowl of a
high-fiber cereal. Look for one with at
least 10 grams of fiber or more. There
are plenty on the marketplace. For
lunch, as we enter into the winter
months, you want something warm. So,
have a bean soup, lentil, split pean.
Um, both of these will give you
approximately eight grams of fiber. And
then when it comes to dinner, bulk up on
what we call cruciferous vegetables,
broccoli, cauliflower, asparagus. Um,
these are going to have more fiber than
things like potatoes. So, always serve
two cruciferous vegetables and you'll
get at least six grams of fiber with
your dinner. Keep the mega colon away.
Yes. T, by the way, has got the F factor
diet. You check it out. Be wonderful
book. And you got lots of constipation
remedies on dr.com. Check them out. Just
spread them with your friends. And we'll
put some photos up there of the mega
colon which you can scare your family
and friends with as well. We'll be right
back.
[Music]
[Applause]
Eye drops. They seem harmless enough,
but did one woman use them as the
ultimate murder weapon? All new Oas.
That's coming up
[Music]
tomorrow. At 18 years old, Cheryl Hunter
set off for Europe to become a model.
What she thought would be a trip to make
her dreams come true would become a
nightmare she couldn't escape.
No sooner did we land in France than a
man wearing a camera around his neck
approached me. He asked me if I was a
model. Told me he make he could make me
one if I were to just go off with he and
his friend standing over there. That is
how easy it is to become a model in
France. They drugged me.
They took me to an abandoned
construction site and beat me
mercilessly. They drugged me again and
raped me repeatedly. They dumped me in a
park in Nice 3 days later.
After surviving the trauma of her
attack, Cheryl set forth on a mission as
an author and speaker to connect one
another through painful experiences and
help those find peace and forgiveness in
life-changing moments that we didn't
choose for ourselves. After hearing her
speak, I knew I needed to hear more of
her story. So, I invited her as a guest
on my podcast so she can share more of
her survival story with you. To listen,
download the Dr. Oz podcast on Apple
Podcast or wherever you get your
podcast. It's free. Share it with your
friends as well. Together, change is
happening. Everybody, our journey is
just beginning.
[Applause]
[Music]