Another controversial investigation. An
uproar over coconut oil erupted when a
professor recently called it pure
poison. The video of those comments went
viral and sent shock waves around the
world. We've been following every twist
and turn and today we investigate the
most recent claim against this popular
food. Is coconut oil guilty as charged
or is there a way to use it smarter?
[Music]
Coconut oil is being called out as one
of the worst foods you can eat.
According to this Harvard professor,
this viral video created a flurry of new
headlines questioning coconut oil,
stoking outrage and even enraging a
whole country. India is now calling for
an apology. Just recently, it seemed
like coconut oil became America's health
food darling overnight. Hundreds of
YouTube videos popped up touting it for
improving your health both inside. Great
for anybody who's trying to fight heart
disease and out. Coconut oil can
actually help stimulate hair growth.
Today, health food blogs and Pinterest
still praise it for helping with
everything. Weight loss, lower blood
pressure, brain health, digestion. Heck,
it's even supposed to be good for your
dog. And studies have backed up the idea
that coconut oil's unique chemical
composition is beneficial to your
health. We even covered it on this show,
but recently the tide has turned on
coconut oil. Last year's negative
headlines, prompted by a science
advisory from the American Heart
Association, which recommended against
eating coconut oil made me want to take
another look at it. So, is coconut oil
healthy or not? Today, we're cracking
the case and telling you the truth.
So Shana is here and says the recent
headline sent her into a tail spin of
questions. When did you first start
using coconut oil? So just a couple
years ago at a women's conference,
someone I spoke with said that she was
using it for her hair, skin, and also
food that she cooks with. And so I said,
"Well, let me try it." So like many
other folks, she began. And then slowly,
I understand it became part of your
life. So Tashana kept a coconut oil
diary for us. Really important to
understand what's really going down
because like a lot of things, a little
bit you can get away with, but too much
might be an issue. Now I understand you
like hush puppies. Yes. Is that right?
Yes. All right. So, but they look good.
That's coconut oil in there. Yes. I'm
from the south, so we eat those with our
seafood all the time. Yes. That's right.
Well, in the south, you know, gravy is
the beverage. So, it just sneaks up on
you. So, tell me about these hush
puppies. You cook them in there. How
long you keep them in the oil? Uh, keep
them in there for about maybe 20 30
minutes. Yeah. And how much coconut oil
do you have to add? I use three t
tablespoons. Three tablespoons. All
right. So, I did the math on that since
I had your diary. All right. And it
turns out that comes out to about 364
calories. 33 grams of saturated fat. You
just might want to keep this in mind
because approximately 10 grams is sort
of the goal. So, not not you didn't
drink this stuff after you're done with
it, but it gets into it. Okay. Now, I by
I think I got to commend your cooking
because look at this everybody. This is
the shrimp and that looks really good.
But how much coconut oil did they have
to put in there to make it? So, for this
I put two tablespoons. All right. So,
the shrimp added an extra bit. So, now
you up to 677 calories with 55 grams of
saturated fat. Y. And then of course you
got to have dessert. And I understand
you're a a real wiz at these babies.
Yes. Cookies. Yes. What kind are they?
Uh those are coconut cookies. Yeah.
Coconut cookies and coconut oil. How
much coconut oil did you add to them? Uh
two tablespoons for those as well. All
right. So that's total amount for the
day of 850 calories, 77 gram saturated
fat. Guys, this is half the calories you
can get for the day. And it's, you know,
almost eight times what you're supposed
to get max for the day. And nothing that
you did seemed all that out of the
whack. Mhm. And that's I think one of
the reasons it's causing all this
controversy. So, we're going to learn a
little bit more about it. Yeah. All
right. So, this is really a case of, you
know, it's not as dangerous as people
think, but it could be more dangerous
than you think. So, it was claimed to be
more dangerous than lard. We have tried
reaching out to the professor to get her
explanation and did not hear back. We
did receive a response from one of the
universities she works with. They said
in part, "It was never our intention to
upset people." Well, she's upset people.
To dig a little deeper, we have two
people who are upset. They're experts.
Dr. Dr. Mark Hyman and nutritionist Maya
Feller. They helped build a saturated
fat scale. Let's reveal how these all
stack up. So Maya, again, it was said to
be worse than lard. Yeah. So you got a
scale from 0 to 100 of saturated fat.
Lettuce, cucumbers, you know, fruit,
it's all down here at zero. There's no
saturated fat in all the produce we tell
you to eat. How much fat is in saturated
fat is in lard? Okay. Well, get ready
for this.
That's very kind of you to bring real
lard, right? It's around 40%.
On scale from zero to 100, we're around
40%. So almost half of lard is saturated
fat. Exactly. Dr. Heyman, how does that
compare to butter? Well, butter is a
little more saturated fat. It's about
60% saturated fat. So, it's more than
lard. More than lard. And how about
coconut oil? Where's that? Coconut oil
is by numbers the worst, but it may not
be the worst. It's about 80% saturated
fat. So, coconut oil has percentage wise
twice as much than lard. Yes. Of
saturated fat. But it's very different
saturated fat. Well, hold on. So, this
Harvard professor who says that it's
worse than lard in terms of percentage
saturated fat was right. True. All
right. But is it worse for you? Is it
worse for you? That's a good question.
All right. So, my I'm looking at this
and coconut oil definitely has more fat
percentage- wise than lard. Does it make
it more dangerous than lard? So, yes,
coconut oil absolutely has more
saturated fat in comparison to uh lard.
However, not all saturated fats are
created equally, right? Am I going to
say that coconut oil is the devil? No,
not at all. Do I think you should put it
on every single thing that you're
eating? No, not at all. But headto head,
is it better or worse than lard?
Headto head, I would say that they're
different properties, right? And when
we're looking at how it affects the
body, I prefer plant-based saturated
fats over animal-based saturated fats.
So, given all things, you'd rather have
coconut oil than lard. So, that's okay.
Just keep in mind that it's not maybe
better than some of the other fats you
might be eating like olive oil.
Absolutely. Dr. Heman, you disagree. Dr.
Heman thinks saturated fat is actually
about to change how it's being
perceived. And we've been down this road
before, right? We all thought
cholesterol was the devil in our diet.
No eggs, no shrimp. And when this show
started, that's what people were saying.
And we actually, the truth is, we never
really took a hard look at the evidence
in our dietary guidelines. And after 35
years, they did. They were like, "Oh,
it's not a nutritive concern anymore. Go
ahead and eat your whole eggs." Right?
The same thing I believe is going to
happen with saturated fat. And if you
look, the American Heart Association
doesn't always get it right. They told
us to eat a low-fat diet. They told us
to eat margarine. They told us to eat
lots of carbs. Bad advice. And in this
review, they only looked at four studies
from the 50s and 60s which were really
flawed. And they've ignored dozens of
other studies since that exonerate
saturated fat. In and one in particular
talked about coconut oil and olive oil
and butter. And they looked in a
randomized control trial, the most
rigorous trial design, they found that
olive oil and coconut oil were about the
same in their effect on the bad
cholesterol,
whereas butter was a little worse. But
what was interesting was it actually
helped the good cholesterol get even
better. So the overall profile from the
coconut was better even though it has
80% saturated fat. Why? Because the
kinds of saturated fats in different
foods are different. Animals have
different this has different than this
has different than this. and they have
different properties in the body because
food is information. So these tend to
actually do a little better with us. I
also think we're going to look at this
differently in five years when the new
dietary guidelines come out because the
National Academy of Science has realized
there's something fishy up that no one's
really looked at the evidence. They go
saturated fat's bad. Everybody believes
it. Why should we bother looking at it?
Well, they're going to look at in the
next round and we're going to find, I
think, that saturated fat's going to go
the way of dietary cholesterol. But one
caveat here. You cannot eat a diet high
in saturated fat or any other fat if
you're eating a diet full of starch and
sugar, which Americans do. They eat
about a half a pound of sugar and about
3/4 of a pound of flour every day. It's
that deadly combination I call sweet fat
that will kill you. So Tashana, for
example, was okay with the coconut oil
shrimp. Listen, Tashana, but shrimp's
good. Yeah, shrimp's good. But she
wasn't okay with your fat on the
cholesterol. That's But the the hush
puppies and the cookies, those are a
problem. Dangerous. Yeah. Yep. Put it on
your broccoli.
So, my final thoughts. It was initially
thought coconut oil was heart healthy.
You know why? Because there are low
rates of heart disease in places like
Polynesia where they eat lots of
coconuts. But if you look at it closer,
they ate coconut meat. It's not quite
the same as the oil because it has a
little fiber in it. And their diet was
very low in other saturated fats. They
probably didn't eat some of the other
refined sugars that Dr. Heyman was
complaining about. But these days, many
of you are using coconut oil on top of
other fats. It ought to be used, I
think, as a replacement for other
saturated fats like butter or lard or
anything else. I would not replace
unsaturated fats yet, like olive oil.
Although I appreciate that we're not as
hard set on that as we like to be. So,
the big question is, how much should you
be using? The surprising amount both of
these experts say you can use. Stay
tuned for coconut oil and its protocol.
It is time to help clear up your coconut
confusion with a coconut oil protocol to
help you get the most benefits. My med
team and I reached out to many experts
all over the medical community in
nutrition and heart health and those
researching the latest data to come up
with a smarter way to use coconut oil.
The first of course is how much do you
use? Nutritionist Mayafella is back. You
know Tasha earlier was putting a total
of seven teaspoons of coconut oil in her
cooking and she made some beautiful
stuff. So how much can you use? So I
always say limit yourself to a maximum
of one tablespoon a day. If you want to
spread it out over the course of the day
and you're having three meals, go for no
more than one teaspoon per meal. You're
not going to put it on starch and
sugars? Absolutely not. We're not going
to put it on any refined grains or, you
know, things like that. We're also not
going to put it on things that have
added sugars. So, we're not looking at
pancakes, cakes, cookies, none of that
with your coconut oil. That you're not
getting that extra bounce for that. You
don't get extra credit. You don't pass
go. Definitely not. All right. Thanks,
Maya. Next up, what are you going to
look for in the label so you get the
right kind of material? Dr. Diamond, how
do we pay attention? Because there's so
many types of coconut oil out there now.
Yes, true. A lot of the old studies that
showed coconut oil was bad were on
hydrogenated, highly processed, heat
treated coconut oil. You want the raw.
You want the virgin stuff, right? You
don't want refined stuff. All right.
Next up, how do you actually eat coconut
oil smarter? There's a secret ingredient
that might actually help manage the
cholesterol issues and could be a
one-two punch with the coconut oil, and
it is fiber. Just like those
heart-healthy Polynesians, right? When
you eat coconut oil paired with fiber,
it might not make your bad cholesterol
go up as much. And from my perspective,
that's a win-win all around. Yeah.
Because it's one of the few ways to
helping your good cholesterol. Okay.
Give me some examples. You got grains.
Okay. So, this is one of my f favorite.
I love wheat berries. Love, love, love
them. I make it like salads. I do all
the time. They're getting popular wheat
berries. They're everywhere. You can
really find them all over the place. And
they're not weak. No, they're not. I
know. That's the great thing. It's kind
of like wild rice. Yeah, exactly. Why do
they name things the wrong thing? I have
no idea. Just to confuse us. Why I call
it wheat berry but it's not wheat.
Doesn't that make you mad? Well, who's
running the branding for wheat berries?
I know. And it's an ancient grain.
That's also why I love it. You know,
full of vitamins and minerals, fiber,
phytonutrients. I love it. Barley.
Barley and quinoa. Right. So, these are
some of the whole grains that I like to
pair the coconut oil. One of my favorite
little stories. When we first started
the show, I would talk about quinoa.
Nobody could find it in stores because
they didn't know how to spell it. You
all know how to spell quinoa now. Right.
Exactly. I hope so. There is progress.
10 years of spelling. All right. So you
have grains here and you have legumes on
the other side, right? And so I chose
legumes that are easy to find like
garbanzo, kidney, and lentil. Also ones
that are easy on the pallet and lentils
cook super quickly. And kidney and
garbanzo, if you go for the dry ones, it
takes a little bit longer, but well
worth the wait. And just you're putting
other hat on as nutritionist. If you if
you soak them, it gets rid of the gas
problems afterwards. Absolutely. So
that's what I you know, you can actually
even soak it with a little bit of
kamboo, which is seaweed, helps even
better. I like that, Maya. Nicely done.
everything. You're going to find this
coconut protocol. It's all new. It's on
dr.com. Share it with your friends. Do
it right. Thank you for watching. Don't
forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good