If laughter is the best medicine to get
ready for a double dose from one of the
funniest people I know, Wanda Sykes is
here. Nothing is off limits. Her health,
her kids, her hot flashes, she finds the
funny in all of it. Please welcome my
friend Wanda Sykes.
[Applause]
[Music]
It's a workout.
It's a workout to get here.
So, I got like a little Gatorade table
or something halfway here. Good lord.
Well, thank you for coming. Well, thank
you for having me. Let's start with
these hot flashes I've been hearing
about. You turn 50, right? How bad are
they? They're they're pretty bad. It's
like, you know, like the night sweats
and uh I put it this way. If I ever
murdered somebody,
all I need is a jury of my peers, a
bunch of women also going through hot
flashes. And they would get it. I would
walk. They would let me go. They don't
understand. They like, "Oh, yeah. I
understand. It's it's it's embarrassing.
You're just sitting there all a sudden
you feel it coming on and it's you're
just sitting there just a mess. Just a
mess." Well, sometimes you do things
that contribute to this problem. I
understand you have a love affair with
wine. Oh, I love wine. Yes. And it helps
you unwind a little bit. Yes. Yes. Wine
keeps me sane.
But that hot flashes make you insane.
They bounce each other out a little bit
cuz wine causes hot flashes.
Well,
guess I'm just going to be a hot, sweaty
mess then, huh?
I deal with the hot flashes. Trust me, I
I'm I'll be better as sweaty and a
little tipsy, people. So, father's got
these beautiful 5-year-old twins, Lucas
and Olivia. What's the best part about
motherhood for you? The best It's the
most rewarding thing I think I've I've
ever done, and it's the unconditional
love that you know, but it's uh the I
guess that's the best part. What's the
worst part about motherhood? The worst
part is they're in your face every
minute. They they just suck the life out
of you. It's like all your hopes and
dreams just toss them in the trash can
and just you just put put your life on
hold and that's it. You know, cuz I I'm
tell you I I used to I used to know a
lot of stuff, Dr. Oz. I used to, you
know, read the paper and watch news. Now
it's nothing. I just empty up here. It's
just all kids and you're all constantly
like solving problems and everything.
And and I I just picture like, okay,
this is what I'm going through as a
parent. So imagine if you're doing this
and you were like the president.
Can you imagine that? You know, like
like the president, you know, run
running and say, "Hey, uh uh Mr.
President, Vadam President, uh uh Putin
just invaded Crimea and and he's taking
part of the Ukraine." And as my mother,
I would just go, "Well, you tell them
that I'll take it and now neither one of
them can have it."
Yeah.
So, let me move on to something because
you're so open about your health. Yes.
2011 diagnosed with breast cancer,
right? We all probably have heard the
story, but part you don't know about is
the difficult decisions you had to make,
including the decision to remove both
your breasts, right? To me, it wasn't a
difficult uh decision. Um, I have a very
strong history of breast cancer on my
mother's side. Like, she's lost, you
know, like two sisters and we have like
first cousins like, you know, and and
also prostate cancer, you know, for the
men. So, it's a strong history there.
And actually, I was very fortunate how I
found out I had cancer cuz I went in for
a breast reduction cuz I I had real big
girls. I mean, they were they were big.
I mean, you know, my my my back was sore
and I got constantly knocking over
stuff. You know, you going to reach up
for something and it just clear out the
whole shelf. It was it's just awful. I
mean, they they were big. I would take
my bra off and people thought Law and
Order was coming on. You know what I'm
saying?
So is Lord know that no I just took my
bra off. So I had the reduction. It was
through the pathology that they found
you know early stage uh uh breast
cancer. So I I just said you know what
I'm going to what is my best odds to not
have it. So I opted to have the the
double mastctomy. You ever look back
with regret thinking maybe I didn't have
to have that? No. No n not at all. I you
know I feel great. uh you know I'm not
like worried about okay what what is it
doing now? What is it? You know and and
guess what now I can swim Dr. Oz. I it's
like having built-in floaties.
I'm Before I would get in the pool and
just sink and then then after the after
the surgery I got in the pool and I was
like hey what's going on here? All
right. This is nice. That's right. This
is all right.
Watch out, Michael Phips. It's coming
your way. So, listen. Folks knew you
were coming. I got lots of uh posts on
Facebook about you. Here's a It's honest
question. This is from Sheree. She asks,
this is her question, not mine. Okay.
When you had your breast removed, how
did you decide how big to make your new
breast during your reconstruction? Oh,
that's a great question. That is a great
question. You know, cuz I went I started
with the reduction, you know, so I
wanted them smaller and then when I
found out I got cancer, I was like, you
know what? I'mma go back to bigger boobs
because my way like poking cancer in the
eye, you know. Hey, how about that? Take
that. Look at my big boobs. Huh?
So, you got a question for me? I
understand. Yes. Take it away. Uh, I
have a problem snoring. Yeah. And it
Well, actually, I don't have a problem
snoring. My wife has a problem with my
snoring because when I'm asleep I'm
apparently I'm snoring but she wakes me
up. She does? Yeah. To tell me I'm
snoring. Isn't that rude? It's like look
I'm doing what I'm supposed to be doing.
I'm sleeping. Don't wake me up because
you can't sleep. You know she's speaking
for all the snorers out there, right? So
So how can I how can I help that? Don't
tell me the wine again, doctor. No, no,
no. Not the wine. We have to the wine.
You know that story. So, I need to do a
little physical exam on you. Okay. Okay.
All right. Let's do it. Let's walk over
to my office here. Okay. Okay. I bet you
a little bed over here. Oh, nice. So,
why don't you hop up here? Okay. Pretend
it's an examination table and lie on
your back or your side or however you
normally sleep. So, just pretend you're
sleeping. Well, do y'all have nudity in
here? This This show is ready for
everything. I'll help you right off. We
won't do that there. Do you sleep nude?
Huh? Um, just a little bit cuz the hot
flashes. The hot flashes. The hot
flashes. Yeah. So you lie like that,
right? So that's the first mistake
because you lie on your back like that
and all of a sudden all that tissue in
your throat collapses back and you sound
like a kazoo. Oh, right. So we're going
to change that and I can understand
exactly why this would bother the people
in your life. So the b most important
thing is open up that airway. So the
best way to prevent you from storing is
to lie on your side. But you don't line
your side too much. I guess I I can try.
I mean All right. No, I I I can tell you
right now you're not going to do that.
All right, here. Hop up here. I got a
better idea for you. Okay, you're going
to love this idea. I built this for you.
These are your panty hoes. Got it from
your house. They're very nice, by the
way. So, you take the panty hose, right?
You put tennis ball in one of the foots.
I'm coming back to this in a second.
Stay with me here. All right. If you
don't mind some 50 shades of Dr. Oz
going on in here. What you doing, Dr.
Eyes? 50 Shades of Dr. Oz. That's great.
So, come over here. Give me 50 shades.
You put put your arms up. Put your arms
up.
I'm kidding. I'm kidding. Okay. So, now
turn around here. So, so I'm going to
tie this up here. I'm tying the
stocking. Not Wanda. All right. Put this
little ball back here. And as you tie
this ball back here. Okay. It's now
going to be a little bit of a hindrance.
You're not going to want to lie your
back because every time you lie on your
back, it's going to remind you to tie on
your side. All right. Give it a try.
Okay. Here. I'm going here. I'm lie
here. I'm I'm going to pretend I'm your
wife. So, I'm here. All right. So, I'm
lying like this. Okay. What do you
think? It bother you? Oh. Oh. Oh, yeah.
That's I
Oh, ouch. That's a dislocate my spine
right there. What? Here. Roll towards
me. Roll this way. See if it works
better. Ow. Ow. Oh, please. You whine
like this.
Wonder.
You got to love her. Listen, she puts on
a great show wherever she is. And guess
what? She's coming to Jacksonville,
Clear Water, Miami, Florida next week,
and lots of other great cities, too.
Catch this woman. She's funnier than
anything. We'll be right back. Thank you
for watching. Don't forget to subscribe
and turn on notifications so you never
miss out on new videos to live the good