Supermarket iced coffee. A quick pickme
up, but do we really know what's hiding
in those bottles?
>> There's two servings there, so you're
getting 50 gram of sugar.
>> And could the ice in your iced coffee
make you sick?
>> The ice cubes be as dirty as toilet
water.
>> I'm never eating out again.
>> Plus, the hip hop health revolution. How
Fat Joe lost the fat.
>> Do you feel as good as you look right
now?
>> Coming up next.
It's that time of year when your coffee
goes from hot, may I? To cold. Enjoy.
Ready to drink iced coffee is in bottles
in cans has never been so popular. We
spend more than $200 million a year on
these drinks. They're certainly
convenient. Just head to the
supermarket, grab and go.
Enjoy.
But what's really brewing in your
storebought iced coffee?
>> Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah,
[Music]
>> I love you guys.
Today, the truth about the iced coffee
at your supermarket. Is there an Oz
approved iced coffee that you'll want to
drink? You're all excited about this for
good reason. Food journalist Mark
Shasker is here to help us investigate.
Iced coffee is not a new drink, but
we're seeing a lot of it in supermarkets
all over the country. Why so popular?
Why now?
>> Well, it seems like for every reason.
First of all, everyone loves coffee.
There's caffeine in it. We all need that
hit of caffeine once a day. Some of us
five times a day.
>> You know who you are.
>> Now, a lot of us are looking for an
alternative to soda, sugar, sweetened
beverages, iced coffee. That for a lot
of people, we're going to look at that.
And finally, there's millennials. They
love this stuff and they're willing to
shell out big bucks for the good stuff.
So now we're seeing I mean it's getting
bigger and bigger and now iced coffee is
right there in the supermarket. It is
super convenient. So coffee has many
health benefits. We've talked about
them, right? Give you more energy. You
know that. But it can also lower the
risks of certain diseases. So do these
supermarket drinks give you the same
benefits? That's the real question. So
let's walk through some of the most
popular kinds out there. The first, of
course, are the flavored iced coffees
that so many folks love. It's not just
mocha anymore. Oh, he comes in all kinds
of flavors.
>> There is everything. Chocolate, salted
caramel, vanilla. Now, you're probably
thinking, "But don't you drink iced
coffee for the flavor of coffee?" Well,
that is a good thought to keep in mind
cuz if you look at a simple iced coffee,
just cold coffee with a bit of milk.
Terms of calories, you're looking at 80
to 100. Now, you know those fancy ones
you get at those fancy coffee shops that
have like whipped cream and they're in
the blender, they got caramel chips.
>> 10 times the calories. Up to 10 times.
>> Now, here's the good news. We scoured
the supermarket shelves. We didn't find
any that were that bad, but we did find
some where the calorie count starts to
creep up two or 300 calories. So, you're
absolutely in the realm of a sugary
drink.
>> If you ran to this because you don't
want the carbonated sugary drinks you've
been hammering,
>> you're no better off. You might even be
worse off.
>> Might be worse off cuz you can't even
tell. All right. Next up, the lattes,
the cappuccinos. Tell us more about
these.
>> So, with hot coffee, if you go to a
fancy place, the barista, you get a
cappuccino or latte that is made with
steamed milk. The cold version is no
different. It's made with milk. I like
milk, calcium, protein. But when you we
looked at the ingredient list, we found
other things like an emulsifier called
keragenan. Now kagen. Yes. It it's
there. It stops the drink from
separating. It gives it a bit of a
richer mouth feel. There's some concern
that caragen can cause adverse gut
reactions. My take is that when we see
the ingredient list starting to expand,
starting to get bigger and bigger. We're
getting more into a processed beverage.
We're getting further away from what we
kind of all wanted in the first place,
which was just cold coffee with a bit of
milk. All right, let's talk about the
trendiest coffee out there. Cold brew.
This is different. This is not a lot of
stuff. It's actually a very traditional
way of brewing coffee, right? You and
this is actually this is I have a little
picture. This is what it looks like when
people make it at home because it's
pretty popular. But this is unique,
different. How do they put it in the
can?
>> Cold brew is exactly what it sounds
like. It's you brew coffee with cold
water instead of hot. And when you do
that, you pull out a totally different
flavor profile. Much less bitter, much
less acidic. So, a lot of people who
don't like that intense, you know,
bitterness of coffee, they really love
cold brewed coffee. Another really good
thing is if you're someone who can't
drink coffee black, you might be able to
drink it black cold brewed. So,
>> takes the edge off it.
>> Absolutely. Takes the edge right off it.
>> All right, last category, brand new.
It's called Nitro, and it's been popping
up in coffees recently. I had never
heard of this before, but we're going to
try it today together.
>> This is wild. This is coffee that's
pressurized with nitrogen. It's like
it's carbonated. Check this out. I mean,
beer coffee.
>> Listen to that sound it makes. Then you
pour it, you get this nice creamy head
on top.
>> Look at that. You can see the
carbonation on the side coming up.
>> Now, I want you to taste this cuz it's
got a creamy sweet flavor. A lot of
people would would drink this and they
would swear that it's got milk. It's got
sugar. It's got none of those things.
This is a zerocalorie beverage.
>> It really does taste creamy. It fills
your mouth completely. I It tastes a
little bit like a like an espresso. Put
a little little half and half in it.
>> Exactly. And and if you're trying to get
away from, you know, you you want
something that's a bit effervescent, got
a bit of sweetness that, you know,
something more exciting than water, but
you don't want to drink soda, I think
this is a great place to go.
>> So, what are the other health benefits
of this besides the fact you skip the
sugar?
>> Okay. It's less acidic. So, some people
don't like the gut rot that you get with
coffee. This is less acidic. You won't
get that. And there's also some people
who think that the nitrogen actually
increases the rate of absorption of the
caffeine. So, you get a bigger caffeine
pop. So, that's exciting for a lot of
us. That's also a double-edged sword
because there's such a thing as too much
caffeine. So, I would say don't drink
more than two of these in a day.
Otherwise, you might be overdoing in the
caffeine.
>> All right, beginning of the show, I gave
the front row who are all coffee lovers
some of this nitro coffee. So, I wasn't
the only one who tasted it. Show of
hands, who's who who liked it and who's
getting a little buzz from it.
>> What do you think about it?
>> It's really good.
>> Like good. Like I'd drink it again or
I'm just saying that cuz Oz will give me
a hard time otherwise.
>> Like good. Like I'm about to finish it,
but I didn't want to be rude. Okay.
You know, I'm I don't know if I'm
getting a little bit of a buzz. Are you
feeling this?
>> A little a little bit of a buzz.
>> Yeah. I I I I don't know if you guys are
big coffee drinkers, but I I actually it
smacks me a little faster, which I guess
makes sense, Mark. Right.
>> Yeah. It livens it up on the on the
pallet and it livens it up in the body.
>> All right. So, Barista Sam is here. Hey,
welcome. You've never had a a coffee
from a a bottle or or a can before?
>> No, no, no. cuz my background is I
manage a micro roaster coffee shop and
so everything I have is freshly brewed
in the morning and even the cold brew is
pulled right out of that 16- hour
window. So what I drink is as fresh as
you can get. So when I was tasting the
bottles it was a different experience
because even though it's bottle and it's
fresh and it's not going bad. It does
lose a little bit of the caffeine and a
little bit of the acidity that some
people might like in coffees.
>> All right. So we we charged you with
tasting all the ones we just presented
and give us your expert opinion with
your micro what's it? Micro what?
>> Micro roasting.
>> Micro roasting. I was going to say
brewery, but I envision the same kind of
thing. Which one did you like the most?
>> Uh the cold brew.
>> The cold brew 100%.
>> Really remarkable.
>> If I if I didn't have to add in the
hospital, you're trained to be wary of
coffee because you it's not doesn't
taste very good where we get it from and
you got to put lots of sugar in there
and creams and like this. I would
actually drink. Absolutely. It tastes
like I'm having something that's real.
This like having carrot juice except
it's not.
>> It's a little better.
>> Little better. I like carrot juice more,
but we'll call that I like kale juice.
Have you had that?
>> Um m
and out of Spanish. All right, Mark,
give us some advice on health. If you're
looking for coffee in the supermarket,
one of these cold versions, what should
we look for?
>> Well, you know, always look at the
ingredient list. The shorter the better.
First ingredient should be coffee.
>> Absolutely.
>> Think about the sugar. Uh try and avoid
sugar. If you have to have it, maybe try
adding it yourself, but let your palette
expand. If buy one of these, cold brew,
one of the nitros, you might not like it
the first time if you're a sugar lover,
but by the third one, your palette will
start to change and you'll go back to
one of those really sweet ones. You go.
What was I even thinking?
>> Yeah, I bet you a lot of folks will like
the cold brew. The night show's really
hitting me in the head, by the way. I'm
getting a little bit of a brain rush
now, but it might appeal to you. I'm
fascinated making the things. Up next,
from iced coffee to ice cubes. Let me be
careful about this. Are your ice cubes
as dirty as toilet water?
>> Think about it. Is it possible? We're
going to find out what our germ test
reveal that is next.
[Music]
Ted Bundy. His last brutal attack before
his capture. A college sorority house.
One survivor speaks out.
>> When he attacked me, my jaw was
shattered. My cheek was torn open.
>> Plus, buyer beware.
>> There's blood everywhere. There's a
woman screaming.
>> When murder houses go up for sale,
>> they've changed the address. They've
reconstructed the house, but still it
hasn't sold. All new Oz.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
From coffee shops to restaurants, even
in your own home, many of you use them
in every cold drink. Ice cubes. But just
how dirty are these ice cubes?
Can these ice cubes be as dirty as
toilet water? Think about that. We're
revealing what our germ test revealed
and what you really may be drinking when
you add ice to your drink. My viewer
Mara is here. We swapped her ice machine
at home. We'll get to that in a second.
But you love ice. I understand you even
chew on ice, which you shouldn't do, by
the way.
>> Why?
>> Because it can hurt your ename. But what
what do you love about ice so much?
>> It freezes my taste buds.
>> Yes.
>> It's refreshing. I don't know. It's
better than smoking a cigarette. How
about that?
>> Well, if I had a choice, I'd chew on the
ice. That's
>> Thank you. Me, too. That's why
>> let's go meet Peter Delucho over here,
our health inspector to help find out
exactly how dirty your ice cubes may be.
We're not going to panic you yet. So, a
lot of us think that because the ice is
frozen, it can't possibly harbor
bacteria because bacteria die in the
cold, right?
>> Well, you know, you think that you take
a look at the ice and just because it's
clear doesn't mean it's clean.
Basically, it's scary. But freezer
temperatures, they don't kill bacteria.
They don't kill viruses. In fact, with
bacteria on the most part, it just kind
of slows things down and not
multiplying, you know, for the most
part. But at the end of the day, once
that ice winds up in your drink and it
starts melting, if it's contaminated,
it's going to make you sick.
>> So, what kind of bacteria we talking
about here?
>> Uh, well, you know what? It's all types
of bacteria. You think scientists have
been preserving bacteria by freezing
them, you know, for for months and years
at a time. But what I'm concerned about
are those food born pathogens. I'm
concerned about EC coli, salmonella,
lististeria, and I'm concerned about
viruses like neurovirus and hepatitis A.
The biggest contamination of ice or your
hands and getting that those bacteria in
there. So, what happens is you're
scooping and your hand goes into the
ice. You're not paying attention. In
commercial ice machines, you're required
to have a scoop. The scoop's supposed to
be outside the machine. They leave it in
the machine. What happens? It keeps
making more ice. The scoop winds up
being buried. So, next person comes
along. Oh, I need to fill up the ice
bucket to bring upstairs. The hand goes
in here. They discontaminated the ice.
>> All their jaws are dropping. The whole
audience, just like yours,
>> I'm never eating out again.
>> And ice machines are not that easy to
clean. So, it's something that, you
know, needs to be done on a regular
basis. So, one of the things, you know,
a recent study showed that a 100%, think
of it, 100% of ice machines swabbed in
the study at five hospitals and two
nursing homes, all came up positive for
bacteria or funguses.
>> Okay?
>> So, just so you know, this is not
theoretical. We went one step further. A
study looked at restaurants, places we
all eat.
>> Six out of 10 of them of the restaurants
didn't just have bacteria. They had more
bacteria than the water in the toilets
of those restaurants.
>> Okay. I really feel like I'm going to
throw up.
>> The good news is we're not getting tons
of foodborne illicites. I don't want
everybody to be scared and never have
ice again. But it's buyer beware. Be
careful. Take a look at situations.
Another concern that I have too, which
we find a lot of times we do inspections
is you'll see bottles in ice. People put
things in to be cool at the bar. Well,
those bottles would touch with your
hands. That's infected the ice. If you
ever see ice coming from there, you
don't want that.
>> Okay? So, no restaurants and no parties.
No.
>> All right. Said or but here's the
question. Are you safe at home?
>> Since you allowed us into your home, we
actually did a little experiment. We got
some ice and we got some of your toilet
seat.
>> Just saying.
>> I am so embarrassed.
>> It is time to
>> No one's going to ever come over.
>> No one's coming to your house. The
results of the germ test. Are you ready?
Now remember, you want a number below
50. Anything above 50 is considered
dirty. Doesn't mean you're going to get
sick. Anything above 50 is not optimal.
Water should be definitely less than 50.
So Mara's freezer germ count was
>> 112.
Now, before we all gasped too loudly,
what was your toilet seat? And it was
>> 143. So, it's sort of close.
>> A little too close, I think. So, here's
the question. How often do you clean the
ice maker in your freezer? And your
answer is
>> uh a couple of times a year.
>> You do? Yeah.
>> If you clean it at all, you're better
than me. Okay.
>> Cuz most of us don't even do that much.
And most of us probably don't even think
about it. But what about the coffee
shops and the restaurants? Are they
cleaning their machine? So, we spoke to
a fast food worker who, well, you'll see
why. He wanted to remain anonymous to
tell us the truth.
>> I worked in the food industry for almost
a year now and um every shift we had,
but people complaining about dirting the
drinks. Um, at least three or four
people a night complained about this.
Um, I believe it came from the ice. Um,
the ice maker was never clean. Um, I
never seen it clean since I've been
there. And also, the buckets that they
use to transport ice was really dirty,
dingy buckets. Um, also hear people
complain more about bugs or whatever in
their drinks as well.
>> Well, there's a that's a bug. It's a
frozen bug.
>> I mean, it's it's going to happen. I
mean, we live in a real world. Things
are going to get into our machine. So,
the issue isn't to never contaminate
them, which is ideal, but you got to
clean them. So, how often should we
clean them at home? How often should
restaurants clean them?
>> Well, restaurants are a whole another
story. I mean, there's and different
size ice machines, different cleaning
frequency. The real big ones that that
are like the commercial grade ones that
they're producing a lot of ice, they
break them down. They're supposed to
break them down every couple of months,
but they're supposed to take a look at
them every day because what happens is
you've got lots of parts and all in a
very moist moist area where you're going
to grow typically mold and fungus more
than anything else. So, you need to wipe
those things down with a sanitizing
solution and keep them clean. But those
ice bins you see that are up front at
the restaurants and all, those are going
to be cleaned daily and even sometimes
multipod times during the day. But at
your home, I'm glad glad to hear you
actually clean it because most people
Exactly. they're not cleaning their ice
machines at home. But if you do it once
a month, that would really be optimum,
especially cleaning this right here. And
they, you know, they come in all
different shapes and sizes, but the ice
basket, that's what you want to make
sure you clean.
>> Okay. I have a question. So, when I
entertain, I have to be in full head to
toe hosmat, you know.
>> Now, if you if you clean this as
described, it's going to be a low number
because what happens is the bacteria is
growing in place. You don't expect it.
But just in case, take this with you.
>> At least we can do appreciate it. We'll
be right back.
So sweet.
>> What you need to know about the latest
allnatural sweetener for your morning
coffee or tea. How's it taste?
>> Sweet.
>> Stay. Pay attention. It's coming up.
[Music]
[Applause]
We are back giving you the truth about
the sweetener you're adding to your
morning cup of coffee or tea. Now,
nutritionist Carrie Glasman's gonna go
take us beyond. Yeah, give her a hand.
She knows all about this stuff. go
beyond the pink, the blue, and the white
packets to break down two new allnatural
options that people are talking about.
She's here with Raquel, who is looking
for a new way to sweeten her morning
coffee. The first idea is completely
new. I have never heard about it before.
I've never tasted it. It is sweet potato
nectar. You always bring these breaking
ideas to us. What is this stuff? What
should we know?
>> So, I think we're going to be seeing a
lot of this this year. So, there's a big
anti-sugar movement going on, right? And
as a dietitian, that makes me very
happy. Manufacturers, however, are
looking for ways to please consumers
desire to still use sweetener. And I
think this is a prime example of that.
Also, it's a great alternative for
vegans instead of honey. So, that's a
great option there. And then from a
sustainability standpoint, it's really
interesting what they they use the ugly
potatoes that would normally be thrown
away and not sold to grocery stores. So
that's good. Good thing too.
>> As I process this, Raquel, your
thoughts.
>> It tastes really good with the coffee.
Like it's not very overwhelming and it's
it's light and it's not as heavy as like
my simple syrup.
>> Raquel, you're absolutely right. It
doesn't smack you. It's not as sweet as
sugar. How does it compare to sugar? How
many calories per tablespoon? All that.
>> Okay, so the calories are going to be
pretty equivalent to honey, which is
slightly higher than sugar. The big
difference is though that this has 6%
fructose whereas honey and sugar is
about 50% and then something like agave
has about 80%. And we know that added
fructose is really the type of sugar we
want to steer clear of as much as
possible because it's metabolized
different in the body and really is
linked to most of the health issues when
we're concerned about sugar.
>> Raquel here and take this and
>> take one of these potatoes too.
>> Thank you. All right, the next
sweetener. The next sweetener we're
going to talk about is something we have
looked at in the past. Monk fruit
sweetener. So, educate us about monk
fruit.
>> So, monk fruit has it comes from the
monk fruit, of course. It has
>> a very religious fruit.
>> It has z I like that person.
>> It has zero calories, but it's about 200
times sweeter than sugar. It has a very
low glycemic index, but it still may
trigger insulin secretion. So Carrie,
before we get to the taste, tell us how
it's sold.
>> Okay, so you can find it in a granular
form similar to sugar. You can find it
in a liquid form and then you can also
find it in a powder form. So it is a
good option. The only thing I'll say is,
you know, if you don't use any sweetener
at all, don't start adding something in
even if it has zero calories because
then you might just increase your
cravings for sweets in other places.
>> Amy, would this do it for you? I
actually I think it would because I
don't like that fake taste of those
other artificial sweeteners and I think
this would do it. Zero calories so it's
kind of nice
>> and it's not artificial. The taste is
fabulous. You like the taste I gather,
right?
>> Yeah, I do.
>> Again, it's got plenty of sweetness to
go around and I can't see any reason not
to do it. Toast to you and your good
ideas.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> As you go back to Becky, as you go to
break, I got a new idea for you to
sweeten up your green tea. You can make
it into a smoothie. Sweetened the
natural way with fruit and honey. Take a
look.
[Music]
Today on the show, we're doing a hip-hop
takeover. We're talking about a hip-hop
health summit with the stars of the
biggest music genre addressing the
industry shift to a healthier lifestyle.
>> Tune in to find out why we are trading
champagne bottles for vegan juice.
>> You won't want to miss this.
[Applause]
>> Sometimes the fame and fortune of the
music industry means living large in
more ways than one. Today, an important
hip-hop health summit with some of the
biggest names in hip-hop coming forward
about a new rapper revolution. A move
away from excess towards healthy eating
and living. One of the best known
rappers of all time, Fat Joe is here
today to reveal how he wants the fat.
Changing his body and his mindset.
Reporting from the front lines of the
hip hop health crisis is Fox 5's Lisa
Avers. You got to love every nasty thing
he says. Listen, Lisa is here with
Styles P and JD Kiss in a few minutes,
but this hip hop health summit is going
to start with a man, a larger than life
persona who's recently dropped 100
pounds. Please welcome fivetime Grammy
nominated hiphop artist Fat Joe.
[Applause]
Oh my goodness.
God bless you for being here. Oh, I'm so
proud to have you. You look amazing,
don't they?
>> And they're they're proud of you.
>> Now, Dr. Oz, it's a it's an honor to be
here with Dr. Oz. Uh, I've always I've
always watched your show with my wife,
with my family, and we love the work you
do and and bringing the the health me
message out there to the community. So,
I really want y'all to know I'm honored
to be here with Dr. Oz. This is a big
deal for you. God bless you. Thank you.
Well, there's so much to talk about. I
mean, I first saw you actually in action
helping kids learn about their bodies.
And what's so important about hip-hop
getting engaged in this is you guys tell
the truth.
>> That's the essence of the genre. So when
you tell kids the truth about their
lives, they listen to you.
>> But I'm going to start with you. I see
you walk out here. You got a swagger to
you. You got to look. Do you do you do
you do you feel as good as you look
right now?
>> Yeah, I feel as good as I look. And uh
I'm trying to feel even better, Dr. Oz.
And you got to keep it real with
yourself.
>> Yeah. Let's go back a second. Your
weight was part of your persona, right?
You named yourself Fat Joe.
>> Well, you know, I was always Fat Joey
from Forest Projects in the Bronx, you
know? So,
I don't think
>> I don't think a skinny Joe ever existed,
man.
>> But you tipped the scale of 460 lbs at
your heaviest.
>> Even more, Doc.
>> Even more.
>> We would go, Me and Big Pun, rest in
peace, you know, you go to Sizzlers and
you know, you put your plate on top of
the tray. We would take the plate off
and fill up the whole tray.
>> So, a lot of guys that come from where I
come from, you make money, you start
thinking you want to eat lobsters and
drinking bottles of champagne and you
want to do you're doing it big. But the
truth is you're doing more damage to
yourself. But take me back to that
point. Your first solo album comes out,
Represent. You go from being well known
in the South Bronx to becoming worldwide
in your appeal
>> and you have access to everything. So,
what are the pitfalls there? What? What?
What?
>> There's too much pitfalls. There's too
much pitfalls from then to now. Dr. O.
Like, everybody always seems to want to
eat, to meet, to talk, to do. It's like
I'm addicted to food. So, if I'm riding
in the highway and I see a McDonald's
signs, it's like McDonald's fries is
chasing me. They break dancing by me.
They doing salsa. Nah.
And And we got to And we got to try our
best to stay away from that. So in my
house, we don't have none of those
temptations. You know, my wife, she's
very health consscious, so we don't even
bring it in the house. So let me talk
about this wakeup call you had 2000. Joe
was scheduled to perform on SNL Saturday
Night Live with two of his closest
friends, Jennifer Lopez and Big Pun, who
you just mentioned a few seconds ago.
Big Pun canled at the last minute. Two
days later, you received the devastating
news. He had passed.
>> We were young, right? So when you young,
you think you're invincible. And so we
got to teach the youth from now.
>> Well, how did it affect you when this
big punk was 28 years old, weighed 700
lb, has a heart attack, respiratory
failure, leaves three kids behind, and a
wife?
>> I went on uh what I call a crackhead
diet where I ain't eat nothing for like
a whole year and I started working out
at the YMCA. So I lost about 100 pounds.
So what's been the key to the what's on
your road to success? What are the the
obvious?
>> Education is key, Dr. Oz. That's why we
love you so much and we appreciate what
you do.
So education is key. So a lot of people
a lot of people so diabetes is like the
VIP, the express lane to death,
>> right?
>> And people don't realize some people
say, "Yo, I don't have a sweet tooth. I
don't have I don't eat all this junk
food." But when you when you go to a
Spanish restaurant, they put bread with
butter on the table. Once you eat that
bread, it turns into sugar in the body.
>> You know,
>> then you eat the rice, beans, and god
forbid you eat fried chicken or
something like that. But let's just say
the rice and beans and platinos.
>> That's all sugar in your body.
>> Then when you turn around and you eat a
dessert or something like that, god
forbid you drink two sodas, you're done.
You're you're recipe for death. So we
got to stay away from the carbs. What I
mean by carbs, I mean rice, bread,
spaghetti, potatoes, all of that we got
to do away with. So, we got to eat meats
if you into eating meats, fish, chicken,
but you got to you got to lace it with
greens. That's the only way you're going
to live. The carbs are the killer. Doc,
>> you want to co-host the show from now
on?
>> No, I mean, I would love to.
>> I'm in. I'm in. I tell you, you got it.
>> All right. So, we got a mutual friend,
Eug
I gather he and others are looking at
you and saying, "If Fat Joe can do it,
we can do it."
>> Khaled is my little brother. I
discovered him and he uh one day he
called me up and he said, "What's the
gimmick? What's the secret?" And I said,
"What you mean, what's the gimmick?"
"Nah, you got a secret. Your your your
neck is skinny." So, I'm like, "Yeah."
So, I said, he's possessed with this
neck skinny thing, right? So I said,
"Kallet, man, there's no other gimmick.
We got to stay off the carbs. We got to
work out." So he had Weight Watchers
help him with the diet. I I put some uh
workout routines with him and I kept
calling him every day, facetiming them
every day. And now he lost close to 50
lbs. So that's what I did to calendar.
>> Before we go to break, one question
about someone else you care a lot about.
>> JLo.
>> Well, I love JLo. She's she's a machine.
>> She is a machine. Uh, she's probably
going to go down as the best looking
older woman ever. Like, ever.
>> She might.
>> There she is. There's Hy Barry. There's
a couple of them. Haley, Bailey, and and
a couple of them. But I think JLo's
going to win.
>> So, are you going to the wedding with
A-Rod?
>> I would love if she invites me, I'm
going 1 million%. I think it's a
beautiful couple. Her and A.
>> He's handsome. She's beautiful. They're
good.
>> They're handsome. All right. When we
come back, Lisa Evers is here with some
of the the biggest stuff you want to
hear about. Music's heaviest hitters are
trained in champagne for vegan juice,
sparking a hip-hop health revolution.
[Applause]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day, but when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
[Applause]
For years, it seemed like the hip-hop
community has kept quiet while its
biggest stars battled health problems
due to lies of excess until now. Today,
a hip-hop health summit with the stars
of the biggest music genre addressing a
big shift in the industry towards a
healthier lifestyle. I'm here with a
woman who's been on the front lines
telling hip-hop story from the very
beginning. Fox 5 reporter right here in
New York City, Emmy nominated host of
Street Soldiers, Lisa Evers. Fat Joe we
just spoke to. He's lost 100 pounds
recently. He lost 100 before that. And
two members of the iconic The Locks
rappers Styles P and Jana Kiss who are
bringing health back to their old
neighborhood one green juice at a time.
Take it away. I want I want you to talk
to folks that you brought to our stage
today because they're each of you iconic
in your own way and I'm very proud that
you're here talking about something that
matters.
>> No, definitely. Well, Styles and JD Kiss
with the juices, the community, their
whole thing. They've been involved. All
three of these gentlemen have been
involved in the community from the very,
very beginning. No matter how famous
they become, no matter the world tours,
the awards, the Grammy nominations, all
of that. And for you guys, this whole
mission of food, especially coming from
the urban centers where you get
fluorescent colored soda or something
fried, that's pretty much it. It's more
of a mission to you. It's not just about
a health craze. Tell us about that.
>> It's very much a mission. I mean, fast
food has been around since the late
1800s, early 1900s, which means in most
neighborhoods, you you're acquired to
living fast and just picking up the the
meals. So, every every poor
neighborhood, urban neighborhood, just
every neighborhood in the country period
should have healthy options like and it
should be known what the healthy options
are.
>> And Chris, what
Chris, what about the influence of
social media, too? because people see
the artist, they see you guys every day,
they see every aspect of your life, they
make all kinds of comments. Is that
playing a role kind of pushing people in
a positive direction?
>> Social media definitely plays a role.
It's definitely a big platform. Um, you
know, a lot of times the kids or the
people, your followers, fans, they
usually go off what they see. So, if you
you in the juice bar, you in your own
crib cutting up some bananas or, you
know, just living a healthy lifestyle,
it usually follows. And you know what I
mean? It'll go a long way. They watch
your pages like more than they watch you
in real life.
>> It'll be so easy for you guys with the
fame and fortune you found just move on
and leave it all behind. That's actually
why I'm so honored you're here
>> because you could have moved on in life.
>> I think
>> that's not what that's not what it's
about. It's always about whether it's
health, whether it's any any type of
issue in our community. We we love our
community. So everybody talks about
getting rich and moving out the hood. we
actually come back and embrace and open
businesses in our hood and show them how
to live a healthy healthy lifestyle. You
know, it's all about our people, bro.
>> And Dr. Oz, I think also the core of
hiphop is about authenticity. So, it's
also about caring about yourself, caring
about your loved ones, too, because
we've seen too many big stars pass away
in their 40s from weight related
problems like diabetes, like heart
issues. And I think when you see stars
of this level and this magnitude,
they're among the others like we see
like Common Erica Badu, we've seen she's
on the R&B side, but we've seen so many
other artists who've shed the weight and
are ador, you know, adopting these
healthy lifestyles and they're making it
a trend. They're also making healthy
eating, a healthy lifestyle,
>> like a lifestyle. It's more than a trend
because trends come and go. Like you
say, this right here is permanent. It's
not temporary. This is to you go.
>> Definitely. Styles and Jada wanted to
share this with all of you guys in the
audience. So, backstage, I heard you got
something ready for us.
>> Yeah. Special. Yes, we do. Yes, we do.
We got the Oz coming.
>> The We got the Oz coming.
>> I have a drink. We got the I have a
drink.
>> We We We are fans of huge fans of Dr.
Oz. So, we know you're a kale fan.
>> Oh, I do love
>> So, we have kale, spinach, bananas,
green apple. Oh my goodness.
Toast tonight.
>> Toast to all you guys. Let's toast to
hip hop health revolution. God bless
your boot
>> and to you Dr.
>> Thanks for bringing this story to us.
You guys are wonderful. Best of wishes
to you. We'll be right back. Last more
to do.
[Music]
>> Ted Bundy. His last brutal attack before
his capture. One survivor speaks out.
>> When he attacked me, my jaw was
shattered. My cheek was torn open.
>> Plus, buyer beware. When murder houses
go up for sale, all new oz.
>> That's coming up tomorrow.
[Applause]
[Music]
Today, the number one thing I never
leave home without, and you shouldn't
either. I'm talking about aspirin. Now,
every year nearly 800,000 Americans will
suffer from a heart attack. Right? It's
a common problem. And listen carefully.
Nearly 800,000 more will have a stroke.
>> But you may be able to save your own
life and the lives of those you love.
Here to tell us more is cardiologist Dr.
Paul Gerbal, who's here on behalf of my
trusted sponsor partner there. Dr. Why
is it that we have so much control over
our future? And how can aspirin, chewing
it in particular, save our lives if
we're having a heart attack?
>> Well, it's important to note that when
you chew the aspirin, it speeds up its
ability to get into your circulation.
And that's where aspirin works. It works
by blocking platelets from sticking
together. And it's that sticking
together of the platelets that occurs in
the artery and your heart. So, by
chewing the aspirin, you speed the
delivery of the aspirin to the clot and
you allow the blood flow to continue.
And it's important to note that in the
setting of a heart attack, you call 911,
you chew the aspirin, crush it, and
swallow it. Now, I know you don't like
the taste of the aspirin. I get that.
But it's really important to remember
this lesson. Let me show you what
happens to your body when you do take an
aspirin. So, let's go inside the heart
first. Dr. Gripple spoke about this, but
this vessel in the middle of the heart
sends blood into the heart so it can
keep beating. This vessel right here.
Let's go inside of that vessel and see
what happens. The blood vessel has
little red cells that are courarssing
through it. But this plaque, this white
plaque, can grow larger. Now, watch
carefully. Right here, there's a little
irritated area and a plaque and it
ruptures. Now, your body has an open
sore in there and platelets which are
sticky form a little clot to heal you.
But unfortunately, they close off the
artery blocking it and boom, it's like
someone punched the front of your heart.
It causes a heart attack. But if you
take an aspirin, right, which again, you
should ideally chew it when you start to
feel that pain. Pop that aspirin in
there, right? And as you chew it, it's
immediately gets into your bloodstream,
right? And it can affect that artery
that I just showed you. It's go back to
that same artery. Now you have those
same red cells running through there
bringing nutrition, oxygen to your body,
to your arteries, and to your heart. But
that plaque when it gets big and it
ruptures, watch what happens. You have a
plate that stick a little bit, but you
don't form this big scab. Blood can
still get around it. A little bit of
blood can escape. That gives us time.
that makes it possible for us to get in
there and push this open with a stent or
do bypass surgery or melt this clot
away. We can do lots of things to save
you. Just give us the time to help you.
Dr. Gerbo, you say that aspirin and
having a good regimen for it is crucial
if you've already experienced some type
of a cardiovascular event.
>> Well, that's because patients who've had
a cardiovascular event have proven that
they can already form a clot, a serious
clot in the heart or in the brain. And
it's in these patients where aspirin is
particularly important. And in fact,
administration of aspirin under the
direction of a doctor can reduce the
second occurrence of a heart attack by
31%.
>> And a a a clot related stroke by 22%.
But of course, all patients need to talk
to their doctor first before starting an
aspirin, stopping an aspirin regimen, or
changing an aspirin regimen.
>> Give us the numbers one more time. 31%
reduction of having another heart attack
if you've had one. 31%
>> 31%
>> and 22% reduction in the occurrence of a
second stroke.
>> These are massive numbers, big numbers
and no one knows them better than Tony
because she's been taking Bayer aspirin
ever since she had an eskeemic stroke.
Thank you for being here very much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> So you had this, if I understand
correctly, this eskeemic stroke
>> two years ago.
>> Yes.
>> You look good. You feeling okay?
>> Yeah, I feel great.
>> All right. So So thankfully you're able
to recover. So you had to get advice. So
what went through your mind after you
had this stroke? You're still a young
woman.
>> Yes. Um I was terrified. I was so
scared. I couldn't believe this actually
happened to me. Um I didn't know what my
future was going to hold, but I knew
that I needed to make some changes in my
lifestyle to um commit to stop smoking.
>> Good for you. Did you do it?
>> Yes, I did. Clean.
>> I like that, Tony. And also I started an
exercise routine
>> running marathons.
>> Oh no,
>> no, but something
>> no
>> that makes us sweat once in a while.
>> Exactly. Yes.
>> So she told me that taking taking bare
aspirin is a key component in helping
prevent a second cardiovascular event in
your case.
>> Yes.
>> How does that fit into your regime?
>> Um my doctor uh put me on aspirin after
my stroke and I've continued to take
that every day since faithfully. It's on
my nightstand.
>> Good for you.
>> And um yeah, I have so much to live for,
so much to be thankful for. My wonderful
husband who has been so amazing and
supportive through my recovery. He's
just an amazing man. And um so it's
important to me that I make every
change possible so that I can live a
long and healthy life. You know, I'm
proud of you for taking charge.
>> Thank you.
>> You had a warning sign. Thankfully, you
recovered from it. Not everyone so lucky
as you. But when you have a second
chance, don't give it up. And for most
folks, they prevent the first problem
from ever happening. That's even better.
So, Dr. Gerbal, who should be taking a
daily aspirin?
>> Well, you know, the the decision about
taking a daily aspirin is best a
decision made between the treating
doctor and the and the patient. You know
there are many reasons patients take
aspirin for pain control for control of
fever for arthritic pain but it's
important to note that aspirin is an
important cardiovascular medicine and it
can save save lives. So the doctor needs
to take into account the total health of
the patient. It's a personalized
decision that needs to be made and in
that setting many patients can derive a
benefit from personalized treatment with
aspirin.
>> Yeah. Remember the word doctor comes
from the Latin for teacher. That's what
we're supposed to be as teachers. So you
were a good student. You came to class
prepared. I'm proud of you for doing
that.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks to my partner Bear. You're all
going home. Everyone here with a Bear
aspirin pill tote to keep in your wallet
or your purse. And that's not all.
You're also getting a $100 gift card to
CVS. Enjoy it. We'll be right back.
Ow.
[Music]
I love those. If you're a cat owner,
then you know your cat could get into
anything. Just like those cats we shot.
This is my family cat. We call him baby
cat. Actually, Daffhne originally got
him, but we've adopted him into our
family. So, when we read that an uber
popular household item can be especially
dangerous to cats, well, I wanted to
find out more. Dr. Heather Lenser,
senior veterary officer with the
American Animal Hospital Association, is
here with a warning. So, what is this
potential new danger that cat owners
should be worried about?
>> It's actually essential oils. Just like
oil and water, cats and essential oils
don't mix. And the reason is their liver
is lacking very specific enzymes that
help metabolize and break down certain
drugs. Dogs and people have this enzyme,
but cats don't. So they're sitting by a
diffuser like this. They get the oil
onto their fur and they ingest it
because you know how they like to keep
themselves clean
>> fidiously. There they are. Look
>> licking.
>> Exactly.
>> Pawing.
>> So you So they or they can inhale it as
well. And so some people actually
accidentally thinking they're doing the
right thing will try to prevent things
like fleas by putting essential oils on
their cats. So not only is it not
effective, it actually can be toxic as
well.
>> So what do you do if your pet is exposed
to some of these essential oils?
>> Well, if especially if they show start
showing signs like vomiting, diarrhea,
difficulty breathing, like if a cat ever
is panting, they need to go to the vet.
That's an emergency. And you want to
make sure that in an emergency, the
hospital's accredited by the American
Animal Hospital Association so they can
take as the great care of your animal.
>> But if my pet my pets baby cat's not
panting, but they got the aroma, can I
shampoo it off? How do I clean?
>> You get the solution to pollution is
dilution. So you can actually just uh
give them a quick bath with a degreasing
shampoo. Even something like dishwashing
detergent is fine.
>> And options if you like the smell as my
wife does very much, but you don't have
essential oils, you have a a fail safe
backup. Uh something soy based would be
a great idea. You just keep it away from
your cat and you know how curious they
can be.
>> Yes. But this would end up in the ground
for us. But but this is what we actually
do right now to keep our cats safe.
>> Excellent.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Have a great day.
>> Together. Change is happening my
friends. Our journey is just beginning.
[Music]