My next guest is a modeling superstar in
the 70s and 80s and she's been a
familiar face in movies on television
ever since. But the past couple of years
have been challenging for Christina
Ferrari. She has fought cancer and she
lost her mom after a long battle with
Alzheimer's. Now Christina is making it
her mission to help improve your brain
health with her new cookbook, Food for
Thought. So Christina, come on out.
[Applause]
[Music]
You know, you do the runway beautiful.
You know, it's been years and I always
worried about tripping. So, thank gosh
do it this time. Well, first of all, you
look wonderful. You look healthy,
actually. I am healthy. I am healthy.
How you doing after this cancer
diagnosis?
Um, I'm doing super well. Well, I'm in
remission. So, I'm glad to hear that. I
had a stem cell replacement and I'm
doing really well. So, thank you, God.
In remission. Let me just get everyone
on the same page. You had a diagnosis of
my multiple myyoma, which is a bone
marrow ailment. There's no cure, but
there are very effective treatments. And
you mentioned you had one, which is a
stem cell transplant. Yes. I was
diagnosed in 2016 with multiple myyoma.
And I'm I'm thinking, "Oh my gosh, this
is this is serious." I thought it's, you
know, I can imagine the feeling at the
moment they use that word cancer. Well,
you know, Dr. Ar, which is really
strange. You think when you get a
diagnosis of of, you know, you have
cancer, you're going to panic and and
all of a sudden you think, "Oh my god,
your life is over." I don't know what
happened. I I I I did not panic. I did
not feel sorry for myself. I did not and
I wasn't scared. And my attitude was,
okay, what is it and how do we deal with
it? So this bone marrow transplant which
which please applaud you because you
were brave in the face of this but this
bone marrow transplant forces you to
essentially reboot your body. Yes it it
did. I knew instinctively the first
thing the doctors told me was to stay
off the internet of course which I
didn't do. I went right to the internet
and I you know I I I read about it and
it said you have two to five years to
live and and I said no no no this is not
working for me. So I instinctively I
said I'm going to look up stem cells bec
and I don't know why and I did and I
said to the doctor we're going to cut to
the chase. We're not going to do all
this stuff. I'm going to have a stem
cell. You know Tom Bro has um multiple
myoma. He's been on the show. Yes. And
uh I've known him for a lot of years. So
I called him and I said uh Tom I have
multiple myoma multiple myyoma. and his
words were, "Well, kiddo, you know, his,
well, kiddo, if you're going to have a
cancer, this is the best one to have
because they've made the most uh they
made the most inroads as far as finding
a cure and it's manageable. You'll be
able to live a very long life and I've
known people through my support group
that have that are 20 25 years out. So,
I'll probably die of old age, I hope, or
you know, before that, you know, before
most of my own." I don't know if people
know what this is, but which you get
chemotherapy, they basically kill off
your bone marrow and then you replace
the now dead or cancerous cells with
healthy ones. So the whoever gave the
bone marrow to you is basically you. It
was me. I was my own donor. Oh, good.
Yeah. They find that if you are able to
manufacture your own stem cells, you
have a better chance of a longer uh
recovery time. So I opted to use me. And
how do you build your immune system back
up after the transplant? How do you get
it back to recovery range? Uh well, it
my doctors were really uh shocked at how
well and how quickly I recovered from
it. And I I believe it's because of the
way that I've always um I've I always
ate. I was always uh very skeptical
about, you know, the pesticides,
chemicals, eating organic. And my
doctors, I was supposed to be in the
hospital for almost a month. I was there
a little less than two weeks and I was
home. and they said it was because my um
the way that I ate that it helped my
body um to heal much faster. And while
you're struggling for your life, your
mom has Alzheimer's. Yes, my my mom my
mom has suffered from Alzheimer's for
about eight years. Uh she passed away
two years ago and uh it's one of my
missions in life. I'm working with Maria
Shrivever on this new book, Food for
Thought. You know, Maria's in the
forefront of finding a cure for
Alzheimer's disease. her father,
Sergeant Shrivever, passed from the
disease. So, we work every I'm working
uh with her in the Women's Alzheimer's
movement, and part of the proceeds of
Food for Thought are going to go to the
women's Alzheimer's movement. And that's
something um you know, I have two
passions now beside, of course, my
family. There's three um is multiple
myyoma and Alzheimer's disease. So, this
is this is what I'm doing now. This is
my mission in life. Well, what you're
really really good at, I think, is
giving us tools to help with both these
issues. So, up next, Christina has chose
us a recipe from her new book. It's so
darn fun to make. Your kids and
grandkids will want to help you out.
That's how good it is. Trust me, it's
fun. It is fun. This is worth it. Stick
around. Fun. It's fun. We are back with
Christina Ferrari, who has a new
cookbook, Food for Thought. It's all
about food that can improve the health
of our minds and our bodies. I love your
body healing salad in the book. Yes.
It's a cute idea. It makes sense. Moms,
grandmas can make this with the with the
kids, teach them about the body. Yes.
So, we're going to start at the top of
the body. This is the brain. We should
be eating a lot of walnuts. These are
anti-inflammatory. As you can see,
there's a left and right hemisphere, and
it looks just like the brain. The next
thing, you're going to love this one.
Did you ever cut open a carrot? And if
you look really carefully at it, you can
actually see the pupil and the iris of
the eye. So, what is what do carrots
have? They have beta carotene and
vitamin A, and they're good for the eye.
Did any of you know this? Anybody? Did
you ever look at it and see? We have We
have the smartest audience in
television. And they know about carrots,
but they didn't do the anatomy lesson.
This is one I did. I'm a heart surgeon.
I didn't think about the tomato for the
heart. You cut the tomato in half and
there's actually the chamber of the
heart. Look at that. And this has
lycopine in it and it's good for your
heart. It's also very anti-inflammatory
and it's full of vitamins that you need.
Also anti-inflammatory. And the reason
why I keep saying that is your health,
all health begins in the gut. So it's
your gut first, then your heart, and
then your brain. You have to feed all
three parts of those bodies for body
parts for ultimate health. You have
ginger for the stomach. This is for your
tummy. Do you ever have a tummy ache or
you're you are nauseous? This is a great
thing for you to eat. Ginger is good for
your tummy. This I love is your
pancreas. I mean, there's a pancreas. If
this is a sweet potato, it actually
looks like your pancreas. And why why do
you have an avocado here? Now, I love
this. This is my favorite. This is an
avocado and it's shaped like your uter
Well, if you're a woman or uterus, your
uterus. And it has a seed. Come on. It
has a seed in it. So this feeds all all
the the parts and it also has all of the
good fats in it that you should be
eating. I eat a small avocado every day.
U this is uh the grapes and or figs
which are low hanging fruits. Uh this is
for uh the testes or testicles. Now wait
now men have you know now there's
testicular cancer, prostate cancer.
These are all the things that uh grapes
have resveratrol in it which is um
anti-inflammatory as well and you should
be having that because it lowers your
LDLs and your lowers your cholesterol
and what does that do? It helps your
heart and our bones are like celery.
Celery and they have silicon in them and
you should be eating that as well
because it's hard to come by uh
naturally. You'll have to take
supplements but you should be eating
this. And so um I like this. Yeah. This
is you should There you go. There's your
body. Okay. And you can just throw them
together. Yes. Make a salad. Now, what I
did is I took all of those elements that
you had there and I have there and I
added arugula and some spinach.
Everything is organic. Look how
beautiful. And then the dressing itself,
this is spectacular as well. Pretty
straightforward. Yes. This is this is
from the book and I have other um
dressings in the book, but this is the
citrus Asian marinade which we're going
to pour over the salad. And we'll do
maybe about five or six tablespoons.
There you go. Here we go. You don't have
to deserve it. Just look at this. And
you tell me the family won't dive into
this. Yeah, I've done all this to
address the healthy part of the show,
but something that's a secret that
everybody is going to enjoy. It has to
do with dark chocolate. Dark chocolate
is actually good for you.
You chocolate turtle apple lovers. What
do you got for us? Well, a lot of people
think you can't eat desserts. I have a
whole dessert section in the book.
Eliminating all the sugar. I I sweeten
everything with maple syrup and um uh
stevia, which is a healthy uh sweetener.
And what we did here, your kids can help
you, too, or you could just do it
yourself. These are green apples. I made
them nice and chilled. And you stick a
little um stick in there. And then you
melt your chocolate, your dark
chocolate, which is very good. I eat a
piece of dark chocolate every single
night. Every night, look at that. Isn't
that beautiful? And then when we're
done, what part of the body is a
chocolate, you think? Oh, all parts of
your body loves it. Yeah, your heart
especially. Okay, so then you can
decorate it any way you want. You could
have your kids come in and do it. And
then you put them in the refrigerator.
And what I love about it is I made a
whole bunch for um New Year's Eve. Uh
New Year's Eve. Oh, he's going in. Oh,
you guys get to eat some. You keep
talking over. So for New Year's Eve, you
just put it in the freezer and then you
can have your dessert. So you don't
forget you can have dessert. And I guess
we're going to Everybody, you know what?
You're all going to get chocolate
covered apples.
All right, guys. You like it? Yeah. You
get all these recipes. You like these
things every day. Yes. You get all these
recipes on dr.com. Grac's new book. It's
called Food for Thoughts. available now
and a portion of all the proceeds will
go to the women's Alzheimer movement.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good