[Applause]
Are you living every day to its fullest?
A simple question. Or do you feel
drained like you're sleepwalking through
life? Well, my next guest says he has a
plan to awaken you. Epac Chopra is the
guru who Oprah and Madonna turn to
today. He's your own personal guide,
giving you the ultimate personality quiz
to unleash your infinite potential.
Please welcome my good friend Deepak
Chopra.
[Music]
Thank you.
Thank you. This is the man I rely on
when I have deep questions. And I've
always and I've told everyone this. When
I was a a young surgeon, I would stay up
late at night watching videos you had
made just to understand what was deeper
than what I was facing in the hospital.
And I'd love if you just give folks a
little bit of an insight into because
everyone sort of sees, you know, what
you see is what you get. They think
about that for themselves, think about
that for the life around them. But you
say there's so much more potential.
You've always said this. Yes. We only
see that which you're conditioned to
see. So when a child is born, the child
is full of wonder, curiosity,
uh joy, love, compassion, empathy. And
then we impose limitations by saying you
are this entity with this name, this
nationality, this ethnic race, and now
you're bamboozled into a restricted
identity when in fact your potential is
infinite. It's the awareness in which
the body and the mind and the world is
happening all at the same time. Use that
word awareness. Yes. Is is awareness the
new word for I don't know mindfulness
what used to be the phrase that we were
using. Are they the same thing? It's a
little beyond that because awareness of
the mind is not the mind. If you're
aware of a thought then automatically
you know that I'm not the thought. The
awareness of this experience is not this
experience. This is a perceptual
changing experience. The awareness is
the timeless sear in the midst of time
bound experiences. What spiritual
traditions call the soul the timeless
seer in the midst of the changing
scenery. We're right now in the midst of
the changing scenery and our body and
our mind is part of the scenery because
you're aware of this this this and what
you're thinking all at the same time.
And we're above that. We are above that.
So how aware are you? That's the
question of today's show. So, we've got
a quiz to recognize and realize your
infinite potential. So, grab a piece of
paper or use the the notepad on your
phone. Just keep track of the answers
because we're going to give you these
couple questions and have you count up
the points at the end. The choices are
always going to be never. Now, I never
do this. Sometimes it's true or it's
always true. Keep track of how many of
each number that you get and we'll give
you your score at the end. So, first
question, how often do you desire to be
understood better by others? Three
points for never, two points sometimes,
one point for always. See, I I actually
always want to be understood. I'm a
teacher. I I drives me crazy if my kids,
folks watching the show, frankly, even
my opponents who don't like what I'm
saying, I want them to understand my
point. Yes. But if you're focusing on
that, then you're not focusing on making
them understand your point. So the
journey is the destination. If I'm
walking from here to there, if I'm only
looking there, I'll stumble here. So
it's question of being in the process
and being detached from the outcome at
the same time knowing that the outcome
is guaranteed. If you're studying for an
exam, then you study. You're not
thinking about the results all the time.
Then when do you do the study? Okay,
next question. Shnie from audi is going
to help us with this. You ready, Shnie?
Yes. Deep's going to blow your mind. So,
how often do you sense flawlessness and
beauty in everything and everyone just
as they are? One point. One point for
never, two points for sometimes, three
point for always. Oh, three points for
always. Always. Um, I believe that
flawlessness manifested me being here
today. Today is my birthday and I didn't
make plans. Good for you being here.
Yeah.
And I'm I happen to be using the
meditation around abundance that you
have created and I'm on day eight and I
manifested you and this because I
believe like flawlessness shows up. I
don't have to do much of anything. So
flawless flawlessness
flows as effortless spontaneity and
synchronicity. It's what the spiritual
traditions call grace. Some people call
it good luck and some people call it
being at the right place at the right
time. meaningful coincidences. This is a
sign that you're in touch with yourself.
You're aware of being aware. Oh, sure.
You got grace going for you, which is
always nice. That's it. All right. Next
question. How often do you feel that you
are defending the self-image you hold
about yourself? I'm going to come back
to grace in a second and and soul and
all these big ideas, but keep track of
your points for now. Please explain this
question because it's an interesting you
know defending what you're holding on to
and motiv being motivated by fear and
mistrust are are continuous conflicts.
If you're constantly defending your
selfimage you're sacrificing yourself
for your selfie. You are not your
selfie. This is right now the perceptual
snapshot of your self-image. Who you
really are is a field of infinite
possibilities. If you go beyond your
selfimage to your true self, you have
insight, intuition, creativity, vision,
high consciousness. This is what we all
want. That's unbelievable.
All right, next question. How often do
you feel your actions are motivated by
fear and mistrust? Fear suggests that
you feel separate from existence,
but there's no way to be separate from
existence. We are part of existence. And
the opposite of fear is of course, as
everybody says, love and compassion and
joy and loss of fear, which allows you
to tap into the ecosystem that we call
life. When you're connected with life,
your life flourishes. All right, last
question is, how often do you feel truly
alive, filled with vitality? It's
something we talk about, but you got to
grade yourself now. So, well, I wake up
every morning with four intentions.
joyful energetic body, loving
compassionate heart, reflective alert
mind, and lightness of being. If if you
do that, you give yourself three points.
If you sometimes do what he was talking
about, two points, and if you never
think about the whole question, it's one
point. So, hope everyone counted their
points up because it's time to reveal
the results. Where do you fall on the
awareness spectrum? If your points added
up to between 12 and 15, you're most
aware of your potential. That's pretty
cool. If your score fell between 8 and
11, you're more or less in the middle,
right? moderately aware of your
potential. That's sort of where I ended
up. I had 11 points on the scale. And
those of you who score between five and
seven, you're the least aware of your
potential. So, you got something to do
about it. So, Shaunie, let's bring you
back in again if you don't mind. What
was your overall score? 13. 13. Yes.
Look at that. She manifest everything.
Yes. True grace. All right. For the for
the mere mortals like me and a lot of
the other folks watching now, we're
going to give you some clues because
coming up, awareness is a new
mindfulness. Deepac's ultimate trick to
becoming more aware. Stick around.
Before the break, we gave everyone a
quiz. If you missed it, you can find the
entire quiz on dr.com right this second.
Now, apex says there is a spectrum of
awareness. What does that mean? To be
fully present to experience in the
present moment and also to yourself
is presence which is awareness. It is
the timeless factor in every experience.
So, I'm going to ask you guys, are you
present right now? Yes. Yes. Say it a
little more enthusiastically.
Now I'm going to ask you the same
question, but don't answer it. Are you
present right now?
Be aware of being aware. Be aware of
that which is listening. So one can at
any moment stop and ask oneself, am I
present? And that's the way you expand
your awareness. Because if you're not
present, then your awareness is very
restricted. If you're present, then all
this is happening right now and it's
joyful and there's nothing wrong with
it. The wrongness comes from
anticipation, regrets, memories,
resistance, and that interferes with
what we call flow, transcendence,
effortless spontaneity. So Debb's a
wonderful new book. It's called
Metahuman: Unleashing Your Infinite
Potential. And he calls this the high
level of selfawareness.
What exactly is a metahuman? Meta means
beyond. Human in this case refers to our
robotic conditioned mind. Everybody is a
bundle of condition reflexes constantly
being triggered by people and
circumstance into stressful outcomes. If
you step back and you can be aware of
yourself, that's the highest
intelligence to observe yourself without
judging yourself. Oh, it's deep stuff.
So Deepax team found that we can improve
your score on the awareness spectrum in
as little as a week of focused mind and
you know your body can improve it
accordingly as well. Yeah, the body is a
projection. So the test we just took in
the last segment you can actually
improve your skill in not just a little
bit of effort. So there's one thing that
people can start doing right now you
talk about in the book and has to do
with closing off your ears a little
sensory deprivation. Well you close your
ears sound becomes muffled. You open
them, sound is there again. You are
present as awareness in the sound and in
the absence of sound and in the wide
range of sounds that are part of every
moment of experience that applies to
every sense. All right, let's just do
sound for a sec. Everyone, if you don't
mind, put your hands before you before
you close your ears off. Keep your hands
there till I take my hands down. It's
fair to do this. Look straight ahead.
Cup your hands over your ears. Right?
And if you just give that two or three
seconds
and put your hands down. Now that
deprivation of sound allowed us to
you'll have better appreciation of sound
if you muffle the sound and experience
it again. Similarly, if you close your
eyes in darkness and then immediately
open them, your visual acuity will
improve. I think is I always thought
because I read the book, I thought there
was also a benefit of allowing yourself
to be free of the distraction of sound.
So for example, one more time, put your
hands, make it more challenging.
[Music]
Did any of you notice that loud guitar
playing?
I mean, Sean's worldass musician, but
still it's distracting. And I say, if
you can master the muffling, Deepac, if
I'm right on this, if you can master the
muffling of the loud stuff that's going
on in the world, then just to get rid of
some of those distractions, then you can
be much closer to the self-awareness
that you're preaching to us. That's
right. And you can be present to
experience as it happens. And also by
muffling the sound and expanding it
again, you can play with your senses and
you can actually improve your capacity
for sensory experience. Guys, discover a
part of your body, parts of your body
you never thought of before. Thank you
very much. For this full personality
test, go to drz.com. You can also pick
up a copy of Deepak Chopra's fantastic
book, Metahhuman, for the full 31-day
guideing your infinite potential. Sean,
play the break.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good