Today is salad safe to eat again?
Recall. This lettuce recall is
nationwide outbreaks. Parasite outbreak
triggers recall. Contamination.
Contamination is widespread. We go
inside the lettuce industry. The leaders
of today's top brands answer the tough
questions. Plus, can you overdose on
probiotics? New headlines raise the
question, is it too much of a good
thing? Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you
[Music]
guys. You hesitate at the salad bar or
think twice before buying bagged salad.
Well, maybe. Maybe you wonder, is it
safe to eat salad again? Consumer
confidence is down when it comes to
lettuce safety. And it's no wonder. It
seems like every day there's another new
headline about a food born illness
outbreak with lettuce as the culprit. So
today, for the first time, we're going
straight to the source. In just a few
minutes, you will hear directly from the
lettuce industry leaders who out there.
We're going to find out what they're
doing to keep your salad safe. Take a
look.
The Roma scare hit hard with epic panic
over the E. coli outbreak, leaving
Caesar salad and rap lovers afraid. Ever
since the Roma lettuce scare last year,
I've just been very unsure if I should
feed my family romaine lettuce. I've
read the headlines and now I'm
horrified. Is it less safe to buy bags
of lettuce or heads of lettuce? Every
year, one in six Americans get sick from
food. That's 48 million people. And
lettuce is frequently implicated. More
people getting sick from lettuce linked
to an E.coli outbreak. This year, the
largest E.coli scare in over a decade
stemmed from people eating greens grown
in this part of the country, Yuma,
Arizona. But those Yuma greens were sold
nationwide. People in 36 states got
sick. Almost a hundred were
hospitalized. And five even died before
that crisis was over.
And just this month, the FDA and CDC
along with state and local officials
wrapped up their investigation into
another multi-state outbreak linked to
greens. This time it was cycllos
parasis. From salads consumed at
McDonald's, but officials weren't able
to identify a single source of
contamination. From romaine to all the
salad greens you love. Today, lettuce
industry insiders and brands are
answering your
questions. Let's look at what food born
illnesses look like. This little
parasite here, it looks like the death
star from Star Wars, right? It's called
cycllospora, which recently caused a
large outbreak thought to be linked to
fast food salads. I mean, this thing
there's not bacteria. They're little
proto little little parasites. Then
there's salmonella, right? You've heard
of salmonella. Has these little hairike
things. They're known as psyia that help
them move through your system. It's one
of the most common causes of food
poisoning in the United States. It's not
so pretty when it's inside of you. And
then there's this little guy elegantly
swimming. See my motoring along here,
right? It's called E.coli. This is the
bacteria behind the Roma outbreak
earlier this summer. Again, these are
spectacular species, but not when
they're attacking you. So, when you eat
something contaminated by one of these
bad boys, you'll feel it. Most people
just get vomiting. They'll get diarrhea.
But a few thousand Americans do die from
the effects of food born illness every
year. So, it's important we track these
outbreaks. We asked Consumer Reports
chief scientist James Dickerson to help
us understand what happened with
lettuce. I should point out during the
Roma outbreak last summer, Consumer
Reports advised consumers to stop eating
Roma even before the government issued
warnings. So, you're ahead of the game
and thank you for being there. Do you
think we're just reporting this more
often? Are we truly having more food
born outbreaks? So, the simple answer is
we're not entirely sure. It could be a
little bit of both. We certainly have
rapidly growing population. Uh we have
more sources of food, but there's more
media coverage. So it could be really a
combination of both. And why is lettuce
so problem problematic? I mean it's it's
the best food force. Why is it the
culprit? So as you mentioned the center
for disease control uh stated that 20%
of all food born illnesses related to
ecoli particularly come from leafy
greens. The thing is is that there's
nothing intrinsically wrong with
lettuce. No, it's it's what we're doing
to it. Walk me over here and show me the
major steps of contamination. And James,
you know this area really well. So,
we're going to break it down. There are
basically five ways that lettuce, poor
old innocent lettuce, because it's
usually a bystander, gets contaminated.
Okay. Step number one has to do with
these beautiful wildlife. Wildlife, they
trounce around our fields and near our
fields. They might fly overhead and
leave things if you know what I mean.
Yes. Darn birds, rabbits.
The next
thing is the water sources. And so,
water can get easily contaminated. The
sprinkler systems can get contaminated.
And this we believe is the source uh for
the recent uh ecoli uh outbreak uh in
Yuma, Arizona. Contaminated canal water.
Right. So both the both the tubes but
also where they get the water from.
Water from Exactly. And then know the
people making the the harvest.
Certainly. We have our workers that have
gloves and boots, their their tools.
They're handling the food uh each and
every time. Exactly. Next we have the
factories. Now imagine food coming from
all around the country coming into one
location and you have just one potential
uh source of contamination. It could
crosscontaminate the entirety of the of
the food system. And then and then
lastly it's that last part of the farm
to table last mile. Yeah. The last mile
which is your grocery store all the way
to your home can all be sources of
contamination. James, thank you very
much. Very very helpful. Thank you so
much.
So this alarms me so much because
there's a lot of fear amongst computer
among consumers like you when it comes
to eating leafy greens and you know
they're so essential to healthy eating
that I don't want to take them away from
you. So for the first time a lettuce
industry insider is appearing here for
you. Please welcome Scott Kosfall who's
the CEO of California Leafy Greens
Marketing Agreement. That's the group
that creates the regulations that keep
salad safe for us folks who are the
salad lovers like me. Appreciate what
you do. So you say it comes down to a
culture of food safety and how we
actually grow our lettuce and produce
the product. Explain what does that
mean? Well, to me, Dr. Oz, a culture of
food safety exists when everybody in an
organization from the management to the
farm worker to the supervisors, they all
recognize that protecting public health
is their number one priority. And I'll
give you one example. The industry used
to be based on speed. What's really
changed in the last decade or so is that
if a worker spots an issue or a
potential issue, even if it slows down
production, even if it means uh say a a
a machine needs to be cleaned and and
sanitized, they're commended for that.
And to me, that's what a culture of food
safety on the farm is all about. So,
break it down for us. You brought us
some exclusive views of what it actually
looks like. There's a harvest training
video, and it's what you're trying to
use to change the culture. So, what are
the safety measures actually taken? And
we're going to start off with water
since it's the probable culprit in the
most late in the latest outbreak, right?
There's uh a lot of focus on water in
the from the recent outbreak. So, we've
always required all of our members to
test their water. They test it every
month, but we've just recently added
some changes to our standards uh for
situations like what we just went
through. uh and we're going to see more
water treatment for instance so that
farmers can be even more sure that
they're they're using water that's safe
and and uh adequate for its and what
about animal contamination? Animal
contamination is a real issue. We grow
products outdoors. Uh there are a lot of
environmental concerns um from rodents
to birds to you name it. Um and so
farmers will uh every day they do an
inspection and if they see any signs of
animal encroachment they'll they'll mark
that part of the field off occasionally,
not often. They may walk away from an
entire field, but they will not harvest
anything that's uh that's been deemed.
And what about us? Human contamination.
Well, we grow or we harvest most leafy
greens by hand still. So, workers are
very important to that process. So, we
have a host of uh requirements for
workers. Handwashing is really
important. Uh we've created a a
handwashing app that growers can use to
train their workers. Um everything is
being done to make sure that the product
is as safe as it could be. Scott, thank
you for trusting the process, for taking
an insidider look. Thank you. into our
living rooms. I think it'll help address
some of the fears consumers have. Now,
when we, you know, I've said this many
times, we believe that when it comes to
what you eat, you have the right to
complete transparency. So, today we're
actually holding a salad summit. For the
first time ever, one of the biggest
brands, Dole, is actually here answering
your questions directly. Stay with us.
[Music]
He would say, "Shut up or I'll kill
you." All new Oz. True Crime Tuesday is
back. How new DNA science helped crack
the case of the Golden State Killer.
This guy is the devil on Earth. That's
coming up
[Music]
tomorrow. A lot of you are worried about
recent lettuce recalls, but fear and
food should never go together. So today
we're hosting a firstofits-kind salad
summit. We want to create a safe space
for you to interact directly with the
people who know your produce best. So we
have invited three representatives from
the salad industry to answer questions
from our audience
members. First I want to welcome to our
salad selling panel Natalie Dansson. She
is the vice president food safety and
quality at one of the biggest lettuce
brands Dole. John Boltz is also joining
us, the first vice president for Arizona
Farm Bureau and he's also a grower,
knows firsthand what it takes. And Tommy
Advidor, food safety consultant who
knows about food germs at restaurants,
grocery stores, and especially in your
home. So Natalie, there are a lot of
misconceptions, a lot of fear around
food born illnesses. Why was it so
important for Dole to be here today?
Well, I think as consumers when you hear
about food safety rec food food safety
issues or recalls or things like that in
the news, it's easy to forget we have a
really safe food supply in this country.
And for Dole, we're committed to
transparency. We're committed to being
an innovator and a leader in the
industry. And we really wanted the
opportunity to come and talk to
everybody about the standards that we
have and the practices in the US that
are really designed to protect the
consumers. We invest millions of dollars
every year like many companies do in
research, in innovation, in um expertise
just to make sure we're producing safer
products. Give me an example of what you
do with Dole to make the food supply
safer to make salad easier for people to
trust. Yeah. Well, we have robust
controls all the way through the
continuum. It starts in the field. So,
we have practices that our growers
adhere to in the field during harvest,
during transportation, cooling, all the
way through our processing facilities.
Everything is intentionally designed
with those controls to ensure that the
product is kept safe. And John, if I can
turn to you, you're a grower. Yes. You
speak for growers. We just saw a video
about food safety tactics, things that I
could imagine some workers using, some
not. How do you make sure that
everyone's trying to follow the rules
even though they might seem not
applicable to them? Well, Dr. Oz, the
the best thing that we can do is rely on
the best science. So, as a grower, I go
to preeminent minds in that field of
science like those at the University of
Arizona that are leaders in the world in
food safety and pathogens and keeping
them out of our food. And we work handin
glove with them and we develop uh
training for our employees and we work
through the whole process and uh it's
really it's really important. It's
something that we're passionate about as
a grower and uh we just love providing
safe food for people. That's what we do.
You're okay with some questions now from
the audience? Absolutely. All right. So
Nicole, you're gonna go first, right?
And I understand you have a question for
Natalie and John. I haven't eaten
lettuce since the outbreak. Is lettuce
safe to eat again? Absolutely. Um, you
know, we are consumers, too, and we eat
the product and we serve it to our
families and the health and nutrition
benefits of eating fresh fruits and
vegetables far far outweigh any
perceived concerns that there are
associated with these products. I
absolutely agree. eating leafy greens is
is absolutely safe. And uh I just wanted
to say, you know, the lettuce that I
grow in my fields that is shipped all
over the United States and Canada, it's
on your plates at restaurants, you take
it home to your family, Dr. Oz, that's
the same lettuce that I harvest in my
fields and take home to my family. Go
next. Jasmine. Hi. Is eating bagged
lettuce less safe than eating regular
heads of lettuce? No. All lettuce comes
from the same place. It's all grown the
same way. It's all harvested the same
way. It's really a matter of convenience
for customers. Can you address something
that I read about sometimes, which is
that when when it's pre-bagged for you
or washed, someone has to touch it. So,
how do you know it's not getting
contaminated then? Actually, human hands
don't actually touch the product, we
take a lot of care during the wash
process and during handling to ensure
that there is no going to be any
contamination. We can save some time. My
good. I've been shying away from it.
Joan, you've got a question. Hi. What
can we do when we take lettuce home to
make sure that we clean it properly?
So research shows that if you do have
ecoli on the lettuce, the bacteria
itself actually goes into the crevices
within the lettuce. So you can't wash it
off. Um, but there are things that you
can do um to keep lettuce safe. You
actually can wash it in a colander. The
colander actually prevents it from
touching the bottom of the sink where
you might have some dirt from whatever
you've been washing before. After that,
you're going to move it to a cutting
board. Now, it's not just the cutting
board. You want to make sure the surface
is clean, your hands are clean, right?
you just touched your cell phone, went
to the restroom, wash it, the knife is
clean, and then after you chop it for
your salad, and let's say you're eating
it later, you need to chill it in the
refrigerator and then serve it.
So, finally, I'm going to give it an
idea on this, and I think everyone
should be listening carefully, too. 90%
of us, 90% of all the people who hear my
voice don't eat enough fruits and
vegetables, right? So, you can't be
afraid of salad because it just takes us
down the wrong path. In fact, I think
not eating lettuce can be a bigger
health problem than the occasional
outbreak. Although I don't want to have
a problem with either. So when you see a
scary headline, why not breed of lettuce
and switch to another kind for a few
weeks. That's what it takes to clean it
out of the system. When we do that, at
least we'll keep eating our greens,
making sure our families are healthy and
give the industry a chance to catch up
to whatever problem afflicted that that
breed of lettuce. I want to applaud all
of you for being here. I know it takes a
big uh amount of trust to come on our
set. You came on television, you faced
these questions. Thank you very much. A
healthy dialogue between consumers and
the food industry is the only way to
ensure healthy and safe food. So, we'll
keep doing it for you. We'll be right
back. Are you taking your probiotic all
wrong? We're revealing the biggest
mistakes you may be making and if all
this good stuff that could actually
causing your bloat and brain fog, it's
all coming up. That's next.
Bloat and brain fog, the two things you
dread the most. There's hammering on
you. Now, new headlines raised the
question. Could probiotics actually be
the blame, right? Is this a tough one
for me? Because, well, my favorite
probiotic of all is that it's Greek
yogurt and I have it every day. Now, I
know you take your probiotics a number
of ways throughout your day. Some of you
take pills and or yogurt, kefir,
smoothie, kombucha, right? Is it adding
up to be too much of a good thing?
That's why a new report raising
questions over whether probiotics may be
doing more harm than good caught my
attention. Can you overdose on
probiotics? Take a
look. We are in the midst of a probiotic
craze with consumers everywhere turning
to them to solve their digestion
dilemmas.
When we started this show a decade ago,
one of the most popular probiotic
sources, Greek yogurt, had only 1% of
the market. But now, it has skyrocketed
to 52% of all yogurt sales. And that's a
good thing. But could we be overdoing
it? Recent findings suggest we might be.
The study out of Augusta University in
Georgia found that some adults taking
probiotic supplements and eating
probiotic rich foods were experiencing
negative side effects, feelings of
confusion and difficulty concentrating
and issues with gas and bloating. Some
reported that their episodes of brain
fog were so bad that they had to call
out sick from work. Today, we're busting
open the lid and revealing what this
news means for you.
So, I've assembled a probiotic power
team to help us break this down. Max
Luger wrote the book on the brain gut
connection. He's here in our gut lab
with women who suffer from bloat and
brain fog. They've agreed to stop their
probiotic intake for a week as a social
experiment. In just a few minutes, Max
will reveal if it made a difference. And
Dr. Raj is here to help us take a deep
dive into this new study. She's a gut
health expert and author of What the
Yuck? Nice picture, by the way. So, you
looked at the study. Is this hype or do
we need to be worried about this stuff?
Well, this is a very remarkable study
because we've been talking about
probiotics for years now and how great
they are, but this raises the question,
can you get too much of a good thing?
So, this study looked at 30 people who
had brain fog and then eight people who
did not. They all had abdominal pain,
bloating, distension, gas, and they
actually told them to stop taking
probiotics and see what happens. Many of
them actually felt better. So the
question is were the probiotics causing
the problem? However, I have to say I
have some issues with this study. It was
a very small sample size. There were a
lot of other factors involved. Many of
these people actually took antibiotics
as well. So that what actually made them
feel better. We're not sure, but it
certainly raises a lot of questions and
patients are going to definitely start
asking me about it also. So I got
curious about this because I wanted to
understand what the thought process was.
Let me explain it all to you. So we set
up some surveillance cameras inside the
gut. Right. inside the gut to show you
what's supposed to happen when you take
a probiotic. Now, normally you take the
probiotic up in your mouth, right? It
comes down through the swallowing tube,
the esophagus, into the stomach, right?
And it's supposed to pass right through
your small intestine and set up shop in
your colon, right? Where they work
really hard, right, to digest your food.
Now, according to researchers, in some
people, those bacteria don't make it to
your colon. Instead, they get stuck way
up high in the small intestine, right?
And they camp out there, right? But they
still want to eat what we're eating,
which is a problem because they're doing
way ahead of when they're supposed to.
And they eat more than they could ever
get to in your colon, which leads them
to create basically a waste environment
that ferments and builds up with gas and
a substance called o dlactic acid and
that's putting a target for bloat on
your belly. Right. That's the theory. So
Dr. Raj, what happens when there's a
buildup of gas and dlactic acid in your
small intestine? We'll pretend this is a
small intestine. Exactly. So imagine
this is your small intestine. Your small
intestine is not used to having a lot of
gas in it. It feels very uncomfortable.
That bacteria is being fermented. It's
actually going to produce gas. You feel
like you can't button those pants. That
awful feeling like you're absolutely
going to pop. Some people hate that
sound.
Uh but yeah, I mean it can be very
uncomfortable. So here's the big
question, right? Do probiotics seem to
actually cause bloat in brain frog? If
they do, why does it happen in
everybody? Why do some people take
probiotics to get better from bloat and
brain fog and others get worse with it?
Well, we are all different. Our bodies
are all different, including our guts.
Not everyone reacts the same to a
certain probiotic. If you're not feeling
great on this one, let's take a break
and try a different one. Dr. Rush, thank
you very much. Okay, now we understand
how probiotics can cause some bloat in
folks, but what about the brain and gut
connection? So, let's talk to Max about
this. Some of you studied quite a bit.
You asked viewers suffering from bloat
but also this this brain gut connection
to go on a probiotic elimination diet
it would be hard I think for a lot of us
to do that right but you wanted to see
if their symptoms would be reversed
right were you happy with it yeah I mean
I think that the results that you're
going to find are very interesting to
say the least but you know Dr. Oz,
what's so fascinating is that the gut
influences the brain in such a an
interesting number of ways. In fact, the
gut is often referred to as the second
brain. Let's see what actually happens
in practice. So, we got each member of
our social experiment standing behind
their traditional source of probiotics.
Thank you all for being here. Thank you.
So, I guess we'll start with you. I
really impressed. I even saw across the
studio how much of variety you have. I
love you have sauerkraut in there, not
just Greek yogurt. You got a lot of
sources. That's good. Was it What was
hard to give up? Was it more difficult
than you thought? Yeah, it was actually
difficult to give it up, but it actually
helped me though because I actually was
less bloated and I had less foggess. And
Ariana, you also have a couple different
sources. How was it for you? I was
actually the opposite of her. Like I
missed this. This was like the hardest
thing I've had to do because like I got
all the symptoms back. So like that's
not a good thing. So I got a little
surprise for everybody. I actually took
the probiotic elimination challenge
myself. I was curious cuz I ate lots of
probiotics and it's u it's not that easy
for a Turkish kid to give up Greek
yogurt. Take a
[Music]
look. I'm going to miss you, my
friend. So, it's the afternoon. Usually
I have lots of energy, but I can really
tell the difference. I didn't have
yogurt this morning. It's like all the
little embers in my body have gone out.
[Music]
It's worth it.
I failed. It was a massive fail.
Actually, Dr. Raj, you say maybe it's a
good thing that I failed that I kept
eating my probiotics. I do. And I don't
want people out there to run to their
fridges and throw out their Greek
yogurt. That's not what we're saying
here. Actually, if you were feeling well
on your probiotic regimen, then we say
if it ain't broke, don't fix it. You
keep doing what you were doing. And most
people out there will benefit from
probiotics. Yeah, everybody. Everyone
out there, most of you are probably like
me. We can still eat our Greek yogurt
and all the other probiotics we're
talking about. God bless you. Max, for
the f folks out there, and I don't think
there many, but there probably some who
should think about elimination. How do
you identify them? As a first line of
defense, I would say removing the
probiotics is worth a shot. You know, if
your probiotics are not working for you,
then try eliminating them from your
diet. It's a very simple elimination
style approach. One week. One week. Try
it for a week. Try it for a week. And if
your symptoms don't clear up and
resolve, go see your doctor. All right.
When we come back, are you taking
probiotics all wrong? There's a whole
different issue. Are you taking them
with the wrong stuff? And what's the
right amount for you? We'll tell you
after the break.
An all new Alzheimer's alert. The latest
Alzheimer's breakthroughs that you've
been seeing in the headlines. Could your
body type determine your risk? It's
going to surprise you which one. All new
Oz. That's coming up on
[Music]
[Applause]
Wednesday. We're back asking, are you
taking probiotics all wrong? My experts
Dr. Raj and Max Lug are here with
probiotic mistakes you could be making.
These are going to surprise you. The
first probiotic mistake you may be
making is you're getting your probiotics
from only one source. Why is that a
problem, Max? Well, Dr. Oz, you see,
your gut, like any healthy society,
benefits from a broad range of voices.
Diversity is key, right? So, the same
thing goes for probiotic bacteria. If
you're getting your probiotic bacteria
from only one source, that's not going
to lead to the best scenario in the gut.
You want to make sure that you're
getting your probiotics from a broad
array of sources. So, here we have
kombucha, we have Greek yogurt, we have
a probiotic containing supplement. All
right. Next probiotic mistake that many
of you guys are making is you're not
pairing your prebiotics and your
probiotics. So, probiotics, you know
what those are, right? Those little
bacteria that are in your gut.
Prebiotics, what are they and why they
so critical, right? So, prebiotic is
anything that promotes the growth of
probiotics. So, of course, why wouldn't
you want to enhance those probiotics
that you're already taking by pairing it
with a prebiotic? It's a power duo. You
can get prebiotics from anything that
really contains fiber. Blueberries,
which I know you love, bananas, and
really, you want to get those both into
your diet every day. Pro and pre. Max
calls these brainberries. Am I right?
You know, you know I love my
blueberries. He does. Here, have another
one. It's a present from the show. Next
probiotic mistake that a lot of you guys
are making is you're taking your
probiotic with heartburn medicine. Let
me take a step here. Heartburn medicine.
I get why so many folks take it, but it
does cause a lot of interactions and
it's particularly a problem with pre
with probiotics, right? So, there is a
concern that if you're reducing the
acid, which is what these medicines do,
you're going to have an overgrowth of
bacteria in your small intestine. Now,
does that mean when you take a
probiotic, you're even adding to that
problem? Maybe for some people, I would
say if you're already taking your
antacids and your probiotics and you
feel fine, keep doing what you're doing.
All right. And the final one's going to
really surprise you. There's a big
mistake that a lot of us are making
because done right, it's not a mistake.
Done wrong, it's a big problem is you're
taking your probiotic with hot coffee or
tea. Now, Max, hot coffee and tea
generally, I thought were good for the
gut. Yeah. So, absolutely independently,
coffee and tea are very good for the
gut. Most people are conf are uh
surprised to hear that coffee is
actually beneficial, but um I've looked
into the research, you know, and I'm a
I'm definitely a fan of coffee. The
issue is that these scalding beverages
can the same way they can burn our skin
can also burn these delicate probiotic
bacteria that we want. So my
recommendation is to separate your
consumption of hot beverages and and
when you take your probiotics by a half
an hour. I'll toast to that. Hey Raj,
this is to you. Thank you so much.
Wonderful folks to have on the show. Max
and Dr. Raj. We'll be right back.
Is there hidden dairy in your nutmilk?
We did the testing. Find out what our
investigation uncovered next.
[Music]
An urgent recall is sounding the alarm
for nut milk lovers nationwide. The
number one selling brand of almond milk
reported traces of cow's milk in their
product and pulled them from the
shelves. What does this mean for you?
Today we investigate. Is there hidden
dairy in your almond milk? Joining me is
investigative reporter Marsh Gavakampo
who looked into this and g give us the
headlines if you don't mind. What was
the big manufacturer of almond milk who
decided to voluntarily withdraw their
product? Yeah, the company is Blue
Diamond and it's their vanilla almond
breeze. Now, Blue Diamond is the top
seller of almond milk in the country.
It's the most popular by far. They
issued this recall because of the
possible presence of dairy in the almond
milk. Now, that may sound like a small
thing, but if you have a dairy allergy,
it can be very dangerous. In fact, the
company itself said that this possible
contamination had the risk of serious or
lifethreatening allergic reactions for
people who have dairy allergies. And let
me speak to this Blue Diamond did they
did the right thing, right? They
rectified the situation as soon as they
found out about it. And I want to
commend you all for doing that. But I
want to get back to this almond milk.
Companies do the right thing. So how
much was contaminated? Do we have any
idea of what kind of risks it could it
could offer? Yeah, it was a very wide
reach. There were
145,000 more than 145,000 cartons
recalled. These were half gallon
cartons. And you can see it was shipped
to 28 states. That's more than half the
country. So, it's a very wide reach. So,
let's look into what the real issues
were because I want to look at who buys
almond milk and which of these issues
are affecting our viewers. So, we asked
our viewers why they like almond milk.
This is from our folks just like you,
right? Here are the responses. I prefer
the taste. I'm on a paleo diet. It's
lower in calories, dairy sensitive, and
allergic, right? It's these two groups
at the bottom that are most concerning
to me. That's what gets me nervous
because these issues can be
life-threatening. They'll make you sick,
especially if you've got dairy
allergies. Take it just a tiny little
bit as you were mentioning, Mara, can be
a main problem. And some folks really
rely on this nut milk. So, trust is an
important issue. Did anyone get sick
from half the country basically being
exposed to this this almond milk
contamination? Yeah, the company said
they received reports of one person
getting sick and luckily it was not very
serious. That person did not require
medical attention or hospitalization,
but again, as you noted, th those dairy
allergies can be very serious. So, let
me ask a question. I'm sure everyone's
thinking, how does it happen? I mean,
you don't you don't milk an almond tree,
right? So, how did how did the almond
milk get mixed with the dairy milk? How
did this happen? You know, we don't
exactly know for sure. Here's what we do
know. Hood is Blue Diamond's parent
company. They're a major dairy producer
and it's been reported that they were
manufacturing dairy, cow's milk and the
almond milk at the same facility. The
only thing the company will tell us is
that it was caused by human error.
That's what we know. We don't have the
specific details of what that human
error was. Well, you we've all seen
labels on food products where
crosscontamination could be a risk,
especially if there's an allergy that
could cause a big problem. You've all
seen this, right? say it'll say may
contain traces of milk or this is pretty
common made in a facility that also
processes tree nuts. Now, did Blue
Diamond have a little warning label like
this at potential contamination? We went
out and we checked the Blue Diamond
almond milk did not contain a warning
label warning of potential traces of
milk. And on the flip side, Hood's milk
that is possibly manufactured at the
same facility as the almond milk didn't
contain a warning label about the
possible presence of tree nuts. So if if
dairy and nuts are being first of all
they're pretty common period right
they're produced in a lot of places and
they can cause bad allergies that folks
might need to know about. So is there a
warning required by facilities by the US
government or anybody else? You know we
reached out to the FDA and we spoke to
them about this exact issue. Here's what
they told us. They recommend that
companies include these allergen labels
when products like this are being
manufactured in the same facility, but
it's not a requirement. What they did
tell us though is that it's the
company's responsibility to make sure
there's no crosscontamination. So we
reached out to Blue Diamond for a
statement and they referred us to their
press release which we're going to post
on dr.com so you can find out much more
about the recall. The next thing I
wanted to do was figure out is there
hidden dairy in other nutils or is this
just an isolated incident? So Mara and
the medical unit got together right we
collected samples from the top five
leading brands of almond milk. There
they are right pretty fairly got them
all and we sent them off to an
independent lab where they were tested
for any traces of hidden dairy. We just
wanted to understand whether this is a
possibility that could be affecting more
of you. So Mara, ready for the results?
Yeah, absolutely. Take it away. All
right. So of the five brands that we
tested, we found the presence of dairy
in none of them. In none. None. That's
good. So right now people can breathe
easy. That's fantastic. Yeah, it's very
good news because this concerned a lot
of people who are trying to avoid dairy.
I'm happy. It's very reassuring. And I
want to point out that Blue Diamond was
actually in this as well. So they seem
to have fixed their issue. Kudos to
everybody all going around. Up next, why
the FDA is going to war with non-dairy
milks. It's a heated debate you won't
want to miss. But first, if you want the
safest and healthiest all milk, the best
thing you do is make it yourself. We
have a video showing you how. And it's
easier than you
[Music]
think.
Here's your daily share.
[Music]
You got milk? Well, if you're an almond
milk lover like that little girl we just
saw, the answer isn't so simple anymore.
The FDA has soured their stance at how
non-dairy milk should be labeled, and
it's being called an allout war. The
dairy industry is pushing to remove the
word milk from popular non-dairy
alternatives like almond, soy, and
coconut, claiming they're not really
actually milk, but nut milk makers say
consumers are going to be confused. So,
how much does one word really matter?
I've got two containers here. All right.
One is almond milk, the other one is
almond beverage, right? So, quick quiz,
audience member, I want someone to be
honest here. Are you an honest person? I
I think so. You look honest. All right.
What What do you think about these?
Would this be at all confusing for you?
A little bit. Because when I see
beverage, I think of sugar or maybe
processed versus milk. I mean, I know
it's non-dairy, but it's more familiar,
I guess. Is that your mom? That is my
mom. Let's see what a word of wisdom.
What do you think? I like almond milk,
and the wording wouldn't make any
difference for me. So, if I just showed
you almond beverage, you'd be okay with
it? Yeah. Wouldn't confuse at all? Nope.
All right. So, it's a mix. We'll see.
How many of you might think almond
beverage isn't the same as almond milk?
Yeah, I mean it's most of the audience.
Okay, here. It's no gift for you guys.
Enjoy it. All right, so to be clear,
these are the exact same products. The
only thing has changed is that almond
milk has been rebranded almond beverage.
But I wanted to hear both sides on this
debate. So we set it up with Dr. Joel
Khan, author of the plant-based
solution, who's here to argue that nut
milks should just be labeled milk. And
then we've got nutritionist and New York
Times bestselling author of the 10day
belly slim down Kellyanne Patricia who
says they should not. Right. Dairy milk
is the only true milk. So Dr. Khan, you
get to go first. Don't you don't take it
easy on her. She'll come after you. You
got 45 seconds to defend your beliefs.
Convince us that milk from a not should
be labeled as milk and not something
different. Got it. Thank you. Thank you,
Dr. Oz. Simply put, it is just silly to
think that milk has to be a cow
secretion. I call it utter nonsense. And
actually, when the FDA director a few
weeks ago pointed out that almonds don't
lactate, he was really buckling under
pressure of a shrinking dairy industry
that's still 20 times larger than the
plant-based industry. They're crying
over spilled milk overall. But this does
actually make a difference because
there's health consequences. The number
one food allergy in infants and children
is dairy. 90% of people in some
populations can't digest milk sugar and
feel bad. And finally, in my field,
people are flying away from milk because
they're trying to reduce the risk of
heart disease. It is a very broad term,
the word milk. We don't need new terms
to confuse the public. The bottom line,
call it milk, whether from plant or
animal, and just let the food industry
have a cow over it. All right, that was
pretty good. That's 45 and a half
seconds. Thank you, Dr. Kelly. Makes
some good points. Kelly, I'm going turn
it to you. 45 seconds. defend your
argument that there's a difference.
Yeah. So, Dr. Khan, you made some good
points, but you seem to be having a cow
over this. So, let's help straighten
this out. Boom. Here's the problem. The
problem is that a lot of these
companies, these companies that are
producing these alternative milks,
they're placing them on the shelves next
to regular milk. Can you see how this
can be confusing to the public? Because
here's why. The nutrient density of the
two products are drastically different.
They shouldn't be compared at all. So
really, it's telling the consumer
something that's not true. And if you
really dig in deep, say if you look at
almond milk, it's only 2% almond and the
rest actually is all water. So what
you're actually getting is almond water.
So can you understand how this is really
disheartening to all those hardworking
dairy farmers out there? Not good. I
mean, it's not the same product. That's
all. It's like calling a potato chip a
pork chop. All right, Dr. Con, she threw
one last little jab at you. So, you get
to defend yourself. Make it short.
Wounded and bleeding. But I'd say again,
there's many health benefits of
plant-based milks. And what the consumer
doesn't need is new terms they don't
get, like nut juice. Call it milk. Plant
or animal. One term for all. All right,
audience. Let me just pull you guys real
quickly. Who out there thinks they ought
to both be called milk? Put your hands
up. And And who thinks they should all
be different? Beverage for nuts and milk
should be called from dairy cows milk.
So, it's like the US population is split
5052. I didn't say anything else either.
No, it's okay. I I like it. It's a
debate. It's how it's going to be
settled. You You guys make some noise
out there. We want to hear from you. So,
you can vote at dr.com. Should almond
milk be considered milk? Here are the
results so far. 71% yes. 29% say no. Oh
my goodness. All right, you guys vote.
We'll be right back.
He would say, "Shut up or I'll kill
you." All new Oz. True Crime Tuesday is
back. How new DNA science helped crack
the case of the Golden State Killer.
This guy is the devil on Earth. That's
coming up tomorrow.
Dr. Oz, I know you're trying to catch up
with me. Okay, so you hit the 10 mark. I
think that's pretty good. 10 mark. Um,
we did that around 1996. So, you got a
ways to go, but you're really, really
going strong. I'm proud of the work that
you do, not just on the show, but your
dedication to making a sense of wellness
and well-being for everybody in the
country and throughout the world. Uh,
I'm proud of you, the courage it takes
to get up every day and to say what you
say and do what you do. All I got to say
is keep doing it cuz you got 15 more
years to catch up.
Oh my goodness. You know, I I wasn't
allowed I wasn't allowed to see any of
these videos, so they know I get
emotional, but I want to thank Oprah.
Your mentorship means the world to me.
I'm very grateful for this platform to
inspire people all over the world, to
take folks on a on a health journey they
wouldn't have been able to go on and
take their health into their own hands.
It wouldn't happen without you. So,
bless you. Over the past 10 years, I've
seen all of your healths transform
before my eyes. You've seen it
yourselves. And I'm going to keep moving
forward. I want you to keep coming with
me because together we're going to make
the next 10 years ahead of us the
happiest and healthiest of our lives.
Does that sound good? I know we can do
it. We're just getting started. So, I
asked some celebrity friends of the show
to share with us what they want their
next 10 to be like. Take a
look. In the next 10
years, I hope I'll still be doing what I
love, directing, writing, and recording.
I feel very fortunate to have music as a
creative way to express my feelings. I
see myself in the next 10 years super
happy, super healthy, and changing the
world. Maybe saving a puppy or uh you
know, stopping human trafficking, but no
matter what, inspiring the world and
giving back to the world all the great
things it gave to me. Seriously, 10
years that would make me
96 just to be here. I just hope to be
here to do everything that makes me
happy. I'm going to look very carefully
in the mirror and see what aging has
done to me. And I'm going to do
everything in my effort, massage and
exercise and good food and non-smoking
and non-drinking. I'm going to try and
make myself look as good as possible.
Really doing things that impact the
world. You know, I don't want to just,
you know, be in front of the camera and
be behind the camera for self- serving
purposes. I really want to do things
that impact society. Dr. Oz, I just want
to say that for the next 10 years, I
hope I continue to age backwards like
you
[Music]
are. I love what they're saying and I
love that all of you are sharing your
next 10 goals with me on social media
using the hashtag my next10. I've seen
some of you pledge all kinds of things
from adding an evening walk to your
routine to making plans to see that
friend you follow on Facebook but you
lost touch with in real life. And a lot
of you plan on crossing that dream trip
off your bucket list to the next 10.
I'll be following all your posts with my
next 10 hashtag and responding myself
with some little notes of encouragement.
I'll send messages to you as well. But
when it comes to goals, there's nothing
like a little motivation, is there?
Something to sort of nudge you
along. So, how about this? All year
long, we will be surprising a few
creative and lucky viewers with the best
posts and best ideas. And we're giving
you all some gifts and some surprises,
including trips to Iceland. That's
right. I took my son there. One of the
best trips of my life. And you get to do
it now. Our friends at Wow Airlines, the
lowfare airlines that everyone is
talking about, are going to send 15 of
you and a guest, that's 30 people total
on that dream vacation you've been
putting off. Wow. Airlines will fly you
out to relax in those healthy hot
springs that you're always seeing on
Pinterest to get some of that thermal
healing. It's worth it. And I always I
want you guys to get more sleep. Keep
saying that. So Rison Hotels will
provide you with three nights hotel
accommodations in Iceland at their Rison
Blue 1919 hotel in Rekavic, located in
the heart of that beautiful city next to
the North Atlantic and accessible to
both city and countryside attractions.
Now everybody remember it's just the
beginning. We're going to keep doing
this because together change is
happening and our journey it really is
just beginning.
[Music]