[Music]
Microwave breakfasts, omelette cups,
burritos, and egg muffins. Fast, easy.
When it comes to frozen food, breakfast
foods are queen. But are they really
good for you? Are they just junk food in
disguise? Plus, fat shamers. I can't
take care of it because it's both so
fake. Caught on tape. She's eating too
much chocolate. Why are you insulting me
about my weight? Coming up next.
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
[Music]
I love you back.
Today, an investigation into a giant
shift happening in your frozen food
aisle. The food industry is offering an
unprecedented number of microwavable
frozen breakfast food options, including
your favorites. Breakfast sandwiches,
delicious looking omelette cups,
burritos, and egg muffins, all hot and
ready in minutes. Many even claim to be
healthier. But are they? Or they just
junk food in disguise? Investigator and
mom of two, Marciao put many of these
options to the test in the best food lab
there is, her own busy kitchen.
Okay, so I'm shopping for breakfast
sandwiches. I can't remember the last
time I bought a breakfast sandwich, so
this should be interesting. Hey,
Quesadilla.
Do you want to try these for breakfast?
Um,
what are they? It's a breakfast sandwich
made on a waffle. It's bacon, egg, and
cheese. I don't really like eggs or
cheese, but I could try it with
something else. Maybe just bacon. So,
this is what I ended up getting. We have
two different English muffins. They are
different. This one is like on a waffle
and this is a breadless egg cup which I
am very excited about.
Marian, was that the best assignment you
have ever been given? You know, any
assignment that involves tasting food.
I'm in. Sign me up for it. And your
daughter's already an investigative
reporter. She's very discerning. Yeah.
You know, breakfast is a really hard
meal for me. I was really happy to get
this assignment because this is tough
for me. I'm a low carb eater, so I'm
always looking for portable low carb
options. And with my kids, I'm looking
for alternatives to the staples that are
high sugar, high carb, like cereal and
pancakes. So, this could change things
in my house. And how big have these
products become now, these microwavable
breakfasts? When it comes to frozen
food, breakfast foods are doing so well.
Really, it's for two reasons. One is
millennials. So, 82% of millennials say
that this is a good option for their
kids. And case in point, I agree with
that completely. The other one is the
keto crowd. Keto is huge right now.
They're looking for low carb options.
Those two things are driving this
industry. Yeah, that they use the the
bun is actually egg and it looks so
delicious. It does look good. All right,
let's start. So, we asked food scientist
Taylor and he's a fanatic, by the way,
about breakfast food. Taylor Wallace
will be here to break down exactly how
microwavable breakfast made. Let's start
with the prime ingredient of all, the
egg. Is there a real egg in these
microwavable breakfasts? Crack the egg
for me. So actually, yes, many of these
products, the main ingredient is a whole
egg. Now, also in these products, you're
going to see some of your other normal
culprits, different food additives. Now,
they might look scary, but they're all
in there for a functional purpose,
right? So, for instance, it looks scary.
Zanthan gum, that's just a dietary fiber
that we add to food. We add it to eggs
because we don't want the egg to crumble
when you bite into it and fall into your
lap. modified cornstarch that just
provides a little bit of texture to the
product. And then you have all these
different flavors. And you might ask,
well, why not just add butter? Because
butter oxidizes and makes the product go
stale. So instead, we add these flavors
that won't oxidize and produce a bad
taste. But you just express the bias. I
love that it's a real egg. I sort of
wish I didn't have to add all these
things in there, but I know you guys
have other technologies. For example,
you have a way of making the the frozen
microwavable breakfast flavorful and
locking in that flavor. And it has to do
with this. And you're a flavor
scientist. So what does this have to do
with flavor? Well, so there's two main
things that you have to worry about in
products like egg sandwiches. One is
water because we know water makes things
go bad. And two is oxygen because oxygen
oxidizes things. So what do we do? We
freeze the water because frozen water
can't do much. And then we add nitrogen
to the bag or to the package. So very
similar to what you see in potato chips.
If you buy a bag of potato chips with
all the air inside, that's nitrogen.
When you open the bag, then the oxygen
comes in, you leave it out for a day and
it goes stale. The same thing happens
with egg sandwiches. All right, so let's
take a look at different types of frozen
breakfastes that we find at the grocery
store. I took that list that you just
got, Mara, that whole that treasure
trove and I split it out and I know that
there's a big keto move. So explain how
people have hacked that system. Yeah. So
just as a reminder, it's very very
highfat, very low carb. So when you take
a look at these traditional breakfast
sandwiches here, these are not going to
be an option for keto followers because
of the bread. But when you look over
here, this is really a game changer if
you're a keto devote. They have made the
bread out of eggs. So this is breadless.
It's essentially I saw that. I wasn't
sure if that was real. It's real. It's
eggs. It is high protein. It is
extremely low carb egg bun. Yeah. So
this is the industry responding to that
demand. They have heard loud and clear
what low carb dieters want. All right,
so seven grams of carbs. How do the rest
of your options? So you can see it's a
big difference. So the English muffin
option, 28 grams of carbs. So I've never
been good at math, but I think that's
four times the amount, right? Better
than you say. Exactly four times. And
here we have the croissant, 27 gram.
Pretty much the same. The biscuit, which
to me looks like the most dectable,
delicious one. I think that's a pretty
good deal. Oh my goodness. I'm working
hard not to This was intriguing to me.
Flatbread's a good idea. Flatbread is a
great idea. You see that it is the
lowest carb of all of them, but still
much higher than the breadless one. And
you tasted these and you had that
discerning daughter of you taste as
well. How did this breadless version do?
It was absolutely delicious. I did not
miss the bread at all. But I did have to
wonder, is that too much protein? Am I
overdoing it? Now I looked into it. I
think the protein's okay. The bigger
concern for me is salt. Okay. Sometimes
in order to make it flavorful because
you freeze things doesn't taste the same
always. They could have more salt than
you want. So just take a look at that.
But I'm overall I was impressed that you
had this many options. But I want to go
talk to our audience member here because
the next microwavable frozen breakfast
investigation had to do with the the
crustless kiches.
There's no carbs in a crustless kiche.
Do I have this right? Yes. Well, I want
to do me compare these two and see if
you taste the difference. Mar, you can
go do it as well. Here's Oh, thank you.
I thought you'd never ask. Exactly. I
feel you ate them all at home before you
got here. Now, I'm going to reveal
something to you in a second, but these
are not quite made the same way. So,
which do you like more, least? This
one's much better. Much better. Mhm. All
right. So, I'm just going to reveal
something to you. One of these is
actually homemade by yours truly, and
the other one was made in the store.
This
was made by us. Nice job, Dr. Oz. Oh,
wow. This is the storebought one. I only
point it out because this didn't take a
ton of time. I think most people prefer
it, but I get why you don't do it,
right? It's a lack of time. Did this
taste good enough that if you didn't
have time to make it on your own, you'd
still be okay with it? Yeah, I'd be okay
with it. All right. So, it works. Yeah,
it's a great option. You pick and choose
what you want. I don't think it's quite
the same as making it yourself, but it's
probably good enough for most of the
especially the busy moms out there. Yes.
How do they compare nutritionally? So,
it's actually there's a lot of good news
here. These have the the store-bought
ones are real egg or egg based, which is
just basically liquid egg. Now, they do
have other things added in because they
do have to live on a shelf. They do have
to be frozen, but for the most part, it
is very close to the real thing. You can
feel good about eating them and giving
them to your kids. off at home, Lisa.
All right, let me one last topic here.
We investigated frozen microwave
breakfast burritos. Taylor has these
guys gotten a lot of criticism over the
years, but they seem to be making a
comeback, right? You know, when I was a
kid, it was like these things are
terrible, right? I mean, they're mushy
and gooey and not great. Food scientists
have this down to an art. And now, just
like over there, they taste fantastic.
And not only that, there's vegetarian
options, there's farm-to-table options.
We've got something for everybody. All
right. So, you still want to watch the
sodium on these, especially if you got
pressure issues. We always say make
bacon a special food. So, you don't want
to have that every day either. Maybe
twice a week kind of thing. When we come
back, we show you a brand new
microwavable breakfast that allows you
to use your own fresh egg. Is it the
best of both worlds? We'll find out when
we come back.
[Music]
[Applause]
If you have ever tried to make an omelet
and this happened, right, you're not
alone. Guess what? Restaurants, the best
ones in the world, use making omelette
as the ultimate test of a chef's true
skill. So, I didn't pass this time, but
I'm I'm getting better. I can cover it
up. I can stitch this back together
again. I've got the technology. Anyway,
today we're investigating a brand new
shortcut. Turning omelettes into a
weekday quickie meal using your own
microwave. These are called omelets in a
cup. Now, food scientist Taylor Walls is
here to help us figure out what's really
in these. There's two main kinds of
almonds in the cup. Break them up for
us. Okay, so your first kind, go ahead
and open the package. And what you'll
see, it's got everything inside, right?
So, you've got your little vegetables
and meat. Uh, and then you have a liquid
egg. So, go on and and check it out. And
a liquid egg is basically the same thing
that you buy in the grocery store in
those milk carton like jugs. It's just
been pasteurized a little bit more than
the whole egg to prevent bacteria from
growing. Pour it in here. Yep. So, pour
it right in. You can pop it in the
microwave and you're ready to go.
Basically, put my fixings in there. I'm
good to go. Absolutely. It's so easy, so
simple. Absolutely. So, how's yours
different? So, the second one, this is
for consumers that prefer their products
a little less processed. So, we charge
them the same price, but don't add the
egg. You have to add your own. You're
kidding me. It's the same price, right?
And it's a instead of the egg, it's you
have to add your own. And it's not a
liquid egg. So if you see, you've got
the cheese, the vegetables, the meat in
there. Same thing as in your other
product. You break the egg. Yep. Oh,
heard to break it on plastic. Oh my
goodness. Here. Break it over here. Then
put it in the pan. There.
All right. That's it. And then you add
the substies in there. Then you add the
stuff. Mix it up. And there you go. I
got to say, I'm impressed. This is
actually so close to what I would
normally want to do. I probably would
think about this. Right. Right. And like
Mara said, they're very close to the
normal food product that you would cook
in your kitchen. Got a little bit of
additives in there to help prevent mold
growth or bacteria growth. Uh but
overall, it's the same thing. Food
scientist is happy. I'm happy. All
right. And the price you mention is the
same. Yeah, the price I mentioned is
about $3 a pack. So great for someone
like a college student or somebody like
you and I that are on the go. Might not
want to feed the whole family with it
because that gets kind of expensive, but
great on the go. I got to say as I look
at these I I wish I didn't have the
preservatives. It's not that complicated
to cut this up. I would think I just put
it in the fridge and add it myself.
Well, remember the number one goal of a
food scientist is to make sure your food
products are safe. So, you have to add
those in there because you want them to
be shelf stable so they don't grow
bacteria on there so you don't get sick.
Fair enough. Those who know what you're
getting. All right. Thanks, Taylor. So,
for those of you who want to make
breakfast in the microwave,
an idea, Mara's got a DIY solution that
has become incredibly popular. It's all
over the web. Yeah, share it with us.
This is a great food prep hack. You can
get a fresh omelette in the morning in
seconds. So, a good idea is to start the
night before, right? You take a mason
jar. You just finished eating dinner.
You're putting away leftovers. Just take
a spoonful of each of these leftovers.
And while I'm doing that, can you please
be my sue chef? Can you crack those eggs
for me? Put them here. Here uh in that
bowl. So, you put your leftovers. You
got some veggies. Maybe you have some
meat from dinner. You put it all here in
this mason jar. And of course, I would
be much neater if I were actually doing
it in my house. And then you take this
and you just stick it in your fridge.
You put this in the fridge. You put it
in there overnight. In the morning, you
wake up. You do what you just did. You
crack a few eggs and you pour them into
the mason jar. That's it. That's it. So,
you're getting an omelette in a cup. You
stir this up. You put it in your
microwave. Put a You put the paper towel
on it. You put the rubber band over the
top. Oh, I like this idea. You put this
in the microwave. And we have a little
switcheroo here. It's actually hot cuz
we did just cook it. Okay. And then you
have Smells good. An omelette in a cup.
You microwave it 45se secondond
intervals. You stir. You put it back in
for 45 seconds until it's done. Put it
down. Let's test this. And then you can
run out the door with this. You can eat
it on your commute and you have an
omelette to go. See this? This I like.
There's no preservatives, no products. I
bet this doesn't cost much either. And
no, I mean it's fresh. It's leftovers in
the end. Easy. It's leftovers. You do
most of the work the night before. It's
delicious. I toast you, Mara. Thank you
very This is how a mom makes breakfast.
Thank you very much. We'll be right
back.
[Music]
Up next, we investigate. Can you get
addicted to microwave meals? What you
need to know about what your favorite
frozen foods can be doing to your brain.
[Music]
I know. Did you start to salivate at
that sound? Right? You start to think
about food and that beep starts with
your microwave. Millions of you rely on
quick microwave meals because it's a
quick lunch or ready in minutes hot
dinner. But can you get addicted to
these fast food frozen foods? How does
your freezer look? Does it look like
this? Someone in our audience is the
owner of this stocked freezer full of
those microwave meals and is being
turned in for their obsession with
microwave meals. Please welcome Angela,
who's turning in her best friend, Su
Ella.
You didn't know this was happening, did
you? No. No. I'm I I think I'm fine. You
think you're fine? What What is the
issue here? She has a problem. She has a
very big problem. And that's a real
photo of her freezer. Yes. And how often
is she eating microwave frozen food? All
the time. Breakfast, lunch, snack. I'm
busy. No, it's not. I really love it.
No. But what do you love about it so
much? Well, it's they have healthy ones.
I eat lean queen scene. I I like um hot
pockets sometimes when I'm really in a
rush. So, you know, it's easy. It's
convenient. What do you think about your
friend's concern over your perceived
addiction towards microwave fast food? I
don't know what her concern is. You
don't know my concern? No. You send me
coupons. You want to You want to buy
things off eBay. It's it's microwavable
food. No, you go to the dollar store.
You go to all of the stores. No, no, no.
It's too much. Too much. Let's just talk
about Come on up here a little bit.
Well, we got a little discussion. I
understand. No, I know. I understand the
allure of frozen meals, but in reality,
there's something that's really
addictive in these foods that makes them
so desirous for us. But they taste good.
So, Mark Shasker, food journalist
extraordinaire and a real expert in the
area. He's made a taste test for us that
you and I are going to be participants
in. You got to tell the truth, though.
All, right, so take us. What are we
going to taste and what what kind of an
organization do you have here? Okay. We
got three lasagnas. The first one is
fresh lasagna. We made this. This is
like what you'd make at home. This is
also lasagna we made, but not fresh. We
froze it and then we reheated it.
That That fresh is good. Keep going. I'm
moving along here. And then we got This
is the microwavable lasagna like you'd
buy at the supermarket. Let's look at
the microwave here. There'll be
something interesting here.
That is good. That is really good. Tell
tell me what you like about it. You
should have this. You like it. Yeah, it
tastes real good. Okay. So, there's
something really interesting. This is
This is actually better than the fresh.
Better than fresh. Something really
interesting happening here. So, this is
another tale of taste bud trickery. This
is where it's it's in the flavor. It's
in how they created this experience of
lasagna in a frozen food where we're
going to find something interesting.
Let's uncover the anatomy of a microwave
meal. How do they actually pull that
off? Cuz I do think like you, it
definitely tastes better than the frozen
stuff that you made yourself, right?
What did they do differently? So the
first issue is preservatives. Mark, what
kind are we talking about? Okay, so
yeah, one thing they do to get that
flavor, they use synthetic flavorings.
We've talked about that before, but
that's how they they jack up that
flavor. We also see a lot of the same
guilty suspects that we see in other
processed foods. There's polyorbate 80.
That's a bulking agent that makes the
sauce taste nice and smooth. There's
something called potassium bromate.
That's a dough additive. It's actually
illegal in some countries. And then we
have sodium nitrate. Now, we've talked
about that. It's illegal in some
countries. It's illegal and it's in it's
in our frozen foods. Oh. Oh. All right.
So, these are theoretical concerns, but
but the next issue is a real concern,
which is sugar. How much sugar?
Actually, why would you even add sugar
to lasagna? There's already pasta in
there. Well, because as we saw, that
flavor takes a beating. So, what's an
easy way to jack that flavor back up?
Just dump in some sugar. And you're
going to be shocked at how much. We
found one frozen entree that had 29 g of
sugar in a serving. Did you hear that?
Okay, it gets worse cuz guess how big
the serving is? This big. It's only
half. Most people think they pull it out
of their microwave and they think I get
to eat the whole thing. Well, then
you're getting 58 g of sugar. That's the
sugar that's in two candy bars. So, who
would ever think I'm nuking my dinner,
there's two candy bars worth of sugar in
there. It's crazy. So, a lot of sugar.
And then there's another hidden source
of carbs, modified starch, which I don't
even know what do you modified starch to
do? Yeah, modified starch. What is it?
Well, it's there to get rid of some of
the problems that you get when you
reheat frozen food. You don't get those
puddles of water so that it holds its
shape. Uh, but it's essentially
carbohydrates that have no flavor. So,
you're getting carbs in your tummy that
you don't taste on the way down. And I
think that's where the worry is. So,
stay with Mark for a second. I'm going
explain to everybody what happens to
your brain while you're having all these
empty carbs that are hidden from you.
So, you got the brain here, you got you
there, right? Take a bite out of one of
these meals, right? And what ends up
happening is you begin to to fall in
love with it, right? Begin to crave it.
Then what happens? Your blood sugar
starts to spike up. When the blood sugar
goes up, dopamine is released from your
brain, which makes you really happy,
smiley, right? We all know that, right?
Like comfort food. But then over time,
your blood sugar falls back down again
and you crave that high you just had. So
your blood low blood sugar levels cause
an increased appetite, right? You eat
more food because the time seems like
it's the right to do. And the next thing
you know, you eat more of those frozen
meals that you've been craving and
feeling okay about doing it. So Mark,
you say in addition to this, which is
sort of a chemical addiction, there's a
psychological addiction these microwave
meals can can cause. Yeah. So we've seen
this interaction before. You got things
like foods with a lot of sugar and
flavoring, makes it compulsive, makes it
really delicious in the moment, hard to
stop eating. So I think there's a lot of
ways these these get us eating too much.
So don't be a killjoy here. If we're
going to eat our microwaves, cuz I think
Suela, who's nervously laughing now, is
probably going to still eat some of the
microwaves that are in her freezer. Give
us some tactics, some hacks. Okay. So,
one thing is to look at the ingredient
list because they're not all the same.
The the ingredients that come at the
beginning of the list, there's more of
them. So, look for the good things. If
it's a broccoli pasta, look for broccoli
at the beginning of the ingredient list.
If it's at the very end, there means
there's not much. And if there's if you
don't see it at all, be worried about
that. So, Sella, I need your verdict
here. Your friend, me, doc professor
Shasker next to us seems to think you're
probably better served to eat your
microwave meals a little differently.
What do you think? I don't think I'll do
it every day now. I think I do it like
maybe maybe twice maybe three times a
week slowly process on my addiction on
it. But um thank you for having an
impact. Nicely done. Thank you for
saying that. We'll be right back. Thank
you.
Shocking updates on the house of
horrors. Why the parents tortured their
own children. Louise Turpin's sister
reveals their intimate prison
conversations. any expression of remorse
and Oz true crime investigation. That's
coming up on Wednesday.
We're back with our investigation in the
public fat shaming. Would you know what
to do if it happened to you? What about
if the if it came from the one person
you trust the most, your own doctor?
According to one study, about half of
women half say they've been shamed by a
physician with weight being one of the
top reasons. Latoya says she was fat
shamed by her doctor who ignored her
pain symptoms. And after feeling ill,
Rebecca says her doctor told her to lose
weight, but turns out her health issues
were not a result of her size. It was
actually cancer. So, Rebecca, let's talk
about your case. It's pretty serious.
So, you go to the doctor, you're not
feeling well. How did the physicians
respond to the observations you were
making about your own body? Yeah. So,
um, a lot of times it was very much a
dismissal. Um, it was kind of a a
dismissal of symptoms, um, over and over
and over again. just a well basically if
you would just lost a little bit of
weight you'd be fine. If you just lost a
bit of weight you could breathe better.
Um we don't really know what's going on
but if you just lost a bit of weight
everything would be okay. So after 3
years three years everybody looking
around you finally got a diagnosis. What
was really happening inside your body?
Uh, I had a tumor um in my left main
stem bronchus in my lung. Um, and it had
kind of killed the bottom half of my
lung and they had to take the whole left
lung out. In part cuz it took three
years, I think, to figure out what was
going on. Yeah.
What What was it like when you finally
realized you actually had a
life-threatening problem that was
causing this and not an issue with your
weight, which you never thought was the
problem to begin with? Um, it was the
first time that like I had finally
gotten a diagnosis and I spent so much
time trying to figure out what was wrong
with me and then somebody finally told
me that something was wrong and it was
just so freeing to realize that there
was something that was actually there
that like no, I'm not just fat.
Something is wrong in this body. So, I
wish you were the only person who felt
the way you have stated you felt because
it turns out that obese patients are 65%
more likely than others to have
significant undiagnosed medical
conditions. We write it off, say it's
something else. And sometimes it is the
weight is that's a problem, but often
times it's not. How you feeling okay
now? Yeah, I've been um cancer free
since 2012. Good for you. Good for you.
Thank you.
Latoya, let's talk about your story. Uh,
also an example of doctors overlooking a
real diagnosis. What happened? Well, in
my case, I've been in pain for the past
two decades. Um, since I started my
menstruation when I was about 10 or 11.
All I can remember is feeling this
crippling paralyzing pain every time my
menes would come about. When I went to
the doctor initially, it was, you know,
well, how about we give you some birth
control? When I started gaining like I'm
going to say I started gaining weight.
Um, particularly after I had my son, it
was automatically shifted to it has to
be your weight. So, your your doctors
actually finally found the real
diagnosis, right? What was going on? My
real diagnosis is that I was diagnosed
with endometriosis.
And that wasn't found until I miscarried
several times. Like over I stopped
counting after four times. Oh, I'm
sorry. And um it's something that so
many people brush off as it's nothing,
you know. It's I I find that's the issue
in a lot of things in reproductive
health. Well, the reason I'm passionate
about this topic of fat shaming is
because it can embarrass people and
people can do bad things to themselves
because they're ashamed by it. But we
also missed the real diagnosis, right?
Which is a much more obvious way that we
hurt people. Now, I should share Latoya
is about to run her 17th marathon in
three weeks.
So, you didn't get held back. Neither of
you did. What is your message to doctors
who are too easily writing off symptoms
to being to their patients being
overweight? Actually, listen to your
patients. Um, be patient with your
patients, you know. Um, essentially
don't just brush it off or just look at
them and then try to give them a
diagnosis. Actually do the work. Look
into it. Do blood tests, which I've had,
which proved that I didn't have some of
these things that they thought that I
had. Actually listen to us. Because when
you don't listen to us, then we have a
distrust. We have a worry and a real
fear that nobody's going to take us
serious. It makes people not want to
actually come to you. We we essentially
go to you to trust you. So, just listen
to us and know that this is not all in
our heads. We know our bodies more than
anybody else. Thank you for sharing your
story with us. We'll be right back.
Up next, fat shaving caught on tape. The
videos you have to see to believe. Find
out what got one woman kicked off a
flight.
That was a small taste of what got that
passenger kicked off a recent flight.
She called her seatmates big pigs, among
other things. Today, we're exposing fat
shaming caught on tape. Strangers
bullying and verbally abusing others
because of their weight.
It's a malicious and disturbing online
trend. Unrestrained and hurtful comments
shared in posts are leaving people
outraged and shocked. Hurt feelings,
some show no mercy. Looking at these
videos, you have to ask yourself, what
drives people to such hatred?
Norma, the woman who recorded that viral
video of her seat made publicly fat
shaming her, joins me now. First off,
thank you for coming to the show. Oh,
thank you for having me, Dr. Oz. Let's
go back to what happened when you first
got to your seat.
Getting comfortable, seated at the
window seat, um realizing that this
woman that was coming into the middle
seat was having a bad day. She wasn't a
happy person. Um, verbally saying
negative things and making it a little
uncomfortable. And how did it make you
feel when you appreciated what she was
really getting at? Uncomfortable.
Um, angry,
angrier,
and matter. Um,
that's why I started doing the outbur
the, you know, with her outburst, I
decided to go ahead and do the video and
she kept going even with your recording.
Yes. And she knew I was recording. So,
what prompted you to want to post it?
Because it does put you at risk, too.
You're so, you know, said the whole
thing is so embarrassing, of course, for
her because she's doing all this stuff.
I guess because as a nurse and I have a
platform, um, that I thought that
bullying and body shaming is
unacceptable behavior for children and
even more so for adults. Um, so I felt
the need to actually show this happening
to me. Good for you. Yeah. A lot of
people would have just pretended it
never happened and then it gets
tolerated. You travel a lot. Have you
ever been publicly
an attempt made to publicly shame you
like this? 15 years on the road and this
was truly a first. I'm on the road
almost every week and this was a first.
Yeah. And you probably at the you must
have at some point been disbelieving
this was even happening. I did. There
was a delay, but when somebody attacks
you and you're in the public, you can
get up and walk away. You're in a plane.
There's no place to walk to your
confined space. In fact, maybe it's been
that's the reason, but the airline
ultimately kicked her off. What was the
reason they gave for doing that? Well,
they saying that they had uh there were
so many people that were complaining
beside myself. Um, when I got off the
plane, there were people behind me when
we got off the plane in Newark that told
me that her behavior after I stopped
videotaping was she was still ranting
back there. So, the airline had to take
her off the plane for the safety of all
of the passengers. So, we reached out to
the airline. It was United Airlines. And
here's what they had to say about the
incident. United flight attendants care
about the safety and well-being of all
of our customers, which is why they
acted quickly to find a different seat
for the disruptive customer. When it
became clear that this passenger's
behavior was likely to be problematic on
this flight, she was provided
alternative travel arrangements first
thing the next morning. So, she spent
the night wherever you were coming from.
Looking back on that tape, why do you
think that woman was so angry? And I
don't think I'll ever know why she
behaved that way and why she thought
that was acceptable behavior.
Well, your brave desire to share that
experience resulted in a video that
attracted 600,000 views within a few
weeks. If you could talk to that woman,
and there's a pretty good chance she
might be watching this broadcast, what
would you tell her?
Um,
she needs to be healed. She needs to
look inside and determine why she
behaved that way.
um what is hurting inside herself that
makes her think it's okay to hurt other
people. Hurt people hurt people. Yes.
Hurt people hurt people. Hurt people.
And she needs to understand why she did
what she did. I am on the path of
forgiving her because as a woman of God
that is my job to forgive and move
forward.
This is a teachable moment which is why
I agreed to come on because this is a
teachable moment. Um, I would like to
take a quick moment just to apologize to
the United flight attendants. Um, cuz
they did an amazing job, but for my
language that I used in the video to
tell them I'm sorry for using that
language toward at them when I was
referring to the other woman. I don't
think you have to apologize for that.
God bless you. Yeah. Coming up, where's
the line between fat shaming and
concern? What should you do if you feel
like your doctor is fat shaming you?
Stick around.
Shocking updates on the House of
Horrors. Why the parents tortured their
own children. Louise Turpin's sister
reveals their intimate prison
conversations. Any expression of remorse
and Oz true crime investigation. That's
coming up on Wednesday.
Unfortunately, I was fat shamed a few
years ago. I went to the doctor um after
a car accident and he was supposed to do
some work on my back. Um, and while I
was there, he told me that I, at the
time, I was 100 pound, almost 100 pounds
heavier than I am now. Um, and he told
me I should just go ahead and have
beriatric surgery done. Um, because I
was never going to be able to lose the
weight naturally and I was just going to
be back in a few years asking for his
help. I was gaining weight like crazy
and I would go to my doctors for help
and all they ever said was to work out
harder, eat better. They said that I had
fat jeans. They said I would always have
a weight problem. They disregarded all
of my other symptoms and said I was
crazy. And this went on for about 8
years. And I finally did my own research
and discovered I had a brain tumor and
that was causing all my weight gain. And
a year ago, I had brain surgery. I had
the tumor removed. Since then, I've lost
40 lbs.
[Applause]
We're back with our investigation into
fat shaming. Could you be fat shamed by
your own doctor? Where's the line
between concern about weight and fat
shaming? Dr. Jennifer Codle joins us
now. We are hearing more and more
stories of patients saying they are fat
shamed by their doctor. But why is there
an increase? Well, first of all, this it
breaks my heart. This absolutely breaks
my heart as a family doctor to think of
to hear. And I'll be honest with you,
you know, we're doctors. I'm not
entirely surprised. And I don't actually
think this is new. I think we're hearing
about it more now because people are
willing to talk about it. We're willing
to record it. are willing to have
conversations and and things like social
media has really opened up the platform
to really share our stories and and
compare experiences. So, give us some
advice. Give the average person watching
some advice as a physician. How do you
know if your doctor's just, you know,
doing his best or crossing the line into
the shaming into the shaming area? Yeah.
You know, this is what I always say. I
say, "Trust your gut. If it doesn't feel
right, if you don't feel right, if you
feel shamed or humiliated or criticized
or embarrassed, you know what? Believe
yourself. Believe exactly how you feel.
And and and and a doctor wanting to do
the right thing does not excuse making a
patient feel any of those ways. That's
never okay. And I say as a doctor, we're
both doctors, but I'll say if you have a
doctor that makes you feel that way or
you're not comfortable, I'm giving you
permission right now to find a new one.
Let's see what some numbers are on this.
Studies have found hallelujah that
overweight women are less likely than
average to to get p preventative care
like pelvic exams and breast exam and
mammograms. I I there's no excuse for
this. No, but people treat overweight
people differently. What is the right
way for a physician to address a
patient's weight, do you think? Well, I
think there are a few things. And first
of all, as physicians, we've got to be
talking about this. Okay, these are
discriminatory practices. It's wrong. We
have to talk about it and be very
cognitive of this. But as physicians, we
need to talk with our patients. Let's
not talk at but talk to. We need to ask
our patients questions. What's your
journey? How do you feel about your
weight? You know, tell me what you've
what you've been doing, what you tried,
what your story is. Asking questions is
key. And something that we've also
talked about is this idea of never
dismissing a patient's symptoms just
because of their weight. That idea, we
shouldn't dismiss patients symptoms
because of anything, anything. We should
always be doing our due diligence. So,
this idea of saying, "Oh, it's your
weight." Just offhand, never okay in my
opinion. Um, and the last thing is, and
this is something a little bit
different. You know, I think in the
doctor's office, I'm a family doctor,
and do I take someone's blood pressure
out in a public space or do I take their
pulse or their temperature? No. Never.
But sometimes in doctor's offices,
people are weighed in public places,
either in the hallway or in waiting
rooms or things like that. And my thing
is, all of this should be private,
right? This is our personal protected
information. Uh, it's no one else's
business. So there are things as doctors
that we can do better to make this a
more comfortable and appropriate
situation. Yeah, you guys ought to feel
comfortable insisting that for example,
you wait because I don't want you not
going to a doctor because you're worried
about it. Weight's uncomfortable. I know
that's true for a lot of us, but it's a
necessary topic. So make sure you're
talking about the doctor, not at with
with folks as you care about it. So I
want to bring in Norma, the nurse who we
met earlier who was on the plane and
being bullied for it. Come on up, Norma.
What's the best way do you think a
patient
should be able to address their doctor
if they're worried about weight issues?
Letting the doctor know this is new to
me. Um, this is unusual feeling. I've
been feeling like this for two weeks or
two months, putting a time frame to it.
And if the doctor is still not asking to
you, change doctors. Get always get a
second opinion. That's right. Always get
a second opinion. Thank you very much.
Thank you. Let's call as always. We'll
be right back.
[Applause]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
It's a big day. Hey, I'm excited to
announce the launch of my all-new Oz
Guide. Their new quarterly single topic
minis, little magazines, cute little
things that will tackle some of your
biggest health problems. Our very first
issue will be on the news stands and at
supermarket checkout counters later this
month. It's an Oz approved plan
featuring the healthiest fats around,
which are mufas.
Of course, you know, mufas are
monounsaturated fatty acids. They're
plant-based fats. So, the easiest way to
remember them is to look for healthy
fats that aren't from animal sources
such as avocados come bouncing down. Or,
you know what else counts? Nuts and
seeds. They can really fill you up. And
one of my favorites, olives,
black, green stuff. So, there was a
study done through the American Diabetic
Association that found that a diet rich
in mufas works to actually reduce belly
fat. It's a big deal. But we don't want
to want, you know, we don't really want
these foods getting boring. All right,
that's the problem. I know, I know
you're thinking that. So, I've been
hearing reports of nuts and seeds
fatigue. Oh,
shy away from this problem. And then
there's avocado apathy. Nobody wants
that. Making headlines. And then, of
course, olive monotony. One of the worst
problems to run into. Oh, I have
challenged three Bite Club members to
come up with new Mufalicious recipes in
my first ever MUFA awards. This is a
very serious competition.
[Music]
We have spared no expense as you can
tell. I hope you're impressed by that.
The MUFA Awards, the inaugural launched
here. The dishes were judged by a team
of tasters who are harsh people, tend to
be sour and der in nature. So, I'll
present their reports to you. Prior to
the show, they tasted all these foods.
The winner will take home our coveted
golden avocado.
[Music]
So, I'm excited to hear what they make.
Jenny came up with a new way to use nuts
and seeds. What did you make? So, um I
made a burger. Um I combined macadamia
nuts, am um almonds, cashews, and pecans
with a lot of seeds. pumpkin seeds, hemp
seeds, sesame seeds, and um quinoa,
mushrooms, olives, and there you go. You
know, it could have been dry, but it's
not. Very fulfilling. Tastes meaty
without the meat and rich as you
described. Nicely done. Thank you. All
right. Next up,
Robera came up with a next level way to
use avocados. What did you do? You have
a sweet tooth, don't you? So, I do.
Secret agent chocolate pudding. Very
clever. Diabolical. You know why? Why?
Cuz our avocado is the secret agent.
Now, this goes great with wine. Sorry, I
just had to throw the wine in there. If
you brought some wine, it could have
influenced the judges probably. It's so
decadent, so delicious. You wouldn't
even know that there's avocados in
there. It's very thick and it does fill
your mouth. And it's very chocolatey.
Nice combo. This is a very strong
competitor event, but yours was too. But
before we judge, thank you very much. We
have Paula. Paula, what do you have? You
have an olive looking item here. So, we
have uh tah tahini filled uh hummus. And
these are actually gluten-free crackers
that are made from all those seeds that
just fell from the sky over there. You
love green olives. I do. Delicious. And
a lot of people who eats hummus.
Everyone eats hummus, right? Love
hummus. So, I lighten the hummus up a
little bit by adding some cauliflower.
So, it Yeah. It lowers the It lowers the
calorie count. You can't tell the
difference. No. So, and then also this
is a daicon radish. This is a carrot. 46
calories. 10 calories. If you need a
vehicle to get the hummus in your mouth,
try daikon. Give me that daon. I like
this idea. I, you know, you put a lot of
garlic in this. I'm very proud of you. I
did. It's delicious, isn't it? So flat
hummus. All of these you will lose
weight with if you eat them the right
way. But
I have the unfortunate and difficult
task of revealing the winner. Are we
ready for this? No hard feelings? All
right. So, I've deliberated with the
judges and the first ever MUFA award.
And the person taking home the golden
avocado today is
Paula.
Oh my goodness. Paula win. Paula,
look at that. Don't worry. You like me.
You really like me. I like all three of
you actually cuz although you won this
and that was fantastic. I got to say
don't worry cuz we're going to be
publishing both of your recipes in the
book book the mini bookine. So I'm very
proud of you. The guide to a fat belly.
It's available on news stands and at the
supermarket check out counters later
this month. Check it out. Share it with
your friends. And remember everybody,
together change is happening. Our
journey is just beginning. I'll see you
next time. It's really good.
[Music]