[Music]
Craving carbs? Counting calories? We're
slicing up the truth behind thin versus
light bread. How do you make something
light by adding sugar? And Oz
investigates frozen fries. There are
still a lot of questions about what's in
this bag and exactly how they're made.
Plus, need a little coffee with your
creamer? A lot of these creamers had
about 10 different ingredients, and
guess what? They weren't milk and cream.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you, Da.
[Music]
[Applause]
We're about to conquer one of the most
feared areas of the supermarket. That's
why you're excited. I know it. We're
talking about the bread aisle. It's been
so much time, you love it. With so much
fear of carbs and calories, though,
other alternatives have been popping up,
such as light or thin bread. You've
heard those terms. Yeah, we all have.
With about half the calories, you think
you can have two slices instead of one.
But what's really in them? Are they
better than other loaves? One of my
viewers is a fan of these breads
already. So, Kelly, why did you make the
switch to these light and thin breads?
So, who doesn't love bread? We all love
bread, Dr. Oz, but we just don't want to
have so many carbs. So, that's why when
I heard about light bread, I knew it was
a great alternative. And it comes in
many different forms. There's wheat
bread, there's English muffins, even
some flatbread. So, there's a multitude
of options for you and it's also still
healthy. So, just because this this is
just a regular bread that's been
flattened or just called or just called
flatbread. I guess it's just called
flatbread, but it definitely feels like
you're eating less and um low carb, low
calorie. And which ones do you
personally like the most? I like English
muffins. I think it's really nice to
have with egg and cheese in the morning
and a little bite-siz sandwich. The
smile on your face says it all. You guys
love these things. But here to
investigate the breads because we have
to do a little bit of this is a
journalist who I trust on these issues
who's uncovered how food companies can
hook us. Michael Moss along with
rockstar baker Zachary Gulper from
Benqui Bakery. Very well. Did I say it
correctly? Benqui. That's it. Yeah.
Thank you. But he's very French. All
right. So, some people have come to fear
bread. You know, there are some of our
audience members who've gotten
comfortable with these newer versions,
but bread itself has become a problem.
What do you think about these
supermarket breads? Yeah, it's so
interesting. I mean, you walk in the
door of the supermarket and there's so
much that can terrify you, right? The
soda aisle, the the chips, the frozen
foods. I mean, you and I have talked
about a lot of these minefields that I
always saw the bread aisle as this safe
haven of innocence, right? But it's not.
Bread is a product made by some of these
same big companies. And we need to think
about it. All right. Since the beginning
of time, bread has been basically flour,
water, and yeast. It literally allowed
humans to live together because we can
make enough of it. Zachary, these light
breads look very similar to the regular
ones. And literally, look at this.
Regular bread, light bread. You'd have a
hard time telling them apart. I've
actually tasted them. You've heard from
our audience members as well. They're
similar, but they have half the
calories, right? A lot fewer carbs. How
do you actually do that? Well, the way
that you would make a super light bread
would be through using uh enriched
flowers, uh dough conditioners, a huge
amount of yeast, and the fermentation
time would be very very short with the
idea of getting a very large rise uh
quickly to get a lighter loaf. But some
of the problems fall in with uh some of
those dough conditioners will include uh
monoglycerides, which we know to contain
trans fats, and that can be a little bit
dangerous to your health. But um
ultimately what's happening is you're
creating a very similar looking loaf
that's a lot lighter in weight. So when
you slice a slice it weighs less than
that which you would find at your corner
bakery. And the fact that the
fermentation times are different just
it's not just a science experiment
observation. I understand again I'm
thinking about as a doctor that there
there could be profound effects on our
health if the natural way we have made
bread for thousands of years is hacked
by speeding up fermentation. Indeed, I
agree with that. And I think that when
it comes to people who are having
trouble digesting wheat, that probably
has to do with the fermentation time
because with an extended fermentation
time, the enzymes break down the complex
carbohydrates and convert it to a simple
sugar. Then the yeast and bacteria
consume it so our human body doesn't
have to. Let the bacteria help you.
They're digesting the stuff in your
belly anyway. Yatsource digestion. Let
it work outside the body as well. Okay,
let's uncover some surprising
ingredients that we have found in these
light supermarket breads. The first
surprising ingredient, don't be shocked
by this. It's sugar. Zach, I thought
these supposed to be light. How do you
make something light by adding sugar?
Well, I think it falls into the same
category of trying to get it to rise as
quickly as possible and get as much air
in there as you can. Uh, so we've got
corn syrup here. We've got white sugar.
We've got honey, which of course is a
natural sweetener. We've got molasses,
which is a byproduct of Look at that the
ingredient list actually on bread says
high fructose corn syrup sometimes. So
we actually found that over half of the
light breads half looked the ones we
looked at had added artificial
sweeteners as well as high fructose corn
syrup. They were top of the list. It was
already present. So Michael, this is
something you've been pretty vocal about
that adding sugars to these foods, all
foods, but but bread in particular could
be a gateway for a lot of people. Yeah.
You know, sugar addiction is usually we
think about something with like candy
bars or a pint of ice cream, right?
Because the sugar rushes to the reward
center of your brain which sends back
that feeling of pleasure which can turn
into cravings and get you to eat too
much. But the fascinating about bread is
that besides kind of the added sugar,
it's one of those things that converts
to sugar in your body. And there's some
school of thought that the more refined
the flour is, the whiter the flour, the
faster it gets converted into sugar in
your body. And the stronger that reward
signal and feeling of pleasure be that
comes out. So the danger is you may end
up overeating the bread or move on to
even more sugary products. It triggers
people. Yes. Like any other addiction.
All right. There's another category of
lower calorie breads we've been hearing
about. They're called the thin breads.
You saw in the counter we shot up
earlier. So, exactly what what makes
them thin versus light. Well, your blade
slice them thinner.
You've got you've got less. Literally,
the thin bread is a thinner bread.
You've got less bread. Yeah. Gosh. So,
that's going to have fewer carbohydrates
because it's smaller. So, you know what
we do in our house? We actually cut the
bread ourselves. All you need is this.
Get a serrated knife. Looks like this,
guys. You don't have to be a surgeon to
use it. You got to toast the bread a
little. If you took a butter knife,
you're not you're just going to m you
know, mash up the bread. Get a serrated
knife, toast it a tiny bit to harden it
up, and then keep your hands on top of
the bread and you'll get a nice thin
slice. My wife can cut these things a
micron thickness. You can't even tell
there's bread on there. But all you need
is to be able to hold the stuff inside
the sandwich. Sure, you don't want two
inches of bread on either side of it and
it still works. By the way, it's the
same price. All right, so let's talk
about taste. You got a sandwich in front
of you. Couple different options. You
have regular bread to use a whole slice
and then put over what are you going to
put in the middle versus some of these
thin or lighter slices that you would
then sandwich literally the food in. So,
which one would you guys prefer? One
slice of regular, two slices of light
because that's the trade-off our
audience is going to make today. I'm
going to personally go for uh naturally
fermented bread in a single slice
format. That would be my choice. I sort
of thought you might go that way,
Michael. Yeah, I I love this choice.
Single bread, whole whole bread. So my
vote now that I've learned about the
importance of fermentation is to go with
the regular. But I think the thin is
okay too because ultimately it's good
portion control. So it's a nice little
hack to get you over the hump if you
don't want to take the knife like I just
did. But we got some options out there.
Take advantage of what's the industries
is offering to you. Back's book is
called the art of bread. Looks tasty on
the surface there. The insiders as well.
Check it out. When you come back we go
deeper into the bread aisle with the
wheat versus white debate. Here's the
question. Is whole wheat really that
much better for you? We'll find out
[Music]
the latest on the mysterious death of
Natalie Wood. Two witnesses, her
husband, a person of interest. Robert
Wagner said, "Stick to my story." Her
sister still waiting for justice.
Natalie Wood was pushed overboard. What
does her autopsy reveal? There are at
least 11 bruises to the back of
Natalie's legs. Plus, one of the most
infamous unsolved murders. Who killed
Black Dollia? He was untouchable.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
It is one of the biggest bread debates,
wheat or white? Now, whole wheat bread
outs sells all other supermarket breads,
but who here misses the soft white
pillowy stuff? That's the question we're
all asking. So, today we investigate, is
whole wheat bread really that much
better for you? Is it worth it? Guys,
who's team whole wheat here?
Any team whites?
It's broken in the middle. So, let me
bring in a family who's very divided
about this issue. Sharon, I understand
like so many members of my audience, and
you're speaking honestly. You're a big
white bread person. Why is that? I am
because the best grilled cheese is made
with white bread. That's a good point.
My girls, we go back and forth on bread.
And you know, I'm a chef, so it makes it
very hard. They give me a hard time in
general. In general, well, you're the
mom. But they do the I have three
daughters. I know what it's like. They
come after you. No. Oh, yeah. They see
every small little Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
So, you grew up with white bread. You
know how to make it right. There's some
things you just can't cheat like grilled
cheese. I get it. You can't. It's
classic. Now, I've got daughters here
and these are some tough daughters,
Dominique and Shane, I want you guys to
start us off. What is it that's wrong
with what your mom's doing? Why do you
like whole grain bread more? I mean,
it's healthier. You know, I'm a whole
grain, multigrain type of girl. That's
what I make my grilled cheese sandwiches
with. So, you know, I just think it's
better. And Carme and uh and Monique,
what what what happens at a family
gathering? You guys fight? You quibble?
What goes down? Um we just get both. You
get both. Yeah. Here, hold on to that.
That's right. Here's the white for you.
But if you don't mind, stay with us on
Sharon because I'm going to walk you
through this with Michael Moss, who's a
world expert in this area, and see if we
might change some minds here. Either
way, we'll find out. changed them.
Changed them. Change them. All right,
we're going to try to settle this food
debate. Michael Moss joining us with
some diagrams and with some evidence.
Okay, let's get to the truth about some
of these foods, nutritional truths on
these things. First up, calories. Is
there a difference? So, this was really
surprising to me. And for your viewers
who count calories when they should pay
attention to that, there's actually not
a lot of difference between the white
and the whole wheat. If you're shopping
and making a decision just based on
calories, this is like not a concern
that you have. All right, so it's a
draw. Next up, sugar. This surprised me
because I didn't realize how much sugar
was being added to bread, white versus
whole grain. Um I was really surprised
to learn that the whole wheat bread um
has as much as as two or three times as
much sugar as the white bread. Right.
It's more. Yeah. It's really startling.
Like why would they have to have more
sugar in whole wheat, right? But if you
think about it, all those great things
in the whole wheat kernel, the the germ
and the brand gonna have some bitter
notes in there. So they're using that
bit of sugar to make it palatable,
attractive to you. So you will eat the
whole grain. Have we changed any minds
over there? Let me start with the
daughters first. No. No.
They own the whole wheat. I don't know.
Sharon, you raised some stubborn women
over there. How about you? How do you
feel about this? Well, I'm I'm not
really changing, but I want to keep my
white because nothing makes no bread
makes a good uh grilled cheese like a
white bread. Come on. Come on over here.
So, come join us at this last table.
See, my vote my vote is to get the whole
grains. And I'll tell you why. Whole
wheat has a unique set of health
benefits. But I hear you. So, the
question isn't are you going to have
only white? The question is, will you
have white with something else? So once
in a while when you're not making
grilled cheese or making some food that
has to have white bread in it and you
want to look for a whole wheat
varieties, you have to at least know how
to pick it because you got some options
out there. So like how do you know? So
you walk in the bread aisle. Yeah. And
color is is a big driver. Color is huge
and you see that throughout the
supermarket, right? The companies use
color in lots of ingenious ways. This
bread, for example, this one looks the
same as these, right? Be back. It's
darker than this bread, right? Y'all see
that? Just compare them head to head.
Watch this. Molasses did it. Ah, that's
the color. Exactly. Yeah. So, don't go
for the head fake. How do you tell the
difference? You got to look at the
label, do a little work. It's either
going to say on the front 100% whole
wheat or whole wheat. And then you can
check the fine print on the ingredients
and make sure that whole wheat um is the
first ingredient. And if it doesn't say
whole wheat, it might have a little
kernel or two, you know, dancing through
the white bread, but it's not the same.
It's got to say whole wheat or 100%.
100% whole wheat. Now, go take care of
those daughters of yours. God, they're
stubborn. Check out Michael's book. It's
called Salt, Sugar, Fat. Fabulously
written, very well documented. We'll be
right back.
[Music]
We go behind the deli counter. Now we're
revealing whether deadly bacteria is
lurking on your sandwich meat.
Investigating what you need to know
before you brown bag it. Which cold cut
lasts the longest? And are all tortilla
chips really created equal? Is there a
healthier option? That's coming up
Wednesday on Dr. Oz.
Dip your frying hair. I promise you, dip
it in here. It's gonna change your life.
Stop being skeptical. Dip it in.
Mhm. Taste that thing.
Mhm. Mhm. Mhm. Daddy know what he's
talking about, don't he? Can I get a
fried dance?
I love that. Catch up with my fries.
Works every time. Thanks for rooting her
around in the right direction, Dad. You
all love that. Yeah, the first time a
child tastes ketchup, there's a reason
why this stuff tastes so good to us
because when it comes to frozen French
fries, there are so many options out
there to dip in the ketchup. You got
crinkle cuts, you got curies, you got
shoestrings, seasoned sweet potato, even
French fries shaped like happy emojis.
Going to pass these down. Don't eat them
all yourself. Share. All right. So,
investigator Marcia Gavoc is back to
help us figure out which of those is the
best. Besides the crispy, crunchy
deliciousness of golden fried French
fries, what else makes them so appealing
to moms and their kids? You know, for
one thing, there's the convenience,
right? You put them on a baking sheet,
you pop them in the oven, you don't have
to worry about it. Kids love these, but
there are still a lot of questions about
what's in this bag and exactly how
they're made. Let's just answer some of
those. The first thing we learned about
frozen French fries is is that they are
prefried. They're cooked first. I wanted
to bring in food scientist Taylor
Wallace to help us figure out the
process of making the fries, or at least
one of the ways that they're made.
Walk us through. I had no idea they're
already cooked. You know, I thought they
were healthy. They've never been fried
before, but they actually already are
cooked. So, you might be surprised.
Bagged frozen fries are actually cooked
multiple times in the manufacturing
facility before they're actually put
into the bag and sent out to the grocery
store. And yes, they're actually fried.
That's what gives them that wonderful
texture that they have when you bite
into them. Potatoes go through a whole
process to become frozen fries, mature
into fries. So, what I'm going to do is
walk you through what Taylor's talking
about. And I love this little animation.
You'll never forget it. Potatoes rolling
along the conveyor belt. You'll see it
here, right? And they're separated by
size to create the different styles we
know of, right? The classic strips. You
can get the rings, right? Not not an
accident. They're picked that way. Then
they travel to the steamer and the
peeler for about 10 seconds, right? That
makes the skin soft enough so that that
skin falls off when brushes are there.
Because they get brushed, right? They go
through there, they get brushed around a
little bit, and off goes the skin. Now,
workers actually inspect each potato to
make sure they make the cut, pardon the
pun. They pay close attention to the
look, the shape, the freshness, right?
No black marks. Next, after that,
they've got the chopper, right? The go
chopping through there, right? And
slices up the potato against the blades.
Water pushes the potatoes into those
blades and the conveyor belt moves all
those newly cut fries along. They go
through another inspection, right?
Another round. Then the blanching
process. Now, here's the important part.
The fries are placed in hot water to
cold water real quickly. It's like like
being in a spa, right? To firm up the
flesh and make the potatoes flavor that
much more pronounced and then into the
fryer again for approximately 2 minutes
to become partially cooked. Partially
cooked. The newly parcooked fries are
frozen and then the weighed bags are
delivered to the grocery store. So once
you get to that bag of frozen fries, you
can crack it open, lay them out in a
baking sheet and put them back in the
oven again for the third time. I guess
that's cook them all the way through. Is
that all right? Yeah. So what happens
is, as you mentioned, is when they're
cooked in the factory, those cooks are
par cooks, which means they're only
partially cooked. So what you have to do
when you get home is you lay them out,
you have to cook them all the way
through to kill any potential bacteria.
You have to make sure you check the bag
for the cooking time and temperature
because you do really want to make sure
that you finish the cooking process.
Okay, next up, some of these frozen
French fries are pre-browned. Taylor,
the secret ingredient, since you're the
food scientist here, how do they do it?
Okay, so you're not going to like this,
Dr. your eyes. But the secret ingredient
is actually sugar. Sugar to brown them.
Yes. So, in fact, in your organic
products, you're going to see something
like apple juice concentrate. In your
regular products, you're going to see
just regular dextrous, which is just
regular sugar, and that's because it's
cheaper. I like how you start smiling
when you start talking about fries. All
right, Taylor, thank you very much.
Makes me happy. I throw it over. So, we
asked sweet potato fries
whether they're healthier than regular
fries. It's an endless debate. Jennifer
from our audience came in today to
arguing that in fact there is a
difference. She knows it for sure. Do
you buy the frozen sweet potato fries? I
do. And what do you tell your kids? Are
they healthier? Much healthier. I have a
grandson that doesn't like uh much
healthy foods and he actually likes the
sweet potato. He goes for this. He goes
for this. He doesn't like any
vegetables, but he goes for So the nice
thing about the show is we tell you the
truth. So Mara did a deep tubular dive.
Okay. Right. She learned all about
potatoes of every type. Please explain
if there's a difference what it is.
Okay. There is and there isn't. So,
nutritionally, there's not much
difference between sweet potato fries
and regular white potato fries. But
where there is a really big difference
is with the glycemic index. Sweet potato
fries have a much lower glycemic index.
So, it's a little bit of good, a little
bit of bad. Wow. Well, at this point, if
he's eating, you'll be happy. But you
want to train those taste buds. Eat
things that really do matter. And
there's some good news in the frozen
section. Now, they're actually frozen
veggie fries. Really true veggie fries.
They're made from carrots.
green beans, broccoli, there's a bunch
here. Mar Jennifer and I are going to
taste these if you walk us through
exactly what these are. Yeah. So, these
are packed with nutrients. It's a great
way to sneak some vitamins into your
children. So, they are a good option,
but again, there's always a catch. You
can't fool yourself into thinking that
this is a serving of vegetables. It's
not. But they are a good option. What do
you think, Jennifer? Give us a
kids. I think they're good. Yeah,
grandson might take it. I think so.
Like you said, French fries would never
be a health food, but I'm glad to see a
movement towards better options. Proud
of you all. Buy the healthier stuff.
We'll be right back.
Up next, how much cream should you be
putting in your coffee? Missed the big
hot debate you don't want to miss. Plus,
we're investigating the new coffee
creamers at your supermarket.
[Applause]
We've been investigating the new foods
popping up in your supermarket and now
it's time to look into the new coffee
creamers you may be mixing into your
daily cup of Joe. We are investigating
what's in these creamers. We're also
going to tackle the question breaking
the internet. Which coffee and cream
type are you? Here's the scale, guys.
Find yourselves. Are you a B2? Like up
here right there. B2s, you know, you
like your coffee a little extra creamy
or, you know, that's what my wife does,
by the way. It's basically beige coffee.
Or are you a F5 right over here? See the
F5? Right? Just a little drop of cream
in there. Not too much, right? You want
to keep it nice and dark, right? You
find yourself in here. But before we get
to what kind you are, I want to talk
about what you're putting in there to
make it look that color. Nutritionist
Kelly and Patricia is here to break it
all down for us. Knowledgeable in all
these things.
So, we got half and half. We got the
milk, we got the creamer. What is the
real difference between these things?
So, let's break this down. Let's start
with the creamer. So, creamer, this
comes in either a liquid or a powdered
form. And as you know, this is the rage
with coffee drinkers. They love to put
creamer in. But here's what these
everyday coffee drinkers don't know is
that guess what? I was so surprised to
find out there's not a lot of creamer
milk in the creamer. There's just simply
not. No. companies are using other
ingredients to get it to taste and feel
like creamer, but there's no creamer.
And what about regular milk, for
example, versus half and half? Okay, so
regular milk has about 0 to 3% milk fat.
So, it's not going to give you that same
creaminess as half and half. I did a
little homework just on the calories,
and there's not a lot of difference
between a creamer and your half and half
when it comes to calories. They're
almost identical. Milk has less calories
than the other two, but you usually put
more milk in your coffee or your tea.
So, you probably end up with something
similar. So, don't torture yourself just
on calories alone. Let's zero in on
these traditional creamers which come in
plastic containers. They're in the
refrigerated section of your store. They
look like this. So, if these creamers
don't have a lot of cream in them, as
you just highlighted, what are they made
up of? So, so funny because we put them
in the refrigerator, but I want everyone
to know that I I wonder if this is for
show sometimes because there are some
countries that actually keep them on the
shelf. These these creamers, some these
creamers, some of them are actually kept
on the shelf. So, you know, who's to
say? But I will tell you this, a lot of
these creamers had about 10 different
ingredients and guess what? They weren't
milk and cream. No. But you know what I
think about when I see that? I just know
it's a processed food. Simple as that.
And that we're eating something more
processed. A lot of times folks say that
it's non-dairy, but in fact, if you look
at the label, there are little milk
derivatives in there. Yeah. So, you have
to be careful of that. So, when I looked
at a lot of these labels, they did say a
dairyfree product, but what that means,
Dr. Oz, is it doesn't have lactose. It
doesn't mean it doesn't have case. So,
again, if you don't have a big time
problem with dairy or, you know, that's
okay. Then you can this is just going to
be fine for you. But if you do happen to
have a big issue, pay attention to that.
Again, how about the the creamers that
come with all these flavors? I see the
the cinnamon bun flavors. They have
candy bar flavors. I don't understand
how this even comes into a creamer
category. Well, it's great. Like
desserts. It it is like desserts. And
here's what I want you to think about.
For every two tablespoons, you're going
to have about 12 g of sugar. So, let me
ask you a question. Would you walk out
of the house in the morning and pop two
chocolate chip cookies in your mouth?
No. Well, that's what you're getting.
So, you don't want to start with all
that sugar. And it's not just sugar.
They have other things they add to them
as well. So these I get really concerned
about because of the sugar and because
it's not real as you should. These may
be okay depending on whether you got an
issue with dairy or not. So okay, next
time we think of creamers, the new
non-dairy alternatives. There are
almond, there's soy, there's even
coconut creamers out there. One of my
viewers, Marie, has been here trying
these out. What do you like about these
creamers? Uh I love the fact that they
make you healthy. Um I love the fact
that you can also get flavor involved
without all the excess sugars and the
calories. So I'm trying to be healthy.
I'm trying to lose some weight. So these
are much better alternatives than the
others. What appears to be working. So
keep it up. Thank you. What surprising
ingredients have you found here? So
again, we have almond, soy, which is and
these coconut creamers have gotten very
popular. So let me talk about what I
like. I like the fact that opposed to a
lot of the other creamers, they actually
have as the first ingredient on a lot of
these coconut or soy or almond, which is
amazing. But if you look down the
ingredient list a little bit further,
what you're going to see is some added
sugars which you have to watch out for.
And also those those milk derivatives,
they're on the table. There's good,
there's not so good. But I've got a cup
of a new creamer I want you to try
that's not on this table. Okay. Are you
ready? Yes. Okay. Now look at the color.
Notice it's goldeny appearance. And now
as you taste it, I as you taste it, I
want everyone to take a look at this new
non-dairy creamer trend from a good
friend of mine. It's uh it's called Fat.
Mhm. Check it out. Hey, Dr. Oz, you know
that I love my morning cup of brew. And
look at how creamy and frothy my coffee
looks. You might be surprised to learn
that I didn't use any milk or cream in
this brew. No, all I used were two
ingredients. One of them is ghee, and
the other is MCT oil. Now, both of these
ingredients have become very trendy
lately. MCT oil has been linked to uh
weight loss and even improved cognitive
function in a handful of very small
studies. Ghee, look at how pure that
looks.
People that are dairy sensitive tend to
do very well with ghee. And all you do
is you combine ghee with a little bit of
MCT oil, which is right there. It's very
clear, in your coffee, blend it up, and
you get this beautiful, delicious,
creamy brew. You don't need any milk or
cream. Check that out.
So, we've been tasting it. Is it creamy
enough? It is absolutely creamy. It
completely coated my mouth. It was just
delicious. An explosion of flavor. I
love it. Look at that. Max is on to
something. I must say it's caught on
fire right now because people like the
fact it keeps them full all day long and
let's caffeine last a little longer
probably as well. So Max, he's out
there. So Kelly, of all longer that's
good. Yeah. Of all the supermarket
trends you identified, all the creamers
we looked out there, what were we
looking for? What's the most important
things to check out? Well, for me
personally, I love almond milk. It just
has a taste I like. But if you're not
into all those milk alternative milks, I
actually really like half and half
because you're going to have that creamy
richness and I like the nutritional
profile that it offers. But always just
look, as we always talk about on the
show, you want that shorter ingredient
list. And remember what we talked about,
these products don't have milk and cream
in them. So when you're looking at the
label, make sure it has milk and cream.
Simple as that. Simple, simple. It makes
sense. Glad you enjoyed the little
surprise here. Dr. Nice to meet you. Cuz
up next, it's the biggest debate on the
internet. Which coffee cup are you? Look
carefully. Just how much creamer should
you really be putting into your coffee?
You got to vote. You're somewhere on
that list. Be right back.
[Music]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
We've been investigating coffee creamers
and now it's time to answer the big
question dividing the internet. How much
creamer should you be pouring into your
cup of coffee? So, which cup of coffee
are you? Look at this, right? Pick the
cup that looks like you. Do you drink
your coffee light with a lot of cream or
is it dark with barely any cream in it?
So, I took a coffee creamer poll before
the show to see what you're all really
drinking. 27% of my audience said they
liked their copy light and white. Did
not realize that. That's more than I
expected. 73% of the audience like their
copy towards the other end of the
spectrum. Dark brown. Some even like
black with nothing added to it. So that
stated we all have our biases. So coffee
lovers Lori and Mariana from our
audience are standing by standing in our
coffee scale. All right. So two of you
are going to be our taste testers today.
Walk over to the tasting table. Taste
the concoctions we're about to describe
to the audience. I want some honest
feedback. Tell us what works. So, what
doesn't work for your pallets? Fair
enough. So, wherever you are, guys,
light, dark, you got someone who speaks
for you. Go taste it up. Okay, let's
head over to the coffee lab.
Nutritionist Kellyanne Patrrui and
barista Sam Keliso are here. They have
been experimenting to help uncover the
perfect coffee creamer formula. You got
to put the right amount of coffee with
the right amount of creamer so you can
still enjoy the taste and get the health
benefits too. So, Kelly, you are filling
up your mug with a lot of stuff. It
looks pretty white to me. Is this if
that's what people are doing, is there a
better solution? What what what is the
coffee benefit of that looking coffee?
Well, if your coffee ends up looking
like this, then you're probably
discounting all of the health benefits
of coffee because actually coffee is a
really low calorie drink. But what
people don't realize is when you add all
the pizzazz of the creamers, it adds up
really quick to the tune of about 280
calories and about 12 gram of fat. Okay.
So, if you take about 8 oz of coffee and
you add in one just a quarter of whole
milk, bam, that will really set you off
for the right track all day. That's our
energy formula. Let's get to the flavor
formula. Let's go to the barista. This
one I want it to really taste great. And
you know, coffee purists think adding
too much cream takes away from the
coffee flavor. So, what's your formula?
Well, let's be honest. Coffee with some
people don't know is kind of like wine.
You know, it's filled with different
flavors and notes. like wine, you want
it to compliment whatever you're putting
in it or with it. I mean, you're not
going to put ice in your wine cuz it'll
dilute it. So, why are you going to put
something bad in your coffee? Coffee has
this natural nutty flavor to it. And
like Kellyanne says, a/4 cup is the
perfect amount cuz it still embraces all
that flavor. But I like oat milk. And
you have to worry about it. It's
guiltfree cuz I mean, you know, in the
morning you have oatmeal for breakfast
cuz it's a good healthy breakfast. So,
why not add oat milk into your coffee?
Okay, now I don't drink a lot of coffee.
I mentioned that. I admit that I got
used to not drinking coffee because in
the hospital you really don't want to.
So when that happens and you want a
little pickme up, you run into an
impass. So I've figured out some hacks.
So Paulie, our great camera uh uh ex
expert is also an expert in espresso.
Puts a little pinch of cinnamon in my
coffee. I don't really like a lot of
sugar in it. The cinnamon is a good
hack. It'll work for you.
My favorite and it actually helps you if
you got blood sugar problems, but when
I'm on the go and I can't take my camera
team with me, unfortunately. I wish I
could. I wish I could. I'm starting to
like this. It's nitro coffee. Have you
guys heard of this? All right. So,
listen. It's my favorite. Nitro coffee
is when nitrogen is actually added to
the coffee and then the bottle is
pressurized. So, when it comes out, see
how creamy it looks? You see that cream?
There's no cream in it. That, my
friends,
it's all mechanical. And I'm starting to
love the fact that we can get the same
taste as adding sugar and cream to your
coffee by mechanically mixing coffee up
with a little nitrogen. So now we have
our taste testers. Lori Mariana, you are
speaking for the light coffee drinkers
and the dark coffee drinkers. What have
you liked so far, Lori? Uh I prefer the
one in the middle. It has um it's sweet.
There's a little nuttiness to it. That
that's that's the oat milk. Yes. I like
it. And the flavor works for you. Yeah,
the flavor works for me. All right,
you you tend to like it a little darker.
What do you think? Well, I tasted this
one. It looks creamy. It doesn't taste
creamy to me there. And it's like a
little bit bitter. I feel like I need to
add a lot of sugar to that. This, on the
other hand, um doesn't look like it has
any cream or anything in it, but it
tastes so much richer and bolder. Nitro
coffee. Yes.
Bottom line, I'm learning from you and
I'm learning myself from our experts
here. Taste stuff, guys. Do something
different than what you have always
done. We've got all these habits in life
and the amount of creamer and the kind
of creamer we add to our coffee is one
of them. Just mix it up. Take advantage
of all the technology that's out there
and these new ideas. You you might enjoy
what you find, especially going on a
different kind of a caffeine bus. We'll
be right back. A toast.
[Music]
The latest on the mysterious death of
Natalie Wood. Two witnesses. Her
husband, a person of interest. Robert
Wagner said, "Stick to my story." Her
sister still waiting for justice.
Natalie was pushed overboard. What does
her autopsy reveal? That's coming up
tomorrow.
[Music]
Ah, the summer it brings a lot of beauty
benefits, but the increase in
temperature and humidity means an
increase in frizz. And when the heat's
on, I know too many of you say it's a
struggle to have a good hair day. So to
help me tame your frizz, I brought in
Dr. Jenny Thomas, who's here on behalf
of my trusted sponsor partner, Hank Key.
Why do we get frizzy hair? It happens to
so many of us. It's because our hair
absorbs humidity from the air. I mean,
your hair can absorb up to 30% of its
own weight in water. It's crazy. My hair
gets heavy, I guess. Well, you might
feel it. you what you will see is as
your hair swells the curvature the
texture will revert to something that
most people would describe as out of
control and not what they want. So you
can see here we've taken hair and we've
put it into a room that's 80 and 80%
humidity. So think beach summer sounds
gorgeous not necessarily great hair.
That's over only an hour that that much
change has happened. Yes, it's happening
every single day. Okay, it it grew
magic. It does. And the more damaged
your hair is, the more and the faster
that this happens. And that's because
his hair is damaged, um, it becomes more
porous. And so it's absorbing that
humidity like a sponge. So when people
see that and they're not happy with
their hair, we make mistakes as we try
as we try to tame the frizz. Yes. So so
many of us, the first thing we do is go
to heat styling because it's a great way
to get back to smooth. And that's okay
as long as your hair doesn't see too
much heat. Where it becomes a problem is
when that heat becomes so high, bigger
issues come into play. How many heat
stylers are there here? Yeah, I thought
so. All the women, the bald men didn't
put their hands up. Come on over. All
right. So, I know eliminating all the
heat isn't an option. You're not going
to do that. But Dr. Thomas says a heat
protectant spray may help. So, I built
you some models. These high-tech models
represent your hair in a ponytail. All
right. I'll be the average person who's
using products that are not designed to
protect the hair or don't use any
products at all, which is probably for a
lot of us what goes down. And that means
your hair is exposed to extreme heat.
So, let me just pull out one little
fiber here. Right. There's a little
fiber. Right. So, I take my normal hair
product and I just want to straighten
it. I'm just straighten this up right
here. Ready? Watch this. Oh, jeez. That
was messy. Well, let me just try again.
Okay. Just in case. All right. So he can
get a little bit of hair and all you go
and oh,
let's go back in slow-mo, folks. That's
literally what I did here. But
figuratively, it's what's happening to
you. Look at that. All that muck that
starts to fly away is your hair getting
destroyed as you apply heat to it when
it's not protected. Dr. Thomas, please
do it your way since you're the expert.
So, a really good heat protectant
product should disperse that heat very
evenly because you had an extreme hot
spot happen that can lead to more frizz
or can even lead to breakage. So, I'm
going to show you how this works. You do
the same thing. Just give it a couple
spritzes before you apply the heat.
And you can see that you can smooth out
that unruly texture while still
shielding your hair from extreme
temperatures.
Don't you hate a show off? This drives
you crazy when someone's just good at
something. Come on over here. So, what
do you recommend to protect your hair
from frizz, which so many of us are
going to experience in the summer? So,
you definitely want to beat the heat,
and I think the best way to do that is
with Pantene's thermal heat protectant
spray that you see here. So, this can
protect your hair up to 450 degrees,
which is how hot some of these flat
irons can get. So, go me through the
routine. So, a after you've protected it
while you apply the heat, then what do
you do to sort of seal it in? So once
you've got your dry styled hair just
like you want, it's in control. Then
what you want to do is help hold on to
that as you're going to go throughout
your day. So I like to finish it off
with the Pantene airspray. So it's a
finishing spray that's free of drying
alcohols and it's especially good for
these hot humid days. So, we use these
humidity resistant polymers and it gives
hair a flexible hold um while also
working to resist humidity and more
frizz. So, I think many of us have had
the experience you use a styling
product, it's humid outside and all of a
sudden it feels like a sticky gummy
mess. So, these resist that humidity so
you can keep the look that you created
without the stickiness and also without
the stiffness. All right. So, if you
don't mind, just do a little demo.
You're about to go out in the day and
it's humid. So, what do you do? Super
easy. All you do is just take that dry
styled hair, give it a simple spritz.
You can see a little bit goes a long
way, but it's also it still moves. It's
flexible. It's not stiff or sticky. Come
on over here. Now, Chen Alexander has
been protecting her hair against frizz.
She's also joining us on behalf of
Pantene. So, how would you typically
describe your hair this summer? Well, I
uh I'm going to do a big spoiler alert.
Oh, please. For your audience. I'm not a
natural blonde.
Uh so, with my very very dyed hair, it
tends to be really brittle and really
wavy. So, in the summertime, it just
blows up. So, I've managed to kind of
keep it sleek here today. Look good like
that. Mhm. So, give me your normal
routine. What do you do? The hair
routine that we should all be trying.
Yes. Okay. So, I wash my hair every
couple days. I don't wash it every day
to keep kind of like the hold and less
heat styling on my hair in general. Good
for you. But thank you. Um and then I go
ahead and put the thermal the the
thermal heat protectant on it before I
blow dry. But I'm I'm doing the bad
thing where I'm using two types of heat
on my hair. The blow dryer and then I'm
going over another pass with the flat
iron. So that really protects my hair
from the heat. And then I do the
airspray all over to kind of lock it in
all day. Because from my house to the
subway, which is one block, if I don't
use a heat protectant and a hairspray,
it's like giant frizzy mess. Right. So
if if it was a mess before, you've
gotten a meaningful result by using a
heat protectant. Absolutely. You're
happy with it? Yes. Dr. Thomas, how
typical are those results? So very
typical. And you get those frizz
reducing benefits from the first time
you use it. But Chen and I have very
different hair types. Even though it may
not look so different right now, she's
actually got quite a coarse texture, a
lot of bleach, I have a much finer
texture. So, we've both used the heat
protectant spray and the airspray, and
we still get to our what we want for
this version of controlled defined look.
So, where can you find the Pentene
thermal heat protectant spray and also
the the the air not hairspray, airspray?
Exactly. So, you can find it at most
grocery stores, um drugstores, and mass
retailers like Walmart. Who here wants a
little bit of hairspray for their frizzy
hair? Hands up. All right. So, we're
going to go around the audience. You
take that side. I'll take the middle
part. We're just going to spray your
hair just a little bit. We got one
contain. Is that good? No. They're not
happy with that. This audience, they're
the smartest in television. So, thanks
to my partner, Pantene, you will all be
receiving your own Pantene thermal heat
protectant spray and the Pantene air
spray. We'll be right back. Share it.
[Applause]
What do all these Insta posts have in
common? Right, they're all part of the
latest viral trend. Hashtag procrastic
cleaning. The mission putting off
whatever task is at hand by scrubbing,
vacuuming, rearranging, maybe even
deciding to go fullon Mary Condo. You've
all done it. I've heard about it. And we
have a procrastic cleaner here today
who's about to be turned in. Are you all
ready?
Whose spotless kitchen is this? Now look
carefully.
Are you Lisa? I'm Lisa. Yes. Before I
get to Lisa, Robin, why just had you
turn your friend in? Your former friend?
Because she loves to clean. Like how so?
Like she'll come to my house and clean
my kitchen.
That's loving to clean. I mean that that
is an impeccable kitchen. What gives?
How are you avoiding
a big mess? Well, you avoid the mess.
But I mean to spend that much time
cleaning your kitchen, there might be
other things in your life you're not
doing. Grocery shopping, organizing
clothes, a lot of other tasks, too. Come
on over here. I might open your open
your eyes. You can hold the mic if you
want. Take a little walk here to the
monitor. So there's actually some good
news here because many folks choose to
procrast procrastinate
because clutter, right, is not the best
thing in the world. It's linked to all
kinds of negative emotions. So when you
look at a cluttered spot, right, it
creates this feeling that you've got
negative emotions around you. There's
stress, there's anger, there's
frustration, tension, worry, right? You
don't want those, right? When the space
is clean, we get rid of all this extra
clutter in there. It's like those
beautiful positive emotions, the
happiness, the calm, they can actually
evolve and float and elevate you. Now,
here's the part that I want you to focus
on. Researchers are saying that folks
who gravitate towards repetitive
behaviors like cleaning their kitchen as
meticulously as Lisa does in times of
stress do it because you need a sense of
control in life. Does that sound
familiar to you? It does. Yes. All
right. So, procrastinating
to a limit after to a limit to a limit.
After that, you got to deal with the
real issues that are worrying you. Now,
since you have been procrastinating so
effectively, I'm going to give you a
time-saving hack from another audience
member. So, you can't spend as much time
procrastinating. You have to get back to
the big issues in life. So, Ya, how are
you? I'm great. So, show us the hack you
got that might save Lisa enough time
that she can go back and deal with the
big issues in her life. So, when you're
trying to procrastinate on some things,
you can Everybody has these laying
around on the floor, that kind of thing.
You can use these. These are dryer
sheets. Yes, dryer sheets. You can just
use these to kind of clean up different
things. You can use them to dust. You
can use them to polish things off and
you can also use them to even clean soap
scum in your bathroom. So, one dryer
sheet, take it to the kitchen, give the
kids some chores, and then things you
got to focus on aren't about the kids.
It's about you. I'll tell you a little
secret that I learned. It's your kids
aren't going to treat themselves the way
you treat them. They're going to treat
the way themselves the way you treat
yourself. That's what needs to be dealt.
We're into this? Yes. All right. Little
gift from the show. Cleaning something?
Yes. No. Just just start scrubbing here
and we'll come down to my dressing room
afterwards. All right. Lisa, thank you
very much, Lisa. The owner. Thank you so
much. To the end of change is happening.
Your journey is just beginning. I'll see
you next time.
[Music]