[Applause]
You only have one life to live. So
nothing's more important than feeling as
young and as vital as possible. But if
you think you're aging too fast, the
truth is you have the power to outsmart
the clock. So let me ask the audience.
Who feels older than they really are?
Let me make sure you show
hands. Oh, a couple people here. Let me
go over here. Who has you had your hand
up? Take that if you don't mind. How old
do you feel? You don't have to actually
tell me how old you truly are, but how
old do you feel? 27 28.
That's a good age. I think I love to
feel So what what makes you worried
about how old you feel versus your true
age? Well, compared to my age, I would
say stress makes me feel older than I am
and just worrying and the responsibility
that kicks in after a certain threshold.
So, right. So, stress and
responsibility. Perfect. Let me keep
going. You had your hand up also. Yeah.
Go ahead. Reluctantly. Yeah. So I think
it's because of I sit and work all day
in front of a computer and I I feel like
my body is aging really fast because of
that. Okay. So you may not be able to
control your chronological age. That's
that's already written in stone. But you
can't control your vitality age. So in
order to get your vitality age younger
than your chronological age, you got to
think differently about what you're
doing in life. So I want everyone to
take a look at Camille's story. I'm sure
a lot of you can relate.
I feel like a 70-year-old trapped in a
51-year-old body.
I used to have tons of energy, but
lately I feel like I'm dragging through
life, like the wind's been taken out of
my sail. I'm just like always kind of
sluggish. It's not just my insides that
feel old. I'm starting to feel old on
the
outside. Now, when I look in the mirror,
I see bags under my eyes, like a little
sagging. I can't lose weight. I feel
like my body is working against me. I go
to the gym. I eat right. I try to stay
active. and I walk a lot and I still
feel like my scale is
stuck. I feel like the light went out
and that I'm not the person that I used
to
be. I really want to enjoy my 50s from
the inside out.
Camille, you're describing your body as
something that's actually working
against you. Yes. Let me just start to
feel this change happening in your body.
About five years ago, I my eldest
daughter left for college. my mom who
lived with me for 20 years and I was her
caregiver. We moved her to Florida to
have a better life. And last year my
youngest is now in college and you go
from like feeling vibrant and bright to
like five years ago starting to have the
candle flicker a little bit and then
this year it's like I'm feeling burnt.
Use this word uh candle flickering. This
phrase interesting one I think a lot of
people can identify with it. Coming up
here I want to take you through a little
voyage. Okay. You like reading books?
Yes, I do. All right. So, I love books.
So, I love everything printed. So, I'm
going to if I can explain your life in
the form of a book because a lot of us
look at aging like it's a book. Okay. A
book about us. So, for example, what do
books have? They have chapters. So, the
first chapter in a book usually is our
childhood chapter. Yes. Right. Cute
baby, by the way. That is you, right?
Yes. That's me and my dad. My dad passed
away. I'm sorry. Yeah. 20 years ago. But
you got mom still. Yes, I do. And I take
care of her. But this chapter, every
with mom here is still gone, right?
You're not a child anymore. In fact, you
got to do your own. So, let's flip it
forward. Chapter two for most of us is
our adolescence chapter. We do foolish
things, but we do fun things, things
that give great outfits, by the way. No,
thank you. Nice little hat there.
Siling.
So, all these events that we get to
become part of our memories and that's a
nice thing. Then we want to get on with
life. We get married. Yes. Right. We
have a marriage chapter and you had a
great marriage. 25 years.
Congratulations. I'll be 30 years this
year. Oh, congratulations. So, so best
thing I ever did get married. And for
most of us, we feel that way. sometimes
doesn't work that way as you desire but
it is a chapter of our life. move on
past that there's a fourth chapter which
is parenthood comes in different people
sometimes doesn't happen at all but it's
often there's my girls and then what
happens then what happens I know then
what's the next the kids are gone and
it's just a big question mark most of us
by this time in our life are only
halfway through our life yes and yet the
book is done you haven't filled the rest
of the pages and before we resign
ourselves to old age the truth is we've
got a lot of writing to do a lot of
things things that matter have to fill
the rest of our lives Yes. And that's
why I felt passionately about this
because I think a lot of us forget that
reality. Your kids need you and love
you, but they need you to be there for
yourself. Yes. Not a resign passive, but
actually fulfilled. And the question for
you is what are you going to fill those
pages with? I know. Have you decided?
Um, well, I did get a promotion at work,
so that's a plus. But I'm looking to do
things for myself, you know. Um, I love
painting. I love dancing and Zumba, so I
do that. Yeah. But you like Zumba? Yes.
I always Zumba. Are you doing it? Yes, I
do it. I like that. That's right. She
does it. I love that. And the reason I
like that so much is because as you
write these chapters, many of which will
have emotional elements, your body has
to be there for you. So, when you say
your body's holding you back from being
there, well, that's a problem because
you can't get that back readily. So,
let's combine those issues. I've got a
plan to help stop down aging. It's going
to work. It's also going to work because
you're going to with by stopping down
aging of your body, keep your mind
intact. Come on over here. I want you to
meet Caroline Aovian. She's a world
expert in this area. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you. How does someone like
Camille get their zest back for life?
So, Camille, you know, we're hearing
about your story. You can't control
everything around you and everything in
your life. But you know what? You can
control your body. And when you
rejuvenate your body, your mind and your
spirit are going to follow. And so, the
plan that we're going to talk about is
going to help your next chapter be a
page turner. And that's what we want.
Good. Thank you. It's not the last
chapter, it's the next chapter. Many
more to come. We come back has the plan
to stop aging too fast. You won't
believe the simple changes you can make
in your routine to get you looking and
feeling younger. Stay with us. Camille
says something we can all relate to. She
says she feels like her light went out
inside, like it's just flickering inside
there. To help her and many of you, Dr.
Carolina Povian is back with her plan to
stop aging too fast. Her first step is
to reboot our bodies by incorporating
amino acids into our diet. Why are they
important and which ones do you have to
focus on? So amino acids are the
building blocks of our bodies. The three
most important are right here. So I'm
going to build these for you. So
leucine, arginine, and glutamine. Guess
what? They spell out lag. So you can
remember because if you're lagging, it
means you need more of these, right?
Leine, arginine, glutamine. Forget about
the names. You know why? Because they're
in the foods that we can find every day.
And here they are. She's like Carol
Merrill over there reveals. So when you
lag, that means you need more protein,
more amino acids. We find these in eggs.
Eggs are wonderful things. They're
they're building blocks. Low-fat dairy,
milk, cheese, and yogurt, but even
animal protein, shrimp, meat, fish, and
you know what the hero here is? Turkey.
Turkey has a lot of arginine and also a
lot of stuff that helps us with sleep,
which we'll talk about next. But if
you're a vegetarian, you find these
amino acids in soybeans and lentils and
other legumes. So, make sure you get a
lot of these during the day, hopefully
at each meal to prevent lag. Okay. All
right. Next up, we're gonna revitalize a
routine for brain health. So, Dr.
Pobian, how does this help? So, your
brain very important. So as you're going
through your life, if you have a routine
and it's predictable, guess what? Life
gets very boring. Okay? So you say you
like to dance, Zumba,
painting, do it. You know why? Because
your neurons will regenerate because it
when you do new things, it makes new
connections and you feel wonderful. You
feel a zest for life again. Make that
chapter a page turner. your next
chapter. Make it wild and crazy. And we
talked about sleep earlier, but let me
just finish on this. We want you to
actually schedule your stress because if
you don't do that, you're not going to
be able to get the sleep that you need.
Dr. Pov, it sounds very
counterintuitive. How do you schedule
stress? Well, do you sleep enough and
No, I What happens? I wake up like three
times a night, you know, worrying about
everything about work, my children, my
mother. So when you're worried about
this at 3:00 in the morning, is it going
to help to work? You know what? You need
your sleep. You need 7 to eight hours of
sleep a night because your cells need to
rejuvenate and sleep is very important.
It's very restful. Gets you back going.
So what are you going to do whenever
you're worried at you find yourself in
the middle of night worrying about
everything? Schedule a time to stress
about it. Not when you're sleeping.
Stop. Okay, maybe write it down. Okay,
I'm going to do I'm going to think about
this tomorrow when I have rested and
that would be a great way to try to get
that 7 to eight hours of sleep a night.
That would be nice. It would be
wonderful for everybody. Thank you for
sharing your story. I appreciate it.
Good luck to everybody. Thank you. You
get the full plan and information from
all of our truth tube experts on dr.com
and make sure to check out Dr. Caroline
Povian's book, The Agedefying Diet.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good