What were the last words he said? When
life comes to an end as we are dying,
the brain experiences a burst of energy.
Often final words are spoken. My father
looked down at my son and said, "I
promise, buddy." But what do they really
mean? He was trying to say to him, "I
promise I'm going to be with you." We
investigate the science behind final
words. We are aware of what we're
saying. Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you back.
[Music]
[Applause]
In those last moments before a loved one
dies, there are so many emotions and
questions. Today, we unravel the most
mystifying question of all. What do the
final words uttered before someone dies
really mean? For the first time ever,
we're investigating the science about
what's going on in the brain as death
nears and piece together the meaning of
final words with the insights of an
intuitive grief counselor who says she
can help uncover what your loved ones
want you to know today. What insights
can you learn from last
words? The final words of the dying can
often be a mystery. These last thoughts
can offer comfort or even
advice. Bob Marley imparted a poant
message in his last moments. Money can't
buy life. While some final words
revealed the weight of tragedy and
shock, Princess Diana's reported final
words were, "My God, what's happened?"
before going into cardiac arrest that
fateful night in Paris. Many have tried
to analyze the last words of tech
visionary Steve Jobs. He said, "Oh wow.
Oh wow. Oh
wow. Viewers from across the country
have also been puzzled by the final
words of their loved ones. My mother
hung up the phone, sat back in her
chair, closed her eyes for a second,
said oh no, and then she was
gone. I always wondered what she saw or
who she saw. I lost my son when he was
18 years old, and his final message to
me was, "Don't ever leave a hat on the
bed." It's been 29 years, and I still
have no idea what that means. My
mother-in-law said before she passed,
Leonard, that's my father-in-law, and I
never really thought you would work. And
I'd like to know exactly what that
statement meant.
Brianna's here. She says her loved one
said something that still baffles her
today. So, you lost your dad 13 years
ago. Describe those last moments. um
those last moments with him
um because he was dying of cancer, he
would think that other people was his
family members and we knew that that was
coming towards the end. What were the
last words he said to my son?
Um my son was helping my mom and he was
helping my mom with my dad to use the
bathroom. Mhm. And my dad stood up with
my mom and my son. They both were
holding him. And my son told my mom to
be
gentle. Just just wait a minute. And my
father looked down at my son and said,
"I promise, buddy. I promise. I promise,
buddy."
And that was it. That was it. What does
that mean? What? Have you piece that
together? What? No. And that's what we
want to know. And what overall questions
do you have about his passing? What
questions do you think your dad could
help you with right now? I just want to
know honestly if he sees the man that my
son is. Um I was 15 when I had my son.
Um after I had him, my dad actually
pulled me aside and told me that because
of my
son, that's what stopped him from taking
his life. He credits your son with that
with saving him. Yes.
Okay. Yes. Let me bring in two experts
who might have some answers because I
hear these a lot in medicine. There are
last words. Usually there's family there
to hear them. Anna Ramandi is here.
She's an intuitive grief counselor and
medium. Erica Goldblad. I who researched
the field of death for more than a
decade. Thank you both for being here.
So Erica, what are the the most recent
studies tell us about the kinds of
things people say at the end of their
lives? What are the three most common
things people mention before death?
Sure. Well, there was a recent survey
that asked people what the final words
uh that they heard from their loved ones
were. And interestingly enough, uh most
people were given advice of some kind.
In particular, they were given
relationship advice. And then the next
category down was about careers. But
what's also really fascinating is there
have been other studies that have
explored what the meaning of final words
could be. And what's been noticed is
there are a variety of categories that
people repeatedly fall into. So for
example, frequently people talk about
taking a trip somewhere or as we saw
with Steve Jobs, they may repeat the
same word over and over and over again.
So ultimately we're still trying to
figure out what's happening and I really
tell my patients that uh the meaning of
final words is going to be up to the
people in the room uh left to decipher
them. Does the person who's giving the
final words have the awareness? Are they
really aware of what's happening around
them? clears their mind. What's
happening biologically? Well, as you
know, death is defined as the moment
that the heart stops beating, right? So,
there's no longer any blood flowing to
the brain. That's how we define the time
of death. What's so fascinating though
is that as we are dying, it appears that
the brain experiences a burst of energy.
So, we're trying to say something. Maybe
our tongues feel heavy or our jaws feel
tight and the words aren't coming out
right, but we are aware of what we're
saying. Anna, take us to a deeper level
here. It's not just the words. There are
other non-verbal cues that people can
give as they're dying. Yeah, sometimes
they point um they either point up,
sideways, down, or to other people in
the room to try to convey information.
Um looking into their eyes, you know,
their eyes speak. Um so if you look into
someone who's passing's eyes, you'll be
able to see what's really going on
within them as well. So let me ask you
if you can give some support here. What
what do you make out of the final words
that we're talking about and other clues
that might be evident and particularly
the issue about your son and what your
father is seeing in your son? Well,
first of all, your father had a very
deep connection to your son on a soul
level. He wanted your son to know that
he was not being abandoned. So, I feel
like there was abandonment before that
and your father came in and that he was
always going to be around your son
because your son was suffering and
grieving before it happened. He was
trying to ease the grief. He was trying
to say to him, "I promise I'm going to
be with you because I think a lot of
that was going on at the time in your
son's in your son's head." He absolutely
sees what a great guy your son is and
he's very proud of you. Okay? So, you
should know that as well. It's not just
your son, it's you, too. Was there
tension when your son was born when you
were only 15?
There was some tension. Um, it was
unexpected. I didn't know I was pregnant
until I went into labor. Oh my goodness.
Yeah.
Well, it's a good last bit of advice to
give then by your father. Yeah, that
would have been an important moment in
his life. How does it make you feel to
hear that interpretation from Anna? Um,
it makes me feel good. It make it it
answers what I wanted to know. It does
answer what I wanted to know. Brought me
some closure. All right. Up next, what
do people see or hear when they're close
to death? And what can your loved ones
last words reveal about the other side?
Stay around.
Giant fibroids. This was about 70 lb.
Painful fibroids. It can crush organs.
Can hair care products be the cause? Has
there been a link identified between any
of these compounds and these these
reproductive organ issues? So many women
suffer in silence. It has hurt the
intimacy. Absolutely. We investigate
fibroids. And just
listen, it's pretty heavy. All new Oz.
That's coming up on
[Music]
Monday. We're back investigating the
final words said before death. What
could they really mean? Grief counselor
and medium Anandi is back. And you say
sometimes the last words that a person
utters here is actually what they're
seeing when they've crossed over. Oh,
absolutely. Because as they're dying,
they're in two different places. So
they're in this dimension and they're
halfway into that dimension. So some of
the things they're saying have nothing
to do with what's going on right here.
It gives it a bit more power. We could
be getting a glimpse into the other
world from Oh, absolutely. these words,
these insights. Absolutely. And one of
the members of our audience, Emory,
let's go meet her, says that her father
whispered these final words to her. What
is that noise? That's what she said.
That's why I was thinking about this
issue of what he was potentially seeing.
Emry, how are you? So, what what was
going on that day? What the room was
virtually silent, I am told.
He had come back from his evening walk
with my mom and he was calm and then all
of a sudden he just kept saying, "What
is that noise?" And I didn't hear
anything and he kept saying it and
saying it and saying it and I said, "Are
you in any pain?" And he's like, "No,
I'm fine." He'd go to the window, he'd
look up and he'd say, "What is that
noise?" And he just kept repeating it.
And then I I got a little nervous so I
said, "Do you want me to call an
ambulance or something?" He said, "No."
He said, "Wait, we need to pay some
bills." I'm like, "Okay." So, we paid
all the bills and then he said, "And we
need to pray." I said, "Okay." So, we
just kind of sat there and prayed
together and he said, "But I just wish I
knew what that noise was." And you can't
hear this noise. I hear nothing. And
it's odd because he was really deaf for
the last 40 years of his life. And then,
um, when we finished praying, he said to
me, "Call." So, I said, "Okay, I'll
call." And no sooner had I hung up the
phone with the
paramedics, he collapsed. and all of my
uh first aid and CPR training that went
out the window and I'm shaking him and I
just kind of looked at him and I picked
him up and I'm screaming, "Daddy,
daddy." And he was, you know, you can
tell when a person's gone. And he smiled
and it was the first time he'd smiled in
about a year cuz he had not been well.
And it just while I was extremely
emotional and very sad and angry and
scared, I was also filled with peace
because I saw that smile that I missed.
I know. How would you interpret those
final words? First of all, he heard
symbols. I know that sounds crazy, but
symbols. He heard symbols being played.
It got his attention. Okay. It was them
saying, "Get ready. Get ready." So, on a
soul level, his soul was getting ready
to go. But also on a conscious level, he
told you, "Here, I'm going to go." And
he saw when he passed. Um, there was a
woman waiting for him. Um, your mother
passed before he did. No, she's still
there was a woman. Then that was his own
mother. She was waiting for him and
there was a party and I feel there was
music and drums. There was a lot of
music around him. He was never the same
when she passed. So yeah. And so that's
what you know she was providing this
great big party for him. It's a very
beautiful story. You should you should
be very happy about that. I was once I
saw that smile. It was the comfort I
needed to get through, you know, well
today. So So what do Anarie's loved ones
want her to know? Well, first of all,
your father wants to know that there's a
party on the other side. Okay. Okay. I'm
sure there is. And they're having a
grand old time, but they're also around
you. And you followed his wishes down to
the tea. Um, and he's thanking you. Um,
and he's very much around your mother.
Okay. So, I don't know what's going on
with your mother, but he's around her
completely. Thank you. You're welcome.
For for many folks listening right now
who who are trying to make sense of the
last words of their loved ones, what
what do you what's the overarching
lesson there? What do you What do their
loved ones want them to know about
what's going on? I think the most
important thing they want everyone to
know is that a they're okay. They're
going to a good place and that they're
never going to leave us. Truly, love
never dies. It's always around us.
They're not, you know, a million billion
miles away. They're right here and they
want us to communicate with them.
Thanks, Emry. Thank you. As always,
wonderful insights. We'll be right back.
[Music]
A real life fatal attraction. She was on
this obsessive path focused solely on
Dave. Could the accused stalker be just
another victim? 911. What's your
emergency? I've been shot. All new Oz.
That's coming up on
[Music]
Tuesday. Today, are you being tricked by
fake reviews on the internet? Have you
ever bought a product based on a
positive review? Probably yes. Right.
Right. How do you know it's real?
When you want to shed the pounds, the
only thing more tempting than a piece of
cheesecake is the desire to type a bunch
of diet plans into a search engine and
see what works. But your search may pull
up a website that looks like this. At
first glance, it seems like a review
website like you might see for
restaurants or hotels. It even has star
ratings offering opinions of the
different diet plans out there. However,
if you read closely, it becomes clear
they may not be independently offering
unbiased subscriptions of the diets
you're interested
in. And if you click on some enticing
image, it may bring you to another page
with a special offer you can't
resist. Today, we're investigating these
fake review sites that could be luring
you into buying questionable products.
[Music]
Last year, a company called Golo filed a
lawsuit against this show, claiming we
and other media outlets were duped by
these fake online reviews. But now, we
are joining forces to expose the
problem. I'm joined now by Dr. Jeffrey
Cudson, a spokesperson for Golo. He is
here because he is passionate about
informing the public about this threat.
Why is it so important to you, Dr.
Catson? It's very straightforward, Dr.
Oz. It's um scamming and it's um
dishonest. And for the most part, when
you talk about the diet industry, you
have a group of people who are very
vulnerable. They're out there searching
for something. They're looking for a
better lifestyle or they're looking to
lose weight and they're being led away
from something that might really help
them going towards something that
someone is just trying to make money.
So, here's the deal, everybody. you see
a negative review of a product on one of
these fake sites with a onestar rating,
should we be able to identify? Should we
believe them? And that's an issue that I
think has got all of us fumbling because
I want to trust those sites. We all want
to trust those sites. But in the diet
industry, there is no site out there
that's going to be doing reviews. If you
see somebody who's saying they're
reviewing something, it's a scam right
there and then you know that you're
being tricked into doing something that
you weren't intending to do. But there
are some big review companies, right,
the Consumer Reports or Consumer Labs
that sort of do this stuff
professionally. Yes, indeed they do. But
not in the diet industry. There's nobody
out there. You can almost be assured
that if you see something that says it's
a they're reviewing something, it's just
not true. They're looking to lure you
away from a product. So everyone just
put down what you're doing right now and
listen for a second. You know how
constantly angered I am by scams on the
internet. You guys have all been
targeted. I've been targeted myself of
my image being stolen to promote
products I do not endorse. And it's
almost impossible to stop these things
down, right? No one's doing anything
about it. So it's up to you to be
informed. Now I had no idea, Dr. Cson,
that there were so many fake reviews out
there. But now that I appreciate it, I
get it completely and you will as well.
So Dr. Cson has some red flags to look
out for that I want you all to pay
attention to. We've created a fake
review site. We went through the trouble
of making a fake review about a plan
that doesn't exist. We're going to call
it the thinned down diet. Does that
sound good to you guys? All right. It's
fake. I made it up. We even bought the
URL because they knew scammers would
watch the show and immediately start
creating fake, you know, the thin diet
versions to take advantage of you. So,
we're trying to protect you. But once we
Google a diet, once you're in there
clicking away, right? You're on your
server and you write down the thin down
diet, right? more websites than just the
homepage of this company come up. For
example, right, this one down here says,
"Is the Thin Down Diet legit or scam?"
You see that down here? Right. Would you
click on that if you're interested in
the Thin Down Diet? Right. I would click
on that. So, what's the first way to
know that this might be a fake review?
Well, is the whole just the article. I
mean, come on. This is showbiz. Is a
Thin Down Diet legit or is it a scam?
That alone tells you that they're trying
to scam you. They're trying to move you
away from what you probably were trying
to look at and get you to look at this
diet. All right. So, just from the title
alone, you got a red flag. Normally,
this is a little too, as you mentioned,
show busy. Something's going down here.
Right. The next way to f to spot a fake
review if the title doesn't turn you on
to it is that the author didn't buy or
test the product. Look at this. Right.
This is you click down on that little
fake title and do you see anywhere here
that it says they tested this, right?
It's clear they they may or may not have
tested it, but if they had tested it,
they would have told you about it. They
would have uh put out their appropriate
statistics. So, they're not testing the
stuff. They're just throwing it out
there to catch your attention. That's
just a another way to pull you away from
what you're looking for and have you buy
a product that you never started looking
for. I just made just a common sense
test. If you did a lot of work to test
this product and put women on it for
weeks and weeks and weeks, wouldn't you
brag about it, right? You tell somebody
about it. They're not telling you
because they didn't do it. The next way
to spot a fake review is there are links
there for competing products. Let me
just for a second. So, you saw we went
we went to find the thin down diet. Now,
you're you're in the review. They're
telling you check out our top
recommendations for weight loss. How
does this work? Well, first of all, let
me say when they put something in like
um our top recommendations, that's just
being completely biased. They're taking
you away from what you're looking at,
they're taking you to what they're
probably getting paid to show you,
right? And actually, speaking of being
paid, they actually can put ads on the
site. And I'm curious if they've lied
about the rating and the testing, are
these ads legitimate as well? Same
situation. I mean, there's another way
of making money here. If you put an ad
up, every time someone clicks on that
ad, everyone's making money. You're
losing money, but they're making money.
So, what's being done to about these
fake diet review scams?
That's the saddest part of all. It's
nothing's being done. Legal system can't
handle it. It's too overwhelmingly
large. And who's the big loser here?
It's the consumer. So, the only way that
consumers can possibly figure this out
is they need to do their own homework.
They need to go towards sites that are
legitimate. They need to see that
there's clinical trials to prove what
they will accomplish for you, but this
stuff is just not the place to be. So, a
big message is no one's policing these
fake review sites. That means you got to
step up and protect yourself. So, take
advantage of the red flags we gave you.
Tell your friends about it. Let's stop
this down ourselves. We'll be right back
with more.
Giant fibroids. This was about 70 lb.
Painful fibroids. It can crush organs.
So many women suffer in silence. It has
hurt the intimacy. Absolutely. That's
coming up on
[Music]
Monday. There are so many weight loss
plans and sometimes hard to find what
works for you. We're back with Dr.
Jeffrey Cotney. is a spokesperson for
Golo who just revealed that there are
sites online that could be tricking you
with fake reviews on some of the most
popular diets. So, how do you tell? How
do you know which diet to choose? So,
what should folks be looking for as a
doctor in a diet or a meal plan? Well,
I'm glad you said as a doctor because
that's the truth. The truth is this is a
medical condition. This is a medical
issue. It may be weight loss, but weight
loss has everything to do tied in with
good health. And so as far as what they
you should look for, you should look for
something that works. I've spent 35
years in practice in obstetrics and
gynecology as you know. And I can tell
you what doesn't work. That's for sure.
Because I've been trying to find the
product that does work. and the products
that work are the ones that you've got
to get away from these review sites and
you've got to go to their site and you
have to see if they are looking at
clinical studies, studies that can prove
that their product, their process works,
their plan works, their supplements
work. So, you recently completed a
clinical trial, a a pretty important
one. What were the results? Results were
quite clear in in Golo, which is the
company that I've decided to support is
has done a study and we're so excited
about it. It was a clinical trial that
was done last year and it had two
groups. Both were on the go diet and one
group received a placebo. The other
group received release which is the
supplement. We're so excited about it
because the release group had a 79%
increase in weight loss over the placebo
group. So good that we're off to having
this submitted and reviewed for
publication in the near future. Right.
So go brought someone from their
clinical trial here today. Dawn lost 42
pounds on her plan. 42 pounds on the
gold plan. During the trial, she's gone
from a size 20 to a size eight. Now,
here's the part that I really care
about. Her triglycerides went from 247
to 107. And she also lowered her
cholesterol. Here's what she looked like
before. And here's what she looks like
today. And we get to meet Don. How are
you? I am great, thank you. Well, you
have a lot of energy in your eyes. How
do you feel? I feel fabulous. And since
the the clinical trial, I've lost 23
more pounds. I've lost 75
lbs. Went
from a year ago, I was in a size 20, now
I'm in a size eight and I feel fabulous.
I'm 66 years old.
Are you really? Yeah. Oh my goodness.
You have other other secrets then as
well. What did you like about the Golo
program? I could see that it was a very
nutritious plan. It was balanced. You
had fats. We eat olive oil and butter.
You have
carbohydrates. You eat a very balanced
and it's a lifestyle change. It's a
healthy lifestyle change. It's clean
foods. There's no preservatives in the
foods that you eat. So, I love that.
What was the biggest challenge being on
the diet? Well, I had a lot of bad
habits I had to break. like lots of
people, you go home, you know, you skip
breakfast, you eat fast food for lunch,
you go home and you graze all the way
until that salted caramel ice cream at
the end of the night, you know, and so I
had a lot of bad habits and I had a lot
of misconceptions. I thought skim milk
was good for you, you know. I thought
that canola oil was good for you. There
were all these things that have
additives and I've learned to eat very
pure, which is great. The the problem
with a lot of diet plans is when you go
off them. Yes, because they were
ownorous or hard to do. You've sort of
slipped back. But you say you've gone
the opposite direction as you mentioned.
I keep losing weight because I'm going
to eat this way for the rest of my life.
And I think one of the things that you
talk about is it's a healthy lifestyle.
And I love it. I love going through the
grocery line and everybody seeing all
the healthy foods that I eat. Everybody
comes up to me and goes, "How did you do
that?" And I'm going to eat this way for
the rest of my life. My mom is 92. I
want to go out dancing. I got a lot of
years left. I think you're coming at
her. So, what are the main components of
the plan, Dr. Cassin? As Dawn has
already told you, and we've spoken
before, she's joyful. She loves this
diet and it's not just a diet for her.
It's a new way of life. And what this
program is all about is making it easy
to sustain weight loss because it's the
slow loss of weight over a sustained
period of time. She can go out with her
friends. She can go out to dinner with
her family. She can eat the same food as
her family. We're not asking people to
get rid of one major food group, not to
get rid of carbohydrates and be high on
proteins. Eat like you should eat with
all the food groups, including
vegetables, including carbohydrates,
fats, and and um and protein, and be
able to enjoy your meals. Who wants to
go start not enjoying eating? Loneliness
becomes the biggest problem with a lot
of plants. Come over here. Show what
you've concocted for us. This is a
typical day. So, this is a typical day
of what I eat. and I eat all this food.
What's great is that I take the release
and I'm not hungry in between. That's
how when I was on the clinical trial, I
knew that I was on release. But one of
the things that we love is super fuel
and it's a mix of
carbohydrates. It's proteins. I saute
them in a little olive oil with a lot of
fresh vegetables and I just love it.
It's healthy for you and it's just fun.
Look at all this food, guys. I lost 75
pounds eating all this food every single
day. You ever put hot sauce on this? Oh,
yes, I do. I like it a little spicy.
Good. I can tell. All right. I'm very
proud of you. I really am. Keep it up.
Keep spreading the wisdom. Thank you for
all you do. God bless you, Dr. Kas.
Thanks very much. All right. We'll be
right back.
[Applause]
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day, but when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your
[Music]
podcast. Today, your biggest bathroom
secrets exposed. I want to find out what
all of you could be hiding behind these
closed doors when no one else is
watching. What are you really doing in
here? Could it be helpful or harmful to
your health? I want to get to my first
confession, but you'll just have to
excuse me for just a moment.
[Music]
Hey, Dr. Oz. I am a busy mom. Between
taking care of my kids and taking care
of my house, my life is absolutely crazy
and frantic. And you know what?
Sometimes I just want a little me time.
And I like to indulge. And as funny as
it is, I come in my bathroom cuz I can
finally get some peace and quiet.
Inevitably, while I'm in here, I have a
snack attack. So, I always bring in some
kind of snacks with me, like
blueberries, cuz you know, I'm trying to
be healthy. Sometimes I even like to
really indulge and have cake. I brought
this in with me, too. Dr. Oz, I have to
confess, I am a multitasker. I like to
eat and sit on my toilet all at the same
time.
Rebecca the multitasker joins me now.
Blueberries. Really? I I know. I I
usually do eat the cake. I was trying to
be good. No one let you show off that.
What kind of foods do you normally eat?
Seriously. Um seriously, I'll have
granola bars, maybe chips. Oh, the stuff
in front of me here. Muffins. How did it
all start? Cookies. It's unbelievable. I
I just feel like I finally get quiet
time when I'm in the bathroom. And the
minute you yell out I'm in the bathroom,
people are silent. So, I I do have some
concerns about germs, which I will get
to later in the show. But there's
another surprising risk to stack on the
toilet that I'm going to share with you.
When you bring a snack into the toilet,
what do you do? You tend to sort of sit
there for a little while, right? Rush
through your bagel or your muffin or
whatever. Sitting on the toilet for
prolonged periods of time may increase
the pressure on the veins down below
like where you go potty and everything
that causes hemorrhoids. And
hemorrhoids, you don't want to have
them. It's not worth the bagels, the
muffins, and everything else. How might
this potential concern change your
snacking habits in the toilet? Well, you
might think it's kind of funny, but I
don't want to leave my quiet bathroom
where I'm have time to myself. So, maybe
I'll just stand up. That's good. Don't
tell them. They don't They don't know if
you're sitting or not, right? I know.
Thank you, Rebecca. All right. The next
confession is actually one of the
biggest debates breaking the internet
right now. One woman in the audience is
outing her fiance for a secret that is
cringeworthy. Take a look.
Hey, Dr. Oz. Right now, my fiance's in
the shower. I think you can hear it
running, but that's not the only thing
that you hear. He literally keeps peeing
in the shower, and it's so gross. He's
not listening to me when I ask him to
stop. Please help me.
So, Summer and her fiance are here. You
didn't expect this, I guess. No, not at
all. Yeah, I mean I know I know I do
gross things sometimes, but I didn't
expect this.
Why do you pee in the shower? This is a
question all women ask us. I figured it
was normal. I mean, I thought most
people do it. No, I mean, how many
people pee in the shower here?
Notice all the men there. A couple
women, too. So, why does it bother you
so much? Why Why are all women bothered
by this? It's just gross, you know? I
mean, I shower in there. My daughter
showers in there sometimes. Your feet
are stepping on that same area. Yeah.
It's just gross. Didn't bother you at
all. I thought it was completely normal.
I mean, uh, I do everything in the
shower. I brush my teeth in there. It
saves time, you know? You don't You
don't go number two in there, right? No.
No. Not just number one, right? All
right. Come on over me. Cuz Vic, you're
not alone. Right. You know rapper Cardi
B. I do. She asked her Twitter followers
if they peed in the shower. Here's the
post, by the way. And the response, it
was overwhelming. She says, "Keep keep
it a buck. Do you pee in the shower?"
And all the answers in there are pretty
honest reflections. Most people said,
"Of course we do." What are you talking
about? So, are you ready to hear the
truth? Can you deal with the truth on
this? Yeah. Summer, all the women, can
you deal with the truth on this? All
right, come on over. Let's go through
the
numbers. So, I'm just going to knock it
out to you. First of all, toilet
flushing, it accounts for 27%. Come on
closer. I'm not going to bite. 27% of
all the water, indoor water, you come
over the side, um, is consumed because
we're flushing whatever we're doing down
the toilet. That's a fair amount of
water. Yeah. Okay. One time you flush
it, every time you flush it, seven
gallons of water. Wow. Did you think
about that? You could take a shower,
seven gallons of water. Yeah. And peeing
in the shower, it actually saves water,
which saves money and therefore it's
good for the environment.
So, although I made you nervous, it
turns out it might not be so bad. Does
this influence you at all, Summer? Um, a
little bit. But I mean, I guess I still
kind of feel that it's gross, but you
know, now that I know that it saves
water, I guess it's okay. All right. So,
if you're worried about the ick factor,
which some some of of the viewers now
are, you probably still have a little
bit of that in the back of your mind.
Come on over here. Here's the thing.
Urine is actually produced by the
kidneys, as you know, right? And is
stored in the bladder. And there are
some little bacteria. Come over close to
me over here. Come next to me. You're
going to enjoy this. All right. So,
these bacteria are actually really
important. Now, we didn't even know they
were there till recently, but they're
good bacteria. They sort of protect you.
It's like an ecosystem in there, right?
And although the urine is not sterile,
these bacteria are pretty easy. They're
non-toxic. They don't become a problem
unless you don't pee enough or unless
you keep ura, which is the waste
material, concentrated in your body
because you're not letting it go out of
your bladder. So letting it all out,
letting you pee is actually fine, right?
It's probably better for you. Even if
you pee in the ground, as long as you
don't have it cut in your foot, you
don't pee on your foot, right? No, I
didn't think so. Then you're good to go.
and you're just stepping on old mats
that that urine's already gotten washed
down. So, now that you know it all, you
know that it's okay to pee. Probably
better to pee. You doesn't really matter
that there's a little bit of bacteria in
there because they're not the bad kind.
And you know you're saving the
environment. You're okay now. I feel
better. Much better. I do. Happy
customer. Congratulations. Thank you.
All right. Here's a question. How often
should you wash your face? How about
your hands and the towels? That might be
an issue here, too. The towels. How
often you wash them? The definitive
answers. And they are they are they're
out there. We'll share them with you.
That's
next. Here's your daily
[Music]
share. Today, we're exposing the biggest
bathroom secrets. I know all of you have
been hiding. I asked you to come clean
about how often you really wash your
face. Lots of options. Then I asked
about your hair. You're all over the
place. How about your towels? Even your
towels aren't always being washed the
same way. So, what is the real answer on
often you should be washing these
things? We're going to give you the
sciencebacked answers that may surprise
you. The first debate has to do with
face washing. How often should you wash
your face? Comes up all the time. I have
a twin experiment. As rare as they are,
they'll help us find the answer.
Identical twins, Najanique and Nea are
here. Welcome to the show. Thank you.
Nani, start us off. How often do you
wash your face? Once a day. Once a day.
And Naja? Twice a day. Twice a day. You
both look the same still. Your mom can
probably tell you apart, but most of us
will be a bit confused, but it's a
perfect twin experiment. Theoretically,
you're genetically the same, so we
should be able to figure out if it makes
a difference to go once a day or more
than once a day. So we use cutting edge
imaging technology called Canfield Vizia
complexion anal an analyst system. Come
on over. That'll help us find out how
often you should really wash your face.
Now it's going to give us an idea of how
many bacteria you have up there. We're
going to take a look at nausea skin
first. This is what washing your face
twice a day, twice a day looks like
through a microscopic lens. Each of the
little dots represents sort of a
bacteria count. Are you ready for the
answer? Ready. Your score was 2347.
That's the instances of bacteria on her
face. Now let's take a look at her twin
Nanique. Her face is next to her sisters
who washes only once a day and she has
2,28 instances of bacteria on her face.
There's no benefit. There's no benefit
of washing more. So it turns out that
just looking at this data, washing your
face once a day is enough. What do you
guys think about that? I'm shocked
because I would think twice a day would
at least make that number significantly
lower than that one, but that's very
surprising to me. That's why it's sort
of good to look at what's really
happening. Such a common problem. Let's
bring in Dr. Dennyman. Uh she's a
world-class
dermatologist. Daniel Angelman knows
everything about this. I need the final
answer here, which is uh just from this
information, it seems to me that once a
day is enough. Yes. How do you paint the
picture for our twins? Yes, please. Once
a day is often enough, and especially if
you have dry or mature skin, once a day
is plenty. If you're oily or acne prone,
you know, you can go twice a day without
stripping your skins of your natural
oils. But the secret is not to wash more
than twice a day. How often do you wash
your face a day? I do washing a thorough
washing at night and then I just tone in
the morning. There you have it. Do with
the dermatologist. All right. Is that
helpful? Thank you. Yes. Tell tell your
mom she raised very pretty young woman.
Beautiful. Thank you. I appreciate it.
No matter what your scars are. Thank you
very much. All right. Next debate. How
often do you wash your hair? Right. Lot
of debate here. There's been a big
movement to stop washing your hair.
Let's come on over here. We've got two
guests from the show who have different
philosophies. Lauren, how many days a
week do you wash your hair? I wash my
hair every single day. Seven times a
week. That's right. Very You do
everything else rigid. Rigid like that
or you're pretty flexible. No, the thing
just just once once a day for my hair
because I work out almost every day is
kind of the one thing I stick to and
showering, but other than that. All
right. And we got Megan here who has a
different philosophy about hair washing.
I wash my hair like two to three times a
week. Uhhuh. All right. Walk us through
as we have a basic oil test to help
figure out who's wiser. So, I'm going to
use these blotting sheets just to see
how much oil is at the root of the hair.
And so, I'm going to start first with
Lauren, who we know she washes daily.
And she works out and that makes sense.
A lot of my patients who work out, but
see how much oil there is there. Yeah.
Let me hold that. Yes. And then Megan,
who's only two to three times a week.
Okay. Let's see what we're making this.
I've got my
Oddly, oh my goodness. Less oil. How was
that? Wait a second. The once a day hair
has more oil than the twice a week hair.
Yeah. And these results are quite
shocking and surprising, right? Because
you would think if you wash more, your
hair would be cleaner and less oily.
Well, how do you explain this? So, the
way that I explain it to my patients,
and it sounds a little scientific, but
if we stimulate the hair follicles,
we're actually stimulating the sebaceous
glands at the root of those when we're
washing, and it increases oil
production. So, actually, you can have
oiler hair even though you're washing
more. Look at the smile on her face. She
just loves being right. Just doesn't eat
at you a little bit. I feel triggered.
All right, let me explain. Come on over.
We got a little animational. So, when we
wash our scalps less, it actually
changes lots of things. And I'm going to
demonstrate it for you because here we
are with doc with Dendi sitting here in
the middle of our scalp. And when you
when you wash your scalp less. You see
down here you got some oil. You actually
produce less oil. The body naturally
produces its oil at its own pace. So it
disrupts your body system when you
shampoo too often. It'll throw your oil
production out of wax. So more washing,
more scrubbing under my feet here,
right? Translates to more oil. Look down
here. See the oil? More oil down there.
And here's the bigger problem. If you
shampoo your hair every single day,
you're ultimately gonna strip away the
natural oils and it can lead to dry,
brittle hair, which you don't want
either. So, bottom line, wash your hair,
not every day, every other day, every
third. I agree. Did I get it right? You
got it right. A+
A+. Before we go to break, we asked our
audience how often you wash your towels.
Now, 46% of you said once a week. We
asked the experts at the Good
Housekeeping lab to reveal the truth
about how often you should be washing
your towels. Pay attention to their
[Music]
advice. Hi, Dr. Oz. It's Carolyn Forte
from the Good Housekeeping Cleaning Lab.
You're asking about bath towels. We
recommend that you wash them after every
3 to four uses. You're coming out of the
shower, you're clean, so they really
don't get that dirty. Just make sure you
hang them up between uses so they don't
get moldy.
Giant fibroids. This was about 70 lbs.
Painful fibroids. It can crush organs.
So many women suffer in silence. It has
hurt the intimacy. Absolutely.
That's coming up on
[Music]
Monday. Today, we're exposing the
biggest bathroom secrets you've all been
hiding until now. We're asking the
question, could you be brushing your
teeth with poop particles
and not even know it? Does it have your
attention? I thought so because what I'm
about to show you will change the way
you flush forever. And Kimberly is going
to help explain all this to us. Thank
you for being here. Thank you for having
me. So, let's start with a simple
question. When you flush your toilet, do
you normally put the lid down? Does it
matter to you? Um, most of the time, but
sometimes I don't. So, well, I think
most of America just flushes. What's the
big deal, right? It's your bathroom.
It's going to stay in there anyway.
That's what I think. You probably think
that, too. Have you ever heard something
called the toilet plume? No. Never.
Interesting word, isn't it? Toilet
plume. Yeah, it is. Official definition.
It's the term for what happens when the
force of flushing sprays microscopic
particles into the air. That's what it
is. Kimberly, just to demonstrate a
toilet plume, if you don't mind, just
put your finger over there and flush
there. Just push it down. Yep. Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa. I mean, we've got
stuff plopping all over the place. Right
now, it might look pretty having this
confetti flying around here. I sort of
like the gymnastics of it, but I'm going
to assure you something. The stuff
flowing out of there is not as benign as
pieces of confetti. It could be pieces
of poop, pieces of urine. It could be
lingering stuff in your bowl. How's that
make you feel about the toilet bowl? Um,
it does not make me feel good at all.
So, you might notice how it's played all
over here, right? It seems pretty
dramatic, maybe overly. So, yeah, people
have actually studied what happens to
that toilet plume and how big it is. Let
me show you how far away it will reach.
Hold the end here and start stretching
it towards that counter there. Keep
going. Keep going. Keep going. Keep
going. Keep going. Stop. That's as far
as it goes. Six feet. Wow. Now notice
what's in between the toilet and six
feet away. The toothbrush. The
toothbrushes. Right. The poop makes its
way to your sink and everything around
it, including your soap, but most
importantly, your toothbrushes, cuz you
put them in your mouth. Disgusting. How
does that make you feel about your
dental hygiene practices? It needs to be
wrapped up. Like all of this needs to be
wrapped up or put someplace else. Like I
tell you what I would do instead. It's
much easier. I go like
this. Then it's all done with. So, a
partying gift to you. A measuring tape
to see how far your toothbrushes are
from the toilet. You can keep those
toothbrushes. They're clean. I'll take
my chances and not take them with me.
Together, change is happening. Your
journey is just beginning. Close your
toilet lids.
Nicely done. Thank you. Thank you.
[Music]