[Music]
Today on Oz. Is there a problem with
pain? Real housewife Claudia Jordan gets
real. The embarrassing condition she's
lived with for years. Celebrity toes
that are jacked up. You become the corn
queen. I've got a little home remedy for
you that could help you out. Plus, a
real estate air turn murder suspect. A
late night host's painful surgery. And
the fashion duo under fire for their IVF
baby comments. The biggest health
headlines straight out of Hollywood.
We've got the inside scoop coming up
next on Dr. Oz.
If you've ever seen The Real Housewives
of Atlanta, you know it's all about the
drama. And the newest cast member,
Claudia Jordan, fits right into the mix.
They've been taking on Atlanta housewife
matriarch Nene Leaks. A lot of activity.
Claudia's fellow housewives aren't the
only things irritating her. She recently
revealed a medical condition, multiple
corns on her feet that she's lived with
for years. Wait till you see them. And
today, I'm going to offer up some help.
Claudia Jordan, come on out.
[Applause]
[Music]
Thank you, boy. Come have a seat. Oh my
god. You're like, "Wait till you see
them." We We are going to look at him in
a second. I I got to ask. I mean, I It
gets pretty heated on the set there.
What What irritates you more, your
relationship with fellow housewife Nene
Leaks or the corns? My corns are
extremely annoying, but they're nowhere
near as obnoxious as Nene Leaks. I can
cover my corns up. Yes, you can. And
they don't talk back. So So Nid's been
on the show. You guys don't get along
for personality reasons or it's just,
you know, we work together before. She
asked me to like um take over for a job
that she couldn't do one time years ago
and she was following me on Twitter for
years. So I didn't think we had an
issue. So when I got there, I was kind
of surprised that she kind of was acting
like that. But I know people put on TV.
They had to get their moment. All right,
let's talk about your corns. First of
all, I am curious that you're being
public about them. Have they been a
long-standing issue and why are you
talking about them now? Um, I've had
issues since I was in college. I ran
track and um I was all-American in track
and field and when we would comply. Good
for you. I was a sprinter, but I would
wear track spikes that were like a size
too small because I felt like I gripped
the track better, but when I took my
shoes off, my feet would be irritated
and my toes would kind of be like this.
Then I became a model and deal or no
deal. And I like, you know, 19 hour days
in heels. And a lot of times it'd be
brand new shoes. They maybe weren't the
best fitting shoes. So a lot of us have
feet kind of like dancers. So mine just
I mean the skin on my feet. They're just
really sensitive. And it's tough
sometimes when you're dating, especially
now, ever since the movie Boomerang came
out, nobody cared about feet until Eddie
Murphy made it a big deal. And now it's
like, let me see if you I'm like, let me
keep my socks on. Well, to to paraphrase
Eddie Murphy, can I see your feet? Oh,
you can. Don't judge me. Don't judge.
So, I've got a corn cam. A special corn
cam that I got you.
I I don't want the audience to miss any
part of this. No. A corn. You got to Can
you like like make it like a soft focus
and maybe like dim the lights a little
bit, a romantic ambiance? It's the one
thing I'm extremely insecure about. So,
this is like I'm doing this for the
sisters out there, the women out there
who have bad feet. Yeah.
I am your mascot.
It is a brave thing to do because a lot
of women would never be caught without
their shoes on. But you'll say that as I
take my foot my shoe off. Well, I think
first of all, you're doing the right
thing. And of course, I can go through
this entire audience do the exact same
thing. So, let's start with yours with
your little cords. Okay. They're a
natural. It's like Cinderella. All
right. So, give me so. Well, I'm just
looking. But don't wiggle all the time.
Wiggle I don't want you to focus in on
them. Well, here. So, just a couple
things on corns. Okay. Uh they're
obviously they're adaptive. They're
thick, hardened layers. They are. Look
at that one in the end. Oh, is that the
one you put without the top? That's the
big one. Yeah, that Oh, yeah. That's
pretty. It's like a little pearl stuck
in there. Don't judge me.
So, here's the thing. The These are
actually very adaptive. They form on
joints that are being rubbed on against
friction, pressure, as you know, running
in those shoes with them. Um, not
wearing socks does this. Do you wear
socks much? No. Yeah. Because socks will
provide a little bit of cushioning for
that. Um, and then the other thing is,
of course, if you have hammer toes or if
you have bunions, you don't have a
bunion. Nope. Um, but this is a little
bit of a hammer tail. Probably from
being in those shoes for a lot of times.
If it pushes up like that and as it
pushes up like that, it'll start to So
my toes are deformed now because of the
years of abuse. Years of abuse, which
you know, sort of predictable, but the
good news is that things we can do about
it. What have you, First of all, how
long you had them? Since college. Since
college. So that was quite a while ago
because I'm 41 years old now. So it's
been a while. So, um I uh that's when
they first started and there was a time
where I would wear flats and they got a
little bit better and I would get
pedicures and they looked, you know,
presentable somewhat, but then back in
the heels and I will tell you the
expensive shoes were way more damaging
on my feet. They were they were and I
just don't understand how they can
justify the price of some of these shoes
if they're going to cause this kind of
damage. So, I look at these shoes here.
This look like like a chain. Is that is
a chain. All right. So, you have these
high heels which is what you normally
wear. I usually wear higher ones in
those. Higher than this? Yeah. like
stilts, right? And when is it is there a
problem with pain or is it the cosmetic
aspect of the corns that bother you? The
problem is well it doesn't hurt. My feet
don't my corns do not hurt. They're just
extremely hideous. And now, you know,
being on such a big show or just being
in the business, like when you go to red
carpet, you guys, the photographers,
they're so sneaky. They'll put the
camera on your toes and you think you're
you're looking at your face and you're
just doing all this and they got the
camera on your toes and it ends up on
this weird website where they're like
celebrity toes that are jacked up.
You're like, I'm thinking you looking at
my smile. Oh, you got a closeup of my
feet. And it's humiliating. So, I just
figured, you know what? I'm going to be
on the show. I mean, I rather take
ownership of my flaws myself instead of
someone else pointing them out. And why
not? Why not? Absolutely. You go. And
it's not like it's not like I did
anything wrong. I mean, this is
something that happens when you wear
certain type of shoes. And I since it's
happened my inbox on Facebook and on
Instagram I got so many people send me
pictures of their feet that are just as
bad if not worse and they're like thank
you for you know being brave because
I've been embarrassed and I don't know
what to do and so you know if it helps
people kind of deal with it and you know
make them feel a little bit more
comfortable like if she can do it I can
do it then so be it. You've become the
corn queen and I'm proud of you. Come on
over. What what have doctors told you
about this in the past here you here
I'll still you just lean on me. I'll
hobble this way. Go hop. You got me?
Yeah. Gotcha. Go. How about like that?
All right. So, have doctors try to do
much for these things? Okay. I went to
one doctor and I went to two doctors and
one was like much like yourself. She
said, "Listen, if it's not in pain, I
really couldn't justify doing surgery.
It's a cosmetic thing." And then another
doctor that just really wanted to take
my money said, "You know what? I could
do it for like 45,500. I just got to cut
the tendon and then you'll be okay." And
like I'm like, "Wait, wait, wait, hold
up. It sounded very medieval." And he
said he want to cut the tendon so the
toes will lay flat or remove part of the
joint. And I'm thinking I I still want
to be able to run. I still want to be
able to, you know, wear heels and I
don't think like I'm like, "Okay, am I
hurting my body long term for a cosmetic
issue? I don't want to do that."
Indications for foot surgery are pain,
pain, and more pain. Do not touch those
feet with with a scalpel unless you've
got pain. Now, that stated, I've got a
little home remedy for you that could
help you out, okay, that a lot of our
viewers, you know about the salicylic
acid passes, right? But this is
something different. So, this is a
special foot bath. Put your foot in
there. Enjoy yourself. Get comfortable
in there. Now, in that foot bath, and I
want everyone at home can do this as
well. Is that like hydrochloric acid?
It's an acid, but not hydrochloric acid.
Very gentle acid. It's apple cider
vinegar, which is a bit acidic. You'll
like the smell, right? And that actually
softens up the skin. So, 15 minutes
after this, go ahead and put your feet
up on here. Would you recommend, you
know, when you go to the nail shop, they
want to like file stuff down and cut
stuff. Is that dangerous? Um, if they do
it gently, I don't like to file with
anything sharp. I like pumones, which I
think are fine. Okay. In fact, after you
do this, you take a pumone, you can
gently rub it like that. Okay. Again,
you can't feel it, but when you begin to
feel it, it means you've gone deep
enough. And then here's the big thing.
See, I've roughed that up a little bit.
My corn cam's gone, but you can sort of
see that everybody. That's fine. We can
leave that over there. Okay. So, then
you're going to take a little castor
oil. Here's the magic solution. A little
castor oil. Just dab it on there and let
that soak. And over about 10 days,
you'll see that get softer and softer.
But I got to say something to you. Yeah.
And I think you're a smart woman.
Obviously, you know this already. If you
keep wearing those high heel shoes that
you're wearing, you're never going to be
able to get into a situation where these
things can heal themselves because this
is a scar protecting you. So, I want you
to try wearing flat shoes. But I realize
that you don't like wearing flat shoes
cuz you don't like seeing those corns.
When I was living in New York, I wore
flat shoes like every day pretty much
for like nine months. I rarely wore
heels. I gave them a little bit of a
rest. But then back in Atlanta, I really
have to be glam all the time. So, back
into the high heels, I went I made
something very special for you. You
have? I have corn coverups for the first
time ever. And they're especially for
you because Mimi leaks is on the corn
cover up.
So you just put these on like this
and you're basically I'm going to send a
few of these extra home with you like
that.
These all the ones you need from me. So
take those back. This is the Nini Leaks
foot appearance and give us extra ones
to her. I have a whole year supply
there. You'll enjoy them. I love them.
Thank you. It was really a pleasure. You
can see Claudia on the Real Housewives
of Atlanta Sunday nights on Bravo. You
can find out more about her in an
exclusive OS five video on oz.com. We'll
be right back.
[Applause]
[Music]
Coming up next, there are Hollywood's
biggest health headlines. The stories
everyone is talking about. From high
fashion battle over IVF to painful
procedures, get the inside scoop from a
panel of top celebrity experts. Coming
up next, all new Oz. And tackling one of
your biggest addictions, carbs. But your
love affair with bread and pasta doesn't
have to end. I'm excited about this cuz
you've got two really big new ideas. The
plan to eat carbs to beat carbs. Plus,
Dancing with the Stars judge Bruno Tony
breaks the newest celebrity health
trends. I'm turning myself off. Will it
be Bravo or Brav? No. All new Oz. That's
coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
Hollywood's biggest health headlines and
want to get the inside scoop from a
panel of top celebrity experts. Alicia
Corals is here from ENews, a
correspondent there. Caitlyn Becker
back. She's a host of HPO Live and of
course AJ Callie, my good friend, is a
correspondent for Extra.
He's on his best behavior today. Let's
get right to it. First, the story that
everyone's talking about, Robert Durst.
Man, I got to say before you get into
the background here, what I'm most
interested in is why he agreed to do the
documentary in the first place. So AJ,
bring us up to date. Okay, so there was
a fictional movie about himself. He saw
it. He called the producer, said that he
it would be a good idea to do an
interview. He decided to do this
interview and went into the restroom,
still miked up, and kind of was talking
to himself and confessed. There's a
fascinating article in the Washington
Post where it breaks down why he would
agree to do this interview. His lawyer
said, "Do not do this. I'm not advising
it. Don't do it. This is a guy that has
allegedly murdered three people. He's
saying stay away from it. But then it
breaks down his psyche. It says he's a
narcissist and also people want star
power. So even the fact that, you know,
he knows he's probably guilty. He just
couldn't stay away from that camera. Why
wouldn't he do it? Why wouldn't he do
it? He's in the last chapter of his
life. He's gotten essentially gotten
away with murder. He admitted on the
stand to dismembering the body of a
human being and walked. Why wouldn't he
do it at this point? He's basically
untouchable. So, he's he's clearly a
sociopath. But then, if you think about
sociopaths, what is it that and by the
way, people who kill people like the way
he probably did? Here are some
characteristics. Inappropriate
self-esteem. So, he's being told he's
fantastic. It's inflated, but it's not
true. He knows it's not true. He can't
deal with that. A lack of empathy, a
lack of sense of of worthiness. And so,
then he gets jealous and almost angry. I
think that he's not getting the credit
for getting away with these murders.
That's exactly what the article said.
There's no way he should have done that.
And during the alleged sort of
confession, I don't know if he's
confessing or not. The audio is picking
him up in the in the restroom. And it
sounds like he's having one half of a
phone conversation. He's posing
questions. He's answering questions that
haven't been asked. It sounds like he's
talking to someone that we don't hear.
Yeah. Okay. They move on to the
designers Dolce and Gabbana. They are
under fire for comments about babies
born IVF, which I was sort of surprised
by. Agent, what were the comments? The
comments were they they called them
synthetic babies. And he also said that
they don't feel that gays should be able
to adopt which infuriated so many
celebrities including Elton John and
they called out for a boycott against
Dolce and Gabbana. Yeah post here you
can see says how dare you refer to my
beautiful children as synthetic. That's
the actual word they use. And just
before we get into the discussion Doian
Gabbana stood by their statements. They
added we oppose gay adoptions. Now
they're gay of course. They oppose gay
adoptions. The only family is a
traditional one. I should emphasize that
one in 10 women have trouble getting
pregnant. 2% of all babies born now are
IVF. So what gives? There's this is
infuriating on so many levels. They were
a couple for 23 years. At one point they
wanted to have their own family. And um
you know they made these comments saying
that they grew up in love in a
traditional family. A family is what you
make it. You can have a a mother parent
and a father parent and not be the best
home. It's what you make it. So I'm
proud of all these celebrities for
standing up. I just interviewed Andy
Cohen who's selling his Dolchen Gabbana
stuff for charity.
Kayla, I think the the crazy part is is
they gave a second interview to CNN just
doing the worst job backpedaling. It was
a it was terrible, which they
essentially just went out there and
said, "We we you know what? We love
everyone. Everybody's fine. We love
everyone. This boycott is a terrible
idea." You know, you can see what
they're doing. They on one hand said,
you know, these are our views and and we
love everyone and that's that's all
okay, but don't don't boycott our
clothes. That's that's medieval is what
um is what they refer to it as. That's
that's medieval. And it's so interesting
to um to sort of stand by comments and
stand by your freedom of expression and
then get irritated when people don't
want to express themselves in your
clothing because they don't agree with
what you're saying. I think it's a bit
of a reflection of how fast we're
evolving as a people. Now, when you're
making that many babies, miracles
because parents desperately want to have
children. Of course, they can't have
them often times. So, when that happens
and our society can't keep up, we end up
with this friction. But this is how we
evolve. Most people in this audience, I
think, would agree that you'd be
celebrating a family that had a child
because they wanted the best. All right,
Jimmy Kim, we all of them. He opened up
recently about a very painful opening in
his body. He was actually very honest
about uh a process. Uh you want to be
the lead on this one. This is a topic
you and I might suffer from, but the
women really I don't know if I would
share it even on Dr. Rouser. Anyway, uh
Jimmy Kimmo was at South by Southwest
and he spoke about a procedure he had on
his urethra and it he they opened it was
closing up, I guess, and they went in
and opened up and then they had to go in
there again and open it up, which I've
got to give. Y'all know what he's
talking about, right? It it it it Oh, he
shared a lot. Shout out to our Mark
Malgan from E who broke the story. He
did the interview. He shared with Mark.
But I say I say good for Kimmel. As
women, we're forced to share a whole
lot, right? men never talk about these
kind of things. I didn't even know about
this. So, I think he's starting a
conversation at least. So, these urethal
strictures, they happen from trauma,
from inflammation, and you know,
infection, things like that. And often
times, you get this urge to go to the
bathroom. You can't cuz the straw is
stuck, so to speak. So, I've been
corresponding with him. And he says, he
says he's doing fine. He's enjoying the
joys of urination.
We all We're very happy for Jimmy. I was
going to say I was at South by Southwest
and I went to his taping and his
afterparty. He looked like he was in
good spirits. Um and and part of his
health conference. I was there for the
health part. So it was actually apppropo
that he was speaking about this. Jimmy,
he has turned his life around. He's in
great shape and lost weight and you know
dealt with a lot of the issues a lot of
us delayed dealing with. So kudos to
him. Isn't it a great thing that he that
he shared it? So many people not only
would be too embarrassed to tell to tell
their their significant other or their
best friend. But what about people who
are too scared to go to the doctor? Now
you have a celebrity like this saying,
"Hey, this is this is kind of
embarrassing. This was uncomfortable. I
got help. It's okay. You can do and men
don't talk about health like that. AJ,
you can do. They really don't. Just
kidding. What do you got to share, AJ?
Anything? No. I love having you all
here. We'll be right back. Thanks to our
panelists.
[Applause]
Have a health question? Ask on dr.com
and get answers directly from Dr. Oz and
his team of experts. No question is off
limits.
Next. Trying to cook healthier, but all
you create are kitchen catastrophes?
Give your family meals they can enjoy.
Lydia Bastionic is here to help the
worst healthy cooks in America. Easy
healthy tips to solve all your cooking
dilemmas. Coming up next,
all new Oz. And tackling one of your
biggest addictions, carbs. But your love
affair with bread and pasta doesn't have
to end. I'm excited about this cuz
you've got two really big new ideas. The
plan to eat carbs to beat carbs. Plus
Dancing with the Stars judge Bruno Tony
Ooli breaks the newest celebrity health
trends. I'm turning myself off. Will it
be Bravo or Brav? No. All new Oz. That's
coming up tomorrow.
You have the best intentions and all the
right ingredients to cook the healthy
meals. You set out to make this, but it
turns into this. I know you've all been
there. Or you're hoping to make these
little babies here. Oh, and you serve
your family these
not so happy. So, when I received an SOS
call from a Maryland family who say they
live with the worst health cook in
America, I knew I had to step in. Take a
look. My wife has been trying to cook
healthy, but me and the kids can't take
it anymore. It's disgusting. Everything
she cooks is either mushy or tasteless.
I don't like it. She has to be the worst
healthy cook in America.
What is King W? More like King Wow. This
is disgusting.
That is harsh. Tanisha is here. Did you
have any idea gotten that bad? No, I had
no idea. He's in trouble when I get
home, too. I agree. So on
you have trouble cooking just healthy
foods, is it all foods? No, it's just
healthy foods. So, I can cook the rich
foods like for holidays and things like
that, but just the healthy foods that
I'm trying to get the kids to eat. All
right. So, you did us a favor. You
actually brought in an example of why
her family has labeled her the worst
healthy cook in America. Um, let me just
look at this. Well, it's not as I guess
what it probably would have looked like
if you'd Well, I don't know. Yeah, it's
a little dry. It looks a little dry.
What What is this actually? Looks like
Sahara Desert.
It is a zucchini and ground turkey
casserole. It was supposed to start off
creamy, but it was kind of dry. So,
sometimes I'd like to add cheese to get
it looking a little better. It didn't
work out and thus the looks on your kids
and your husband. All right, here's the
thing. I want you all to be healthy and
I want healthy food to be something that
your family will enjoy. So, you are in
great luck today because I brought you a
good friend, celebrity chef Lydia
Bastian. She's here with tips for all at
home healthy cooks who feel like the
chefs are in their own kitchen, but
they're not really in there. Come on
out, Lydia.
Welcome.
Tanisha's story. How common is it? Very
common. Tanisha, don't lose your spirit
because I hear this all the time and
it's very easy to be corrected. It's
very correctable. Okay. You're you're a
grandma, right? Five kids. Five times
over. I'm a grandma and they're about
the age of yours. Actually, mine are a
little bit bigger. So what is the key to
fixing this problem of being a healthy
cook and at the same time getting kids
to embrace it? Uh the key is because you
want to be healthy also I heard. Yeah.
So it's getting choosing the primary
ingredients, the right primary
ingredients. Be conscious about your
pasta. Be conscious about you buying
vegetables and using vegetables, using
lighter meats, chickens, fish or less of
the more tasty meats. It's okay. You
want some crumbled sausages. Don't put
whole sausages. Open it up. crumble it
up and put a little crumbles in there
and that'll give you a lot of flavor
texture and you don't need a lot of it
to make it flavorful. That's my problem.
Well, that makes work in that a little
bit. So, one dish that you cannot get
right is this zucchini casserole, ground
turkey casserole that I think we saw
evidence of. So, Lydia, if you don't
mind, show us your recipe, your way of
making this. Okay. So, this is basically
a casserole. It ends up a casserole like
yours with pasta. Your kids love pasta.
They do. Okay. So, the choice is first.
Whole wheat pasta. Okay. Will they know
the difference? No, not really. And the
sauce now. Tomatoes. Plum tomatoes. Some
nice zucchini, sliced zucchini. You have
onions. You have your proteins. Chicken
in there. Now you can put shrimp in
there. You can put whatever they like.
Fish in there and substitute it. So this
is the Now you notice the ratio of the
vegetables and the protein versus the
pasta. Throw in the pasta. Go ahead.
Okay. The pasta is cooked, but it's
always a little bit undercooked. I leave
it because I don't like mushy pasta. Do
you like mushy pasta? I do not. Okay.
Kids like it, but I don't. No. No. But
again, you got to teach you. No. No. Put
Put some more in. Put some more in. We
have to fill this. We have to fill it.
Come on. That's it. No, you're doing
okay. You're doing okay. All right. So,
here we are. What I would do this now, I
would add a little bit of the grated
cheese. Go ahead. You mix. And I add
Okay. So now we're flavoring this. You
know, the question is of the flavor.
Fresh herbs, a great source of diversity
of flavor and bringing that freshness.
Do your kids object to They do not. They
like that. They like flavor. Mine just
never has any.
Well, are we getting there? A little bit
of cheese. You notice all of this? This
is cooking. The pasta is cooking in the
sauce. It's absorbing the flavors. We're
getting there. Lots of fresh basil.
Okay. So, how do you layer this now? You
just you just dump it all in there at
once. So, now No, no. Nice and easy.
We'll do it. Go ahead. Now, you you do
it. You've done this. Do do a a layer of
that.
Like, put about half of it. And it's
okay if it's a little bit of uh uh uh
moisture in the bottom because as it
cooks, it will absorb. Actually, you
need a little bit. Okay. I I heard you
saying that yours is a little dry. Yes.
Most of the time. Okay. So this is how
you how you avoid that step. So here we
are halfway through. We'll put a little
bit of cheese again for flavor. We'll
put a little bit of the mozzarella
fontina. Nice flavorful cheese in
between. So when they get when they get
in there, there's a little surprise and
flavor. Now put the rest in there on
there.
Okay. And what do you put on the very
top again? Some more cheese. The same
layer. The same thing. a layer on top.
And I say more for the top because I I
like that that crust. And you know,
something like this is is great when
when your kids bring home their friends
and whatever. You put it in the oven.
So, how long do you leave it in the oven
for? Well, this is just about everything
is just about cooked. You can put a
little more. So, I would say about 20
minutes, 30 minutes. If you want to give
yourself more time, you put a foil paper
on top of it. Let it kind of get really
warm because you can prepare this and
leave it cool and you can prepare it and
almost leave it in the refrigerator when
you come home. Oh yes. You put the top
the cheese and put it in the oven. Let's
see if you like the taste. Would Would
your family like that taste is the
question? They will love it. They'll
love you.
They're going to love you, too. Thank
you very much. Everybody, Lydia's got a
new children's book out. Lydia's egg
sighting farm adventure pardon the bun.
help you and your family learn to cook
healthy at home just as we did today.
And guess what? Everyone in the audience
is going home with a copy of breakfast.
Oh, I got one for my That's for you and
your children and your grandma
granddaughter.
[Applause]
Next. Looking for a better way to battle
that belly bulge? Are you ready for a
strong and slender stomach? We have a
full body workout that will strengthen,
lengthen, and tighten your tummy. Easy
yoga moves to get the abs of your
dreams. Coming up next, all new odds.
And tackling one of your biggest
addictions, carbs. But your love affair
with bread and pasta doesn't have to
end. I'm excited about this cuz we've
got two really big new ideas. The plan
to eat carbs to beat carbs. Plus,
Dancing with the Stars judge Bruno Tony
breaks the newest celebrity health
trends. I'm turning myself off. Will it
be Bravo or Brav? No. All new odds.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
Yoga is known for its relaxation and
flexibility benefits, but it's also a
full body workout that strengthens and
lengthens and tightens your abs. So,
today, easy yoga moves to get the abs of
your dreams. Yoga instructor and fitness
guru Glenn Lawrence is here. So, revved
up yoga, how does it actually help with
b with the belly, the abs? Well,
arguably every move that you do in yoga
targets the abs. So, it's a no-brainer
that you pick yoga to flatten them out.
And how does it work for beginners
versus experts? It doesn't matter. We
picked some pretty user friendly moves
today, and I'm going to show you ways
that you can kick them up if you want
to. So, it doesn't really matter. Who
wants stronger, slender abdomen bellies
and stomachs? Ladies, come on out. We
have six volunteers from the audience.
Believe me, they're not experts. They're
just like you. Maybe there some of them
are experts. We're going to find out in
a second. But everyone start doing this
with us. Take it away. Simple moves to
get us revved up abs. All right. So, the
first one we're going to do is elbow to
knee pa. So, you're going to start in
what's called chair pose in yoga. Nice
flat back. You're going to bring the
hands behind your head and keeping the
back flat, you're going to tip it elbow
to knee. Come back to center. Elbow to
knee. Keep going. That's it. Smile.
Smile. If you're not having fun, it's
worthless, right? And I like I don't
like to do counting. I like to have a
timer. I'm notorious for my timer. So,
30 seconds to 2 minutes, depending on
your fitness level. Two minutes of this.
Oh, yeah.
How you guys doing back there? How is
it? Great. Good. All right. Right. You
feel that? That's that's going to target
our waist. Trim the waist and get in the
side into the obliques. All right. I
quit. All right. Let's go to the floor.
I quit for you guys, by the way. I'm
trying to help you.
So, everybody has a block. We're going
to lie down on our backs now. And you're
going to put the block between your
inner thighs, right? We're going to
raise the roof with our legs. Okay?
You're going to flex the feet. Arms are
down by your side. And all you're going
to do is tiny little moves. Lifting your
legs straight up, squeezing the block.
And again, you want to do 30 seconds to
two minutes. So, no counting. I want
folks at home doing this because I'll
tell you this little move is much more
impactful than I thought. Yeah. What
part of our belly is this workout? We're
we're working nice lower abdominals
which everyone's concerned about. And
putting the block between the inner
thighs gives us second benefit of adding
a little tone to the inner thighs.
Everybody's good. Same thing. 30
seconds, two minutes. All right.
Depending on your fitness. Look at this.
The sadistic smile. Yes. You know me.
That's it. So, we're going to keep the
block. Might as well just keep the
block. If you guys want to just rock
yourself up to seated. Keep the block
between your inner thighs. We're going
to go to boat pose. And this is going to
target the whole front of the stomach.
Now, all right. This is going to be
level one. Legs, lower legs parallel to
the floor. Level two and level three.
And all you're going to do is hold it.
Got to breathe. Squeeze the block. You
can feel it, right? If you shake, it's
good. We're going on a boat trip. It's
like a little trip. Level one or two.
30 seconds to two minutes. If it's too
easy for you, you can bring your arms
up. You can bring them course. Make it
worse. Make it worse. You can bring it
in and out. Bring it on. Maybe the pain
more pain. So, again, 30 seconds to 2
minutes of this will really tire you. Oh
gosh. They're always trying to sabotage
my timer when I'm working out. I
shouldn't have shown off. All right. All
right. And the last one, last one is
going to be a forearm plank. So, we're
going to come on to the hands and knees.
Lower down to your elbows. It's really
important that your elbows are under
your shoulders for proper support. So,
our bodies are made to fit ourselves.
You want to pivot the arms. Wrap your
fingers around your elbows. That way,
you know they're shoulder width apart.
If they're too far apart, you're going
to overstress the the chest. Okay. Bring
them out. Palms flat. He's already in
it. I I was copying. And then and then
go ahead and press trying to help. I
tell my belly is sore. I would not. Yes.
30 seconds to 2 minutes. Two minutes is
a super challenge here. You could always
just drop it down, take a break, and
come back up. But right before you quit,
give it another two breaths and then
come down. Baby, putting your knees down
is a sign of weakness, everybody. Oo.
All right, that's the challenge right
there. They're still holding. I'm going
to go to break with us. Keep holding it.
If you're at home, please do this with
us. Gren's book, Body Sculpting with
Yoga. It's in stores now. It's a
fabulous book. You can find more yoga
moves in the Everyday Yoga video series
at drought.com. Oh, help. I'm back. Stay
with me.
[Applause]
[Music]
How has yoga changed your life? I
started doing yoga 2 years ago and
wasn't a huge fan, but over time I began
to relish how it made me feel. Now I'm
fullon obsessed. I make all my friends
join in. Tell us on Facebook.com/d.
Next. Diagnosed with a terminal illness.
Dr. Oz is making a wish come true for a
very special 16-year-old girl. This
aspiring doctor gets the dream visit of
her life behind the scenes and in front
of the camera. Her inspiring day on the
set is next. We are bringing a healthy
back this season and want you to bring
it too. Grab your prescription pad for
fun and sign up for free tickets today.
You can go to dr.com/tick
and sign up. Did I get it right?
[Applause]
[Music]
In the six years I've been doing this
show, I've been lucky to meet some
pretty amazing people. But today, you're
about to meet someone who's not just
amazing, but inspiring. She touched my
heart. I found out about her from the
Makea-Wish Foundation. And when they
told me about her wish, well, I couldn't
say no. Take a look. Thank you so much
for granting my Make a Wish. I chose you
because I want to be a physician when I
get older. Your show is so entertaining
and educational at the same time. When I
was diagnosed with medula blasto in
August of 2013,
it changed my life forever. I couldn't
do things that other people got to do.
But now since I'm cancerree, I can
finally do those things. Thank you again
and see you soon.
Aubrey's Wish is one of 14,000 wishes
granted by the Makea-Wish Foundation
each year. And it's been a great honor
to spend the day with her. In fact, we
had a blast behind the scenes taping
another show earlier today.
How are you? Good. Can I give you a hug?
Such a great honor that you wanted to
come see the show. I got all kinds of
good stuff planned for you today. Ready
to go? Come on. First stop, a meet and
greet with my show guests.
being here. Then I took Aubrey to
rehearsal where she served as my standin
and helped me get ready for the show.
You okay? While I headed to hair and
makeup, Aubrey, who dreams of becoming a
doctor, got up close and personal with
some real human organs, compliments of
our medical team.
Finally, it was showtime. Get him. You
ready to go? Let's do it. Yog.
[Music]
Aubrey is still here and if she still
has the energy, I would love her to come
down and be my assistant of the day. Are
we come to come on down?
So, I know you were only supposed to
play backstage, but I was so proud to
have you here today. You okay? Yep. How
you feeling? Great. So, how was the show
backstage? It was really good. What did
you like the most about it? Um, probably
seeing the organs. You like those
organs, don't you? Yeah, I do. And you
want to be a surgeon, I understand.
Maybe more a doctor or physician, a
regular internist. Surgeon. And what do
you love about medicine? Um, I love
helping people, making them feel better.
And you know what that's like. So, you
told me you were fascinated by the
digestive system of the body. There's a
lot of things there. So, if you're
willing to do this, since you are the
assistant of the day, I'd like you to
help me share something with the
audience. All right. Okay. Now, I
customized this for you. Of course, you
have the purple gloves.
Don't forget those. They're pretty
important. And I did a little homework.
I was talking to your mom who's just a
doll, you know. And she shared with me
that you have a tremendous affinity for,
is this true? Pancakes and pizza. Yes.
No one's ever admitted that on the show
before. All right. So, we'll put the
pancakes in your mouth because this is
example of your digestive system. Here's
the pizza. Why don't you hold that for a
second? So, these are your teeth over
here. Okay. Right. So, the teeth are
like scissors. So, chop up that pizza in
your in your stomach over here. And I'll
work these little babies. All right. To
get going on this will be the teeth
there. And cut the pizza up. I need more
help with that. I can mash this with
these. These are my these are your mers.
I'm working. Do I put them here? You can
put them anywhere you want cuz they're
going to end up in your stomach, right?
No matter where you put them to start
with, once they're on your plate, at
least at your age, they pretty much end
up in your stomach. Okay, that's good.
Let's throw that in there. Now, add some
saliva. That's the raw ingredient we
need. Good. Add that in there. You can,
if you really like the food, you usually
salivate a lot. Yeah. Is that what
happens to you? Yeah. Oliv Oh, that was
a lot. All right. Now, you're really
salivating. Okay. Now, take what's in
your mouth and you got to put it in your
stomach. Yeah. So, remember when you
learned about this in biology? Go ahead
and pour that in there. When the food
goes in your stomach, you end up
releasing gastric juices like that. Oo.
Look like that. Yeah. Now, let's get our
hands in there. We got to work this up a
little bit cuz the stomach begins to
digest all this food. Oh, okay. Now,
where does it go from the stomach to the
small intestine? Very well done. Okay.
Let's empty it in there. That's good.
Empty the food in the small intestines.
Oh, it's a sloppy intestine. It's okay.
It can't be neat all the time. Keep
going. Okay. Now, once it's in your
small intestine, then it's got to get
pushed through the small intestine. And
here's where this crazy stuff happens.
Not all the food. Go. Let's milk it
through here. Push that in there and
milk it through. Not all the food gets
through. A lot of the food has to get
sucked into the bloodstream like down
below. And those nutrients, you broke
the intestine. You just broke the
intestine. No one has ever broke an
intestine before. This should all forget
about this. It's fine. So notice how the
juices are leaking into the bloodstream.
So the body sucks its nutrients out of
the small intestine as it's supposed to.
Keep going though because we know what
happens next. You can push it way in
there. Milk it all through here.
Whatever the body can't absorb into the
bloodstream, where does it go? Goes down
here into the colon. You know what's
coming, don't you? Yeah. Yeah. It's like
a boa constrictor this intestine. There
he goes. Now come down here. Once it's
in the colon, you've got to actually
milk it through. So go ahead and take
this. What's the major goal of the small
of the colon? It's to absorb fluid. So
any extra fluid that's in there gets
absorbed. Push that all the way down.
And then it goes to the rectum, which is
this bag. And guess what happens from
the rectum? It goes out. It goes out,
doesn't it? So go ahead and demonstrate.
Now it's too late to turn back now.
Your your classmates will see this
happen, but there it goes from the
correctum into the toilet. And she did
it perfectly and brilliantly done.
Did you ever have a dream that you'd be
squeezing poop into a toilet when you
made your Make a Wish Foundation dream?
No. Not at all. Yes. I hope I hear back
from them in a positive way about this.
That's good. You've gotten it all out of
there. Nicely done. Listen. Keep your
gloves on. Keep your gloves on. I want
to show you something else. This is
actually a real intestine. It was such a
blessing having you on the show. I
really want to have you take You can
take your gloves off. Uh put new ones
on. I want you to appreciate uh because
we didn't get to see this before how
magnificent the human body is. And when
I look at you and I see how wonderfully
you've done after a really bad problem,
I realize the marvels of medicine. And I
also realize how unique and special each
of our bodies are. So the intestinal
system is made up of these tiny little
nooks and crannies. And this is the
rectum. That's what you just squeeze the
poop out of. Right? This is your small
intestine. See how it's smaller? Go
ahead and feel that.
And as you look at that, and I show
these organs on the show because I think
the body is majestic. Yeah. And I think
we're all so special and we really
appreciate it when we look at our
organs, parts of our body that we don't
always see from the outside. Yeah, these
are cool. They are pretty cool, aren't
they? Yeah. So, I was thinking what kind
of a prize to give you, and I was going
to send you home with these intestines,
but your mom won't let you take them.
And because she says I'd killjoy your
mother, I instead decided to give you a
more orthodox. You can take these off uh
present. So, I'm giving you your own Dr.
Oz jacket.
Now, the you can take that off.
These we give very, very rarely on the
show.
And they're notice they have special
buttons. H they take a little bit of
wearing in, but you should wear this all
around school from now on. People will
be very intimidated by you. And I want
you to have your own pair of Dr. Oz
scrubs. But most importantly,
since you're going to be a doctor, I
want you to have your stethoscope on and
listen to the hearts of all the people
you're going to touch in your life. So,
take care. We'll be right back.
Did you hear it?
All new odds. And tackling one of your
biggest addictions, carbs. But your love
affair with bread and pasta doesn't have
to end. I'm excited about this because
we've got two really big new ideas. The
plan to eat carbs to beat carbs. Plus,
Dancing with the Stars judge Bruno Tony
breaks the newest celebrity health
trends. I'm turning myself off. Will it
be Bravo or Brav No. All new Oz. That's
coming up tomorrow.
All new Oz. And tackling one of your
biggest addictions, carbs. But your love
affair with bread and pasta doesn't have
to end. I'm excited about this cuz we've
got two really big new ideas. The plan
to eat carbs to beat carbs. Plus,
Dancing with the Stars judge Bruno Tony
breaks the newest celebrity health
trends. I'm turning myself off. Will it
be Bravo or Brav? No. All new Oz. That's
coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
[Applause]
I have a terrible fear of heights. And
since I'm always telling you to step out
of your comfort zone, I decided to
finally step out of mine and face my
fear. So, I went on an adventure. My
team has prepared a surprise for me.
They have chronicled this adventure on
this little video. Let's take a look at
what they did. I don't like heights, but
other than that, I'm good to go.
[Music]
It doesn't look too bad, does it? I can
tell you it was much faster. They must
have slowed that down. I went whipping
across this thing. That's a video of me
ziplining at the Mall of America in
Minneapolis. And it was much I thought
scarier than it looks. Anyway, you can
watch me. There's a version of that, a
scarier version I'm going to make for
facebook.com/docraz
and share the fear you're ready to
conquer on my page so I can celebrate
with you. We could all do it together.
Now, it's time for in case you missed
it. First up, the newest cast member of
Real Housewives of Atlantic, Claudia
Jordan. She showed us because I was on
the show today that there's something
that annoys her even more than her
fellow housewives. the corns on her
feet. Now, she's lived with these for
years, and I'm offering her some help.
Now, we all know that salicylic acid
works. It comes in little patches. You
can put them on the corn, but here's a
special foot bath that could also help.
I hear this from a lot of viewers. You
soak your feet for 15 minutes in warm
soapy water, but you got to add a cup of
apple cider vinegar to it. Then, use a
pummus stone to gently, gently is the
operative word here, remove layers of
dead skin. Then, dab on some castor oil
after you've taken your foot out and
stride. Just take a little bit of the
cotton swab, just dab it on there. And
over the course of about 10 days, those
corns will get much better. Finally,
please be careful of dubious people
online that make it seem like I'm
endorsing their products because I
don't. To see a full list of our trusted
sponsors and partners, you go to dr.com.
And I'll see you next time.
[Music]
[Applause]