[Applause]
gas, bloat, constipation. Sometimes it
seems like no matter what you try, you
can never make the stomach pain fully go
away. That was the case with Christina.
She recently came on to our show into
the truth tube and asked for help. Now
she's back. Let's take a look at how
she's been doing
time.
Remember school teacher Christina? She
was constantly constipated.
None of the things I've tried have
worked.
So he called in specialist Dr. Amy
Meyers to help. She's a gut flush that
everyone can use to take back their
digestive health.
Definitely excited for this.
You will keep a poop journal for us.
Yes. Yes, I will.
So, how's Christina doing today?
When I left the show, I started the
recommended detox by eliminating dairy,
gluten, soy, corn. I was given a list of
foods that I was allowed to eat.
Spinach, um, kale, there was fruits,
different proteins. At first, nothing
was happening, but by the end of week
two, I was hopeful. Today is day one,
and I went with no trouble. Day two, and
I went. And for five straight days,
things were great. I was able to go.
Yay.
But then everything stopped.
Unfortunately, today hasn't been my day.
I'm not giving up, though. I think part
of my problem is is that my diet is
getting repetitive. the foods are not
changing and it's the same thing over
and over again. So, I'm looking for
different foods that I can incorporate
into my diet. I don't want to get backed
up again. I know I can do this.
Let's get straight to the truth, too,
because we have some good news to report
on Christina. Now, before the show, uh,
and before you started getting a little
help from us, you told us you're having
roughly two bowel movements a week,
right?
Sometimes even less.
Yes. Unfortunately.
Unfortunately, which is never a pleasant
feeling to have. No.
Your bowel movements since the show on
average
four times a week.
I think it's fabulous. Yeah.
How's that feel?
Very good. Very good. Relieved, happy,
excited.
So, it helps with a little bit of this
stuff. So, the good news is you're
pooping, which I'm very happy about. So,
I think that part of it was the things
we talked about in the last show, but
you might have a problem that a lot of
Americans have right now that we don't
talk about much in Western medicine.
Okay.
But people who do functional medicine,
look at the root causes for problems.
Dr. Myers does this.
They have other tests they can do. So
they sent the test off. It's a
comprehensive stool test.
Mhm.
And they came back with a absolutely
fascinating finding.
Okay.
You have candida and bacterial
overgrowth.
Okay.
In your poop.
So there are things growing in there
that aren't supposed to be grown in
there.
Okay.
So I want to try to address that today.
And I also want to address your concern
about the fact that you're eating the
same food all the time and you want some
diversity in diet. If I do those two
things, we'd be smiling and happy.
Yes. Maybe even poop more.
Yes.
All right. So, uh, I have been
searching, searching, and I think I have
the answers. And Dr. Myers is here to
join us. She's going to walk us through
her gut flush food rules. These can help
anybody, by the way. Anybody who's got
constipation or bloating, all these
things can help you with all of them.
But we're going to help you in
particular, right? Come on over.
Even better,
Dr. Myers, how are you?
Hi. Good. Good to see you.
Ye, you can stay in the middle.
I thought you were going to stay in the
middle.
Were you running away?
No, definitely not.
You have to go to the bathroom.
No.
Okay. Just asking. It's possible. All
right. So this this issue of yeast
overgrowth is a big one. It does cause
problems for folks. It's something that
again we don't acknowledge as widely. Uh
but in functional medicine is pretty
popular.
I see it in virtually almost all of my
patients and a lot of them complaining
of the symptoms that you came in with
with the gas and the bloating and the
constipation.
So the first food rule is to drink an
anti-inflammatory ginger root tea. If
you don't mind explain what this is
everybody, why it works and how we would
make it.
Yeah. So ginger is very
anti-inflammatory. Here we're mostly
going to be using some ginger. Boil it
up. Add a little lemon for flavor and
some mint to top it off.
Interesting.
Give it a taste. See if you like it.
It's pretty straightforward. It's sort
of what you might expect, but without
the sugar in it. And it's again the
first of several steps we're going to
give you, but this needs to become so
you'll tolerate that and it's different
from what you had. Okay. This next step
is important. It's going to address the
issue of variability in what you're
eating, but also help us with the
candida and bacterial overgrowth. That's
to get 50 grams of fiber. But we want
the fiber to come from vegetable
sources, not from grains.
Okay.
Please explain why that's so important.
So these types of of vegetables which
are your cruciferous vegetables actually
contain sulfur and nitrogen which help
to fight the yeast. Okay?
So that's going to be the most helpful
part. And then we don't want to be
eating the grains particularly gluten
because that easily converts to sugar
which is what candida and the bacterial
overgrowth are going to be feeding on.
Okay?
Right. So these are several examples.
And if you're bored by these we have
bigger problems.
These look these are some of my three
favorite recipes that we have. The first
one is a cabbage, spicy cabbage, kale,
and sweet onion salad. And there's a lot
of anti-inflammatory ginger and curcumin
spices and herbs in there as well.
Oh, that's really good.
Is it good?
Surprisingly good.
Yeah, it's amazing. Okay, this is one of
my favorite. I eat this almost every
week. This is cherry roasted Brussels
sprouts.
Um, those are actually my new favorite
lately, so I'm excited to
You like Brussels sprouts now? Oh, I
like that.
Yeah, I had some last night for dinner.
They were amazing.
That's uh we have a soup also.
Yeah, we have a broccoli and kale soup
which is super quick. Great on a cold
day like it is outside right now. And
you know, you can just put it in the
thermos, take it with you to work. It's
delicious.
Okay,
so that's sort of the one big area.
Again, it's more fiber than I normally
recommend. We normally say get 25 to 30.
You're about 25 now. We're asking you
just for you to go up a little higher.
But for everybody, we're saying make
most of that fiber not from grains, but
from vegetables. Okay. Next big issue is
to cook with coconut. This is a big gut
flush rule. Why is that?
So coconut is very antifungal, has
antiviral properties as well, but
there's something in it called caprillic
acid, which specifically goes in and
pokes holes in the yeast cell wall and
is going to help kill that yeast that
you have. Um, coconut you can use in all
different types of of forms and the oil
and the milk, shredded coconut. So I
love this shrimp. It is cooked in
coconut oil and then also has the
coconut flakes on top of it. So it's a
coconut shrimp. And this is another one
of my favorites I eat almost every week,
which is chicken pod thai, but we do it
with spaghetti squash instead of pasta.
And you really cannot even tell the
difference. And it is delicious.
That got the audience excited.
Yeah, it's really good.
And then the last little bit here is a
ritual you and I are going to get into
and anyone else who's having issues with
this. It's a detox shot after dinner. So
here's your shot.
I want you to drink the shot before Dr.
Myers explains it. So as we're drinking,
please pray to explain it.
Okay. So, we are squeezing uh the juice
of of a of some garlic and then that
good, huh?
Are your eyes watering, too?
I felt it was good.
Okay. Hard for me to explain with those
expressions.
Definitely recommend that one.
Try to blow the air out of my ears.
I was going to say, is it killing off
everything in your body? It's really
good. Cold and flu season's coming up.
So, this is good for everybody, not just
people suffering from candy. You survive
the shot. The bacteria and viruses
won't.
So, what's in here? You just
I can smell the garlic. So, it's a
garlic. It's about a tablespoon of
garlic. It has uh squeezed a half a
lemon and then a drop of oil of oregano.
Listen, you're well on your way here.
You're going you're going almost every
other day, which means no longer of much
of a concern to me. I want you to be
more regular.
Uh not just going every day, but also
knowing you're going to go every day.
It'll take a big load off your mind and
your intestines.
Yes.
And I think these will get you there.
Plus, what Dr. Myers walked us through
and walked everyone do today is
something you can do every single day of
your life and mix it up so darn much,
except for the shot here, which is still
poisoning me.
Oh, I know.
Easy to include. I know. All these
recipes, they're on dr.com. You are more
than welcome.
Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good