[Applause]
After being diagnosed with terminal
cancer nearly two years ago, Valerie
Harper continues to defy all odds,
maintaining a positive and inspiring
outlook on life. In January 2013,
Valerie Harper stunned the world with
news that she was terminally ill.
Doctors telling her she had only 3
months left to live.
The actress best known for playing Roda
on TV had been diagnosed with an
incurable form of lung cancer that
spread to her brain.
>> I thought, okay, I have it. How bad is
it? What's the fight game plan to fight
this? We don't have to choose negative.
You can choose positive. And that's what
I did with cancer.
Now nearly 2 years later, Valerie is
still going strong, studying her doctors
and defying the odds by tapping into
what experts call the mindbody
connection. What is it and how does it
work? Valerie Harper knows.
[Music]
[Applause]
Her spirit is truly infectious. I'm glad
to welcome Valerie Harper.
[Music]
[Applause]
Darling, it's so good to see you. Oh,
God.
Thank you. And I'll be careful. And I'll
be careful.
>> No falling down.
>> I got to say, it's a dream for me to
have you come on. When I heard the news,
and by the way, the diagnosis Valerie
had would give her three months to live.
Three months. Now, it's almost two years
later. I never thought I'd see you
again.
>> I know. Why do you think it wasn't your
time?
>> I'm not sure. I do not know. And when
someone's time is up, I guess it is. I
mean, I could walk out of here and get
hit by a bus, but the hopefully not, but
but
>> mob by an audience.
>> A that's so sweet. They are. They're
wonderful. And I I've watched you so
constantly.
>> They're such a part of the show, Doc. I
love that. Um, I think I have a crack
team, an unbelievable doctors,
oncologists. Also, I'm doing acupuncture
and I'm taking herbal tea. Then I have a
husband who gets me out there
exercising. So, I'm doing all the good
things you should do anyway and then
taking my pills diligently.
>> Where do you find the strength when when
someone faces a bad outcome? And we in
all our lives are going to face these
kinds of conversations.
>> Where do you go for strength?
>> Well, the truth is that we're all facing
death. It's there. I I hate to break it
to you, but that's
>> right.
>> Yeah. It really just key is don't go to
the funeral till the day of the funeral,
>> honestly, because it's so wise.
>> It really is.
>> Yeah. And I I I I just have kept a open
mind and and I also recently uh realized
with this cancer uh diagnosis that every
moment that you spend in fear and
sometimes you have to be because you're
terrified and you're in pain or whatever
it is, every moment that you sit there
in fear, letting stress and fear take
over, you have forfeited that moment
that could be filled with joy.
>> Yeah. So, so why
>> I I really think it's true. So, I I've
been kind of doing that. I've been
trying to
>> I was struck by some of the comments you
made on visualization that you see
yourself kicking cancer's butt. Kicking
cancer out of your body. Right.
>> Exactly.
>> Describe what that's like.
>> Well, that was the other part. I didn't
get to it. That I I was going to Yeah,
imagery is very important. And it's a
actor's stock and trade. I mean, that's
what we do. We make up stuff and pretend
we're someone else. So all you have to
do is imagine and I imagine myself as
Tinkerbell maybe in a golden gown and um
I just say are you going to stay or are
you going to leave and these little
cancer guys are there and I say if you
don't I'm ridding you. So I Tinkerbell
or Valerie touches the little guy and he
disappears into white light. That's one
of my big images.
>> You know when I sit here next to you I I
don't see cancer at all. I see life.
Real life. Life is meant to be. I do.
>> I would love if you could share some of
these insights, the practical elements
of them with our audience. And this is
true. You could have a very bad cancer
of the brain that spread from your lung.
>> Yes.
>> Or it could be high blood pressure or
something pretty minor. But these mind
over matter issues. You're living proof
of it are important.
>> Oh, they're it's crucial, I think,
because really there are are cells. I
know there are people that say it's not.
It's an invader. Um, but there are cells
going haywire. So maybe we have more
power over it than we really realize. So
>> So I brought you a little I brought you
a little homework right now. I we had
Valerie do this exercise for her, but I
want you all to do this at home as well.
Straightforward. I want you to take a
piece of paper and split it down the
middle. And this is from somebody. This
is not from Valerie. On one side of it,
you're going to think of, in this case,
your cancer, right? Your current health
battle, whatever it might be, diabetes,
you know, headaches, whatever it might
be. uh how you are and what that enemy
is doing to you. Draw yourself against
the battle. So I look at these images
and I see someone who's got some
negative things going on, negative
mindset. They got the cancer is this big
scary monster and
>> look at the arms.
>> Yeah, the arms are big and strong and
you're just unhappy and a victim to it.
And can I show you all Valerie's?
>> Okay, go ahead and describe this.
>> I think it's pretty good.
>> Well, he's a little fable guy and he's
weak and he's doing Yeah. and he's
sneaking around and they and and they go
on tour like in show business they do
they want to do encors they want to have
a return engagement and then they go on
tour to other parts of your body so I
see him as you know kind of a sad guy
that isn't wanted and I'm happy I am a
happy person
[Applause]
>> so I asked a leading researcher yeah
you're winning
>> so far
>> I'd love to invite a leading researcher
in the field of integrative oncology to
join us please welcome Dr. Kelly Turner.
She's interviewed so many people
>> who have kept the positive attitude in
the face of cancer.
>> Oh yes.
>> You know, you've got a lot of
experience, maybe more than anyone else
in this area. Do these images surprise
you? From someone who's fearful and
losing the battle potentially to someone
who's upbeat and maybe winning the
battle.
>> They don't surprise me at all. I've
studied thousands of people who've
beaten the odds against cancer. And one
of the things that they have in common
is taking control of their health. So
for example, many of them are told by
their doctors, there's a 99% chance you
won't be alive in 3 months.
>> But the people that I study, people like
Valerie, respond by saying, I'm going to
be that 1%.
>> Val, you've uh very kindly started
working with the American Lung
Association. This is a great program.
>> Yeah. It's a new women's group and we
have to do this called Lung Force. Uh
give advice to all the women out there
who don't know much about lung disease,
in particular lung cancer.
>> Oh, you must join us. The truth is
there's a huge gap between how women
most women feel about lung cancer. It's
not on the top of their radar or
something to be a risk or anything to
worry about. Breast cancer maybe or
other kinds of cancer. It is the number
one killer cancer killer of women
>> and 1% of the survey said they even
think about it. So that's really bad
statistics and women don't know how big
a threat lung cancer is to them and to
men. I think it kills
>> also number one for men.
>> Num number one for for both
>> and many of them are non-smokers.
>> I'm not a smoker. I never smoked a day
in my life and I got the disease. Here's
the thing. If you have lungs, you're in
line for lung cancer. That's just the
way it is. And I don't mean for you to
sit in fear and go uh it's just get to
get get some kind of screening uh and it
it gets it I I as a doctor well knows if
it gets to force stage because it's well
it's mushy right it's not like bone
>> it goes on tour as you mentioned I I've
loved having you having goals also helps
folks I would love you to come back and
visit in a year
>> and every year
>> you're so sweet
>> keep that goal stay healthy
>> thank you for watching don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good