[Music]
Wipe on, wipe off. Just how many germs
are you really getting rid of? You're
going to be so stunned. We've got the
dirty truth on disinfectant wipes.
And I investigate disposable wipes. Wish
you guys would smell this right now.
They may be flushed, but they're not
forgotten. They're not decomposible.
Correct. And that's causing us big
issues. Plus, just how safe is your home
hair dye? Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you, Becca.
[Music]
Today, we are testing all the wipes that
have become a sanitary staple in our
house. From the ones you use on your
body to the disinfecting wipes you clean
with. So, in the name of science, we're
going to make the ultimate mess to find
out how well these wipes work to get rid
of germs. Come on, Kisia. Come on,
honey. Come on. We'll go to the kitchen.
We'll cut up some raw chicken. We'll
even
sneeze on countertops. We're going to
make the ultimate mess.
Don't worry, I'm not going to tell Lisa.
Lisa is not going to know that you did
this or me.
We are still making a big mess over in
our germ lab because today we're
investigating the dirty truth about
disinfecting wipes. Almost all of us
trust these wipes to keep our house
clean from the nasty germs that are
being passed around this time of year.
But how many germs are you really
getting rid of with one wipe? To help
reveal what we've uncovered is emergency
room physician Dr. Samson Davis back
with all the insights. Thanks for being
here. Thank you. Thank you. So, these
disinfecting wipes aren't just being
used in homes. They're in gyms, right?
Right? They're in grocery stores. Every
in hospitals we have to use them
frequently. And how many of you be
honest? Take it out. It's so convenient.
Right. Quick little wipe down here. You
toss it. Right. Hands up. How many do
that? Right. Most people. That's what I
did until today. But Dr. Samson, you
have informed me that we're doing it all
wrong. At least most of us are. Yeah. It
seems simple, right? You figure you wipe
the areas clean, but cleaning the
surface area and disinfecting the
surface areas is totally two different
things. So, it's important to read the
label to see how long the surface area
must remain wet or moisturized by the
disinfectant wipe. If you just simply
clean it, you may be spreading the
bacteria and the germs versus
disinfecting the surface. So, it's a
difference between cleaning and
disinfecting. Can you imagine that,
guys? You're going to be so stunned when
we're done today cuz we're going to
share with all the But first, let's get
into what's in these wipes. Talking
about the biggest mistakes uh today, but
let's start off with what the heck is in
there that makes them work. So, this is
exciting for me. This is all science
here. So we have water obviously which
is the main ingredient. We have an agent
called sodium C1417 and it helps to bind
all the substance together. We have the
the essential oils for fragrance and
smell. The preservatives which help to
prevent the bacteria and the mold from
accumulating in the wipes and the
glycolic acid which is organic substance
which helps to um make the area smooth.
So how effective are these chemicals in
getting rid of the germs? I mean how
this touch the germ is it enough? It's
well, it's effective in in use in
ridding the germ, but you have to make
sure you use it for the right amount of
time. Wipe the surface for the right
amount of time because if you don't,
then it's not as effective. And we also
find that it could be uh it can if you
use them or overuse, you can create
superbugs, resistance to superbugs by
killing that sort of natural good
bacteria. So, the big question is, are
you using them the right way? Are you
getting rid of the number of germs that
you think you are? To find out, we set
up a germ lab experiment, right? With
the most common germs and bacteria that
you worry about. Take a look at the mess
we created earlier. This is this is our
show, people, right? These tiles were on
the floor in front of me. Look,
someone's chopping up chicken there,
right? And there's raw chicken
everywhere. All potential germs. There's
a dog playing. How cute as he may be.
Then someone was dropping some breakfast
crumbs all over it and then wiping their
hands on the I just saw a coffin there.
I know I did. You're all guilty as I am
sometimes of trying to get away with
that. And I've got Jill here who's going
to sort of represent what most of us,
including yours truly, normally used to
do before today. When you watch that
video, do you shudder? Yeah, it looks
really messy and germy. Yes. I mean,
it's worth cleaning that, right? Yeah,
absolutely. So, you like disinfecting a
lot, I'm told. Yes. So, you took a This
is a little experiment, right? We wanted
to find out how much Jill would be
effective in removing germs because
she's a germ a phobe. Yeah. And we've
got the doc here, Dr. Samson's method is
a little bit more sophisticated. We're
going to reveal the results. Are you all
into this? Yeah. All right. Now, before
the germ score is revealed, I want to
first show you how contaminated, how
dirty these tiles were after you made
those messes. So, Dr. Samson, how messed
up were these plates? These tiles? Oh,
they were they were a mess. They were
pretty junky and and just contaminated
with all types of uh debris. And the
score was And the score for uh for
Jill's was uh 2859. Now, yours wasn't
much better, by the way. 25.89. Just so
you don't penalize her unfairly, right?
And that's the dirty version, by the
way, of pretty much all of these.
They're in that same range. So 2,500.
Remember that number. The Jill, please
demonstrate, if you don't mind, how you
would normally clean up a tile. Go
ahead. All right. Okay. Take it out.
Walk us through this. You open it up.
Yeah. It's wet, right? Yeah, it is.
Okay. Cuz sometimes they're dry, guys,
and that doesn't count. And then I just
Yeah. Wipe S motion. And it's so fast,
so easy, right? S motion. That's nicely
done. I like the boot, the bounce to it.
It's good. It's like a DJ, right? Going
through it. All right. And it looks
pretty clean. I think it looks pretty
nice, actually. And this is the after
version of yours. Dr. Davis wasn't so
convinced. So, he picked as he is, got
out one of those germ machines. And what
was her number after her wipe? So, her
number wasn't bad. It was 149 after her
wipe. Well, that's a lot better than it
used to be. Yeah. Right. I think so.
Yeah. You happy with that score? I mean,
it's not perfect. So, I guess what can
we do more of, Dr. Davis? So using your
method before we get to what it is just
show her what she could have had. So it
it could have been better. It could have
you could have had 37 actually which is
a major improvement almost you know half
or more than half of what it would have
been. So important thing was you did the
right thing. You cleaned the surface
area which which all of us do but we
find that soap and water good old soap
and water never fails us. So we clean
with that first allow it to dry. Then we
use a disinfectant wipe to clean. But
it's very important that you follow the
instructions because what we think is
one wipe and done. But you sometimes you
have to go as far as four to 10 minutes.
So you have to make sure that surface
area stays wet and moisturized and you
may have to use more than one wipe. I'm
going to show you the video of Dr. Davis
doing it the right way. The hard work
backstage. And as you watch this, like
he followed the instructions on the back
of the package. Look how fast he is,
right? But the instructions actually
tell you to do this. It's tiny print.
You've all ignored it till now. But it
says you've got to keep going. It's got
to stay wet. So you don't have to rub it
continually for four minutes, but if it
dries out after 30 seconds, you got to
go back and wet it again and do with a
different wipe. Absolutely. So what do
you think? Could this change your
approach to saying clean? Absolutely.
I'm, you know, all about getting rid of
all the germs. So I got to read the
labels more and figure it out, right? My
takeaway was I probably can't get away
with just one wipe. I probably need to
use a second wipe after it's started to
dry just to make sure I'm getting the
effect. So I get rid of truly the germs
and I get rid of all the junk on top of
it. Other than being thorough with the
wipes, what other strategies do you
recommend to the viewers? So, storage is
very important. Uh, storage of the wipes
of the wipes. Very, very important. You
want to make sure you store at room
temperature. Sometimes we keep our wipes
in our car. We keep some all over the
place and if it's placed in extreme heat
or extreme cold, what happens is you
destroy the preservatives and you may
get fold mold. You may get vac
you'd be actually infecting the surface.
Oh no, Joe. You could have hurt
somebody. Darn it.
So, very important that you store it the
correct way and use it. And also, if you
have like microabbrasions or uh little
uh tears on your skin, just want to make
sure you're not sensitive to the wipes
as well. You may want to use a glove or
something to protect the skin. I stored
these at the perfect temperature for
you. It's a gift from the show. It's the
literally the least I could do. Thank
you so much. Now, now that we're done
this, up next, what about the wipes for
your body? Right from your hands to your
backside. Let's be clear about this,
right? We're testing them all out. So
you don't have to stick with us.
[Applause]
Is alkaline water the latest hydration
hype? When did something so simple as
water get so complicated? We investigate
the health claims. But what are the real
benefits and won't water down the truth?
We're about to reveal those results in
our first ever water experiment. Plus,
Tony Robbins is here sharing the number
one thing holding you back from success.
I want to show people a little shortcut
that'll give you momentum immediately
and give you power. All new eyes.
That's coming up on Monday.
[Music]
Today we've been investigating the dirty
truth about the wipes you've been using
to clean everything from your hands.
Yes. To your backside. Is it better to
wipe or to wash? We tested it out so you
don't have to. Here to help is Lorie
Jennings, director of the Good
Housekeeping Institute, along with ER
doctor Samson Davis. How did wipes
become such a huge part of our culture?
Why is it a new trend in hygiene? Oh my
gosh, they are just so convenient. I
mean, at the end of the day, you can
literally pull it out and you're good to
go. No sink, nothing else required. It's
fast, it's easy, it's very portable.
Yeah. Look at the And we're going to do
this together now. We're going to look
at the most popular body wipes and try
to figure this out. We're going to start
with hand sanitizers, which so many of
you are in love with. Before the show, I
asked my audience coordinator Stephanie
very innocently to shake every single
person's hand who came to watch today
the show today. Aren't they so cute?
Stephanie, aren't they the smartest,
friendliest audience in television? You
know it.
It would seem so. However, you shake
that many hands, you tend to pick up
germs. So, Dr. Davis, the germ score,
Stephanie has two hands. They were both
about the same. What was her germ score
number? So, Stephanie germ score was
659. It's all your fault, audience.
She's generally a clean-handed person.
Right now, backstage, Stephanie wiped
down one hand with the wipes. In the
other hand, she's used so soap and
water. Right. We took the germ score of
each hand separately. It is time to
reveal which hand is less germy. In
other words, if you shake someone's
hand, which tactic is more effective?
The germ score with soap and water was
214 and with the wipe 18. Wow. Who would
have thought?
Who would have thought? I'm actually
surprised. I would I'm a big soap and
water guy. I get the convenience of the
wipes, but they do seem I guess if you
do them right, they work, you know. What
should you be concerned about if you're
using wipes all the time? Well, I mean,
one of the things that people worry
about is dryness. So, if you're using
them a lot, you might want to look for
for ingredients that are moisturizing
like aloe or vitamin E. Obviously, water
is the first ingredient, but beyond
that, moisturizing ingredients. All
right, you all clear with hands now?
Now, let's move to what you really want
to hear about. All right, we've all seen
these wipes over here, right? These
wipes that you got in your bathrooms all
across the country. Flushable. They
called flushable bathroom wipes. Lori,
what happened to paper? When did that
stop doing the job? I mean, for most of
our history, paper was just fine. Well,
and you know what? Paper is still just
fine. And in fact, over 70% of our
audience still use paper. That said, for
those who like the flushable wipes, they
like the feeling of cleanliness. They
like the feeling that there's no dry
residue that that is left behind. They
feel like they're more hygienic. There's
no dry residue. I can just imagine that
crustiness. No paper. No paper left
behind. So, Dr. Sam, no paper, you're an
ER doctor. You take care of people with
all kinds of problems. People are
extraordinarily passionate about these
wipes, but health-wise, are they in our
best interest? They're I mean, there's
no difference. Uh well actually toilet
paper is still the best. It's the best.
TP works all the time. Works magic. Uh I
get the comfort and convenience that
people like to use them because they're
close to the hand. You can grab them. Uh
but it's very important to just stay
with what works, which is, you know,
toilet paper. But also sometimes with
the toilet paper, if it is too rough, it
can cause micro cuts or microabbrasions
as well. So you want to find the right
TP that works for you. I have been an
advocate advocate of using moisture, but
I never wanted to push wipes on folks.
I'll tell you why. This is a photo
recently of a scuba diver getting ready
to dive into the sewer system to unclog
it in North Carolina. And this, my
friends, is what he pulled out. This
poor soul. Look at all that junk. All
that used disposable flushable wipes.
So, the fact it turns out you can flush
them, but they may not go where you
want. What happens when you flush them
down? You have any idea? Well, yeah. I
mean, they accumulate. So sometimes they
can clog your sewer system and they
accumulate the bio is they're
biodegradable but they don't break down
as fast as we think they do. I wanted to
figure this out myself. I wanted to find
out what really happens literally to
follow the wipes down your toilet. So
take a look as I did just that.
Millions of you and I include myself in
this are confidently flushing these
wipes down the toilet and thinking all
is well. But is it? I decided to follow
the trail and it turns out that our
little wipes are causing some big
problems for waste and sewage facilities
like this one all around the country.
So, let's dig a little deeper. Follow
me. In the New York City area, most
wipes travel through 7,500 miles of
pipes to end up getting processed here
at the New Town Creek Wastewater
Treatment Plant. Manager Jim Penn agreed
to give me a closer look. Let me take
you down to the belly of the beast.
There's a smell down there. Well, let's
suit up. We'll see what you think.
I wish you guys could smell this right
now. Whoa.
What is that? Smells terrible. Well, Dr.
Oz, that's the sewage coming in from all
parts of the city. And what what are
these? These are the baby wipes. This is
how the material is coming to us, and
it's causing us big issues. So, where do
you get collected those wipes? Well,
come on. Let me show you. I'll show you
where the process begins.
[Music]
Those are the wipes. Toilet paper breaks
down. You're actually seeing the wipes
in their solid form just the way they
came from the toilet. I can't believe
that. Dr. Oz, take a guess on how many
of these we get into the system every
day. I'm seeing a thousand here already.
It's tens of thousands on a daily basis.
Dr. Oz, since you're one of the people
that are putting these down the system,
I'm going to put you to work. Let's go
upstairs and I'll show you where they're
collected. I can't wait.
Here comes some more. Dr. Oz. Okay.
Jeez. I'm working my tail off just so
you keep your tail clean. This is
exactly what I use. This is what I
flushed down the toilet. Why do they
call them flushable? Well, you know,
they are flushable, but they're not
breaking down. Toilet paper breaks down
on its way to the treatment plant. You
wouldn't see any of this material if it
was all toilet paper. So, they're
flushable, but they're not decomposible.
Correct. And where does it go from here?
Well, we take it and we load it into
dumpsters. Let's go and suit up. Suit
up. Go big or go home.
Dr. Ros, take a look.
Well, look, let's not stand there. Let's
get in there.
[Music]
After seeing all these wipes, I'm
officially switching back to toilet
paper. Yeah.
Audience, are you surprised about that?
What do you think about that? That's
just disgusting. Everyone agree? Yes, we
can do better. So, I got an idea. It's
going to change toilet habits all over
America. Dr. Davis, if you really want
that cleaner feel, is there a better way
that won't clog our toilets? Yes. You
have the toilet paper and a nice water
spray bottle here. You just fold it
once, by the way. Go. And then you just
spray away. And there you have it. Not
too much water. Not too much water. And
there you have it, guys. It's so simple.
And this is disposable. Simple. And this
is uh what are these? 15 cents. Nothing.
You all got it, guys. You knew this. Who
wants this?
So many gifts today. Thank you, Dr.
Davis. Lori, thank you very much. Be
right back.
[Applause]
Up next, an investigation into hair
dyes. Is there lead in your boxed home
hair dye? Find out what we uncovered
about the government's new warning.
[Music]
[Applause]
Today, an investigation into something
that millions of you use to color your
hair at home. Boxed hair dye. It's the
easy, inexpensive way to cover your gray
and to get the color that you love. You
know, you you know the exact box shade
you can get the job done in the comfort
of your own home. It's private. But a
recent national health alert caught my
attention. Lead acetate found in some of
these home hair dyes is a problem. Could
they be the ones that you use? And are
there safer hair dyes you should be
trying? Now, Ken Carl joins us now.
There's a lot of consumer fear out
there, especially since so many of you
are using these products. Dr. Carl's
going to walk us through the facts as we
know them. First off, lead acetate is
used as a color additive. Why? What does
it mean? Right. So, lead acetate really
has been used as a color additive in
certain hair dyes, especially the ones
that are applied over time. Um, what
that does is it creates a gradual
coloring effect. And those types of hair
dyes, that gradual effect, we often
think of as progressive hair dyes.
That's what we call them. That, right?
Second, FDA considers it no longer safe.
That's a big deal. How was this
concluded? Well, it is a big deal
because in the 1980s, you know, lead
acetate was listed as safe to use as a
color additive. Um, this is no longer
the case. The FDA has looked at a lot of
information over a lot of years,
scientific data, etc., and said, again,
this is not necessarily true anymore.
And in fact, exposure to lead acetate is
no longer thought to be insignificant.
And third, importantly, multiple brands
have already done the right thing and
removed it. That's right. And that's
it's a great thing from my perspective.
Um, yeah, a lot of brands have actually
started using other ingredients as color
additives, but there are still a few
that actually do use lead acetate. It's
important for us to remember that
manufacturers have at least a year after
the effective date of final rule to
remove lead acetate from their their
products. So, we have to keep that in
mind. But the guys decide now. Companies
actually did the right thing. Reward
them. Don't reward the guys who didn't
do the right thing. It cost money to do
the right thing. I know many of you
still have questions about hair dyes,
especially did it at home. Mariana is
here. How long have you been dying your
hair at home? I started.
Yeah. There. Thanks for speaking about
this. Yeah. Well, I started dying my
hair um in art school with all the funky
colors like purples, the blues here. Um
Yeah, we got a little blue here. I see
that. Yep. Um you know, a little bit
more rebellious at the time. And then I
started like lighter trends, lightening
up here um you know as I got older and
then now I'm covering up um the new
grays that are sprouting. So but after
this many years I don't know what that's
done to my hair overall long term or to
my health. Well I I see you're we have
photographic evidence of her obsession
with hair color and you're concerned
about health which is the main reason we
wanted to get into this. You know what
should be be telling people about the
hair dyes? Well make sure by way you got
to make sure that everyone understands
this really clearly. What do you look
for in the box? Right? And and that's
the biggest thing is what we look for on
that box. This is the time to be a smart
consumer. You want to look at that box
and obviously look for the words lead
acetate in the ingredients. But you
know, look, if that seems too confusing
or overwhelming or you can't find it,
look for a warning label. The FDA says
that if a hair dye contains lead
acetate, it should also contain a
warning label. So, just look for that
kind of big that big label that really
should be present. So, Mariana, just
between me and you and a couple million
people, what's the next hair color for
you? Um, probably going with a rose
gold. Rose gold. And now you know what
to look for in the box. Thank you,
Mariana. Thank you. Next, Melissa's
here. She says she swears by box hair
color. How long you been using them for?
Since I was 13. Oh, wow. 13. So, two
years now. Right. Yes, I would. Trying
to be helpful. A question you have about
at home hair dyes would be, would there
be a safer option?
I think that's a really great question,
and I think I think that's something
that we should all be asking ourselves.
There are some um hair products that
contain more natural ingredients. Henna
might be an option for some people and
other ingredients as well. You know what
I did? I went to the expert. I've got
Curly Nikki here and she's got the
answer for you. Take a look. Hey guys.
Hey. Hey. So, if you follow the blog,
curly.com. If you follow my blog, you
know I am a huge do-it-yourself
advocate. But what you might not know is
that I'm also a safety advocate. And if
you're going to color your hair at home
with a box dye, you want to make sure
you're protecting yourself. Open a
window in the bathroom. Cut on the fan.
Make sure that you have good ventilation
in there. Also, get yourself some rubber
gloves to protect your hands. And get
yourself one of these.
I hope that helps. Be safe, but have
fun. Nikki's wonderful. Thank you,
Melissa. I hope that was helpful. But I
want one more a rule of thumb for
everybody when you're using box color at
home is is use a patch test. That means
use a little bit of the dye on your
skin, not your scalp, but on your skin
to see if you have a bad reaction or an
allergic reaction or anything other to
it. That's probably the best way to go.
See, good news for you, too. Happiness
all around. Find the ultimate guide to
dying your hair on my website. Up next,
we're testing out the natural hair color
treatments that are breaking the
internet. But do they work? Find out
next.
[Applause]
A wife and a mother of two vanishes
without a trace. Where was this husband?
What's his story? The video message she
left behind. What they revealed changed
everything. And a deadly twist no one
saw coming. Can you imagine doing that
to your children?
Plus, the Alzheimer's blood pressure
connection. Are you at risk? This is
just a terrible thing that's
preventable. All new Oz.
That's coming up on Tuesday.
[Music]
[Applause]
Today we are testing out the biggest
viral hair trends breaking the internet
and they involve some of your favorite
indulgences. Coffee and chocolate. Look
at it pouring out. Now these kitchen
stables have gone viral as natural hair
dyes. But do they really work? Here to
help break it all down is someone who
knows a lot about trends. US Weekly
beauty editor Gwen Flamberg. And I gotta
say, people Gwen love spreading their
nice hazelnut chocolate on on their
bread, but they're spreading on their
hair now. Yes, they are. They are.
They're trying it. So, chocolate
hazelnut spread, not just delicious.
Yes. Contains cocoa, which is a natural
stain. Like you've dropped some
chocolate on your tie and Lisa's yelled
at you. Yes, she has many times. Yeah.
So, you know, it's a natural stain. But
that is not all that it has. It also has
palm oil, which is a nutrient for the
hair. So that is like a natural
superpowered conditioner and it's going
to add vibrant shine. So Gwen in theory
in theory it might work. In theory it
should make the hair just a touch darker
and also it is great for neutralizing
brassiness and of course for giving you
magnificent mirror-l like shine. And who
doesn't want shine? All right, we all
want that. So obviously this is an off
label use of hazelnut spread. So we
wanted to put it to the test for some of
our audience members. This is Kelly in
our hair lab backstage
putting on her hair what she hasn't
already eaten. Getting this sweet
treatment. Y'all want to see Kelly now?
Come on out, Kelly. Show us what you
got.
Whoa.
Oh my goodness.
Well, the brassiness is gone. The
brassiness is gone. Come on over here,
Kelly. What do you think about your new
do? So, the color didn't really change,
but the ends are a little bit darker.
You can see some depth in the color and
I think it's definitely shinier. So, it
feels good. I love it. What What do you
think? I think that this ombre like
little shade on the bottom, this little
just tiny touch of darkness makes it
really interesting, really fun,
especially for the holidays. And I mean,
your hair is shiny, girl. It is. It
smells good, too. Shiny. Yes.
Deliciously tasty. You can call it
ombre, Kelly, from now on. Yes. I love
that. I hope you enjoy it. You can
finish what left over here, by the way.
Oh, delicious. Next up, coffee. This is
a real big one. People are thinking
coffee can help with their grays. Gwen,
how does this work as a natural color
boost? So, coffee again is a natural
dye. It's a natural stain. Like, you
know, people for years have been dying
things in coffee and in tea if they want
it just, you know, a little bit like an
a cruise shade. So, that's going to
work. You know, you just you mix a cup
of coffee, brew up a fresh pot of
coffee, let it cool. You do not want to
be pouring boiling hot coffee on your
hair. Mix that cup with a cup of
leave-in conditioner, couple tablespoons
of coffee grounds. Mix it all up,
slather it in. You need to let it kind
of like cook in for an hour, and you
might get a, you know, a little bit of
darkness. It's It's not for uh, you
know, like a major hair change, but if
you've got a big date, a big meeting,
you're meeting the mother-in-law, you
know, might just help neutralize the
house already. So, Scott is under the
dryer giving it a try. Scott, are you
ready? I'm ready. Your big moment. Okay,
here. One second. Let me pull this up.
Lean forward a little bit. Boom. Okay.
Now, oh my goodness. What do you think?
Look at it. Look at the monitor.
Gorgeous. You like it? I do. I do. And
you know what else? Coffee contains
caffeine. Caffeine stimulates stronger,
healthier hair growth. Describe what you
feel with your hair now. Well, it feels
silkier and I I like the way my hair has
dimension, but it really brought the low
lightss out. like it has the has a nice
coffee odor to it. I like that as well.
And you look very awake. So I brought in
hair stylist to the stars roller. Roy
Tila. Come on over here. Roy, you're
gonna weigh in for us. Thanks for being
here. So you just witnessed two women
who have done amazing things with things
we normally put in our mouth. How often
do you hear these trends from your
clients? We do hear these trends, but I
must warn that not all these trends work
as far as my experience goes. So give me
a hacks, something that that would help
color a woman's hair. a trick, easy,
simple, that you think works, reliable.
Well, with these remedies we're talking
about, it has to be left on an awful
long time and it has to be worked into
the hair in order for it to stay in the
hair the way that we're uh looking for
it to be. So, uh it takes a lot of time,
but also want rinse it out thoroughly
because it could clog the pores of your
skin, create weaker hair growth, maybe
hair loss down the road. So, it has to
be used with caution. So, what do you
recommend? Someone calls you up one of
your big time clients and says, "I got a
crisis. I got to look better tonight."
What do you say? things that we are
doing at home right now. We're using
these powders just to touch up around
the hairline, maybe the part of the hair
just to extend that next visit to the
hair salon. How about mascara? How about
that? Uh that is also another kind of
method that we've been using a mascara.
It's a little thick uh a little bit. You
have to comb it through a little bit
more to sort of stretch it out. But yes,
we're doing that, too. That's what guys
do. It does seem to work. Right. Thank
you very much, Gwen. Everybody enjoy
Scotty. We'll be right back.
Up next, the number one thing 450 of the
world's top innovators say will boost
your memory. My friend and wellness
leader Dave Asper is here to reveal it.
The best part of the secret is it's
free. Can't beat that.
Here's your daily share.
[Music]
Today, the wisdom of 450 of the world's
top innovators just for you. We've got
the number one thing they say will boost
your memory. Here with the game-changing
advice is the man who interviewed all
450 people. He's been called a health
visionary who started the bulletproof
coffee trend. Please welcome my friend
David Ashbrin.
[Music]
[Applause]
Welcome back.
So, I got to say, it's hard to get 450
big-time innovators together to tease
out what makes them special. How'd you
pick the folks that you interviewed? I
wanted to find people who had done
something really noteworthy, something
big, something that changed the world.
And I wanted an excuse to talk to them.
So, I started a podcast called
Bulletproof Radio. And I started asking
them this one question at the end of
them sharing their knowledge. three most
important things that you would tell
people to do so that they could be
better at everything and then I did the
math on all that at the end of the day.
You compiled all their ideas. So
boosting brain power was a big part of
your goal. I I I suspect you were
surprised by some of their insights.
What blew me away is I thought these
people would say I wanted to be the best
in my field. I wanted to make a lot of
money. I wanted to win. You know what
they all said? Number one, my health. If
my body doesn't work, I can't do what
I'm here to do. I won't achieve my
mission. So that's what they cared about
most. They cared about food, community,
stress, sleep. None of them cared about
dollars. Yeah. Like most human beings
care about what really matters. Come on
over here. Number one thing that the
world's innovators say will boost your
memory is actually allowing you to ditch
decision fatigue. Decision fatigue is
all the things you're thinking about
that just wear you down so you start
making bad decisions. It is estimated
that we make thousands and thousands of
decisions in a day. Most of which, I got
to say, you're not even aware of. So,
how do these decisions pile up on you
and drain your brain? They pile up on
you because there's a limit to the
number of decisions you can make before
you just run out. And this just makes
sense. But there's see how full the body
is, see how robust the brain is
energized, see how it drains out because
of that. Yeah. And every day it drains
out. There was a study in Israel where
they looked at parole boards and they
said, "What's the number one thing
that's going to get someone out of jail
early? Is it their gender, their crime,
how much education they did?" None of it
mattered. What mattered was the time of
day when you got your pole board
hearing. If you come in in the morning,
85% chance they're going to make a
decision to let you out. End of the day,
85% chance you're going to stay in jail.
So, what does that mean for us? It means
that if we can reserve some of our
little decisions that don't matter so we
can make more important big decisions,
you can actually change your life. Just
help me with that again. So the judges
were getting so exhausted making
decisions. Yeah. That for them the
making no decision was saying no parole,
right? Exactly. So it was a copout
decision. It was a copout decision and
it was because they were out of good
decisions. They just couldn't think
about it and make decision. Ah, no. It's
easier just to say no and not think
about it. Guys, this sink into you know
how you get muscle fatigue from doing
stuff too much? You can get brain
fatigue, which is why you have to
preserve that brain just you have. So I
asked Trish, a busy mom, to log her
decisions to see how it affects her. She
figured for you. Is this your decision
diary? This is lots of things you wrote
down there. Yes. A lot. All right. So, a
lot more than I thought I would. Isn't
that I I did this experiment just in
preparation for this. So, let's just
start the You get up in the morning.
Literally, you're just opening your
eyes. How many decisions have you
already made? I made 45 decisions. And
who would have thought that? I mean,
here I'm laying in bed and and and the
fact that I had to keep track of these
things really made me think about every
single little decision. Do I turn on my
right? Should I roll to my left? Should
I lay here? How much longer can I sleep?
How many times can I hit the snooze
button? Yeah, the mind is de is a
dangerous place to live. It's all all
kind especially in the morning for me.
It's when I start to ruminate a bit.
Okay. What's the crisis time for you?
The time of the day where you make the
most decisions. Well, it's actually a
pretty long time for me because I work
from home. So, it was about 8:30 to
about 3:00. Um, all of my design work,
it's like every decision, decisions, all
decisions all day, every second of the
day. It feels like almost. Do you have a
final tally? Was it possible to keep
track of how many decisions you made?
Well, I must admit, Dr. Oz, I gave up
around 6:00 because, like I said, I'm a
busy mom. But it was 1,879
decisions all before 6 p.m. Look at
that. That I don't know. I don't know
how you feel about this, but that's
stunning to me. And And if I can just
bring one thing up, at 6 o'clock, when
you were done counting, were you pretty
tired? Oh, I was I was like brain dead.
I felt like I was brain dead. I was so
exhausted. All I wanted to do is just
sit there, veg out, turn the TV on, so I
didn't have to think. I didn't have to
think about making decisions anymore. If
you had made decisions after six, would
they have been good ones, do you think?
Probably not. That's when the bewitching
hour, you eat the wrong things, you you
fight with the wrong people. We can't
stop making decisions. So, help me
understand what's the strategy to make
sure we don't, you know, get into this
fatigue setting. How do we boost our
memory? You can automate decisions. You
can decide, I make this decision every
day and it does nothing to improve my
life. Can I just make it once and always
do it that way? And people we've seen
Mark Zuckerberg, political figures, lots
of people with busy lives have figured
out the secret. And sometimes you'll see
it in what they wear or you'll see it in
the way they do different things
throughout the day because they stopped
thinking about it because they had a
bigger mission. And I think everyone on
the planet has a bigger mission even if
it's just to be nice to our family more.
You can make a decision to do that. Is
that why Steve Jobs always wore a
turtleneck? You think that's exactly
why. Yeah. And Mark Zuckerberg, the
Adidas and the hoodie years. And he did
the same thing as Steve Jobs. Steve Jobs
was a visionary in multiple ways. All
right, so we have a video from one of
Dave's thought leaders who says, "This
has been a very helpful way to boost her
brain power." Take a look. Hi, Dr. Oz. I
used to rack my brain just trying to
figure out what to have for breakfast.
Now, I just drink a blended coffee.
Simple. As an emotional intelligence
expert, this is what we teach our
clients. Bottom line, to ditch brain
fatigue, simplify and streamline your
choices. Thanks a lot. This is something
that everyone can start doing right now.
So, we ask the audience to name two
things they can automate in their lives.
Iris, you are nominated to go first. Two
things. I will stick to only one commute
a day instead of figuring out which
subway could go faster today. Um, and
also uh set only one alarm uh instead of
wondering backups. All right, that's
good. Two things. Yes, I'm a housewife.
So, one of the things that I will try to
eliminate is grocery shopping because I
do that like five times a week. And I I
think I if I could reduce the amount of
time that I go to the supermarket and do
grocery shopping. The other thing will
be my haircut or my hair style and doing
that, postponing that, making
appointment, cancelling. So, that would
be another thing that I would So, I'll
give you what I do. First of all, I try
to dress the same way when I come to
work. I don't change it a lot. That way,
I don't have to spend a lot of time
reinvisioning how I'm going to get
dressed. That's why schools for kids
used to always require dress codes. One
less thing for the kids to think about,
right? And I also have the same
breakfast every single day. That way,
you know, why reinvent the wheel? Figure
something that works for you.
Experiment. Once you figure it out, just
do it for the rest of your life. It's
why I'm still married at 33 years.
Nothing that I automate is what I put
into my green drink. And we've heard
about the green drink, right? And I like
it a lot. But I hear there's a new green
drink with one ingredient on the block
that I've got to try. You will never
guess what it is. We're going to share
the secret when we come back. Ready
[Applause]
[Music]
for this? It's the dish on Oz. Our brand
new food series. Make it tasty. Daffy Oz
and Friends.
We're serving it up every Wednesday. The
dish on Oz.
[Applause]
Today, the new green juice that I have
not tried yet. It's getting a lot of
buzz everywhere, especially since it's
only got one ingredient, which I hear is
flying off the shelves of grocery
stores. I want you all to guess what it
is. Well, Miss Leer Dave Asper is back
with a few hints on what this mystery
drink is. This is an extreme close-up
shot of this vegetable. So, are you
ready for the clues? Ready for the
clues. Clue number one. It helps with
gas and bloating. All right. Notice
there all kinds of little holes in
there. It is a vegetable. You know that
already. And these things probably
represent a little bit of fiber. So just
let you know at Okay, clue number two.
Almost completely made of water.
What do you guys think? Made of water.
You're getting a little better view. I
can sort of see the color a little bit
coming up, right? It's either going to
be a greenish or bluish color. All
right, clue number three. Most people
can't live without this when they have
their wings and blue cheese. They'll
know that. Buffalo wings, blue cheese.
Yes, they all know it's celery. You gave
it away. They wouldn't get it from the
That's what we're talking about. Come on
now. You know, it is a unique time in my
life when I can actually say we have
were buffalo wings and blue cheese and
everyone guesses it's the celery, right?
And all the other clues we threw out
there like this chlorophyll, the green,
nothing. Nothing from you guys. Just
that, right? Everyone's clicking their
nose. They can't believe you actually
make a juice out of it. But people can't
find celery in stores anymore. It's
really easy to make a juice out of it.
All you have to do is take it leaves and
all. You notice there's leaves on there.
Yeah. Dump it in the blender.
Little bit of water. A little bit of
water so it'll actually blend. Although
there's a lot of water and celery. So,
yeah. And you want to keep that celery
water and you just put the lid on, blend
it up. If you have a juicer, you can do
that. But here's the trick. You can just
scoop out the pulp if you want or like I
do, I just leave the pulp in there and
then I drink it. What's the benefit?
What do I get if I drink this? Well,
you're certainly going to be getting a
substantial amount of antioxidants from
this, which is something that a lot of
people wouldn't know. Celery, like all
vegetables, is full of polyphenols.
These things that studies are finding
over and over, not just in celery, but
just that class of compounds. The same
thing in spice and coffee, tea. It feeds
the good bacteria in your gut and it is
an antioxidant directly in the body. All
right, audience. I've given you a little
bit of the juice, right? Give it a taste
while we talk a little bit about this.
Remember, studies on celery juice.
People haven't looked at it specifically
as a drink, but it's a guilt-free food,
guys. There's six calories, six calories
in one of these little stalks. So, front
are you. What do you guys think? Just
don't don't have it vote yet. Just
listen for a second before you judge
because I'm going to try too in case
there's any complainers out there about
the taste of celery juice just in case.
What do you What's a hack for it? I like
to put a few different things in it.
I've tried apple cider vinegar, lemon
juice, but the one that works really
reliably is just a little bit of apple.
You put it in the blender and it
sweetens it up just a perfect way. All
right, let's let's go over talk to the
audience here. Now, my thoughts are I
got to say it does taste a Grab a juice.
It does taste a little bit bland. I
don't want to make put anything awkward
in your mouth. Bland a little, but I can
do it. You could do it. Blend. I think
I'd add lemon or apple. You would? Here,
try the apple then see what you think. I
want some honest opinions here. Are you
a bland girl or a happy girl? Is a
little bit bland? Much better. A little.
Much better. Are you guys related? No,
we're friends. We're friends. All right,
give it a taste then.
I want some honest I got to taste it,
too. Very different with a with a little
bit of a apple, right? Yeah. Oh, that
makes What are you talking about? That
makes a huge difference. It does. Were
you okay with the way it was? Yeah.
They're stoic. If I were you, I had a
little apple juice or some of the apple
cider vinegar. That would get me over
the edge. Listen, David, thanks for
being here. Do not miss him. He's on my
podcast. And check out Dave's new book,
which is fabulous, called Game Changers.
There it is right there if you want to
learn what the famous people and the
innovative people do. We'll be right
back.
[Applause]
Is alkaline water the latest hydration
hype? When did something so simple as
water get so complicated? We investigate
the health claims. But what are the real
benefits and won't water down the truth?
We're about to reveal those results in
our first ever water experiment. Plus,
Tony Robbins is here sharing the number
one thing holding you back from success.
I want to show people a little shortcut
that'll give you momentum immediately
and give you power. All new eyes.
That's coming up on Monday.
In 10 years, my kids have grown up. I
become a grandfather. And I even have a
few more gray hairs. I've gotten to know
myself better by meeting you. It's you
who taught me to listen. You've inspired
me. You've given me hope. And you've
been here for the ride. Together, change
happens. Our journey is just beginning.
It's a story that's going to change
lives and save lives.
So, I feel pretty good about life right
now.
[Music]
It's the foodie trend taking over
Instagram. Taking perfectly yummy food
like this burger and then having edible
glitter. Watch this.
Or little edible edible glitter on these
cupcakes. Or how about this sushi,
right? And not just the glitter, right?
Add a little sparkle to that. Look at
this. Imagine your burger looking like
that. Or cupcakes that are golden,
literally. Right. All the sparkle. I
mean, I don't know. If I had a choice
between sushi with gold and the bland
old fashioned sushi, what do you think?
Would you go for it? Yeah. Even popular
fast food chains are hopping on the
trend with 24
karat chicken wings
like these.
I mean, I don't know about you guys,
but for some, all that glitters is not
gold. So, I am curious, my beloved
audience, what do you think? Could this
be part of your future?
Now, anybody want to taste one of these?
These are very Oh. Oh, we got one here.
Go ahead and give that a shot. Grab one
of those. And while you're tasting that,
just enjoy. Oh, she spilled gold on her
sweater. You're golden. I'm shining. You
like it? I love it. And you're shining.
You said I'm already bright. Like, this
is so good. All right. I love it. Now,
this is not your cup of tea. No, that's
like for Instagram show off. And plus, I
already have enough spark already.
That first of all, is it taste okay? Do
you want the truth? Yes. It's the truth.
It's a little bit too much. But um the
chicken's really good still. It's just
too much gold. But I like it. Oh my
goodness. Let me taste one of these
things. You guys are so picky.
It tastes like chicken. It's fine.
Anyway, I love that people are getting
their creative juices going with their
food. From a health perspective,
consuming Gold Flake or Edible Sparkles
is thought to be completely safe. It
ought to pass through your digestive
system without being absorbed into your
bloodstream. But if it's not your jam,
you can always do it for the gram. Take
the gold. Remember everybody, change is
happening. Our journey is just
beginning. It's a little bad aftertaste.
[Music]