It was a horror story that gripped the
nation. Jennifer and Sarah Hart had
adopted six kids. Then Jennifer drove
the family off a California cliff at 90
m an hour. When we first brought you
this story, we were still struggling to
make sense of it all. Why would a mother
do this? What was the motive? Today,
you'll hear exclusive interviews and new
insight that may help answer why this
tragedy happened. Let's take a closer
look at the Hart family.
is an overturned vehicle 11:24.
That's the California Highway Patrol
reporting on the crashed SUV of Jennifer
and Sarah Hart. Mothers to six adopted
children. No sign of anybody around it.
The vehicle plunged 100 ft over these
cliffs along the Pacific Coast Highway.
There's a lot of unknowns on this.
However, we do know several things. We
know that an entire family vanished.
Jennifer and Sarah Hart began adopting
children in 2006. The couple were
described by some friends as
free-spirited, openhearted moms known
for raising their own food and taking
their family to music festivals and
political gatherings seen here on old
social media posts. Yet, some also
describe a darker side. In 2011, while
they were living in Minnesota, Sarah
Hart pleaded guilty to assault and the
malicious punishment of a child after a
teacher discovered bruises on their
six-year-old daughter. Sarah admitted to
police she had let her anger get out of
control. After that, the family began
homeschooling. In 2014, a photo of the
couple's son, Devonte, hugging a white
police officer during a Black Lives
Matter rally went viral. The couple
claimed racist backlash from the
attention led them to withdraw from
public
[Music]
life. Then the family moved to this
house in Woodland, Washington. Their
neighbors Dana and Bruce Dalb say they
remember Devonte coming to their door
requesting food. The couple reached out
to Child Protective Services and the
Friday before the deadly crash, a CPS
worker came to the Hart family home. No
one answered. The worker departed and
the next morning so did the Hart family.
Now nearly a year later, the Hart family
tragedy is still unfolding. Police just
recently identified the remains of a
fifth child from a deadly crash. Abuse,
lies, and unanswered questions. All part
of a story that ended 100 ft below the
scenic Pacific Highway
[Music]
cliffs. Writer Lee Egan and features
director at Glamour magazine Justine
Harmon are the co-hosts of Broken
Hearts, the podcast about this tragedy.
They join me now. Liz, you were
initially drawn to this story because
you found the women relatable. I just
wanted to understand that a little
better. I first read a headline about
this story when I was on a very long
road trip with my own kids. I have
three, two teenagers, one tween. And I
read the headline that a family of eight
had gone over a cliff in
California. I saw I was intrigued
because of course I had just spent the
day in the car with my own kids who were
bickering and complaining and I assumed
they had been on a road trip also. And
when I saw pictures of Jen and Sarah
Hart, I was immediately drawn to them
because they looked like people I might
know. And in fact, I logged into my own
Facebook account and looked up their
names to see if if I had friends in
common with them. I did not. Um, but I
continued to follow the story and was
what surprised me the most was how
quickly it disappeared from the
headlines. It was such a terrible
tragedy and it didn't seem to get the
attention that I thought it deserved.
Justine, walk us through the dynamic
between these two women. women who do
seem relatable when you see them on
social media, but they're much more
complex. So, they met in college um in
Aberdine in South Dakota and they were
inseparable to begin with and friends of
them friends of theirs from back then
sort of described the dynamic as Jen was
the outgoing one and Sarah was a little
more reserved. Um, but as time went on
and as they, you know, adopted more and
more children, it seemed that the
differences between them, the disparity
between those personalities really grew
at Delta and Jen was the alpha. And it
does appear that Sarah was a little bit
more of a traditional sidekick. And the
kids even said when some of the abuse
allegations came out that um Sarah used
to push back and toward the end she
stopped. And so, um, I mean, I'm not a
doctor, but it does seem that they are
playing two very different roles in how
this family
was reared. How did people react to the
blended family aspect of this? Um, well,
these women moved the children from
Houston, which is a very diverse area,
to very secluded suburban areas. And a
lot of the neighbors we spoke with
discussed that, you know, they didn't
want to appear politically incorrect.
They didn't want to appear intolerant or
racist. Um, and they had a hard time
understanding where the line is between
being respectful of a family that
doesn't look like your own and turning a
blind eye. And I do think the blended
element, you know, two gay moms, six
black kids, a lot of people were hands
off on that and didn't want to appear
to have an opinion that might not jive
with that lifestyle. And I think it was
really important to what happened here.
Yeah. I never thought of the possibility
that being politically correct or
conscious of your own potential bias
might have actually led to the these
kids being ignored. Yeah. I mean, we
live in this faux post-racial society
where people want to believe that we
live in a time in a place where we're
equal and these conversations are no
longer needed. But it's it's the lack of
these conversations that can really
contribute to some really horrible
things. So, I think it's a hard thing to
talk about and it's a hard thing to
address, but we're hoping with this
podcast, Broken Hearts, that we're able
to shed a light on some of these harder
and more difficult conversations. And it
also simulates another idea in me which
is maybe these moms purposely went to
places right where they were clearly
different from everybody else so that
they would be left alone because if they
if they moved to a major urban area
where people might be more
connected to the this lifestyle they
probably would have had people asking
them questions poking at them a little
bit. You go to a rural part of the
country where no one looks like you.
Yeah. I mean, absolutely. And neighbors
Bill Grooner, who lived next door to
them in Westlin, Oregon, said as much.
And Woodland, Washington, where they
lived right before they went off the
cliff, is.3% black. Um 3% 3%. Um, so
there really wasn't anyone to confide
in, to relate to. It's all I mean,
hindsight is 2020, but it all feels very
intentional to keep these children from
being able to reach out, from being able
to connect, from being able to have any
sense of autonomy. Um, so it it is
pretty sinister. All right, we'll be
right back. We're back investigating the
mystery surrounding one of the most
tragic stories of the last year.
Jennifer Hart, whose blood alcohol level
was over the legal limit, drove her
partner Sarah and their six adopted
children off a cliff. Why did she kill
her family? The Broken Hearts podcast is
investigating every angle of this
tragedy. Host Justine Harman and Liz
Egan are back. So, Justine and Liz
talked to several people who considered
themselves part of the Heart's inner
circle, including a photographer who
immediately after the tragedy defended
the women that she thought she knew.
Take a listen.
They were that really bright kind of
presence. It was pretty hard to miss
them. Any event that that I was at where
they were, if I had a camera, I was of
course attracted to that. I was inspired
by them. They gave me hope. Everyone
considered them like a heart tribe. Even
now, Zippy has a hard time believing her
friends were living dual lives. There's
no part of me in all of my looking back
at my observations of them that's
capable of seeing that it was just a
charade.
All right. All right. So, Liz, uh, Jen
and Sarah have six adopted kids that we
know of, but it wasn't the first time
that they were parents. That I didn't
realize. They had a foster daughter. Can
you tell us that story? They had a
foster daughter when they were in their
20s. And the foster daughter reported in
one in, she only gave one interview. Um,
she prefers to remain
anonymous. She remembers that one day
they drove her to a therapist's office.
They dropped her
off. They never came back. And she was
taken from the therapist's office to
another foster family where her
belongings were already in the house. It
had been planned ahead. She had no
idea. So right there, you have to look
at that treatment of another human being
and think that is so incredibly cruel.
I'm stunned that the system would
tolerate that degree of
cruelty because it's not just the
mothers dropping these this child off
and not looking back. It's the fact that
there was a system that supported that,
right? That therapist had to take her
in. Another FOS family had to accept
their the closer delivered without her.
It's astounding. It's brutal. It's
unconscionable. I'm thinking why would
they give those two mothers more
children? Exactly. Why roll the dice
again? Right. Doesn't that seem to be an
obvious question you'd ask unless you
didn't know what's happening? So, Jenn
and Sarah will go on to adopt six kids
in three years. Six kids. Yeah. In an
exclusive interview on our show, The
Hart's nextdoor neighbors, Dana and
Bruce, told us about an exchange with
one of the kids when he came over to ask
for food. He's asking for food. This is
just days before they were killed. These
are all the questions that I understand
you asked. Are they feeding you? What
did he say? That they would, he said,
they withhold food as punishment. And it
used to only be a meal at a time, but
now that it was going for days at a
time. Are they abusing you? And he said,
"Yes."
He said he was being abused. Question
I'm asking, what you're all thinking is,
"How's this possible? How could we have
tolerated this? The people that are
supposed to be in charge? How did these
women get away with this?" Justine, what
role did race play? I think race played
a very big role in what unfurled over
the course of a decade. Um Shondaanda
Jones, who was the attorney for the
second set of siblings, said that in her
22 years as an attorney, um she'd never
felt a tenor like the one she felt in
the courtroom where she was trying to
help their biological aunt maintain
custody of these children. She felt the
mind was their mind was made up that
these two white women in Minnesota were
just more suited to raising these
children than their own biological
family. And white privilege is so
apparent here. and the fact that they
were able to uh mask such horrible a
horrible legacy of abuse based on the
fact that they look passable or look
like someone you can know on Facebook.
This is really intrinsic to what they
were able to pull off whether it was
intentional or whether it's just
capitalizing on a lot of the issues that
plague our society. And so I do think
the juxtaposition between their
whiteness and the blackness of these
children cannot be ignored. And we've
received some criticism about the fact
that we are two white women telling this
story, but it's a story that's worth
being told and I understand the
criticism, but I also really think that
at the end of the day, there are six
kids who died and to honor them and to
recognize some of the issues that led to
that tragedy, it's vitally, you know,
it's vitally important. I come to this
story as a mother having had three kids
in six years and almost losing my mind
at the time. I know that I know the
desperation of having a bunch of kids
who are little and
overwhelming. The idea that they were
able to adopt six kids in three years,
which is essentially three sets of twins
in a row.
You just have to wonder how that
happened. Up next, the hearts choose to
live off the grid. They chose that yet
live much of their lives on social
media. Could their social media presence
have played a role in the tragedy? Stay
with us. We're back. Investigating the
mystery surrounding one of the most
tragic stories of the last year.
Jennifer Hart, whose blood alcohol level
was over the legal limit, drove her
partner Sarah and their six adopted
children off a cliff. Why did she kill
her family? The Broken Hearts podcast is
investigating every angle of this
tragedy. Host Justine Harmon and Liz
Egan are back. So Justine, the Hearts
lived off the grid, right? Yet they're
all over social media. It doesn't seem
that they match up that well. You would
think that, but effectively, everyone
who knew them in their real life says
that what they saw online corroborates
the hearts they knew. Um, and Zippy
Lomax, who we heard from earlier, said
the same. They were very good at
curating
um a version of familial bliss that
existed both online and in person. And I
do think creating that myth across all
platforms really prevented them from
ever being able to go off track and say
actually no, we're having a problem or
we're having difficulty raising these
children because they reaffirmed this
narrative so many different ways and the
abuse lived in such an underbelly. Um
you and we've gone back I mean thousands
of posts we've looked at and there
really is no wrinkle. There's no aha
moment where you're like oh that that
shows that something sinister was
happening. It was a very wellcurated um
reality in a way and it's something that
I think a lot of us do maybe perhaps
subconsciously. It makes the hypocrisy
that much deeper and it leaves me even
more questioning what happened. We've
been struggling for a year now. We all
have in this whole country understanding
why did these women do this? So let's
come back. I mean, let's go through the
main theories you looked into. First is
terminal illness. And I'm curious what
made you go there because this didn't
come out in an investigation. I would
have thought we would have known that
someone had, you know, brain cancer or
something. At one point, Jen Hart took
about a six-month hiatus from Facebook.
And when she returned, in her status
update explaining her absence, she
mentioned the word cancer. She she
listed a whole bunch of reasons why she
had taken some time off from Facebook.
So, of course, we became curious about
whether Jen or Sarah had cancer, whether
they had a terminal illness that uh
might have scared them and made them do
this. We did not turn up anything along
those lines in our investigation. It's
probably not that. Probably. No. Let's
go to number two, which is a common
issue we have across the country.
financial problems. The Harts had about
$20,000 worth of debt. They lived on one
salary of $45,000 a year. For a family
of eight, that's not a huge amount of
money. A lot of people feel financial
stress and don't drive their family of
eight off a cliff. So, I look at these
problems, I'm still left with this last
word of mental health. And I I don't
even know where to put my arms around
this, but it it seems that there's
something going on inside of their
minds. So Justin, what have you
uncovered? Is there a diagnosis we have?
We don't have a diagnosis, but someone
close to the family um does say that
there always was some indication that
there was something going on with Jen,
that there was an undiagnosed mental
illness. Um but we don't have I can't
come out and say, you know, the DSM says
this. We we haven't seen any um evidence
that she was in therapy or taking
medication, but something's not right.
Maybe she should have been in therapy
and taking medication perhaps. Uh right,
that this case is still ongoing in
California. I'm surprised that police
are still trying to figure out is this a
homicide or not? What's left to find
out? Um well, they still don't have a
cause of death on the death certificates
of these children and on Jed and Sarah
Hart. Um, and in March, to mark the
one-year anniversary, they're going to
hold what's called a corner's inquest,
which is something that hasn't been done
in Mendescino County, where they died in
50 years, according to the sheriff. And
it's basically a jury of civilians
determining whether this was an
accident, a crime on behalf of one
person, or on behalf of two people. And
in so many ways, that's the end. That's
what is stamped on the death
certificate, and that is how these
deaths will be ruled. So, what's the
lesson here? What's the message from
this tragedy? What do we learn? To me,
it's
twofold. The first is that we need
better communication between states
about child abuse charges. When Jen and
Sarah moved from Minnesota to Oregon,
the state of Oregon should have been
made aware in some way, there should be
a national registry of child abuse so
that you can't just pick up stakes and
move someplace else when you have some
marks on your record. Mhm. And the
second thing is more personal. It's that
I'm personally trying to st take take a
step away from the screen away from
exclusively inter interacting with
certain friends through social media on
Facebook on Instagram and actually
looking out my window and seeing the
people who live in my neighborhood and
the actual friends who I have in real
life and to build that community rather
than putting so much focus as Jen Hart
in building
this fable online.
Thank you very very much. I appreciate
both yours in the hard work that you put
into researching this case. Since our
story first aired, the bodies of Jen,
Sarah, and five of the children have
been found and identified. The only one
still listed as missing is 15-year-old
Devonte Hart. He's the young boy who
famously hugged a police officer at a
rally protesting Ferguson police. To
learn more about the Hart family and
exclusive details about what happened
that tragic day, check out Glamour's
podcast, Broken Hearts. It's available
wherever you get your podcast. Thank you
for watching. Don't forget to subscribe
and turn on notifications so you never
miss out on new videos to live the good