[Music]
[Applause]
What is it in coffee that's raising
fears? If you could eat a cloud, this is
what it would taste like. A healthy
cloud.
We had the medical unit look into this.
I use these, but I don't trust these.
You got a bunch of burning health
questions, and I'm finding out the
answers. Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you, Becca.
[Music]
Is coffee really good for you? Dr. Oz,
should I really be using cooking spray?
Dr. bras. Do toilet seat covers really
protect you? Is there really a whipped
topping Dr. Oz approves of? Why can't
somebody just tell me once and for
[Music]
all? I'm just trying to close my eyes,
but I can't get these questions for my
viewers out of my head. So, today we're
going to unravel those health questions
that keep coming up. You know what they
say, the loudest voice wins out. Well,
let's start with Renata's big question.
Is there a whipped topping that I
approve of?
Who doesn't love a cloud of whipped
cream? It's so fluffy and sweet and it
crowns every dessert with a happy
halo. There's an explosion of whipped
wonders at the store. I've noticed that
there are tons of whipped creams and
toppings to choose from. You have
original, extra creamy, nonfat, and
light. They come in spray cans,
tubs, and some say they're even low
calorie. Can you tell me once and for
all, is there a whipped topping you
approve of,
Dr. Soath is here in person, and this is
Thanksgiving week, everybody. I know
you're all going to be indulging in
whipped toppings to add to your pies and
everything else. So, today we have
samples of some of the most popular
whipped items. For example, there's the
store-bought whipped cream in a can. Oh,
that sound. Isn't that amazing, guys? M
Whoa, yum, yum, yum. And we also have
the fat-free whipped topping also from a
store, right? I like Oh, look at that.
Look at that. So, so thick and luscious.
Now, here's the question for you. Pop
quiz. Look at these both, right? They
look similar, right? Which of these
barely contains any of this dairy? What?
What you talking about? What What are
you talking about? It barely contains
dairy. Yeah. One of these doesn't have
any dairy in it. They both had dairy in
it. They're cream. They're whipped
toppings and they have cream. The name
cream in it. So that means it must be
dairy in it, right? They taste like
they're creamy, but one of them doesn't
have it. Come on over. We're not I love
when once in a while we can impart a
little knowledge here. The first thing
we uncovered is that's easy to get
ripped off on whipped. So we're going to
go do a little comparison between
whipped and all the other comparative
products out there. Chef Danny Boom is
here with our whipped cream dream team.
That's nice. Okay. I like that. Whipped
cream dream team. So, we're going to
start off with the oldfashioned homemade
whipped cream. So, you know what to
compare it to. Cuz the things I just
showed you actually weren't homemade.
But, you know, the closer you get to
homemade, the better off you are. This
has actually been around for a long
time, the homemade whipped cream from
the 16th century. It was known as snow
cream. And you talk about this being the
gold standard. What What do you say is
in here? And is it a concern? Is it bad
for you? How can natural ingredients be
a concern to anybody? That's the first
thing, right? We're talking about real
cream from a cow. Okay, that's the first
thing. We're talking about real vanilla
from a bean. And then we're talking
about real sugar from the cane. Okay,
that's what I want to see in my food.
Okay, when you whip it together, it's
just as quick. Okay, you have a metal
bowl that you freeze. You have a metal
whip that you whip it with and away you
go, guys. That's where you get it. Real
cream is what it's about. And I don't
want any synthetic stuff in my kitchen
giving me only 2%. There's only 2%
sometimes of any kind of dairy in a
synthetic product. This tastes to die
for. This is how I enjoy it as well. And
again, if it's created in the 16th
century, they didn't have a lot of
chemical processing back then. That's
right. Exactly. But the biggest thing
here is, okay, it may spoil, but that's
the good sign. If it spoils, it molds,
it spores, that's when we know something
is natural and is good for us. It also
actually it also gets rid of out of our
body quicker. We need full fat. All
right, he's preaching to the choir. You
ate full fat, Dr. Oz. Full fat. I heard
him. We need it. All right. Next cooking
nutitionist Rachel Beller here. She's
talking about whipped cream in a can.
Now, give a little bit of history here.
Whipped cream in a can was created in
1940s. Heralding convenience, lots of
memories, fond memories for a lot of us
who got to do what I just did over
there. This little maneuver. Oh, right.
It feels good. It looks good. It's
However, what's actually in it, Rachel?
So, we're not so real here. We have
thickeners, emulsifiers, there's cream,
there's milk, but all these things that
we're adding in. Some of these have 15
16 ingredients. Dr. Oz, that's a lot for
something so simple that Danny showed
us. So really, it's something that could
produce inflammation in the body. Not so
ideal when we want to get real. So been
around a long time despite the memories.
All right, let's get to the fat-free
whipped toppings which became popular in
the 60s, right? And a lot of people eat
these because they are low calorie. Yep.
Right out the And they do they do taste
good. But Danny, what ingredients did
you uncover that we did not expect? Oh,
here we go guys. Look at this. There's
Can you first of all, apart from being a
scientist like yourself, can anybody
else in the audience actually say the
first one? Hydrogenated oil. Okay,
that's the first thing. That's like palm
oil, canola oil. These are oils. They're
not dairy. It's not a protein, is an
oil. So, that's the preservative that's
holding everything together. It's an
emulsifier. Okay, then we look at the
next things down here. Additives.
Additives. Okay. Additives are
flavorings. Okay. That's what makes you
addicted to that. So fat free, but
there's a head fake here. Rana, what do
you think about that? Your take. Oh
gosh, I'm I'm troubled. Um I'm clutching
my pearls. I don't know what to do. I
have three cans of this stuff in my
refrigerator right now.
Um Dr. Oz, um however, I'm going to try
and do it a little bit more natural.
Well, here's the thing. Before you
judge, you you brought something up,
Danny, earlier about how long these
last. So my team was interested to see
just how much of a food fake out
storebought whips were. So we did a
little experiment to see how fast the
foods would spoil. Are you all
interested in that? Right. In theory,
it's supposed to spoil. Take a
[Music]
look. All
right, here's what the whipped clouds
look like today. That's the old natural
16th century version. Not so appealing,
right? This baby here, I mean, it's just
deflated all the gas, but it did go bad,
right? Look at this. The whipped
topping, right? That didn't spoil at
all. That's still good to go. So, we did
some investigating and found some brand
new whipped toppings that are healthier.
I narrowed it down to just one that I
personally am obsessed with. I never
even thought about whipped chickpea
before. It's made actually from aquafaba
that you take the the juice of the
chickpea like this stuff down here. See
that juice? Wow. You take that juice,
it's sort of thick. I don't know if you
can all appreciate that, right? And you
whip that baby up and it looks like
this. So, I want my experts to please
taste that. Rachel, while you're doing
that, tell us a tiny bit about this. So,
I love aquafaba because you're basically
taking I take no sodium added liquid
from the chickpea and you just you whip
it up. Oh, now wait a minute. Yeah. You
could put maple, you could put a little
bit of honey. Mhm. So, this is a liquid
again that's in the can when you buy the
chickpeas, right? Yes. No sodium added.
Four ingredients compared to 16. This is
real. And you can This It's delicious.
Describe the taste.
You like it? It's It's light. It's
definitely light. fluffy, airy, airy.
It's It has a nice It's not overly
sweet, but it has a nice little sweet
texture. And there's this aftertaste
which is really really pleasant. And my
mouth smooth and my mouth doesn't feel
oily. If you could eat a cloud, this is
what it tastes like. A healthy cloud.
This is my first ever Oz approved first
ever Oz approved whip topping chickpea
whip. Try it out. The chickpea whip is
going to be famous. Coming up next are
Well, why can't someone just tell me
once and for all show continues? We
investigate coffee. Recent headlines of
cancer risks. Are they scaring you?
Should you be worried? Stay with
us. This is a first for me. I've covered
the events leading to crimes and the
aftermath, but I've never been inside a
prison to meet a criminal, to see what
it's really like to be in prison. No
cell phones allowed, no electronics,
just the minimal equipment for my crew.
An Oz true crime exclusive. And I've got
to say, when you think of a person in
prison for hiring a hitman, you're not
what I would imagine. All new Oz. That's
coming up tomorrow.
Hey, Dr. Oz. I read that they're putting
cancer warning labels on coffee in
places like in
California. Once and for all, how
worried am I supposed to be about my
daily coffee intake? Because I always
thought coffee was healthy.
It's the biggest coffee controversy
that's boiling over. Could coffee cause
cancer? Nutritionist Rachel Beller is
back along with coffee expert Dr. Bob
Arnold. They're joining me to
investigate. Guys, grab your coffee.
Let's head out to talk to the audience
about
coffee. So, we're enjoying our
coffee, but not 100% sure we should be.
So Rachel, you're from California and so
you've been living in a state where
there are now signs. Let me show this to
you. Signs in the coffee shops warning
people about coffee and cancer, right?
This is a pretty, you know, it's an
opposing warning sign. What is it in
coffee that's raising fears? So it's
acryumide which is formed when you're
roasting the coffee beans and the higher
the deeper the roast, the more acryumide
gets formed. The thing that's
interesting is that something like a
potato chip or French fries has 40 to 60
times the acryumide than our cup of
coffee. So, it's like a needle in a hay
stack. As a dietitian, I am not worried
about it. But the signs that I just
showed are only on coffee shops. They're
not putting them on French fries or
potato potato chip bags. That is
correct. In California, the signs are
up. Bob, your take on coffee and its
dangers specifically with regard to
cancer? Well, what you said, you know,
300 micrograms in a in a chip. you know,
seven on a cup of coffee doesn't seem
like much, but you know, the the really
good environmental chemists are going,
well, it's a liquid, could concentrate,
maybe said there's something there and
it is what's called a developing
carcinogen. They're looking, they're
testing, so there's no kind of final
answer, but the World Health
Organization, you know, you still list
it as a potential carcinogen. They've
given it a clean bill of health may uh
prevent up to two cancers and scientific
reports has 105 prospective studies
saying it may prevent everything from
prostate to colon cancer. Good. So all I
would say is to be safe the smartest
thing to do is drink a low acryomide
coffee. As Rachel said so well the
lighter roast have less in it. That
seems to make the most sense but I don't
worry about it. All right we got two
experts here are not worried about in
fact they're giving thumbs up to your
daily cup of Joe. They're not worried
about coffee and cancer. Are you all
happy about that?
They complain. I take away their
favorite foods. I get it all the time.
So, next question. What are the actual
benefits of coffee? Because I'm not a
coffee drinker. I don't react well to
it. As a surgeon, it's the worst thing
to have coffee before you head into the
operating room. Big problem because you
can't leave the O to take care of number
one and number two. That's right. So, I
never drank dent coffee. Plus, it looks
bad when you stay in your white jacket.
But, but there are studies every day
brewing uh about these these benefits.
Let's go through these. Bob, walk us
through the strongest reason to drink
coffee. The first is to prevent the risk
of death. maybe including cancer. So,
the interesting thing is that coffee
used to be a marker for bad behavior.
People that that ate too much red meat,
they they smoked, they drank too much
alcohol, they didn't exercise, they
didn't have any vegetables in their
diet. It seemed like it was a market for
bad behavior. But these giant studies, 5
million consumer years, showed a
staggering 15% decrease in all cause
death for women, 10% for men. And you
know, there's nothing else like this in
the American diet. no food or new
beverage. It gives you that staggering
degree of decrease in death. Okay. How
about brain protection? And I bring it
up because it's the number one question
that especially older Americans have,
fear of dementia. So the interesting
thing, we actually did a study at the
North Carolina research campus with uh
Dave Neman and we showed a a big boost
in mood and we think that's because it
decreases bl brain inflammation. Good
studies on depression. out of the
Harvard School of Public Health. There's
a 20% decrease in the risk of uh
depression among women drinking four
more cups of coffee a day, Alzheimer's
disease, Parkinson's disease. Also, is
it because it's making you alert enough
to deal with stress better and you know
keep keep active intellectually? What
why does it work? So, the interesting
thing with the Alzheimer's, it may
prevent all those kind of you know
things getting onto the nerve endings
there, but they think it's basically a
decrease in inflammation. Now remember,
no one has done big prospective trials
proving this is a medication. It's just
an observation, but it's a good one. And
depression, fantastic. Well, if you can
reduce inflammation, which is the root
cause of so many problems, I'm in. Let's
head over to our coffee bar for the next
coffee question. We can settle right
now, right here. How many cups of coffee
a day is the right amount to drink for
the health benefits? Bob, since you've
articulated quite nicely that you're
passionately in favor of drinking some,
how much should we drink? New England
Journal of Medicine, men, five to six
cups of coffee a day. Harvard School of
Public Health. I know, trust me. Why
does six cups? Trust me, women, four
cups of coffee a day, 20% decrease in
the risk of depression. But if you are
like you and me and 45% of the
population, you take that much coffee,
you're going to have a SWAT team
following you down the highway, right?
Anxiety, wreck your sleep, ruin your
operation, right? And it could actually
be bad for you because your blood
pressure may go up. So the bottom line
is if you think you're sensitive to
caffeine, you can get away with just one
or two cups of super high polyphenol
coffee. We've gotten up to a thousand
milligrams in a cup versus 150 for a
lesser coffee. That's a great
workaround. The other good workaround is
a really high quality, say Ethiopian or
Mexican decaf that has all the
polyphenols. And the polyphenols, that's
the secret ingredient. That's what
causes the decrease in inflammation. So
you can get it. Lastly, that big New
England Journal study, it didn't say
caffeinated coffee. It just said coffee.
So, take it either way. All right. So,
again, two cups of caffeinated coffee or
if you're sensitive, you can have, I
don't know, four, five, six cups of
decaffeinated coffee without getting
symptoms that, but what you care about
is the fact that you're having some
coffee. Okay, you've got a little hack,
Rachel. A lot of times people adding too
much sugar to their coffee. It's a sugar
and cream that messed the coffee up,
guys. So, how do we get away without
adding on those things in, but adding in
some healthy ones instead? So, I treat
myself a couple times a week to what I
call a Turkish latte. I'm also a little
sensitive like you. And you're you've
got some of that Turkish uh in you. So,
health healthiest coffee there is is the
Turkish coffee. It is sometimes misnamed
Greek, but nonetheless, rich in
polyphenols, which is which is
fantastic. So, what you do is you can
take a shot or two of espresso, put it
in a a nutmilk. I try to avoid dairy
when it comes to coffee because um it
shows that it does decrease the
antioxidant value. It does reduce
polyphenols. So, I use cashew or almond.
And then here's something magical. I
love to power up my coffee with spice
synergy. There is research showing that
if you add cinnamon and ginger to
coffee, they work in sync and increase
the antioxidant value. Oh my goodness.
It's really cool stuff. Yes. So,
what I do is I add some cinnamon, some
ginger, some cardamom and clove. And
smell it. I mean, I'm really smelling
this. This is really good. This Rachel
is brilliant. It's just you're amping up
the nutritional value of what you're
drinking, what you're eating, just with
the power of spice. This will be the new
morning drink. This I'm serious. You
think I'm kidding? Rachel's Morning
Turkish coffee with cinnamon, ginger,
and everything else you add. No sugar in
this, right? No. No. You could add a
little bit of honey if you want to, but
I don't. It's just so good on its own.
So, cheers to that. Thanks for
enlightening us, making us feel better.
That's right. So, be sure to check out
Bob's book, Coffee Lovers Bible. You can
tell that he is one. Up next, do you use
cooking sprays? What you need to know
about what's really in them. Stay with
us. It's the return of jerky. This paleo
snack is now out selling chips. That is
so good. But could this low carb meat
treat have hidden ingredients that could
crash your diet? All new Oz. That's
coming up on Wednesday.
[Applause]
Cooking sprays. It's the kitchen item
that's always generating questions. And
today, I've turned my set into a test
kitchen to answer some of your burning
questions. Brooke and nutritionist
Rachel Bella have started an egg fry
experiment. So, what's your biggest
concern, Brooke, about these cooking
sprays? Is it better than regular oil?
Well, that's a pretty clear question.
What kind of oil do you currently cook
with? Uh, olive oil cooking spray. All
right. So, let's take a closer look at
the difference between olive oil in the
spray versus that in the bottle. We got
a little demonstration going on. You're
both racing. So, in a second, we're
going to find out how this is working.
Now, Rachel, you you just put flannel
olive oil on yours. Pure olive oil. And
this was sprayed. Yes, it was sprayed.
So, it makes a little slippery. Yes. I
While these are finishing up, can you
explain your perspective? Is it
nutrition? What's the difference? So,
with olive oil, what you see is what you
get. Pure olive oil. With a cooking
spray, now you're looking at additives.
And so, you know, you've got some um,
you know, anti- foaming agent like
silicone dioxide and uh, lecithin that a
lot of people are actually allergic to
soy and it's soy leithin. Got it. So,
there's something in there that they may
not be knowing about. And then we've got
the propellant to make it come out of
the can. And so, and that's something
also that is a little bit of an unknown.
It's what we use when we go camping. You
know, some of the propane kind of like
eat at your own risk thing going on.
Netn net does it which one's better for
taste and which one do you think is
healthier? So the olive oil is by far
healthier because you know you're
getting the pure thing. Some of these
oils they use chemicals and solvents to
you know to you don't know what you're
getting what kind of quality of olive
oil you're getting. Is there a taste
difference? I think there is. All right,
you guys ready? Let's just see how they
work first of all. Rachel, you you want
to go first or you're brave? Let's see
if it comes off. Go ahead. So it sort of
comes off. It's a little bit a little
harder, but you can pretty force it off.
It It made it It was not as elegant. Let
me see how yours does. Let's see how you
can do this. All right, let's see. Oh my
god. Don't even slippery. Don't even
need this. That is easier, but that
wasn't crazy hard either, right? So,
what And this nonstick, we understand
why it's happening because of the
chemicals in here. Yes. You recommend a
specific kind of oil if you're going to
spray that you think is a little better.
So thankfully in the marketplace we do
have like for example this is avocado
oil spray and if you look at the
ingredient list there's one ingredient
avocado oil and they even bother to tell
us that it's expeller pressed no
chemicals no solvents no treating it
with harsh chemicals to dilute the
antioxidant level. Oh and it heats up to
500°.
So see what's wrong with that? It's
awesome. Have you ever heard of it
before? No. This is a great idea. This
is a gift from the show to you. It's a
little something for your effort coming
today. This is a great idea. It's great.
It's inexpensive. Really, really great.
All right. Thank you. Now, Stephanie's
here along with her question with Chef
Danny for a spray experiment.
So, Stephanie, what is concerning to you
about these sprays? Well, I'm using a
zerocalorie spray. So, is it actually
zero calories?
Ah, what's the deal with this? It says
zero calories, doesn't it? It It says
zero calories, but zero calories. This
is really really interesting. So zero
calories to the FDA, okay, is a serving
suggestion. Okay, so it comes down to
one serving suggestion can be basically
five calories or
0.5 grams. Okay, so but here's the
thing. When you one spray is going to
give you that, but how many times do you
spray to cover the surface of the pan?
What's a spray mean? In terms of time,
one pump. Well, that comes down to
oneird of a second. A third of a second.
Yeah. So, I've got a little competition
for you here, doctor. All right. Okay.
What we're going to do, Stephanie's got
some spray. You've got some spray. We've
got two pans. And come on, everybody
here. Do you think they really could
cover the surface of the pan with one
pump? We're going to try. Yes. Try.
Okay. You're going to try. So, what I
got is I've got a stopwatch here. And as
I'm wearing my apron, it I look
official. You do. Okay. So, we're going
to give it a one, two, three. We're
going to spray. And then we're going to
sit. Just one pump. One. Okay. Okay.
Because I know you're competitive, Doc.
Okay. One pump. And we're gonna see how
much we spray. And then we're going to
go back and then we're going to realize
how much we actually do put into the
pan. A third of a second. Right. No
cheating. No cheating. No cheating. Hey.
Do I have to get serious here? Okay.
Right. Okay. So, three, two, one. Stop.
You went longer than a third. No, I
didn't. Yes, you did. I saw you. I think
you went a little over the line.
Absolutely did. But what we've got here,
if we just went, if we can continue
this, look at how the pan goes. That's
not going to work real. Okay, you could
get an egg going on there. And remember,
if you're using a non-stick pan, the
first thing is you don't have to use the
oil. If you want to distribute the oil
in an even sense, use some paper towel
and maybe some olive oil. But in
fairness, I that that no one's going to
do one/ird of a second. You can't spread
it that quickly. Well, let's come back
to the calorie question. Yes. Okay. If
we've just used one pump, okay, well,
that's five calories. Okay. But if you
continue to keep doing that, the
calories are going to keep mounting up.
You could end up with 35 calories.
That's what it would take. Okay. So
that's probably about 25 30 calories
there right now. Well, it turns out we
had the medical unit look into this.
Right on. And the average person would
probably spray for close to 3 seconds.
We think it's about 30 calories, right?
With roughly. So it's actually not a
zero calorie additive. In which case,
you think, is there a hack? So you
mentioned a good one, but I'm going to
go one up here. This new beautiful
technology. It's just a bottle with a
pump. All right. Nothing fancy. But
listen, put real olive oil in here. And
then when you spray, watch. Oh, I
missed. I missed. Sorry. See, and you
can do that. And now you know exactly
what you're getting. And this is a
little gift to you. A little olive oil.
You take whatever hack you want, but
there are ways of getting around this if
you don't want to do it on. Exactly.
Thanks for helping me solve the
experiment. Hope you enjoyed the
competition. Congratulations on your
victory. Bottom line, guys, try avocado
spray for a less bird taste and be aware
of how long you spray if you're worried
about the calories. Up next, do you ever
use a toilet seat cover when you're in
the public
restroom? Do you ever do that? Some
yeses and some nos. Find out what our
swabbing investigation revealed about
the germ protection they really give
you. Stay with us.
Ready for this? It's the dish on Oz, our
brand new food series. Get tasty. Daffy
Oz and friends.
We're serving it up every Wednesday in
November. The dish on
[Music]
us. So, let's be honest. Who uses one of
these right in the toilet bowl? All
right. During one of my shows brainstorm
sessions, I learned that my team and you
at home have a lot of questions about
disposable toilet seat covers. For the
first time, we did a swabbing survey in
public restrooms to find out if this
actually protects you or not. Comedian
Chuck Dice, who's a self-proclaimed
toilet expert, is here. You are one of
the skeptics. Yes. Of these covers.
What's your beef with them? You know,
here's the deal. First of all, when it
comes to toilets, that's where I'm a
Viking. Okay. Seriously, I do a lot of
traveling. All right. And I have a lot
of fiber and roughage in my diet. So,
there's a lot of public restrooms in my
life. Okay? That's all I'm saying. Now,
I use these, but I don't trust these.
Okay. Now, what I really do, Dr. Oz, is
I go get paper towels, swab them full of
soap, and clean the toilet. Then, I put
this down on it. So, that's really into
it. Yeah. All right. So, we did our own
experiment in public restrooms to find
out if they're protecting you or not.
Rat is standing by with two audience
members in an undisclosed
location. So, hey, Dr. eyes. Everyone
has their own way of getting over the ew
factor. I mean, the nastiness of using
the public bathroom. Sometimes it
doesn't go the way that we want it to,
but there's two techniques that we have
right now. So, right now, the first one
is, oh my goodness, we pull out the
toilet seat cover and sometimes it falls
in the middle of the toilet and that
makes it really wet and nasty. So, I
mean, we don't want that, right? But
sometimes that happens. The second one
is the DIY method. You know what that
is? Oh my goodness. We saturate the
toilet seat cover with tissue in hopes
that we won't be getting germs from the
toilet. So, that's what happens in the
toilet. So, we swabbed public bathroom
toilets with the covers on the standard
way. Then, we have Ariel's way and we
have Nicole's method. Right. The big
question, do these covers actually
protect you from germs? So, Renata,
Ariel, Nicole, come on out here with the
results from our public restroom survey.
Here they come. Now, according to our
small data sample of public restrooms,
we conducted our swabs using a germ
device. You know, these devices gives
you all a score, right? So, my med unit
ranked you guys. Are you ready for the
results? Yeah. Little nervous. All
right. No. Without any toilet cover,
seat cover at all, the kind of toilet
that that Chuck would never sit on. He
would wash first. 337 was a germ score.
Oh gosh. Not so good. Right. All right.
Now, with the toilet seat cover on the
standard way, which I'll explain in a
second what that is, we found a germ
score of three. Oh, that's fantastic.
Okay. All right. Now, if we modified it
with the wet method like Ariel, we got a
germ score of 39. Oh, that's a lot more
than three. If you make a DIY toilet
toilet paper halo like the Nicole did
and Chuck likes to do, right, you get a
germ score of 12. That's not bad. Not
bad. Right. But it's not any better.
It's certainly easier to take that thing
off there. So, Ariel, will you
reconsider wetting your seat cover
before you sit on it? Of course, you
will. No more wetting. Doesn't it bother
to be wet down there like that anyway?
How do you dry it off? Is that too many
questions? All right. All right. All
right. So, we settled that disposable
toilet seat covers will protect you.
That's what we're going to go with. Now,
let's come over here. One last thing we
got to settle is what do you do with
that darn flap in the middle of the
cover? Right. My question, too. All
right. So, you got you got this toy
cover here. One second. The flap. The
flap. So, here's the deal. Because I do
this so much. All right. The flap
everybody thinks goes in the back
because, you know, it seems intuitive
like this is the shape of the toilet.
So, the flap should be in the back.
Still catch anything. It goes behind
you, right? So you might might it might
act as a catch but no people. No, that
is not how this works. Okay, this goes
in the front. All right, first of all, I
am already feeling so much better about
my life just putting this
down. My life feels safer right now. My
life feels safer. Okay. But it goes in
the front so that when you
flush this water grabs this part and
pulls it in and you don't have to touch
it.
It's genius.
Oh my god. Why am I so happy? Did you
have any idea? I had no idea. I never
touched the thing. I'm with Chuck Knife.
I mean, I get in there and I get to
scrubbing. I lock doors. I get to
scrubbing. But I had no idea. This will
change everyone's life. Put the flap in
the front. I didn't realize. I don't
know. How How did you figure that out?
What's that? How'd you even figure that
out? That is so cool. All I can tell you
is disaster taught me. Okay, now you all
know. Now you feel safe. We're going to
put Chuck's toilet tutorial. We're going
to call it that. Chuck Nice's toilet
tutorial on my website next. I I got
more to go, right? Actually, you know
what? I just got to go myself. But in
the meantime, when we come back, I have
more public bathroom debates to settle.
Should you use hot or cold water when
washing your hands? You know about that?
Yes, I do. We'll find out. And should
you use a hand dryer? Is that the way to
move? Stay with us.
Wife, mother, grandmother. How one woman
hired a hitman to kill her daughter's
best boyfriend. I go behind bars for an
exclusive interview with Melissa
Shfield. That's coming up tomorrow. Hey
guys, I'm here in the bathroom. We're
answering your biggest handwashing
questions. Starting with, is hot or cold
water more effective to wash your hands?
Find out what YouTube science star Nick
Yuas has
uncovered. Everybody knows you're
supposed to wash your hands with hot
water because it kills more germs.
Obviously, your mother, your father,
even your sixth grade health teacher,
Mrs. Schmullenberger, told you that. But
were they
right? As it turns out, the hot water
that we use to wash our hands is only
between 100 and 130° F. And water needs
to be over 212 degrees Fahrenheit to
kill bacteria. And at this temperature,
our skin would burn, leaving us with an
even bigger problem on our hands.
Really, it's the soap and friction that
removes the unwanted bacteria. Fun fact
for you, neither the Center for Disease
Control or the World Health Organization
actually specifies what temperature to
wash your hands. Sorry, Miss
[Music]
Schmullenberger. Yep. At 212 degrees,
water boils. So, to show you what would
happen if I washed my hands with this
water, I'm going to go ahead and dunk my
hand down into this. I'm just kidding.
I'm use my cameraman's hand. There we
go. Yeah. Come on. It's okay. Okay.
Okay. Okay. I'm just kidding. I'm going
to use this steak to represent the skin
on my
[Music]
hand. It's a pretty good piece of steak.
What's most important when washing your
hands is rubbing your hands together to
cause friction for at least 20 seconds,
about the same amount of time to sing
happy birthday. Happy
birthday to
[Music]
me. So, don't forget to rub those hands
while you wash them. But what happens
after you wash your hands? The next
question everyone just wants answered
is, should you use paper towels or a
hand dryer? Take a look at the
experiment that health expert Peter
Deluchia
[Music]
did. If you choose hand dryers because
you think they're the most hygienic
choice at a public restroom, think
again. A new study says hand dryers are
germ spreaders responsible for spraying
bacteria all over. To see if that's true
or just a bunch of hot air, I conducted
a little experiment. But first, a few
facts.
One reason dryers spread germs is
because people have germs on their hands
even after they wash them. Why? Because
only 5% of people wash long enough to
kill infection-causing germs and
bacteria. And only a third of
handwashers use soap. This means germs
are often still on our hands when they
go under the
dryer. Now, back to the experiment.
You're probably wondering why I'm
wearing this hazmat suit. Well, to
protect me from this paint. Think of
this paint as the bacteria and germs
left on your hands after you wash them.
I'm going to put my hands in here and
then we're going to go underneath the
high-speed dryer and let's see what
happens. All on my pants, all over the
wall. What a bacteria
mess. So, we found that if you don't
wash your hands well enough, hand dryers
can spread the germs. But what about the
hand dryer itself? Can it spread germs
to when you clean your hands under it?
Well, we dry your hands under it. So, my
med team researched this and tested 12
hand dryers from across Manhattan and
found that all but one were germfree.
And that that one had germs at such a
low level that it's not really a
concern. So, hand dryers, everybody,
they are safe. They are good to use. But
what about the paper towels, right? We
test the paper towels and they have a
low germ score as well. So low that
there isn't a reason to be concerned.
Paper towels from the dispenser are
safe. So, if you're worried about
getting out of the bathroom germ free,
here's a helpful hack that moms often
tell you to do. You take the paper
towel, right? Dry your hands off. Use
the paper towel to open the door, get
out of the room, and toss paper towel
away. Contamination free. We'll be right
back. Learn something new every day.
It's the return of jerky. This paleo
snack is now out selling chips. That is
so good. But could this low carb meat
treat have hidden ingredients that could
crash your diet? All new Oz? That's
coming up on
[Applause]
Wednesday. It's one of my favorite
phrases and I don't get to say it
enough, so I'll do it right now.
0. Right? We all want things for less,
especially if they can improve our
health. So, here's a question for all
you. Which of these items can you get
for $0? Can you get a cup of coffee for
$0? Or a pack of gum? How about a
newspaper, which they're both on, right?
Not so easy. Or how about a health
insurance plan that may include access
to wellness programs, to vision, dental,
hearing benefits, may even include
prescription coverage. Right? Which one
can you get for
$0? Right? If you guess these, you're
right because it's available now for
some folks. Believe it or not, it is
possible to get health insurance plans
now with a $0 monthly premium. Millions
of people already are doing it and so
could you. Which is why I'm going to
take a few seconds here. I want to talk
about healthcare today because I know it
can be expensive. I hear from you all
the time. So, let me walk you through
this a little bit. You only have so much
money in your piggy bank, right? It's
just only so much there, right? And
counseling and gym memberships, right?
They can cost a little bit of money and
and so these programs can sort of build
up. Prescription drugs can cost a lot of
money, especially if you have to take
more than one. Plus, you got dental and
vision and hearing coverage, right? And
no wonder it feels like your piggy bank.
It just begins to melt away in front of
you to almost nothing. But Medicare
beneficiaries have another option. With
Medicare Advantage, you can get a plan
with $0 monthly premium, which could
mean lots more money in your piggy bank,
which is the goal here. Here to tell us
more is Jalisa Jackson, who's here on
behalf of my trusted sponsorship
partner, medicare advantage.com. Jalisa
is an experienced licensed insurance
agent who has helped thousands of people
learn about their Medicare options,
which is why I trust her. So Medicare
Advantage, walk folks through what it
is. Awesome. So a Medicare Advantage
plan is an option for our Medicare
beneficiaries who are actually looking
to expand their coverage. These plans
are offered by private insurance
companies and provide the exact same
coverage as your Medicare parts A and B.
However, a lot of these plans do provide
you with additional benefits that a lot
of people need, such as prescription
drug coverage, as you mentioned, the
dental, the vision, hearing, and
wellness programs. And I found that
those are game changers for a lot of
people looking to expand their coverage
because original Medicare doesn't
provide services for any of those items
that I just named. Medicare Advantage
plans also include what we call a annual
maximum out-ofpocket limit. So, if you
have a medical emergency or costly
procedure, you're only guaranteed to
spend a certain dollar amount for the
year before the plan picks up. And
that's really great. That's a valuable
layer of protection because if you just
have Medicare parts A and B, there's no
cap to how much you can spend out of
pocket in a year. So, how many of these
plans are there out there? They sound
good. It really is a lot to get out of
one plan. And honestly, Dr. ized.
There's no other option on the market
like this for our Medicare
beneficiaries. Over 2,000 Medicare
Advantage plans are available
nationwide. And most of our Medicare
beneficiaries do have access to the Z
premium plans depending on the area that
they live in. I would think if I could
get potentially 0 expense for some of
the things we just talked about, I'd be
signing up. So why are not more folks
signed up? Well, actually over 20
million people are currently enrolled
into a Medicare Advantage plan. So
that's a lot of people. However, that's
only about a third of our Medicare
beneficiaries. So there's still millions
of people who can have a Medicare
Advantage plan, you know, with less
cost, more benefits if they simply just
look into it. Yeah. Can I speak to the
audience on this? I I bet a lot of folks
are sitting at home right now thinking,
I'm just not going to think about this
right now. Right. Seriously. Right. So
since this show started right almost,
you know, 10 years ago, enrollment in
Medicare Advantage has increased by over
70%. The fact is everyone around you is
signing up, which is why I want you just
to focus and see if it makes sense for
you. If it doesn't, it's fine, but if it
does, stop waiting on the sideline. So
how can folks sign up today? So now is
actually the best time to do it because
it's Medicare's open enrollment until
December the 7th. And for a lot of
people, this is the only time of the
year to get a Medicare Advantage plan.
That's
good. I'm lucky we're doing it today.
So, navigating this can be tough. So,
and let know Medicare itself can be
difficult to understand. So, I want you
to get the right decision and make it
the right way. So, I want to take your
questions. So, put your hands up if
you've got a question. Who's got who you
are here? Go ahead. Take it away, ma'am.
So, who will be eligible for this
Medicare Advantage plan? Oh, that's a
great question. So, generally, if you
currently have your Medicare parts A and
B or someone 65 years of age or older or
under 65 with qualifying disabilities
will qualify for a Medicare Advantage
plan. Okay. Is your mind being changed a
little bit? Perhaps. Perhaps. Good. I
like that. A very discerning viewer. Go
ahead. Take it away. Now, can my husband
and I be on on the same insurance plan
or do we have to each have our own
separate plan? Awesome. So, actually the
Medicare Advantage plans aren't family
plans. So each of you would have to
enroll, but the good thing is these
plans are based on your needs. So your
husband's needs may be different than
yours. So he can have his own plan and
you can have yours. Awesome. That's
perfect. It is right.
She's more optimistic about this idea.
All right. I think look, I I don't I'm
not want to sh you know, I want to nudge
you. I don't want to shove you, but
think about this because 70% increase
since I started the show means a lot to
me. All right. Who's got the last
question? Take away. You said now is a
good time to sign up. Are there any
other times we have that option? Yes.
So, now is actually the best time of the
year because it's Medicare's open
enrollment until December the 7th.
However, there are other times to
enroll. It's just depending on your
circumstance. Thank you. What I'm
hearing is stop waiting on the sideline.
Is that what you're all hearing? It's
the time of the year. Take a moment,
think about it, decide now. So medicare
advantage.com has set up a special phone
number for Oz viewers who want to speak
with a licensed insurance agent about
Medicare Advantage. So give them a call
today. Learn about your options. See
what works for you. They're available to
answer all your questions. Did I miss
anything with the viewers? You did
great. Oh good. I got a good passing
grade from the insurance agent. We'll be
right back.
[Applause]
Wife, mother, grandmother. How one woman
hired a hitman to kill her daughter's
best boyfriend. I go behind bars for an
exclusive interview with Melissa
Shfield. That's coming up
[Applause]
tomorrow. Today, the most Googled health
symptoms in the country. What is a top
health question in your state?
Wisconsin. Well, they're my kind of
state. They're wondering about poop all
the time. Love that. South Carolina,
too. Uh, but they're worried about dark
green stool. H, wonder what they're
eating. Looks like California way over
there. They're wondering about sweaty
palms. You got to wonder why. But
nevertheless, all over the country, the
top three worries that people were
googling were sleep, digestion, and
stress. Let's go to one of the states
that had a question about stress. We're
going to make a Zoom house call to the
state of Virginia and see what the
question is. According to our
state-by-state Gallup poll data from our
partners at ShareCare, Virginia was
actually the 13th best in handling
stress. So, Amber joins us from a state
that knows how to manage stress. What's
your question, Amber?
Hey, Dr. Oz. Everyone in Virginia really
wants to know, does stress cause the
runs?
Does stress cause the runs? Huh? Yes.
Well, it turns out that it can be an
unfortunate side effect of stress. You
know, stress triggers release of
hormones that signaling your body to go
into fight or flight mode. And
unfortunately, side effect of this is
motility in your large intestine because
you don't want to carry all that stuff
around if you're running away from
something that's chasing you, right? So,
it does tend to increase that motility.
So, when the colon moves, it gets you to
have diarrhea at times. But, I'll give
you a little tip to help you from
repeatedly running to the bathroom when
you feel stressed out. Whether you're in
Virginia or anywhere else in the
country, avoid caffeine. That's a
cathartic. It'll move it along.
Carbonated drinks will have that effect.
and actually dairy for some people
because they make your stomach feel
worse. So listen, it's a great question.
I love the fact that Virginia pays
attention to to stress and ask questions
about it. I want you everyone in the
country to see how their state ranks in
health at sharecare.com. Go there, see
where you rank. You might learn
something. Together, change is
happening. Everybody, our journey is
just beginning.
[Applause]
[Music]