Today we're showing you how to make 2019
your most successful year yet. And we
have two sharks here to show you their
tricks to make a million dollars.
They're the same tricks that help my
next guests go from broke dreamers to
millionaire mogul. Please welcome star
the stars of the sharks, Barbara Corkran
and Rohan Ozak.
[Applause]
I am so happy you are here. Nice to see
you. Nice to see you. Roan, how are you?
This side, right. Pleasure. Good to see
you again, my friend. So, these guys, by
the way, they were both wildly
successful, right? But didn't start that
way. And if I just share a little
something about you because I'm Why not?
You're going to share it anyway.
Exactly. These are sharable items. So,
it went from having a thousand bucks
turned into a million dollars. But on
the way, you had 23 jobs. You got fired
from three of them. You had to bring
that up. I wanted to bring that up
because you can do it, right? What got
you motivated to get back on your horse,
fix your finances, and become the person
you are? Well, being fired is a great
motivator because you don't have a job
and I needed the money. So, I had to get
another job. But more much more
important than that is the boss did for
me what I couldn't do for myself, which
was move off of what I didn't do well
and find something that I could really
do well. Well, find your strength. It's
a gift. It's a gift when you get over
the shame. So, Rohan and Barbara are
going to show you three tricks we can
all use today to get us on the
millionaire path. Is that true? Yeah.
You say so. Trick number one is to
increase your stream of
incomes. Akila is here. She has a good
job. Always feels like she's a little
underwater despite that and that your
financially can't get ahead. Difficulty
staying afloat with financially, you
know. And you like the job. Um I like
working. Yes. Okay. It's close. So
explain to Kila. I'd love to know the
difference between the two at some
point. Maybe not enough time today. Why
is watching that your income or changing
your income stream so important? I think
people get stuck on one income stream
and I think you're going to demonstrate
this. Aren't you going to pour it in?
Are you going to pour it on? Actually,
go ahead. No, no, you do it. So, you're
making your job from a job we think you
like. We're not sure. And this is your
budget. This is your budget. You've got
one bucket. You're trying to fill it up.
It's going to take you a long time. If
you had two or three buckets and they're
all pouring together, you would fill
this up. Considering picturing as a
money bank. Oh, here's another one. So,
let's say you have a home rental
business for example, right? Pour that
in there. Right. And you want me to
That's all. I'll be the home rental
income. This is Airbnb being your place.
You're selling old stuff. You're putting
it in there. I'm renting out that
million dollar property I have. Can I
tell you online store? You could do so
many things. The idea is you don't get
stuck thinking you're one person doing
one thing. You could buy the the
terrible house next to you, fix it up,
make it better. Oh, I think you talked
the points. Okay. Well, no. I look at
this now seriously, you have your main
income, right? And then you add all
these other streams, which you point out
is a very important observation. You can
change the size of these, but you're
ultimately floating yourself back up to
being on a budget that you want to live
on. Are there any side hustles that you
might be able to get behind? I mean, we
have great family recipes and I'm I
mean, I'm pretty good cook so I
sometimes cater. more and more people
don't have time to cook at home and but
they want healthier foods and you can't
find them and that a lot of big
companies have exploded with home
delivery but if you can do it just in
your neighborhood that alone is a great
healthier foods are really big deal to
me it's right up my alley I was 340 lb
before you were 340 lb and now I'm okay
that's the story that's like three of
these together you have a story I mean
you you yourself have lost that weight
you've made yourself healthier Mhm. He's
going to fund you. Wonderful. All right.
Come on over. Was it a pitch? Was that a
pitch? I don't know. All right. The next
trick to making a million dollars is not
to wait to automate. So, if you guys can
stand right there, got a little
experiment. Yes. Because this young
woman, Juju, is uh going to want to
learn a bit from you. So, you have we
have a mentality issue here, right? Yes.
So, what do you do with the money that
you make? I try to save it. Try to save
it. Yeah. Or spend it because it's all
over the place. It's hard to do that,
isn't it? put the money aside, which is
probably the biggest problem we have in
America. So, Ran, how do you use this
mentality to make to make millions? So,
first of all, start by pretending that
you only make 80% of your paycheck. It's
like change your mindset. So, 20%
automate goes away. Pretend like it's
the tax man. You can't get it back.
Okay? 10 years later, that's going to
pile up to a ton of money. May not even
take 10 years, even five years. Now, you
have a war chest that you can start
investing with. So let's look at what
Rohan means. This is a really important
principle. So to make it come alive, I'm
going to ask you to step into this phone
booth for a second. Okay? And you see
all the money on the ground there,
right? Yes. It could be yours. Let's
just say your budget
would mean that you could put aside $100
a month. That's $1,200 a year. All
right. So when I turn this on, I just
want you to behave like you're in real
life because that's what real life is
like with money flying around. And I
just want you to grab at $100 a month or
$1,200. You ready to go? Turn it on,
guys. Okay. Grab it. I want to be Go
ahead and grab it. You're on. Good. Good
work. That's it. Good job. All right.
All right. Stop. All right. What do we
have? The year is over. The year's over.
Let's just see what she was able to hold
on to. Okay. Do these count? No, they
don't count. Oh, they definitely That's
exactly the point. They don't count cuz
they slipped out of her fingers. How
much you have there? Let's see. 600.
Less than that. Okay. So, here's the
thing. If you have an automated system
and let's say I'm the automator, right?
I'm the bank and I you just give me $100
a month. The $1,200 gets just put in
your hand right there. It's done. It's
finished. Boom. You automated it. It's
stress free to automate it. And more
importantly, when I put $1,200 in your
hands, it reduces your stress. Half the
people in the country don't have $400 in
an emergency, right? That takes a lot of
pressure on to live your life. That was
stressful. But you struggle. You saw the
stress. You automate it. You take that
30%. Don't spend it all at once. Okay.
Okay. Come on over, guys. The next trick
to make a million dollars is to make
friends that make money move. Make
friends that make money move. We're put
a little pop music in this deal. Oh,
cool. We dance. We dance to it, right?
But is that the same as networking? No.
Networking is so overrated. I think of
networking as walking to a room,
collecting business cards, handing out
your cards. Wrong way to go. I think the
key to building wealth is surrounding
yourself with people within your circle
of influence. People you have some
contact with that have a talent that you
don't have. I know when I started my
business, I was well organized, couldn't
afford an accountant, so I organized his
office every week and he did my
accounting for free. You don't need
money to find talent. Find the people
who are good at it and join forces.
That's how people get rich. You want to
try this little experiment here? Little
social experiment. Abigail, come on in
if you don't mind. So, I met Abigail
just before the show. Come on in. My
sharks here. So, don't be scared of them
because stand right there. They do.
Don't be shy. Do be scared of Bobra. I'm
fine.
They can both be sharks. I've seen them.
All right. So, uh you're one month in
launching a company. Yes. Correct. So,
tell us a little bit about what you're
up to. So, my company, Socktorius, is a
sock line that we launched. I want to
have a product that was in line with my
core values to inspire, to motivate. So,
our socks are beautifully created with
You have them. Oh, you have them on.
Yes. Smart to wear them. Yes. So, what's
the problem? So, the problem is that we
How do I get this out to the American
public? How do I get the sock into the
hands of America with knowing that these
socks have hashtags on it that
motivational hashtags that no excuses?
So, you know, remind you to go ask for
that raise. All right. So, let's take
that. So, we we're all family here at
the show. Yes. So, who might have a
skill set to help publicize a new
company? Right there. Got one. Here.
Come on up here. Number two up here.
What's your name? Alisa. I'm hiding
number two. Alisa, you can stand next to
me. Safer. Okay. So, Alisa, you just
heard the idea. What do you do for a
living? I have my own PR company. There
we go. And what do you So, someone you
trade, right? So, you got to do back. I
would love some socks. I mean, that's
Those are awesome socks, which would
totally look cute with my boots, too.
Yeah. Okay. So, I'll tell you what we'll
do. I'm going to give you guys a little
gift. I want you to go out to lunch on
me. Oh, wow. Work it out. Tell me what
you figure out and just be an example
for the rest of the country. I have a
brilliant idea. If you got to clean
someone's office to get them to chip in
and that which is really what will make
you wealthy to hang with people who can
move money, you should do it. Yeah. God
bless you. Good luck with Storius. Thank
you so much. Byebye. Thank you for
watching. Don't forget to subscribe and
turn on notifications so you never miss
out on new videos to live the good