He was one of the biggest teen idols in
the world with hit records, global
tours, and TV specials. His face was all
over magazines and posters that
plastered the bedroom walls of millions
of teens. But for actor and singer Leif
Garrett, the glare of all that instant
fame led him to self-destruction into
addictions that almost took not only his
life, but his friends as well. Today,
he's burying his soul and revealing his
darkest secrets about how he survived.
He shot onto the scene in the late 60s,
appearing in the hottest TV shows and
even landing a role in the movie that
defined the decade, Bob and Carol and
Ted and
Alice. But his teen heartthrob status
skyrocketed to pop superstardom when he
recorded the hit single I Was Made for
Dancing in 1978. From there, the sky was
the limit for 16-year-old Le Garrett.
But being raised by a single working
mom, Leif lacked a father figure in his
life. Like many child stars with little
or no adult supervision on the road, he
would turn to drugs and alcohol at an
early
age. With international fame, Leif was
running with an A-list crowd and was
given a free pass to do whatever he
pleased. He was exposed to an endless
supply of alcohol, drugs, women, and
near brushes with
death. By the 90s, the handsome teen
idol looked like this. His downward
spiral continued with Leif making
headline after headline for drug arrests
and
relapses. Now he's coming clean about
all of it and what saved him from his
addictions and painful
[Music]
past. Dave Garrett is here in person.
You know, we heard the highs and the
lows. how you survived still a miracle
for many of us to contemplate. Why did
you decide to open up now to tell your
story?
It was the right time. Um I've lived
with some of these uh if you will
secrets for uh quite a while and I I
just needed to clear my conscience, you
know.
Um, and also if anything, if I can help
somebody give, you know, give advice
what to look out for or something like
that, then, you know, that's that's even
better. It's, you know, but I just I
really wanted to uh just tell my story
and and and let people know directly
from me what it's about. You you in your
book, which is fantastic, Idol Truth.
Thank you. Uh you talk about your
childhood about the difficulties uh in
your family. Yeah. So your mom's by
herself as you and your sister, right?
Yes. Decides to put put you into acting
and all of a sudden overnight you're an
incredible child star. What was that
like? Uh it was great. I loved it. You
know, it was it's um you know, it was
first of all, I didn't have to go to
school, regular school. That's good. So
um you know it uh it was just fun too.
It was it was like playtime almost you
know and uh yeah so you're you're riding
high. Now on our show we have talked
about pedophiles in Hollywood. This is
something that you all become aware of
because we've been harping on it because
these are unprotected young people.
There was a producer since passed away
uh that was reported by others not you
to have been a sexual predator of young
boys. Mhm. I know you know this story
and apparently he approached you and
your mom actually more about your
career.
Yeah, he it was under the you know we we
just came back from Israel where we were
for six months and I was I did two films
over there and uh we came back uh you
know all of a sudden we've got somebody
who's Warren Batty's cousin uh who's
associate producer on all of his films
and things like that and he uh you know
was basically under the guise of you
know uh get you into a film with Warren
and and all this and further your career
and nothing ever came of any of that. It
was it was it was creepy. My mom
didn't I I I just I I don't understand
the the train of thought of trusting
somebody that you don't really know,
someone you just met just because that
they're involved in the film business in
a rather good position, so to speak. Um
you know, and Warren B's cousin. As you
look back on interactions with that
gentleman, were there signs that he may
have been grooming you?
Absolutely. Absolutely. I didn't I was
very naive as well, but also very young,
you know. How old were you? I was 15,
16. Yeah, I was 15. Um, and uh we we
played raetball. First of all, he knew
Led Zeppelin was my favorite band. So,
bringing me to a concert, Led Zeppelin
77, uh getting a really nice Jaguar,
rent a car, and here's the Keys kid
drive. and uh oh hey let's let's smoke
some marijuana let's you know stuff like
that you know and you were 50 and how
old was he um I'm guessing around 30
late 30s something like that you know
maybe mid30s and yet there's not it was
an innocent time for all of us it was
it's it's nowadays you this just this
this wouldn't go down like that you know
it's so let's talk about November the
3rd
1979 I'm sitting in Boston in college
and you're almost dying. You're high on
quaudes. Yep. It's uh your 18th birthday
is around then. Yeah, it was uh 5 days
later. So about same age. Uh Dave's car
is on an LA freeway. He crashes it and
it leaves his friend in the passenger
seat at parapolgic for life. Yeah. What
really happened that night? What led to
the accident?
Well,
um just a group of young people hanging
out together, drinking, taking
substances um and because we're feeling
the down effects, looking for something
to lift us up and um we were elected the
ones to go find cocaine. So, you're on
you're high on quao and been drinking.
So, you're partying with your friends.
The two of you leave. Yep. Would you
drive in that state now? Hell no. Do do
you remember the accident? Yeah,
absolutely. Quite vividly.
Um drive we'd actually passed the place
the exit that we knew we were supposed
to get off on a couple of times.
Apparently higher than we thought. Um
and heading back towards the house, he
fell asleep. And I had no idea that
sometimes he fell asleep with his eyes
open.
And I'm holding the steering wheel like
this and I reached over to to, you know,
see if he's okay and just it
car, you know, with the steering the
steering wheel it we uh clipped the rear
end of a another car which spun us
around and then hit the curb and it went
like that down an 80 foot. Flipped over
80 feet. Yeah. Yeah. Oh my goodness.
Yeah. And uh he was he was yelling at me
to to straighten his legs
out and his legs were already
straight and the scent of gasoline was
rather overwhelming and the people who I
clipped were standing up at the
top yelling at me. You know what I was I
crazy you little and and blah blah and
I'm just trying to get help. So I there
used to be the call boxes. Yeah. Um, and
so went up and and I actually was the
one to make the phone call to call the
police and and have them come. And you
divide your life into before November
3rd and after the accident. Yeah. How
has it changed you?
Well, I'm I'm a big- time advocate of
take a
cab. Um, don't drink and drive. Um, and
uh, I wasn't as as close a friend with
the gentleman as you know, Roland as I
was is his name. He has since passed on.
Sorry. Um, yeah. Um,
but it's it's kind of, you know, you got
I had to make better. I wasn't making
great decisions. I
was disillusioned in my own career and
my life at the time.
um taking things I should not have been
taking um but didn't have the parental
guidance that I truly needed. I honestly
wish that I had more discipline in my
life. I truly honestly wished I had
somebody telling me no instead of always
being told sure kid whatever you want.
So coming up the rock bottom moment that
Le says changed everything. Stick with
us. We are back with former teen
heartthrob Leif Garrett who's revealing
the truth about his addictions. Now, in
the wake of a car accident that rendered
his friend a parapolgic for life, life
says his life continued to spiral out of
control. And one of the rockiest times
you argue is when you broke up with
Nicolet Sheridan, which I can understand
how it hit you hard on top of all other
things were going on. Why did the
relationship end? How did it end?
My my career was at that time started
down. Her career was starting up and we
either got we were best friends in the
whole world or we cleared rooms. I mean
it was Was she the love of your life?
Yes. Yes. Um she uh she was my first
real
um deep deep love.
So, in the meantime, you turned to
partying and you continued to crumble
under the weight of your addictions. I'm
going to read this little excerpt from
Idol Truth because I think it was
compelling. Uh, I could handle the
drinking. I could handle the cocaine. I
could handle the quaudes. The heroin was
a whole other story. When did you start
using heroin? Oh, man. That was it was
much later on um in my life.
Um, it was when I was trying to
resurrect the musical
career
and all of my heroes in
music were known to partake and and a
lot of them like, you know, Keith
Richards, um, you know, any of the guys
from the Stones, Aerosmith, um,
Zeppelin, you know, I thought being
categorized in that sort the group would
maybe further or help my moving on to
the rock and roll, the real rock and
roll, you know. So, you get up to $300 a
day smoking blacktar heroin. Yes. When
did you finally hit rock bottom? I think
uh three months in county jail was
pretty much Yeah, that that was Yeah,
there's a that's a great photo right
there, isn't it? That's a good one. That
that haunts the hell out of me, that
photograph. I got to for good reason.
Yeah, exactly. So, Shabbou came out this
week and said getting arrested,
which happened while I was making my
brother-in-law's movie, by the way. Wow.
Uh, saved his life. Did these guys save
your life?
Huh? I guess in a in a in a in a very
profound way. Yeah. you know, because
being locked up is, you know, not having
your freedom is is a really
strong signal, you know, it's it's
very I don't think you realize how
important it is until you lose it, you
know, as as such with many things, you
know. Yeah. How has your recovery been?
I've had my ups and downs with it, you
know, take it one day at a time. I found
though, it's interesting because a lot
of
people subscribe to the the meetings and
things like that. I personally found
every time I went to the the meetings, I
wanted to use more afterwards because
people get up and talk and they're like,
"Oh man, I remember when we this and it
was so great and we were hiring a kite
and we
d and it's a big pickup joint, you know,
right? Oh, I swear to God, it's so funny
because everyone is there changing one
addiction for another one. And you
cannot get sober unless you want to
quit. Um, but you have to to
to check out the things that made you
start using in the first place and then
want to not do it. Come on over with me.
I want you to share something. This
audience loves you. And I love them.
They're
they're representing the pain that a lot
of Americans feel because addiction is
such a big part of our lives. So, come
join me on the stoop here. Have a seat.
All right. I'll I'll turn it over to
you. What's the advice you would give
folks about addiction? What would you
have to say to folks who are struggling
right now? Where where you were when you
got put in
jail? You got to figure out if that's
the road you want to continue down. It's
not a pleasant road. It's um a lot
of it's a lot of pain and suffering and
it's important to want to not do it
because you can't stop unless you want
to stop.
Thank you very much. Thank you. Very
well said. Thanks for your story. Next
memoir, Idle Truth is fabulous. Pick it
up. Thank you for watching. Don't forget
to subscribe and turn on notifications
so you never miss out on new videos to
live the good