Where do we go when we die? We're
unraveling this medical mystery and
examining the last moments of life.
>> And I remember feeling so at peace and
so free of all the burdens in life.
>> Plus, the ladies of the real ask your
burning health questions.
>> Got one that I'm almost too embarrassed
to ask.
>> Coming up next.
[Applause]
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10?
>> Yeah.
[Music]
>> I love you, Becca.
>> All of a sudden, I heard a voice.
>> When I opened my eyes, I was no longer
on Earth. In just a moment, I was
somewhere else.
>> Today, we unravel a medical mystery.
What do we really know about where we go
when we die? We're about to take an
eyeopening look into the moment when
your body takes its last breath and what
comes next. Dr. Jeffrey Long, who has
studied over 4,000 cases of people who
had near-death experiences, joins us
with the latest research in the death.
Pastor Corey Hendrick will show us where
faith and science intersect in death.
Plus, we hear from two women who say
they passed over and managed to return.
What they saw might bring you hope.
Let's start with the latest science of
death. Dr. Long, thanks for being here.
Pleasure.
>> There's a a lot of new information about
what happens to our body when we die.
Please share that with us. Sure.
>> We always thought that dying was like an
on and off button. you go from being
alive to permanently dead. But in recent
years, scientists are finding new
evidence that says that when we die, our
brain cells may take hours and possibly
even longer to become irreversibly
damaged leading to death. We now think
of death as a process occurring over
time and not a sudden abrupt end of
everything. What are the similarities
that you're identifying? What people see
and where they go in these near-death
experiences?
>> Well, while no two near-death
experiences are the same, there are some
characteristic features that are
commonly observed. In my studies, I
found that 45% had an outof body
experience. 64% met a mystical light and
74% had a level of consciousness and
alertness during their experience even
greater than they had during their
earthly everyday life. Other
characteristics include intense
generally positive emotions. They may
review their prior life experiences.
They may meet deceased loved ones and
they may even be involved in a decision
about a return to their earthly life. I
love when scientists can bridge this gap
into the unknown because we don't know,
right? You can't possibly know for sure.
So, let's explore where faith and
science intersect with death. Just like
a doctor, a faith leader is one of the
last people that a person will see
before they die. Pastor Corey Hendrick
is not only seen patients by the bedside
and by their in their homes, but he's
also worked in a funeral home as well.
So, you just heard a science leader talk
about where doctors might think your
body goes when you die. Of course,
>> as a faith leader, where do you think we
go? What happens to our spirit?
>> Well, first of all, Dr. Oz, we have to
understand that we are tripartite
beings, which means we're made up of
body, spirit, and soul. Uh our body, if
you will, is the physical aspect of our
being, whereas our spirit is the
non-physical aspect of our being, and
the spirit actually leaves the body. And
so we believe that you don't die and go
directly to heaven, but there is
somewhat of a waiting area. Some would
call several types of waiting area
purgatory, but we refer to it as
paradise or Abraham's bosom. And uh our
faith teaches us that and that's what we
tend to lead to believe and what gives
us courage and faith every single day.
>> Let me show what happens next. And then
you say the next stage is about heaven,
>> correct?
>> Right. So help us understand what that
might look like. Give us a an idea of of
what that might feel like.
>> Well, many would look at it as a glacial
type place. Some people think of the
clouds. Um some people think of maybe
even um a land flowing with milk and
honey because scriptures does allude to
that. Now obviously we know everyone
doesn't believe the same thing, but
research as you know it helps us be
stronger. It help us understand what
we're really saying and that way we can
fact check and then we learn more. and
fulfills our needs in different ways. An
even clearer picture of what happens
when we die is emerging from those who
have actually experienced death. They've
actually been there themselves. This
next story defies all odds. I know about
it personally. Take a look.
>> I was married in 2008 and 2 months later
I found out I was diagnosed with Hodkins
lymphoma. I began 6 months of
chemotherapy.
I ended up in remission. Everything was
going well. All of a sudden, one day I
just started not feeling well. I was
complaining to my husband that both of
my arms felt heavy. That's when he
rushed me to my local hospital. After we
arrived, I flatlined right in his arms
and doctors were unable to resuscitate
me for over 90 minutes. That was the
moment that I immediately crossed over.
[Music]
>> That was Sher who flatlined for nearly
90 minutes. She's here today to share
what happened after her heart stopped
and what she learned when she came back
to life. I've got to say I I know your
story personally, so I knew it took a
series of miracles to get just to be
sitting next to me today. But I want to
examine what was happening inside of
you, your experience while we were
outside trying to save your life.
>> Yeah.
>> What were those last moments like when
life was slipping away?
>> Um, I remember it being really quick
actually. Um, I remember a couple of
seconds right before I flatlined and I
remember saying to myself, "Wow, I had
spent my whole life worrying and and
seeing like wondering how do you prepare
for that moment when you die?" And the
first thought in my mind was that was so
easy and it was so quick and I remember
feeling so at peace.
There were other beings there as you
describe it. What were they doing? What
were they saying?
>> Yeah, it was interesting because um from
this this instant moment where I crossed
over, it it was really this beautiful
white white light. So, it wasn't scary.
Um I was very safe and I found myself
surrounded by like six beings and they
were surrounding me in like a circle and
I felt free. And I remember realizing
that they were talking to me
telepathically.
And one of the things that I was trying
to say to them was, "I know I died. I
know I know why I'm here. I love it
here. It's beautiful. It's peaceful. I
want to stay." And they gave me time to
think about that. And that's when um a
series of lifetime reviews began. And it
wasn't just a lifetime review of the
past life I had just left. It was a
lifetime review of just every single
lifetime that my soul had ever
experienced.
>> I'm smiling because I I've heard similar
stories from my own patients and since
doing the show and you know after 10
years you get to talk to all the real
world experts. You keep hearing these
recurrent concepts. Let me show everyone
else what they would have seen if they
were there watching you. And what saved
your life is technology that's
relatively new. Your past lives wouldn't
been able to benefit from it. something
called an elvad or left ventricular cy
device, a life-saving tool that kept
Sherry alive by hooking up to her heart
and then taking the blood out of the
heart because the heart can't pump it on
its own anymore. And this mechanical
device and you know it sort of
circulates through here and pumps the
blood back up. So it it's a piggyback
heart. Now, I helped research and
develop uh these elvads and I ran
Columbia's program where Sher actually
had her surgery and then the program
when I came to do the show was led by my
colleague and close friend of 25 years,
Dr. Yoshi Naka. He now runs the program
and he was the one who actually saved
Sher's life.
>> And I'm always curious to talk to
physicians, especially if I ever fall
over and need heart surgery, send me to
him.
>> Yes.
>> The best surgeon that I know. So what
were you thinking about when you first
saw Sherry's case? This is not going to
be a pretty picture for any physician to
look at.
>> Well, that I thought the chance is slim.
Uh simply based on the uh the history
that she was uh CPR, she had CPR 90
minutes. The uh our data shows that that
kind of a long CPR usually not
is not associated with a good result.
>> Yeah. Not having a good result is the
same as having a really bad result.
>> And Sher, what do you have to say to Dr.
Naka?
>> Oh my goodness. I mean,
>> thank you. Thank you for everything.
>> My pleasure.
>> Without without the ELVAD, I would not
still be alive. Um, that's for sure. I
was on the ELVAD for 4 and a half years
until my heart transplant. So, thank you
for not only saving my life but being so
supportive and so good to my family and
we are forever forever grateful to you.
>> I'm glad you're doing well. Sherry,
thank you for sharing your story. Yoshi,
as always, for being the best. Thanks
for being here. Up next, what another
woman who nearly died says pushed her
back to life and what everyone who's
lost a loved one needs to know right
now. Stay with us.
[Music]
[Applause]
Ah, the sizzle of bacon.
Could this breakfast stable put you at
risk? The story you haven't heard. Is
there a bacon cover up?
And we've got the scoop on low calorie
ice cream. They claim you can eat the
whole pint. Is that a blessing or a
curse? Plus, six reasons to fall for
Shamora Moore. It's real.
All new.
That's coming up on Monday.
>> When I was a psychologist working with
the terminally ill cancer patients, many
times they saw old relatives or angels
and I doubted that it actually could be.
But that changed when I had my own
experience.
I was working out at the gym and all of
a sudden I had burst a cerebral
aneurysm. The ambulance took me to the
hospital. I was admitted into the
surgical ICU unit. They said, "You're
really sick. We're going to take you to
another room."
That's when I looked up and saw the
light and I started moving toward it and
I realized I was crossing over.
>> Today, we've been asking, "What do we
know about where we go when we die?" You
just heard from Mary Joe whose friends
and family were preparing to say goodbye
to her,
>> but you're still here.
>> Yes.
>> Which I'm happy about.
>> I'm very happy.
>> What do you remember about those moments
when you're on the brink on the next to
the abyss of of death?
>> What I remember is that this light I saw
was so interesting. It was not like a
light I had ever seen before. And I was
in it. It's like it came and embraced
me. I was in it. And as I was going into
it, I felt like I also saw behind me and
I was able to see my body, but I had no
attachment to it at all. And then the
the place the the tunnel was so warm and
just comforting.
And as I moved through it, then I came
to a larger room.
>> And what ultimately pushed you back
towards us? Well, when I came to this
other room that was a pink luminous
color, I had the feeling that God was
holding me and he talked to me and he
called me by my name and the first thing
he said is, "Mary Joe, you cannot stay."
And I was very upset because I wanted to
stay. It it was so beautiful. And um I
started saying why not? I protested and
then it its voice was just in my skin
and it said, "Let me ask you one thing.
Have you ever loved another human like
you've been loved here?" And I said,
"No, it's impossible."
>> But you had to come back even though you
wanted to stay.
>> Yes. It told me I said when I said I
could not um love like that, it held me
close and it said you can do better. And
>> you can do better.
>> I woke up
>> with your husband next to you. with my
husband crying next to me and
and he was um really scared and he said
that they had told him that um I may not
come back the same but he had to sign
these consents and he was so scared to
make this decision and I said just sign
it. I'm not going to die. I just talked
to God and I didn't know in what
capacity, but I knew I would live.
>> Let me bring Sher back in because both
of you have had near-death experiences.
You've had a second chance. What do you
have to say to people who may have lost
someone they've loved dearly and are
feeling pain because of that?
>> Yeah, I mean, I I absolutely felt
connected and could still connect with
people that were in in my life even
though I was on the other side. And I
really want people to know, especially
around the times of the holidays and
especially when you're used to having
these special traditions with your loved
ones, they may not physically be around,
but they can still feel you. They're
still connected to you. And you can take
the time to really just reach out and
connect with them. You can speak with
them. You can think about them and know
that you're really not separated from
them. They're just in another form.
And all is not lost. They are still
there. They're still connected to your
heart. If
>> you don't mind, I I don't do this too
often, but there's someone in the
audience who seems to have been touched
by this.
>> You okay if I ask you a question?
>> Yes.
>> Why was uh Sherry's comments affected
you so deeply?
>> Both of us have lost pretty much our
whole families. As a matter of fact, we
were sitting right over there last year
when uh his mom was here with us and
she's not now. And uh we're dreading the
holidays. So, because they're all gone,
but you guys have brought us so much
comfort saying that. And not that we
>> I hope the holiday is a measure for you.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless you for coming back. Thank
you.
>> Sherry Mary Joe, thanks for for being
here. We'll be right back, everybody.
[Applause]
[Music]
>> These roses are for a group of women who
made me their #mancrush Monday. I was
surprised and honored. The women of the
real. Dearra, Lonnie, Adrien, and
Janine. Come on up.
There's something else.
[Applause]
How are you?
>> Gosh, I love the energy.
So look, Adrian, I was so flattered. I
really was. And I know the ideal dream
is to get get checked out plus the
hoverboard date, but
>> but I'm a heart surgeon.
>> Okay.
>> So, I thought I'd honor you with a
little bit of poetry
>> from the heart.
>> Oh, what's happening?
>> Wait. Oh, cute.
>> Some say it takes two, but you are the
one who gives my heart
>> palpitations.
Lonnie, Lonnie, it's your comedy that
fills me with jubilation.
>> Oh,
>> Genie, you you give my heart a workout
full of circulation.
>> And Adrien, oh my Adrien, without your
friendship, I'd ask for a do not
resuscitation.
>> Yes.
>> Very lovely.
>> That was amazing.
I could never top you guys, but I think
>> all my dreams come true right now.
>> Oh my goodness.
>> So, part of the reason I want to thank
sexy. Yeah,
>> you're very kind.
>> Very nice.
>> Oh, I like that.
>> It's fun. So, I've enjoyed visiting you.
I enjoyed watching the real and I know
you have lots of questions. So, we can
dive into it. I know you got a long
laundry list.
>> Okay.
>> Who's first?
>> I'll go first.
>> First. Take it.
>> Okay. Is hangry actually a real thing?
And why do some people experience more
than others? Like Lonnie.
>> Now, you all know hangry is when you're
angry when you're hungry. We all know
that, right? We have that in our friend.
So, Lonnie, since she brought you and
threw you under the bus.
>> Yeah.
>> Can I just brag on you for a second?
>> Oh, what?
>> The Lonnie's loss challenge. You
probably all heard about it,
>> but I've specifically seen it on Lonnie.
I've got some pictures of you. went from
a size 24 to a size 18 if I can brag on
you.
>> That's a major difference.
>> Thank you.
>> It's so It is hard. It's kudos to you,
but sometimes hanger accompanies the
loss in dress sizes.
>> Yes. And I just want to thank my co-host
because they deal with me being, you
know, hangry. So, we really need help to
help me to be better to my co-host.
>> Right. Let me show you what's going on
with you, L. But it happens to all of
us. Most of us. I should say all of us.
When your when your blood sugar falls,
right, your body's natural response is
to try to help the dropping blood sugar
by elevating two hormones called
cortisol and epinephrine. You've heard
of them, right? And those make you
hangry because they're there for the
blood sugar, but they're not there for
all the other side effects of taking
hormones, right? So all of a sudden
you're irritable, you're angry, you're
frustrated, and without realizing it,
hangry is coming out of every word you
say.
>> Wow, wow. That is me. I am that thing
right there
>> with hangry pouring out. And epinephrine
makes your heart go faster, right?
>> It does. But it's interesting, hormones
influence in such powerful ways. We
don't always figure it out till later
on. But again, you want those hormones
because they get your blood sugar up
temporarily.
>> So the best thing you can do is use food
instead of the hormones. So what do you
snack on when you feel hungry?
>> Carbs. We do a lot of chips. We do pop
chips. We do skinny popcorn.
>> Pita chips.
>> Skinny popcorn's good. Okay. Chips. I'm
worried about definitely not skinny.
M&M's. You know the problem is our
natural instinct is to take sugar in
because we're low on sugar. But the
things that have a lot of sugar in them
actually mess up your hormones even
worse. So they worsen the hanginess.
You're okay for 5 minutes. You burn
greatly but briefly then
>> you can't and then you can't pull up
anymore cuz you got no sustenance.
>> So I've got the solution for you. Tell
us
>> cuz I love you so dearly. This is what I
eat.
>> Blackberries.
>> Really?
>> That's me in my dressing room right
there.
>> You know they say the blacker the berry,
the sweeter the juice.
>> Wa
wa.
Yes.
>> Well, these these are all yours, my
dear. Blackberry from Blackberry.
>> All right. Speaking of of topics that
are interesting, you got another
question right here, Lahy.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. I enjoy wine, and we all do.
>> Yeah.
>> Is it still okay? Yeah. Is it still
beneficial to have one glass a day?
>> Just one glass.
>> Just one.
>> Well, you know, I might
>> She'll have two.
>> Maybe two. How how many members of the
panel like to enjoy a glass of wine?
>> Oh, yes.
>> Oh, Adrian doesn't.
>> I have recognized that just at I'll be
35 in a week and a half, I can get a
hangover from just one glass of wine.
>> No, I'm not lying. Like, I literally and
it's just not worth it to me anymore.
>> Yeah. Well, it's one of the problems.
>> Makes me feel terrible.
>> Well, then I'll just take her a glass of
wine.
>> Like, I literally will feel awful.
And I and I used to love drinking when I
was younger.
>> Guys, cheers guys.
>> Cheers.
>> I feel so left out.
>> Dr. Oz, this is so cool. It's real wine.
>> I know it's good wine. But here's the
catch. Should you be drinking it? So,
here's the thing. All my career, I've
been telling folks cuz I was told this
by my teachers that a glass of wine a
day was actually good for you. And we
know that other parts of the world that
tends to be sort of true. But then this
huge study that just came out breaking
news everybody
>> and it's alarming to me because it says
that current recommendations probably
aren't right
>> that we should not be drinking a glass
of wine a day. It says that drinking a
glass of wine every day can increase the
chance of dying for example from cancer
by 30%.
>> What?
>> Yes. What a downer, right? That's
stated. That's stated. There's a lot of
other studies that say historically like
when I was learning the stuff that is
actually okay. So what are you going to
say? I went through them all. I had my
medical unit. You know we got this whole
group of folks are pretty young doctors.
>> Sure. that that went through this all
and after a lot of effort we came up
with a conclusion that I think most
doctors will agree with.
>> Okay.
>> Which is you can protect your health
with wine because it does have a benefit
to your heart.
>> If you drink it once every other day, so
three times a week.
>> So three times a week. That's not that
bad. I
>> not bad. You can do that.
>> Yes.
>> Not that size though.
>> Up next, another hot topic. We're
investigating longlasting polish. Nail
polish. It doesn't chip. You guys all
like it. You're all wearing it. Looks
pretty. But there's an ugly truth about
the health risks of using them. Stick
around.
[Applause]
>> Ah, the sizzle of bacon. Could this
breakfast staple put you at risk? The
story you haven't heard. That's coming
up on Monday.
>> Hey fam. So, I'm backstage at the Real
and we are about to go see Dr. Oz. I
don't know if you know this, but we're
kind of obsessed with nails up in here.
So, we're going to see if he can match
the manicure to the host. You got this,
Dr. Oz.
>> So, I always love a good challenge.
We're going to see which of these
manicures are also beautifully done, are
owned by which member of the real. So,
first of all, I'm going to go with
Lonnie on that one.
>> Oh, how you guess that?
>> I'm just guessing. Beginner's luck.
>> Uh, Jeie, I'll take you on this one.
>> Okay,
>> let's see. Uh,
>> hey.
All right, I'll go with Adrien and
Tamara.
>> Right.
>> And actually, I didn't cheat. Well, I
had a little help from Ronnie, so I
didn't cheat.
>> Okay, now that I passed that test,
question is, are they good for you? So,
is longlasting nail polish, which I know
is dominating everyone's
>> attention span worthwhile. What do you
guys think?
>> Who cares? They're so worth it.
>> Okay. Do I think it's good for you? No.
Do I think it's like gonna kill you? No,
either. But maybe I could be wrong.
>> So, have you ever wondered what's in
those acrylics? Those different
chemicals and then
>> I have smell it.
>> Yeah.
>> I always wonder why they have a mask on
and why I don't.
>> True. It's true.
>> Do you all use longl lasting nail
polishes?
>> Yeah. Gel.
>> I I do the gel because they last for two
weeks longer usually.
>> I do it cuz I'm lazy cuz I don't want to
keep, you know, repainting. Plus, we
work so hard. So, I just just, you know,
there it's longlasting. Great.
>> And we bake them in acrylic. We do
acrylics going through. See, I don't do
acrylics. Is gel Are gels just as bad as
acrylics?
>> Well, here's the thing. These
long-lasting polishes all have something
special in them. They wouldn't last so
long otherwise, right? They're different
from regular polishes. So, there was a
reason the top the top coat, by the way,
is is more resilient, harder, so that's
why it works. And there were chemicals
in these polishes that worried me a lot.
I did shows on them.
>> None of them contain those chemicals.
>> None of them.
>> Oh, wow. Really?
>> Yes. So, kudos to the manufacturers.
They actually listened to what we're
talking about.
>> That's good.
But again, another question that that
takes care of the toxicity issue, but I
want to talk about what happens to your
own natural nail when you have those
long-lasting polishes on. So, Junior,
come on over cuz you're you're curious
about that.
>> What's happening? Face the truth.
One of my audience members volunteers. I
Oh,
>> okay.
>> She wants extra wine. So, Marcy's
joining us and she's going to allow us
to put her nails
>> I under a magnifying glass. I understood
you took your polish off for us today.
>> I did. It was not easy.
>> May I examine you?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. So, you notice there's one nail
here that's been left
>> barren. This is Now, see the nail?
>> See how it's sort of chippy? Let me go
back up here to the See the cuticle,
>> girl.
>> Now,
>> that is not pretty.
>> Well, first of all, be brave for letting
me do this, but secondly, you're not
alone either, cuz see how chip see the
actual nail is chipping?
>> Yeah. What's it supposed to look like?
Smooth.
>> Well, it's supposed to look more like
this.
>> Oh. Doctor,
>> that's a healthy looking nail.
>> Now, I have to scrub my nails to
operate. So, it's not quite what it
should be, but it's it's a little
better. And the main difference is I
don't put nail polish on, at least in
public,
>> right? So, so, so when you see that,
does that makes you concerned at all,
Marcy?
>> Absolutely. I mean, even without that,
I'm concerned.
>> And Genie, these beautiful fingers are
yours.
>> I mean, look at my manicure, you guys.
Everybody, look at the tips. It's a half
matte with a little shine. I mean,
elegantly, I like everything you do, but
are you worried about the underlying
nail?
>> I should be, but I don't know why I
should be because to be honest with you,
even if it looks like that underneath,
that's why I keep getting it covered.
So, what what should I be afraid of?
>> Let's join your colleagues. Thank you
very much, Marcy. Cuz I think that's the
key question. What we going to do? I
know I know you're not going to stop
your nail polish,
>> right? I've already tried that
experiment with my daughters. Doesn't
work. Right. So here's what I first of
all there you know nail polish the
holiday is a idea that's catching on now
which means when you take off the old
polish give it a couple days
>> for your natural nail to breathe. Okay?
>> Because the reason these polishes work
in part is they can really embed
themselves deep into the top layers of
the nails. So when you take it off
allowing them to sort of regenerate a
little bit is valuable. But the other
thing is you guys probably use acetone
to take them off.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. I don't I get I get it. It's
faster. But there are non acetone
products out there that don't dry out
the nail cuz you know the part of what
happens is the the long-lasting polishes
suffocate the nail then you dehydrate
them more with the acetone.
>> So use one of the non acetone products
takes a few seconds extra but that
>> a few seconds.
All right.
>> You're right. It takes a lot longer when
you're rehearsing for the real. Just sit
there for a couple hours. Peel it off.
>> All right.
>> All right. Now, this whole thing so far
has been a preamble to what I'm really
excited about, which is your last
question. Cuz when we come back, the
real question these women have been
wanting to ask me since they got here,
you're going to hear it and it might
make you blush. In fact, I know it will.
>> Oh, no.
[Music]
We're back with the burning medical
questions and the host of the real. This
is one they've been dying to ask. One of
you wrote down a question with a card on
it and slipped it backstage to my
producer, Tanal. So, I'm just warning
everybody, it might be inappropriate for
kids. Uh,
>> oh, yeah. I'm not sure yet. Tenil, can
you read it, please?
>> Is it possible to break a man's penis
during sex?
>> Good question.
>> Good question. But the question, did you
ask it? So, I actually had my audience,
>> look at all the guys in the audience.
Their faces like
>> they all sat up tall. They sat up tall.
>> So, I asked the audience who they
thought asked that question cuz I was
curious what they think about you guys
cuz they're all big fans, right? So,
each audience member was supposed to
place a little marble into a jar if they
thought that co-host of the real asked
the question. Here they are. You see
who's voting for you, who's not voting
for you, right? There you are. All four
names there, right? And who did they
think asked the broken penis question to
Neil?
>> Who's the winner?
>> What name is that?
>> Lonnie.
>> Well, it looks like Lonnie.
>> Lonnie Love.
>> Really? Audience?
>> I just got a visual.
>> I have an electrical engineering degree.
I already know the answer.
>> Go get her.
>> All right.
>> Go get her. All right. No. So, you
didn't ask the question, I gather from
that response. All right. Will the real
guilty host please stand?
>> Oh,
good question.
>> You said stand.
>> I'm standing.
>> I'm I'm still newly married and I'm
trying to hold on to a good thing, you
know? I don't want things going wrong.
>> Is that why you asked the question?
>> I just want to make sure.
>> Is that what sparked the question?
>> Yeah. I don't Yeah. So, if uh
>> this can get a little crazy.
>> Yes, I'm proud of you for that. Uh if
you're brave enough to join me over
here, I'm going to show you what's going
down with this question. I am brave
enough to
>> It actually happens. It happens.
>> You see?
>> All right. So, I made you a a simplified
animation. I'll call it that. All right.
And we're standing on it, right? And
there's actually a casing around the
penis that's pretty thin. And when the
penis flexes like this, I'm standing on
it. But look, look right there. It
breaks. See the crack? And when that
break happens, now you got a problem
because it's called the tuna albina,
that casing. And when it begins, lots of
blood starts to pour out. It fills up
the penis with blood, which is not very
prettyl looking. But on the outside,
here's what you see. That big growing
bruise, the swelling.
>> You haven't seen that, have you?
>> No. But I don't want to. I want to avoid
this.
>> That's Well,
>> what can cause this? Well, uh, it's
usually younger men,
>> oh,
>> who are involved,
>> okay?
>> Men in their 20s and 30s, they tend to
be more vigorous, I'll say.
>> Mhm.
>> And the problem with that, of course, by
it can happen to any age group person.
So, but there are certain sexual
positions that tend to be more
problematic than others,
>> which I I can point them out if you're
interested.
>> Gosh.
>> So,
>> this can get this can get crazy. So when
please please have a seat. When uh when
when the woman's on top, it's a bit more
of a problem
>> because usually it happens because an
erect penis hits something hard, misses
the target, so to speak.
>> Oh,
>> and when you miss the target, then the
guy would jump up as a snapping sound
>> which you hear.
>> What's the
>> I didn't know a penis can snap.
>> Well, Tamar is curious now.
>> Yes. See, it was a good question. You
know that that that casing that that
little you don't have you don't have a
>> this happened to me in ' 86. So I'm just
listening. It happened to me.
>> Keep going. Keep going.
>> So you have like a hot dog has a little
piece of so the skin on the outside that
that cracks. It snaps
>> and you can hear it and then once it
cracks all the blood happens and you
actually have to requires an operation
or you'll be
>> Look at their faces.
>> An operation.
>> Like what do they do? that you actually
stitch back the casing. Otherwise, the
penis will stay bent the rest of his
life.
>> How long do you have to abstain?
>> Oh, no.
>> How long?
>> How long does that take you to?
>> We're going to keep talking after a
couple weeks.
>> Did you see that? That's why they say we
men, we made you and we could break you.
>> Ronnie, Adrian, Genie, and the mayor.
Thank you for being here today. Love you
guys. You can watch the real every day.
Check your local listings. I'll be right
back.
Ready
for this?
>> It's the dish on Oz. Our brand new food
series.
>> Make it tasty.
>> Daffy Oz and Friends.
>> We're serving it up every Wednesday in
November. The dish on Oz.
[Applause]
[Music]
Nurses. Ah, nurses. They are the heart
and soul of our healthcare. and I know
firsthand the integral role that they
play in providing education and care and
especially healing to everyone around
them. I personally have depended on the
wisdom and the guidance, support and
nurturing of nurses throughout my career
as a surgeon, which is why I am so proud
to be celebrating them with the first
ever future of nursing scholarship
contest.
They deserve this. Take a look.
It's a global scholarship contest that
started in Asia with our partner Esana
Health Sciences from China to the
Philippines and onto Singapore.
>> We wanted to reward nurses who represent
the future of health. Find out how they
are helping you. And now the contest is
making its way to the US. We've already
received hundreds of submissions from
nurses around the world. They told us
what inspired them to become a nurse.
>> My mother unexpectedly passed away. Ever
since then, I've had a bigger drive to
be something.
>> I can't stand being powerless, being in
a state or a place where I don't feel
like I'm doing as much as I can.
>> My dad had a heart attack. My mom had a
total thyroidctomy. I share those things
because that's what inspired me to
become a nurse.
>> What the job means to them.
>> It's my my purpose. I found something I
see myself doing far into the future.
>> The nurse isn't just there to heal the
person physically to help with their
pain, but they're also there to be that
patient's advocate to make sure that
they are mentally getting what they need
and the emotional support that they need
>> and why they represent the future of
nursing. When I become a nurse, which I
know I'm going to for sure become a
nurse, I'm going to make sure that every
patient is treated how how I wanted my
grandma to be treated inside of that
nursing home.
>> I want to be a voice and guide other
people and help other people.
>> I want to grow and I want to be the best
nurse I can possibly be.
>> Nurses, the unsung heroes of healthcare,
dedicate their lives to helping and
healing others. That's why I partnered
up with USANA to give nurses this
ultimate opportunity. The future of
nursing essay contest will award a lucky
winner with $10,000 towards nursing
school tuition.
The applicants have been pouring in, but
there's still time for you to enter. Go
to dr.com for all the details and make
sure to enter by November 15th.
>> I am the future of nursing.
>> I'm the future of nursing. I am the
future of nursing because I want a
career that's challenging, interesting,
and I want to make a difference in
people lives every day.
>> Could you be the face of the future of
nursing?
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh my, the submissions keep rolling in.
It's not too late for you to enter. I'm
here to tell you more about this contest
is health coach and former nurse Angela
Gray, who's here on behalf of my trusted
sponsorship partner, USANA Health
Sciences. Why was it so important for
USANA to start this this contest?
>> Um, I think actually because I am a
former nurse. I grew up with my mom who
was a nurse. I've seen firsthand myself
like you've shared how important nursing
is and how hard they work. I had an
actual experience with my son and a
nurse who almost died when he was a
baby. And so um the first, you know,
they're often the first responders like
you mentioned. I think um the the stance
that USANA is taking and being so
supportive of these nurses and what they
do is so so important and shows their
support in all parts of the health
industry. So I'm really really proud to
be part of that. My mom was a nurse. I
grew up watching that. My daughter's a
nurse. My son and my other two daughters
are both in the health industry. So it's
a big part of who we are as well. So I'm
so excited to see you son of support the
nurses in this way.
I spoke earlier of how much I've been
touched by nurses, but I remember
vividly Flora Wong who was the head
nurse in the operating room when I
started. Yeah.
>> And Flora would look over my shoulder
when I was finishing open heart surgery.
And one of the big complications we have
is bleeding because you have to give
heavy doses of blood thinners. You put
hundreds of stitch of stitches in so
little holes can bleed. And she would
tell me if she thought the patient had
stopped bleeding enough to close their
chest.
>> Yeah.
>> And she say, you know, I say Flora, what
do you think? says, "It must be more
like the Sahara Desert."
>> Yeah.
>> And that was her goal. We had to be that
dry, that free of blood.
>> And it wasn't just nice to have her pat
on the back and say, "Good job." It also
meant that someone with a lot of
experience who had seen many, many
operations and knew what success looked
like and what failure could look like,
warned me,
>> which is what nurses often do. They're
that early detection system. They'll
often tip us off to issues we may not
pick up on, which is why when you talk
to your nurses,
>> they translate that back to us. It makes
everything work better.
>> Absolutely. So, what attributes are you
looking for in this nursing competition?
>> Um, not only a knowledgeable nurse, like
you were saying, for sure. Absolutely. A
competent nurse, but really I love the
way um that we're moving in towards more
holistic care. So, really someone that
first of all and foremost that they
understand how important their own
self-care is. This is a really, really
tough job, right? And often times we put
ourselves last. So, that's really
important to me because you can
recognize a nurse when she walks in if
she cares about herself, quite honestly.
And if she does, then that's going to be
paid forward in her compassion, in the
innovative way she gives the care, being
motivated. So all of those reasons. So
self-care is really important and
looking for um a well-rounded nurse who
understands the holistic aspect of it.
>> So we've been doing this competition
around the world as you just heard. We
want to hear from all the passionate
nursing students here in this country
who are ready to inspire and help
everyone they meet. And there's still
time for you to enter the future of
nursing contest. You just have to go to
dr.com for all the details and just make
sure you enter by November the 15th.
That's the deadline. For everyone else,
for everybody else, pay attention to
this because we've got advice from
someone who knows a lot because you know
nurses are very insightful about
prevention and they're very open to
supplements. So, they believe in you
being able to help yourselves. For
example, what kind of preventive
supplement do you believe? What's one
that you typically take?
>> Okay. So, I like a lot of them and your
son is great, but this is one of my
favorite ones. This is a probiotic.
Probiotic is such an easy way to take
care of your health. Very important for,
you know, you know, your digestive
system, your immune system. Um, and I
think they're not all created equally
either. Quality is really, really
important. And USANA really has that
covered with I think they have the the
definitely the guarantee that the two
highly most researched probiotic strains
are in every single one of the packets.
So, it's really easy, which is important
for me. So, they're sugar-f free, dairy
free, gluten-free, which is also very
important to us as consumers, right? Um,
but they also have like a mild um, sweet
flavor, which I have a sweet tooth, and
so that's nice. Um, and you can mix it
with any, you don't have to drink this,
but my kids drink it like this, but you
can mix it with any cold beverage. I
actually just take it straight right
from the packet. So, it's super super
simple.
>> Thanks for what you do.
>> Yeah, thank you for having me.
>> It's honored.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks to my trusted sponsor partner,
USA Health Sciences. You can go to
dr.com for for a chance to win one of a
thousand packs of Esana's probiotic.
>> And what about the audience? They're so
attentive.
>> Yes.
>> Should they get some?
>> They absolutely should.
>> You're all going home with you
probiotic, too. Enjoy it, Kill Bell.
We'll be right back.
>> Ah, the sizzle of bacon. Could this
breakfast stable put you at risk? The
story you haven't heard. That's coming
up on Monday.
[Music]
[Applause]
You have a stressful life, you high
blood pressure, even suffer from
insomnia. Well, studies show there's a
new remedy for combating these health
problems that might just surprise you.
It's fish. No, I'm not talking about the
omega-3s in your diet, but just simply
watching them in an aquarium in your own
home. I was so fascinated by this
science that I wanted to deep dive into
the research and find out the truth for
myself. I had a blast doing my homework.
Every evening, I actually make sure I
take a moment and watch those little
fish swim down that yellow brick road
because studies show it can improve your
mood. One study actually showed that
simply watching fish can reduce your
blood pressure by up to 4%. So check out
Tanked on Animal Planet Friday night at
900 p.m. to learn more. And remember,
together change is happening. Our
journey is just beginning.
[Music]