You know our best for making you laugh
and cry in her Emmy nominated role as
Kate Pearson on NBC's IT show This Is
Us. Now Chrissy Mets has taken on
another inspiring and emotional role in
the upcoming film Breakthrough. And in
her real life, she has several
breakthroughs of her own. I'm excited to
welcome my next guest, Chrissy Betts.
Come on out.
I finally finally How are you? How are
you? Oh my goodness. It's been like
years in the making, right? It has a lot
of effort. Yeah, I know. I'm so happy.
Thank you for your patience. I've had a
busy girl. Yeah, you have been busy.
Gratefully, actually, since picking
busy, everyone was stunned watching the
season finale of This Is Us. I know,
right? So, we see you, your character
Kate gives birth to a 28-week old child,
which is a a risky time to give birth to
a child. One of our children was born
early, so I, you know, lived it a little
bit. And, uh, then we have, you have to
fast forward in the show, and I see the
baby's okay. Yeah. I see Toby, your
husband, in the in the show is around,
although he's not wearing a wedding
ring. That's what people notice. Yes.
And where you your your character is not
there. What happened? Who she could be
at the dry cleaner? Who knows? When When
did she die?
What are you a writer on the show? Do
you want to be a writer on the show?
That's the thing is what's so beautiful
about this is us and the writers is that
because it's not linear, we can sort of
take you everywhere and we want to go
everywhere, right? So, um, we'll find
we'll find answers in in season 4, but
and I do know what's happening just in
case you want to know, but I'm not going
to tell you because you you don't want
to open up the present too soon, right?
You want to just you want to I won't
open the present. I know. I You might
want to just give me the I'm a doctor.
Give me the diagnosis she has. Don't
worry about it. Don't Don't stress
yourself. Just enjoy it. So, I actually
knew I was going to love you because I
did what's watch what's happening live
with your co-star Toby. His real name is
Chris Sullivan, as you know. He's the
best. He He adores you. Hilarious guy,
by the way. Beyond. And it told me a lot
about the behind the set events, the
shenanigans that goes on that keeps you
guys so energized. Well, that's him. He
is Mr. Shenanigan. Like honestly I I you
know we're in these like really heavy
emotional scenes and then he's like
cracking jokes you know in between and
it helps like we need some levity of
course but yeah he's always doing humor
it works. So let me brag on Chrissy. She
just had her first live televised
performance at the ACM alongside lots of
powerhouse singers including Carrie
Andrew. There she is. She was singing
her song from Breakthrough. What was it
like being on stage all I mean all of
America's watching you? Yeah. And it's
about a really beautiful song from a
movie we'll speak about in a second.
Yeah. I mean, it was so, you know, I'm a
little I'm a girl from a little small
town in Florida and, you know, you sort
of dream about these things happening,
but you don't ever know if it's going to
really happen. And to be on the stage
with these incredible artists who I've
revered for quite some time and I love.
I was like, this this is a a moment and
a a moment for women uh women in country
music and it was Yeah, it was pretty
incredible. It was special. You're
wonderful. Thanks. I am curious how you
deal with all the emotions. This great
movie breakthrough, it's it's riveting,
but it is it's up and down emotionally
for you so so it can work for us. Yeah.
The the depth that you have to pull from
that well. Yeah. Has involved members of
your family. I know your mom had been
ill for a while. Yes. My mom had a
stroke um two years ago now. Um but
physically she's doing better than she's
ever done before. So it's wonderful. But
I understand the the fear. Yeah. when
she had the stroke. Oh yeah. Helped you
identify a bit more with the characters
in Breakthrough. Maybe catalyze your
decision to move forward with the
project. Absolutely. Um almost verbatim
were the words that I said to my
mother's doctors. I said, "You can give
a diagnosis and I know you're you
practice. You're a doctor. You don't
always know and you don't always have
the answers. You don't know my mom, but
we have to only speak positive thoughts
around her." And Joyce said those exact
same things to her son John's doctors.
And I thought this is no coincidence,
you know, at all. So, so this is me, New
York Times bestseller. I had the
paperback finally. Yeah. Hard to find a
hardback these days.
Famously, you comment that you had 81
cents in the bank when they told you to
audition for This Is Us. Yeah. Yeah. I
needed to borrow gas money to get to the
audition.
That's funny now. But um Yeah. uh you
know, but uh yeah, I mean 12 years in
the making of trying to aspire to be an
actress and you know uh it's pretty
incredible. I mean yeah. So have you
changed since you got the break because
there are lots of people who are still
running around with 81 cents in the
bank. Sure. Looking for your cab fair or
gas money, but they're not getting the
role. Yeah. And I I have to just for me
it was never about oh I want fame and
fortune. It was like I want to relate to
people. I want people to relate to me
and um I think that's so much about what
we do is intention and those were always
my intentions. So So have those
intentions stayed the same because
they're temptations to alter. Sure. I
mean as we do and evolve sometimes for
better or worse sometimes. Uh and of
course in this industry it's it's
challenging. You know you're sort of
treated a certain way and I and I always
have to remind myself that like we're
all the same. Like I am the same as
every single person on watching and in
this audience. It's like I just have a
different job. So, hallelujah. Yeah. So,
I understand you are blessed to have a
shared meal with my mentor Oprah. I
know. Was that cute? She's the best. And
she apparently said something to you
that I I've heard uh from her in the
past, which is you should be proud of
what you've done in your life. Sure. Too
often we sort of distance ourselves.
What What happened? I mean, she she's
not apologetic about anything because
she does exactly what she needs to do.
Also, because she works so hard for it.
So, I walked into her home and of course
I'm like, "What is this place?" And I
said, "Wow, your home is so beautiful."
And she said, "I know. Thank you." And
and people you you're sort of like,
"What?" Because we're taught to sort of
deflect and oh, this dress was on sale.
Instead of just saying thank you or just
owning that moment and saying, "Yeah, I
worked really hard for this." And that's
what she did. And it was like I was
there for two seconds.
Oprah Winfrey, folks. There she is.
There she is.
I'm grateful to her and I think about
her a lot when I have
breakthroughs sitting here on the show
and talk to guests because the ideas
came from her. Sure. The wisdom of how
to let a guest tell their story. Right.
You practice gratitude. Who do you look
to? What what what what ideas come to
your mind? For me, I start gratitude the
first thing in the morning before I even
put my feet on the floor. When I get out
of bed, I at least 10 things that I'm
grateful for. You write them down. You
say I just say them out loud. Um, you
know, I for me it just sort of centers
me and starts the day in a positive way.
So, what are you grateful this morning?
Oh my goodness. That I woke up, that I'm
mobile, that I'm healthy, you know, that
I have incredible people that love me
and support me and who are making all of
these these wonderful things in my life
happen. Like there's I mean, we could
spend an hour on gratitude. We could,
but we don't. But we don't. We don't. We
spend a lot of time on the
anti-gratitude issues. Speaking of
gratitude, Chrissy stars in this new
movie I've been alluding to called
Breakthrough, which is based on an
incredible true story with a big health
element to it. She plays a mother whose
son fell through a frozen lake, drowned.
When I say drowned, like literally
drowned. Yeah. Heart stopped beating for
45 minutes. And what happened next is
very difficult to explain with science.
As a doctor, I can tell you I have no
idea how this happened. But you might be
able to explain it with prayer. Take a
look at this.
do you get the goosebumps we get when
you watch that? You know, I don't know
if it's goosebumps as much as it's like,
wow, that's what I have to remind myself
to do every day, just surrender. And
it's tricky. It's really tricky to do,
but also because the story is so moving
that finally when she surrendered and
she trusted, that's when the miracle
happened, you know. So, when you were
with your mom and in the darkest
moments, is that what you were saying to
yourself? Oh, sure. you know, you pray,
you know, you storm the heavens with
your prayers and then you just you have
to let go and let God for me. Um I I
there's nothing else that you can do at
that point. Yeah. Absolutely. Yeah. When
we come back, Devon Franklin, our
friend, is here. He's a faith leader,
comes on the show a lot, and he happens
to be the producer of Chrissy's new
movie. The little clip you just saw, the
real life medical miracle that inspired
this film is next. So stay with us. You
know, I love I love how emotional you
guys are watching the movie because, you
know, this is a true story. Yeah. You
know, that that we're obviously invested
in and it's still unbelievable for me.
And there was I mean, seriously, Dennis
and Josh and Chrissy are so good in that
moment. Every time I watch it, I'm like,
he's not going to make it.
We were in it. You don't know the
ending. There's a clip from Chrissy Mets
in the new film Breakthrough about a
mother's belief in the power of prayer
to heal her son against all odds.
because he's back with the film's
producer, faith leader, a very good
friend of mine, Devon Franklin. So, I
appreciate the fact that you're
experiencing it with us. By the way, how
is making this movie Breakthrough
different from making This Is Us. You
know, I think it's the turnaround time
was a little longer. We shot it in 32
days. You know, Kate, I've been
cultivating for 30 seasons, so it's a
little different. Um, you haven't been
public as at least I haven't seen you as
public about your faith as uh as has
become evident watching this movie and
hearing you speak about it. How how has
faith informed your life? Oh my
goodness. Faith has always been such a
cornerstone if not like the most
important thing in my life. I mean I as
I talk about in my book and we sort of
touched on is that I had a pretty
tumultuous childhood. I mean all of us
it's all relative but um I mean I would
go to church on my own you know because
I was seeking that connection and that
conscious contact with God and um always
looking for that and and luckily and and
gratefully I I have that and I found
that and that's how I navigated
Hollywood. But what kind of a problem as
a child would you have where you'd find
solace in church? Uh, you know, my my
parents divorced and my mom remarried
and then I became the middle child. And
so, like navigating that through puberty
with a stepfather, God, you know, all of
those things were like, huh, what do I
do? And and just feeling inadequate, you
know, as we do, especially through
puberty, like my goodness. Um, so yeah,
you know, life, yeah, life comes in
handy. Have some faith. You're one of
the most powerful people in Hollywood.
you're very uh you know polite about and
humble about it, but you are you
attracted some superstars to this movie,
but you had to get attracted to it
first. Why? Well, I was promoting
Miracles from Heaven, um one of the
films I produced. And when I was
promoting that film, I met Pastor Jason
John and Joyce Smith. And when Joyce
talked about going in that emergency
room and praying her son John back to
life, I said, "I've got to tell this
because it motivated me then and it
still motivates me now." And I felt like
this is the type of story that people
really want to hear more about.
For years, we've watched this guy
inspire America, finding films to just
touch our chords, just play their play
our chords in a special way. How has he
inspired you? I Okay, first of all, I I
don't even know how he wakes up at the
gym for at 4:00 in the morning and and
like before he even I makes me mad
actually. Stop it. Angry, jealous. I was
going to say that, but I was like,
that's not kind. Um, but just the
motivation and his consistency. Um, and
what's really wonderful is that not only
has he become like a brother to me, but
a friend and like so much of the
guidance I never knew that I needed, but
like I found in in you and I'm just so
grateful. I mean, just the way that he
lives his life is so inspiring. Well,
it's it's the ethics. You go back to
where my skin is. It's true though. It's
so true. And speaking of the ethics of
making a movie, you you felt you felt
you thought it was very important to get
the family on board before you move
forward. Yes. You know, I mean, for
Chrissy and I, no matter how much we
love Breakthrough, this is a movie for
us, but for the family, this is their
life, and it's so important to get it
right. And so, the family was involved
during the development of the script,
they came to set, uh, you know, met
Chrissy, met all the other actors, we
screened the film for them, they love
it. So, the family saying that we got it
right is so important. It means
everything to us. Oh, yeah. Well, you
got it right. When we come back, you're
gonna get to meet John. The film's real
life medical miracle. I still am
curious. I don't understand how he's
able to even walk and talk, but can do
much more. Stay with us. As doctors, we
believe in science, of course, but
science doesn't always have the answer.
Sometimes there are things called
medical miracles. John Smith was just 14
years old when he drowned in a frozen
lake. Yeah, she drowned. And according
to attending physicians, and they quote,
I'm quoting them, he was dead for 45
minutes, which meant his heart had
stopped. His story is the inspiration
for the new film Breakthrough. Despite
all that, John is actually sitting next
to me. He's here along with Pastor Jason
Noble. Back also is the film star
Chrissy Mets who plays John's mom and
the film producer Devon Franklin. I got
to say I I I only saw the movie version
of it because there was no one filming
you when you actually fell into the
lake. But what happened? What
what when the ice gave way under you,
what did you think? You know, you're
just fighting for your life at that
point. Um it's that fight orflight
instinct that everyone has. And at that
point it was it was very scary, don't
get me wrong, but we knew that we
couldn't get back because there was so
much ice between us and the dock. We
were 25 to 50 ft out. So there was no
way we could get back. So at that point
we were just trying doing the best we
can, but we knew that we were staring
death in the face. Your two friends fell
in after you and they were able to get
pulled out. You went under and what did
you experience when you were under the
dark water with only ice above you? You
know, for me it was just I could
understand how dirty the water was. It
was a greenish brown just disgusting
moss and then after that I really don't
remember anything just it being very
cold and the hypothermia setting in.
Patients of mine I'm a heart surgeon so
sometimes during the cases people have
problems with their heart and they'll
have out-of- body experiences. Did you
you have any recollection of what
happened when you lost consciousness?
Did you feel like you were leaving your
body? No sir. Because we believe that
breakthrough is about a family. I mean
from Devon, from Chrissy, from Jason,
all of us. Breakthrough is about a
family event more than a if because if
that would have happened to me, it would
have been it would have been about my
own experience. Breakthrough is about
family and community. So in the film,
John lay lifeless without a pulse.
Doctors gave no chance of survival, no
chance. And then his mother prayed to
God to breathe life into his body. And
then moments later, John somehow came
back, somehow woke up. Have you ever
experienced something like that, Chris,
in your life?
How have you seen prayer play a role in
your day-to-day life? Oh, through
everything everything you know I do and
before I either make a decision or
whilst something is happening I'm like
okay please just be with me. I mean
literally to the performance the other
night on Sunday um there were some
technical difficulties and I thought
okay it's going to be what it's going to
be. I'm just going to surrender and
trust and uh thy will not mine be done.
Cuz you were very calm during that.
That's what That's what they say. That's
what they say. Yeah. When your mom had
her stroke, did you did you did you have
a moment where you felt you needed to
pray like this? Oh, sure. I mean,
constantly. And um Yeah. I mean, yeah.
All the time. And we sort of just sat
around her her bedside. And that's what
I said, like only positive thoughts and
only positive prayers. And like if you
have nothing good to say, then you can
you can step out of the realm. Um and
yeah, I mean, I do that every day
though. It's just that conscious contact
that that positive, you know, collective
energy and prayer. John, any squali at
all? Any side effects? Any bad memories?
Uh, you know, of course, I would I
remember some things, but God really
saved that and keeping it minimal. But I
I have no issues. I was back to playing
basketball within the next month to two
months. This is a picture of her playing
basketball, by the way. I can't believe
this. But, uh, I was back to just being
a kid and having fun. and you know
there's no lifelong issues. The doctors
actually call me back just to see what's
going on with me and they're in awe.
It's not because anything's wrong. It's
just because they want to see me. So
these are these are just some of the
summary notes. The actual packet of your
medical records is quite thick. And one
possible theory is that the cold water
because when you were very cold water
obviously ice there changes how drowning
happens may have decreased the amount of
oxygen that John's organs needed to stay
alive. But you know, when you look at
these records, there really isn't a good
reason why you were able to sit here,
make words with your mouth, and be
neurologically intact. I could imagine
your body having survived. I can't
imagine your mind coming back when I
read what these records are re revealing
to me, which is the thing that's most
stunning. Now, Pastor Jason, you were
there the whole time as you as you as
you witnessed what he was like, and now
sitting here on my stage, how do you
reconcile that? You know, it's the power
of prayer. I mean, there's no question
when we walked into his room, the doctor
said he was brain dead, even after his
pulse came back. Brain dead. Rudiment
rudimentary brain function. Um, if he
survived, he would be a vegetable for
the rest of his life. 1% survival rate.
We took a group of pastors in and we
prayed that night. And some incredible
miracles happened in the room. And I
walked back out to Joyce and I said, "He
is walking out of the hospital. I don't
know how. I don't know why." You knew
it. I knew it. So, speaking of Joyce,
your mom, I know that she's going
through some medical issues. couldn't be
here today. So, since she's not here,
let me ask you in privacy cuz she'll
probably never see this. What do you
think about how Chrissy played her in
the movie? Well, they did a sizzle
before the trailer and me and mom are in
the living room watching the sizzle and
we're looking at each other like, "When
did mom do this this sizzle? When did
mom over when did she do this voice over
and we're sitting there in such
confusion like what's going on?" Well,
it was Chrissy and just we were floored.
Feels good, doesn't it? Yeah. I mean, I
had to get it right. This Yeah, it's
Joyce. Yeah, I I wanted Absolutely. I
mean, it's so important. Let me give you
the final word. What do you want the
audience to walk away from with seeing
this film? Um, you know, Chrissy as
Joyce has a speech at the very end of
the film. And in that final speech,
Chrissy says as Joyce, that love is the
most powerful force in the universe. I
want everyone to walk out of the theater
knowing that love wins. And when we love
each other, we can have a breakthrough.
God bless you all. Thanks for being
here. Break Crew is in theaters this
weekend. Go check it out. And you're all
going home with a copy of Christy's
book, This Is Me. It's now in paperback.
Take the time. Read about love. We'll be
right back. Thank you for watching.
Don't forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good