An Oz food investigation. What went
wrong here? Cheap chicken at your
supermarket. There are options that
won't break the bank, but you have to
steer clear of a few issues. What to
look for so you don't get conned at the
cash register. It is the most overlooked
chicken in the supermarket. It gets no
love. Plus, Dad, how's that barbecue?
Invite the neighbors. The dish crew is
cooking up backyard barbecue favorites.
You can grill them, toast them, butter
them, and grill them, whatever you like.
Coming up next.
[Applause]
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you, doctor.
[Music]
[Applause]
We all want the healthiest, cleanest
meat when it comes to feeding our
families. But when you're on a budget,
it can feel like you don't have many
options. So today, America's Test
Kitchen's Julia Color Colin Davidson is
here going to help us investigate cheap
chicken to find out what you are really
getting. Okay, you pay less for it. So a
lot of folks think you got to spend a
lot of money, a ton in order to get good
quality meat, but you're arguing not
true. There's a secret. And the secret
is that there are lots of good cheap
chicken options at the supermarket,
which is really important because I
often say you should buy organic, you
should buy freerange, air chilled, and
that is the gold standard for buying
chicken, but it's also the most
expensive. And quite frankly, that's not
always in the budget. So, there are
options that won't break the bank, but
you have to steer clear of a few issues.
So, that's what we're going to talk
about. All right, Julia, we're going to
start off with one of the cheapest forms
of chicken in the supermarket. I don't
know why it has a bad name, but canned
chicken has people very skeptical. It
is. It is the most overlooked chicken in
the supermarket. It gets no love, right?
And it sits there on the shelf right
next to canned tuna, which plenty of
people like, but as you said, people are
skeptical of chicken in a can. But the
good news is it's inexpensive and it's a
good product. Well, they get tuna in a
can. Why is tuna fish can in a can?
Chicken's not. Yeah, they're both very
lean meats. And the thing is when we
looked uh peeled off the label and we
looked at what's inside, uh the good
news is not a lot of ingredients. Now,
some of the other ingredients, yeah, a
few cans had a few other things, some
food starch and maybe some preservatives
and some water, but on the whole, this
is a good picture. So, this is a decent
product. I love this. Yeah. So, we
challenged some chicken lovers to come
up with their most creative canned
chicken recipes. They could only use
canned chicken. Paula, who had never
tried canned chicken before, look how
skeptical she is. Look at that. Look at
that. Look. still. Yeah, I was a little
skeptical, but I don't I don't believe
in food shame, so I decided, right, I'm
going to give it a go. Um, so I started
that. Do you want to try it? What should
you make? So, basically, it's a chicken
tortilla uh soup with canned soup, and
it's easy to make. Yum. Um, and it's
easy if you have children under feet or
if you have young kids at home. So,
everything's a it's, you know, a
division of one. So, there's one carrot,
one one celery rib, one onion, garlic, a
couple of cans of canned beans, and then
that canned chicken. It's good. It's
really good. I love it. What do you
think? It's chicken yourself. Good job.
Nice job, Paul. Now, Tina, I hear was a
canned chicken tuna lover, but not a but
actually canned chicken and canned tuna.
You like both. So, that So, that part
was okay with you, but you wanted to
take it to a new level. Yes. I don't see
the chicken. Where's the chicken? The
chicken is in the crust. The the crust
is actually chicken. What? Yes. Oh,
you've taken like a cauliflower crust to
a whole new level. This is chicken. It's
chicken, parmesan, cheese. Oh, it is
chicken. You can And an egg. And it
makes a crust. Yeah. It's It's It's so
unique and different. And I have a
hungry teenager at home who wants
protein. This is such a smart idea. Well
done. This is delicious. One more time.
How do you crush the chicken down in
this very thin crust? You bake the
chicken uh into almost like flakes for
just a few minutes. Then you put it in a
bowl with the egg and the cheese. It
forms a dough. And then you bake that
for about 10 minutes till it's crispy.
Put your sauce, your cheese, and that's
it. And you use lowfat cheese. It's I
mean it's and it has a meaty flavor. I
love it. You know, the next time you
know they always ask you what the exotic
food tastes like and say chicken. Next
time they ask you what the dough tastes
like, say chicken. Chicken, right? The
pizza tastes like chicken. Thank you.
Nice job. Inventive. Thank you. All
right. Next cheap chicken that we're
investigating is chicken in a pouch.
We're seeing this in the exact same
aisles where we're seeing the canned
chicken that we just were bragging
about. What are your thoughts on this?
It's just packaging. Much like tuna has
gone from the can to the pouch. Chicken
is doing the same thing. But the the
pitfall here is that a lot of the
pouches are flavored. And when you start
adding flavorings, that's when you add a
little bit of some nasty ingredients,
some preservatives, some other issues.
This is all the things that you're Yeah.
You can find all of this in pouched
chicken that has flavoring. And it can
be hard to find plain pouched chicken.
So that's the trick here. If you want to
buy it in a pouch over a can, look for
plain. Next chicken chicken is chicken
packs. Always thought the whole chicken.
Probably the cheapest way of doing it.
Yeah, sometimes it is. But but now I'm
seeing these bag these bags with, you
know, every chicken breast that you
could ever find. Yeah. So some markets
are just selling this and this is just
raw chicken that's been packaged bulked
together and frozen. So it winds up
being less expensive than individual
items you'd buy from the butcher
counter. Uh but the thing is that this
chicken can also turn out very dry and
freezer burn. So according to the USDA,
freezer burn does not present any safety
issues. But according to me, freezer
burn is nasty and you should avoid at
all cost. Put the chef at risk. Yeah,
exactly. Will not like you. It does not
taste good. So, there's a few things you
can do to avoid it. And one is you can
look for ice glazed, which is really
interesting. They take each piece of
chicken and they glaze it with ice
before they combine it and put it in the
package together. That ice prevents the
moisture from evaporating, but it also
prevents the chicken from sticking
together so you can get out a portion or
two. Uh, the trick here is you got to
rewrap it really well after you take a
portion out because any air is where
you'll get freezer burn. Ice glaze. Ice
glaze. Sounds like a dessert. All right.
Jill is here with some frozen chicken
that she cooked and she wants to know
why is it. Yeah. When you pull it out,
why does it get all this juice around
it? Yeah. Well, so frozen chicken uh is
often injected with broth or water and
salt and that keeps the chicken breast
moist and juicy during the freezing
process, but they leech out during
cooking. So, you get this. Um, and
there's some other things that might be
going on here. So, I'm going to give you
four more tips to think about when
cooking chicken. First, make sure you
thaw it all the way. A whole day in the
refrigerator. That might have been part
of the problem. Oh, yeah. If there's any
ice crystals or anything left in that
chicken, that's just going to come out
as water. Okay. The second thing is you
want to make sure to pat the chicken dry
really well. Let it sit on a paper towel
for a good 5 minutes. Get all that
excess moisture out before you cook it.
Uh the third thing, don't overcook it.
160 is the magic number for chicken
breast. If you overcook chicken, that
heat is just pushing out the excess
moisture. So, it's in the pan, not in
the breast. Okay, no extra credit for
overcooking. No, don't worry about that.
There's one more trick here is you got
to let the chicken rest before you cut
it because all that moisture that was
pumped out, as the chicken rests and
those muscles relax, that moisture must
get reabsorbed. So, yeah. So, let it
rest for at least 5 minutes. We'll do.
Yeah. Thank you. Yeah. Nice to meet you,
Jill from Philly. Hope that's helpful.
Up next, how to pick out the best the
best $5 ready to eat chicken in your
grocery store. That is right. Rissy
chicken buying hacks. They're there when
we come back.
One of the most shocking mass murders in
American history. Jim Jones led over 900
of his followers to their deaths.
Congresswoman Jackie Spear is here
revealing how she survived Jonestown.
Plus, an Oz investigation. All going
undercover to buy a variety of underwear
to find out if contaminated products are
still being sold. In your sample, we
actually detected
next Oz.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
We've been investigating cheap chicken.
Now, America's cheapest and tastiest
ready to eat chicken that has been
making headlines this past year for its
low cost, the rotisserie chicken. Now,
we're going to reveal the secrets to
picking the tastiest one that will give
you the most bang for your buck.
Everyone loves rotisserie chicken. But
first, some supermarkets are selling
this rotisserie chicken for as little as
$4.99. And that easily appeases a family
of four for a little over a dollar each.
So Julia, what is the catch? How they
doing it? Why so cheap? Yeah, it's just
marketing. And supermarkets big and
small are cashing in on this. From
Costco to my little local market, in
fact, Costco, their $5 chickens, it
reportedly sell over 6 million of them a
year. That's a lot of chicken. And my
local market down the street every
Thursday is a five buck clock. It's the
same idea. Five buck. Isn't that a good
name? Now, the thing is, uh, they're
selling this at a loss, right? It's it's
at or below or around cost. So, they're
not making any profit on this, and
that's called a loss. But the idea is
they're just luring you into the store
with good cheap chicken, and it works.
Well, if you can get good chicken and it
tastes good, and you're not paying for
it, why not? And the name for that is
lost leader. So, this is a classic loss
leader for most supermarkets, but not
every $5 five duck. What? Five buck
cluck. Not every five buck cluck is
worth it. Not every rotary chicken is
going to be created equal. So Jul's got
some insider tricks to picking the best
one. First off, you got to pick the kind
you can actually watch with your eyes as
it cooks. Yeah. The goal here is to buy
the freshest chicken on the table,
right? So if you see that they're
roasting them on site in the rotisserie,
you know it's a short distance from that
rotisserie to that table and they're
replenishing that table throughout the
day. So that's going to be fresher than
if they're roasting them off site. All
right. And finally, a skin check. Yes.
So I got two birds here. One of them you
think is ideal. The other one not so
much. That's it. And I think actually
it's pretty obvious when this one looks
better. It's more evenly brown. But you
can tell this skin is wrinkly. That
means remember it's been sitting under
that heat lamp. Moisture is evaporating.
That means that breast meat isn't as
plump and the skin's wrinkling. So go
for the plumper burn. Yeah. And if
you're if you want to make sure that
you're eating the healthiest rody
chicken of all, look for the one made
without marinades, right? Because the
ones with marinads have a ton of salt in
them. You can also take the skin off. I
don't like to do that personally. I
don't think it's a big headache.
However, if you're worried about the
calories, it can shave off 170 calories
per serving, at least up to that amount.
Julia, I love your insights. Oh, so nice
to see you. God bless you. Thank you.
Make sure to check out America's Test
Kitchen's newest book, Air Fryer
Perfection. It offers 75 new recipes for
one of the hottest cooking gadgets out
there. And Julie, help make it. You'll
love it. We'll be right back.
Coming up, an investigation into those
fun pool floats that you like to relax
in, but could they be dangerous?
[Applause]
Summer is just around the corner and no
pool party is complete without one of
these inflatable pool floats. We all
have them. They come in every size and
shape. Just look at these and
celebrities are obsessed with them.
Vanessa Hudgins posted this photo with
her inflatable swan. Reese Witherspoon
is hanging out in this donut. Looks
pretty cute like that. Even Justin
Bieber got in on fun with this flamingo
which has become quite popular. But
before you blow up that float for your
next summer party, we're breaking down a
new study that says you and your kids
could be inhaling dangerous chemicals
while relaxing on one of these floats.
Maros Gavako has more on the story. And
first off, let's talk about how popular
these floats have become. Yeah, these
are very popular with a wide range of
ages. Everyone from little kids to their
grandparents enjoys playing with these
things in the pool. And as you just
pointed out, they've also become a
really trendy prop on social media.
They're whimsical. They're cute. People
really like them. But here's the thing.
They make a lot of money. One company
estimated that they were selling $20,000
worth of pool toys every day. So, this
is big business. So, what is this study
showing? What's the headline of it?
Yeah. You know that classic pool toy
smell? It almost smells almond like or
rubbery. Well, this study took a look at
the source of that smell and found that
it's coming from chemicals that could be
harmful to children at very high
concentrations. All right. So, the test
was done the study's results showed that
there were very specific chemicals that
they were worried about. Yeah. So, this
test was conducted by German researchers
and what they did was they bought four
pool toys in stores and online and they
found that all four were made of
polyvinyl chloride which is PVC. It's
commonly known as PVC. Most people have
heard of this from being used in pipes
in home construction, but it's also used
in a lot of consumer products from rain
boots to credit cards, even food
packaging. That's what this stuff is
mostly made of. So PVC again, as a
reminder, is a chemical resistant
synthetic resin that comes in two forms.
There's the rigid form. You see it in
pipes and sheeting material,
construction stuff has it. And then
there the flexible ones like we're
talking about with these plastic toys
that you put in the food pool floats.
Shower curtains have. You ever smell the
shower curtain? That little smell,
right? These these are plastics that can
be bent. So a lot of you are familiar
with that plasticky smell. It's not an
accident and that smell comes from
adding certain chemicals to that
foundation of PVC. So what are the
health dangers potentially from these
chemicals? Yeah. So there are three
chemicals that are of concern and they
were found in three of the four products
that were tested. One is a suspected
carcinogen which means it could cause
cancer. One is suspected of causing
genetic mutations and one is believed to
be harmful if inhaled, which is exactly
what's happening when you're smelling
something, you're inhaling it. Right
now, all of this does sound very scary,
but we have to keep in mind that this is
a very, very small study. They only
looked at four toys. Even the
researchers of this study said, "We need
to study it more." So, the takeaway here
is not that these pool toys will make
you sick. It's just that we need to look
into this more. All right, so let's talk
about why these chemicals could be
dangerous. And who better to talk about
chemicals than a toxicologist? And who
better to talk about these chemicals in
plastic toys than the founder of a camp
aimed at getting young people excited
about science. Luckily, Tamaya Anthony
Tamika Tamika Anthony fits the bill for
both. She's the director of Camp Wakanda
and she's here with her camp kids. Tama,
can you put your toxicologist hat on for
a second? Explain to us why some of
these chemicals added to PVC could be
potentially harmful, especially to kids.
Sure. In order to make these PVC
plastics, we need to add plasticizer in
order to make them more soft and
flexible so they can make toys like the
ones you see here. These plasticizers
are usually phalates. Thalates are
endocrine disruptors. So endocrine, our
endocrine system pretty much regulates
all the hormones in our body. So
interfering with that can lead to
anything from reproductive issues,
obesity, in the case of the children,
developmental issues as well. So the
issue with the chemicals is we don't
really know what the um the exposure can
be like. meaning that we know that they
smell a little strange, but we don't
know what that translates to as far as
toxicity, especially because you're
outdoors with these pools, toys usually.
Okay, so going to do a little experiment
with the kids. Take it away. All right.
They're so cute. So, Madison, can you
tell us what this beach ball smells
like? Take a whiff. What does that smell
like? Smells like balloons and plastic.
And it doesn't smell good. Oh, thank
you, Madison. Hey, Bryce, can you tell
us what those toys smell like? These toy
the toys smell like they smell like
plastic and they they smell weird and
they smell good a little bit. Okay,
thank you. You're tiny little
scientists. My goodness, your whole
generation. Thank you,
Malachi. You got a huge cupcake there.
Can you tell us what that smells like?
It smells like
It's It doesn't smell like a real
cupcake. It's It does. It just smells a
little dirty. A little dirty. It was in
storage. It's a very sensitive nose. You
can pick it up. I want our toys dusted
from now on. So, to make what's your
takeaway? I mean, they smell things, but
we don't know if those orders are a
problem, right? We just we know that
there's a clue, baby. What are your
recommendations for families at home?
Right. So, I don't want to like alarm a
lot, you know, a lot of people because
this the study was kind of small. But,
you know, PBC plastics because they're
endocrine disruptors, they are they can
be potentially harmful. And because we
can't know just by looking at a toy like
what the level of toxicity is, the odor
can sometimes help us along with that.
So, when you're going to the store and
you're picking out a toy, you know,
especially a beach ball, can I borrow
this medicine? You know, take a whiff of
it. If it smells kind of strange, it's
kind of like that nail polish, glue,
almondy, strange plastic smell, then
it's probably has some kind of um
chemicals in it. So, when you take it
home, the best bet is to kind of take it
out and air it out before you actually
use it. Now, I know you guys are
probably thinking like, if it's toxic,
why do we have the kids smell it? So,
the toxicity is increased with the
amount of exposure. So, prolonged
exposure to plastics like these can be
potentially harmful. So, it's okay that
we had them kind of smell it today. It
might be okay in the pool, too. And the
amount that we get exposed to might be
okay no matter where you are with it. We
just don't know that, which is why it's
good to ask these questions. So, good
advice for everybody is don't be scared
of the pool floats. I want you out there
having fun. Thank you much for bringing
the kids as well for the camp.
Congratulations.
We wanted to talk to the vinyl institute
and they did send us a statement back.
They're very thoughtful about it. They
said odor alone is not the best
indicator of a health risk. In addition,
the study uses a very small sample size,
only four items, which is insufficient
to produce statistically significant
data. And then they go on to say that
PVC, which we talk about it's inert,
it's odorless, it's safe to use, and
additives used in some flexible PVC
products, can produce the odor, maybe
that the kids are smelling here, does
not mean that pool floats can cause
harm. We're going to put the full
statement online so you can all read it.
Up next, a lifeguard, a real lifeguard,
weighs in on what your family needs to
know about these floats. And this has
nothing to do with the smell. Here's
some tips from my green expert, Tony
Harris, on how to enjoy pool floats
safely. If you're worried about
chemicals and pool floats, here are a
few simple tips to reduce your exposure.
If you're worried about the smell, just
take them out of the package and let
them gas for a few days before you use
them. Don't use your mouth to blow them
up. Use a pump or electric style air
machine like you would use for your car
tires. Never leave pool floats out in
direct sunlight when you're not using
them because it could create more fumes.
If you're looking for greener solutions
for pool floats, consider these. Pool
noodles are made from polyethylene,
which some believe may be less damaging.
And if you worry they're not as
Instagrammable as blow-ups, just get a
little creative.
Where do we go when we die? We're
unraveling this medical mystery and
examining the last moments of life.
That's coming up Friday on Dr. Oz.
We're taking a deep dive to learn more
about these pool toys. And now a safety
warning from a lifeguard. George is one
of our med unit interns on the show, but
for nearly 10 years, he was a certified
lifeguard. These pool floats are very
popular. A lot of parents load them to a
false sense of security. Let's start off
with explaining the difference between a
pool float and a flotation device that
the lifeguard might tell you to put on
if you're on a boat, for example. Yeah.
So, a pool toy, as we can see, we got a
quite a few here, are just that. They're
toys. They actually even have a label on
them that says this is a toy, not to be
used as a personal flotation device. On
the other hand, personal flotation
device, better known as like a life
jacket, is something that has to go
through US Coast Guard uh approval. That
being said, neither one of these
substitute for close adult supervision
and good swimming skills. So you hear
that parents, audience, everyone home,
even if there's a lifeguard on duty,
sometimes we don't have eyes in the back
of our head and there could be hundreds
of children in the water and we need
your help because we want to keep
children safe. So one thing I had not
thought of is these these pool toys may
actually be a hindrance, right? They may
make problems more more of an issue.
Absolutely. So, uh, for instance,
sometimes there's, uh, floaties that go
on kids' arms or even these, they can
clearly get in the way of your line of
vision, so you can't see what the
child's doing. Especially if one falls.
Another thing I know as soon as one of
these big boys went in the water when I
was younger, we'd all start pushing each
other off it, try and play king of the
hill. I mean, mom put a Not you, but
other people. Okay. Not me. No, other
people who didn't become medical
students. Mom put a pretty quick end to
that. So drowning on a serious note is
the second leading cause of accidental
deaths for kids under the age of 14.
It's common. So let me show you what can
happen when a child is on a pool float.
Whether they're wrestling or not, this
becomes an issue. So let's just say this
little bowling pin is your child, right?
And there's nothing to hold on as often
there isn't on these toys or they're
playing king of the hill or they bang
into the side, right? And it flips over.
And when it flips over, now you got a
couple issues going on. Child's in the
water. Depending on how deep the water
is, the child is now trapped beneath the
float sometimes. But more importantly,
out of sight. That's the thing that's so
important. Some of these larger floats
that people have, they limit your view.
So, you're seeing the pool, it looks
pretty calm, but underneath here,
there's really a big issue. You're
distracted. So, a child's drowned
without us even noticing it. So, in a
situation like this, how long does it
take for a kid to drown in a pool? As
you can see, it just takes seconds for
them to become submerged. In two
minutes, a kid can become unconscious
and within five minutes, they can suffer
from irreversible brain damage due to
lack of oxygen. So, let's give some
rules of the road, right? Rules of the
pool, we'll call them. First, limit the
amount of kids per float. I know it's
hard to do. Do your best. Don't buy too
many of these oversized floats. It just
invites more problems. And designate a
parent to keep their eyes on young
swimmers at all times. Don't trust
they've been the lifeguard. You take
responsibility. Never hurts to have a
belt and suspenders, both you and them
checking it out. You can take turns
throughout the day so you're not just
staring at the pool uh for your entire
afternoon. George, thanks very much.
Nice job in the med unit. We'll be right
back.
We are gearing up for the unofficial
kickoff to summer this weekend. And what
is Memorial Day without the perfect
backyard barbecue? Today we are grilling
up my simple but delicious big fat Greek
burgers. Oh jeez. Oh yes. And margarita
marinated ribs. We're getting all up in
your grill. So stick around. Oh my
If there's one thing that brings us all
together, it's food. So, we're calling
everyone to the table to dish on
everything from the latest food hacks
and trends to everyday recipes you can
make for dinner tonight. It's simple.
It's celebratory. And most of all, it's
about having a great time in the
kitchen. What is going on? I'm trying to
help. Let's dish.
Welcome to the dish on us. And we are
gearing up for the unofficial kickoff to
summer this weekend and we have some
backyard barbecue recipes you're going
to add to your menu no matter where you
are. My daughter Daffy's here with her
foodie friends, TV host and bestselling
cookbook author Maras bringing us the
best in Greek tradition, former
professional boxer, cooking and
lifestyle champa Ali's back in the
kitchen. Oh yeah, I like it. And of
course, she's at some of the biggest
food network shows and she's a superstar
in many ways on TV and off. Daffany,
what's on the menu today? First up is a
simple and delicious backyard barbecue
all day long today on the dish. First up
are Maria's delicious barbecue Greek
burgers. I cannot wait burgers people
burgers. We're traveling with our food
today. We then we have Mar Oh, wait.
Stop. Margarita marinated barbecue ribs
with a surprise guest who's bringing the
perfect side. And then we're going to
give you an inside look at how a chef
shops the big box stores to find the
very best food. Okay. Pat show today. So
before we get cooking, let me ask you
one thing. In one word, tell everybody
what is the best thing about a backyard
barbecue.
For me, it's the smell. Cuz that smell
of that charcoal going like that's how
you know whose house you going to. It's
like they cook it. You don't like that's
how you follow the nose. Okay. I like
that. I just think of sauce. Ooh,
sticky sweet.
See sauce. I like sauce. I love the
sounds of kids yelling and screaming.
That's what I like cuz they compete and
do things to build up an appetite so you
can feed them. I like that too. Saw,
sound, smell. Maria, I just like being
outside. And so for me, it's just being
outside and hosting people and having
everybody jumping in pools and then like
grabbing a burger and then jumping back
in and, you know, hopefully not
drowning. Your chain. You're definitely
everyone comes to your house. I feel
like Did you hear that? I love that.
like the cutest thing ever. Um, for me
it's I it's eating with my hands with a
bib sometimes, but at least leaned over
the
bib on. If you invite me to your saucy
outside smelling sounding, don't drown
pool party. I am there and I am I am
there for the win. Okay, taking that
picture and posting it.
butt as apple. Make sure these are not
like you guys. Maria, well, you live in
LA, too, but Maria lives in LA and your
family does love to use your backyard
barbecue all year round, which I'm so
jealous. Look, we got this cute picture
of you cooking like that Thanksgiving
dinner because we were renovating our
house and we didn't have a kitchen to
cook Thanksgiving in. So, my mom said,
"Well, we'll cook outside." So, I didn't
realize, gosh, you can cook anything in
there. We made lasagna in the grill. I
love that. Like the first Thanksgiving.
Exactly. Took us back to the beginning.
The grill can do so much. And today
you're going to show us your world
famous mokos burgers. Talk me through
this recipe dish. So a mkos burger. It's
a lot more exciting than just your
average burger. So we've got some feta
cheese, some parsley, some dijon
mustard, garlic powder. You can use
fresh garlic if you want fresh garlic,
but I like to give you the option of the
powder cuz it's in your cabinet
generally and it's usually there. So
that's nice. So you mix that all
together. A little dijon mustard and you
add this little ingredient which is a
sauce.
Depends on where you live. Worcester. I
don't know how to say it properly.
Woristers. Woristers. Yeah. There's no
way. There's no way those letters come
together. Woresir. Anyway,
British is wor. The Turkish. No, the
Turks don't have any. It's got vinegar
and garlic and onions and all that good
stuff. But the real secret ingredient,
anchovies. Wait, anchovies or wishes?
Yes. Read the label now. Ew, I hate pull
it out like that.
You're already adding wishes. It's
already a contain.
Okay.
It's the best. It's already in. You're
already adding it to the burger. In just
the smallest form. Why do you love
anchovies so much? It's got the umami.
It takes take those taste buds. Not the
sweet and sour ones. The ones that taste
real
[Laughter]
you're taking her down. You're taking
the champion without that yumami
excitement. The MKOS border burger is
not the MKOS burger. This is making it
happen. You're welcome.
Dr. Oz, reset. Reset. So, okay. So,
we're going to Somebody is going to make
this patty for us. Right here. Right
here. We're ready. We got the patty. And
we're going to throw it on here. Throw a
little olive oil, which this is all
really hot. Now, I got to ask you, are
you a Are you a mix with your hands kind
of? Thank you. Are you a mix with your
hands? I'm a mix with my hands. I wash
my hands frequently. I love that you're
like totally commanding this right now.
Like, how do we use this and make it not
as hot right now? No, don't do that.
Just going to blow it up in my face.
Guys, we're going to have an explosion.
No, we're going to get a little water in
this pan. We're going to cool it right
down. This is cooking with a hot grill.
That is one of the tips to making sure
that this is what it would look like. It
would look like you found your house
because of that smell right there. So,
here's what I love about this. So, a lot
of people don't like to eat bread. And
this is such an interesting delicious
burger. You can eat totally plain like
this because of the feta cheese and the
stuff in there. And then we also make
our zitziki. So, Dr. Oz obviously
chopping up the cucumbers for the Well,
in Turkey, this is what we eat all the
time. And we gave it to the Greeks as a
present. Thank you. He just wants you to
rise. Did you guys Are you saying you
created this? Well, you know that. Of
course. I I think the Greeks created
everything. Dr. Oz, back out of this
conversation. We can we can look this
up. But we got some yogurt. We mix the
the the the pureed cucumber. Just to be
clear. So, you take the you take the
cucumbers that I cut up. You pure and
then you strain them. So, to take some
of that water out. Yes. You have to
strain them. And then you add the
garlic, the dill, the lemon, throw some
parsley in there, and you make zazziki
sauce. And I want to make sure everyone
knows how to say zaziki.
Guys, here's the test. He's already
dancing. Zaziki.
Zaziki. Zadiki. Zaziki. Yes. Papa.
Now what you do is you can spread it on
top of your burger or on your bun and
you have a mkos burger. Now as we finish
these mokos burgers. Yeah. And you can
do some sliced cucumbers on there too.
You and your dad had a big hamburger
tradition. We did. My dad used to love
this little hamburger stand. It was like
a hole in the wall, but he used to take
us there after school, but their meat
was always seasoned really well. But I
could tell and I love the way you put
all that salt in there because that's
what really brings out the flavor. I
told you guys before, Wolf Gang Puck
taught me that it's all about like
really layering in the salt and pepper.
I used to be so scared to put salt and
pepper on there. You got to really like
dose it to make it good. So, you know,
great. That's the beauty of cooking at
home also is you're controlling it.
You're dripping
juice on
ruining my burger. Oh, I'm trying to
help. Ew. Well, on that note, up next,
Jamaica's margarita marinated barbecue
ribs. There's no anchovies in them.
Plus, actress and food Daniel Ramirez is
dropping by with what will be your go-to
barbecue dish this summer. You're going
to love it. Amen. Not on the anchovies.
Let's go. I love getting to talk with
you on my show every single day, but
when the cameras stop rolling, the
conversation is not over. I still have a
lot that I want to talk about. So
download the Dr. podcast on Apple
podcast or wherever you get your
podcast. So yes, we always get like
right to the intro if that's not where
we want to start.
All right, we are too excited to wait
for Memorial Day. So we are throwing a
backyard barbecue today. And just like
in just like in real life, my dad cannot
wait to eat. He is sitting down with
some of the audience members chowing
down already. Dad, how's that barbecue?
I tell you what, there's food in my
teeth. You like this food? Oh, fabulous.
Keep making the food over there. All
right, we got some more dishes coming up
for you. Well, my favorite thing about a
barbecue is when friends drop by. So, we
invited a very special guest today.
She's starred in some of your all-time
favorite shows from The Sopranos to
Devious Maids. And she'll be in Jumanji
coming up next. Jumanji the movie. Da
Ramirez. Welcome to the
great. Hi. Um, so obviously we love
food. We all love food. Where did your
love of food start? Well, I grew up in
Dominican Republic with a bunch of
families. So, I grew up smelling food.
Exactly.
Um, and then, you know, my my
grandmother, my aunts, everybody would
cook all the time, but it wasn't until I
was like 12 years old and I was living
in America that my parents both had to
work. And so, it became like a chore at
the beginning. Like, I had to cook one
day, my sister had to cook the next day.
And then I eventually found such a love
for it. It was so therapeutic. It
reminded me of home. You know, food is
love. Yep. Right. So, it just it felt
like the right thing for me to continue
to do in life. But you're right. It is
it's food is love and it's also the
universal language and it's the kind of
thing that can transport you. So, if
your family's missing, you know, home,
it's a kind of nice thing. But I heard
the first time you cooked for your
husband, which can go both ways. Um
things went up in smoke quite literally.
You know, I almost set my my
mother-in-law's house on fire, you know,
the deck outside. So, it was my first
time with the barbecue and you know,
he's from Columbus, Georgia. Barbecuing
is very big in Georgia. So, he was
outside and he leaves me with the with
the burgers and he leaves me with the
with the sausages and I'm texting my
friend and I'm like, "It kind of smells
like it's something's burning." So, I
open up the barbecue and sure enough,
like flames go everywhere. I panic. I
grab a bucket of water from the pool and
I threw the water into the into the
barbecue. And I have to say like I
ruined the burgers, but then we ordered
in, we all laughed about it and it made
me have no fear, you know, and that's
that's the thing. You shouldn't be
afraid of the barbecue. Well, I am
grateful that you are doing side dishes
today. You got on the grill. You guys,
she's legit. Like she like travels and
wherever she travels, she takes culinary
classes. Yes. I just went real. Yeah. I
went to India this past November. I
spent 21 days in India. And so this is
why and I when I we'll talk about my my
special dish a little side dish a little
later. I integrated um some of the
Indian flavors. I love that. So you're
bringing your travels home. So you're
making a side dish to go with Jamaica's
ribs. What's the deal? I'm like I don't
know if they have this in India, but I
am doing spicy margarita marinated ribs.
It's a cool formula when you're using
booze in your marinade cuz you have to
have the acids cuz that like break down
the proteins and you kind of roll with
that and then and it tenderizes it. So,
I have some baby back ribs, and you put
it in the the spicy margarita. I say
make one for yourself first, and then
you put the rest on the ribs, and you
let this marinate. You put it in the
refrigerator for 12 to 24 hours to let
all of the that tequila and everything
just soak into the the ribs. So, then
when you pull it out, you'll pat it dry
to make sure you get all that moisture
off because we want to have a good sear
on the outside. So, then we'll have this
going. And then you just do you can do a
little bit more oil on the top there.
And then you just do salt and pepper
because we don't have to do anything
else because it has all the flavor of
everything that was in the margarita. So
you see where I'm going with it. I love
it, right? Just do a little pepper
margarita. And if you will, my da my
Dominican love. Will you put this in the
oven for me? I love to. And it's smells
delicious, guys. Because here's the
important thing. Like remember there is
alcohol in that. So, if you're doing it
on an outdoor grill, put it on like the
cooler side of the grill because it will
start to smoke and then you don't want
to set your mother-in-law's house on
fire like this one over here did. You
don't want to do that. You're not afraid
of the grill. She said afraid. You
always have a great story to tell. A
great story at 911 on Speed. Yes. And
you can have any store barbecue sauce.
And my little tip to you, don't tell
anybody I told you. Put a shot of the
margarita in the sauce. I'm telling you,
everybody will be happy. If the kids eat
it, they're going to go to sleep like
nobody's business. You're giving some
bad parenting advice today, people. Take
it with a grain of salt. Everybody will
be happy. Trust me. No, you just add a
little hint of the margarita back sauce.
You baste it. You look like you've been
sweating over a hot grill all day. And
you have it. So, are you guys drunk over
there on your
You've been eating the ribs. Are you
drunk yet? It smells It does smell
margarita, by the way. So good. All
right. So, we have the ribs. We got to
have a side dish. Absolutely. So, I
don't know if you guys have ever had
street corn, right? It's with a queso
fresco, a little lime, and we're going
to make it a little spicy. So, that's uh
where where it all came from. That's my
whole thing. So, uh what you want to do
is take your corn cob, raw corn, right?
Now, there you go. Raw. You're going to
brush the ghee. And this is one of my
India ingredients. Your Indian here
rather than butter. Right. Yeah. Instead
of butter. So, you're going to brush the
ghee on your corn, right? Done with
that. And then you want to add your
seasoning salt. And then you have two
kinds of chili here. It looks like this
is the red chili. Yes. Chili pepper. And
this is cayenne pepper. So, I'm only
going to use a little bit of the chil
heat coming into this kitchen. Okay.
See, I would be like crazy. My corn
would look so red right now. I would be
like, you want to you don't want to you
don't want to do too much. People who
are eating at my barbecue is going to
have smoke coming out of every hole just
like I also have kids.
You got to careful with you have kids.
And what happens to
I don't know those tips. Turn it. We
roll it up nice like this. Goes right on
the grill. Goes around this goes over to
the grill about 20 minutes. You turn it
every 2 minutes and then you're done.
But it comes out looking like this. And
this is your finishing step, right? You
got a little lime juice right on top.
Lime juice on top.
A little fresco on top.
Yum. And then if you want it to be a
little spicier, you can use your cayenne
pepper. Now's the time. Wait, Dad,
you're over there manning the grill. I
have been manning the grill. These are
hot off the press. Perfectly done as
instructed by all of you. This really
tastes like a margarita. Now enjoy
these. Delicious. Oh, thank you for
bringing these a taste. I'm Did you take
my Don't Don't all applaud at once.
Please don't all applaud at once. I am
so hold the applause for the end. Thank
you. First of all, I'm going to Thank
you very much for coming here.
Congratulations on your success. Up
next, you ever wonder how a chef shops
for a backyard barbecue? We're revealing
the ultimate shopping list to take you
to the grocery store. It'll make you a
winner. Stay with us.
[Applause]
[Music]
One of the most shocking mass murders in
American history. Jim Jones led over 900
of his followers to their deaths.
Congresswoman Jackie Spear is here
revealing how she survived Jonestown.
That's coming up tomorrow.
We are back with a dish and throwing a
backyard barbecue before the unofficial
start of the summer. That's this
weekend. That is a huge announcement
about what you have coming up this
summer. What is it? Another one besides
the baby. I'm gonna be joining you guys
Gordon Ramsay, Aron Sanchez, and Joe
Bastionage as a guest judge on Master
Chef later this season.
I love competitions. Really fun with
talented Home Coast competing for the
title of Master Chef and the $250,000
grand prize. Master Chef is back
starting next Wednesday night on Fox
8:00 PM Eastern and Pacific. And you can
catch me as a guest this season. I want
to compete. I want the money. A quarter
million dollar. Are you kidding me?
You're not going to win the money.
Before you head to the zoo market to
gear up for Memorial Day weekend, you're
going to want to steal this list. That's
right. Just right. Take it right off.
Jamaica allowed our cameras to tag along
with her while she shoed for a backyard
barbecue at Costco. Check it out.
Hey guys, today I'm going to one of
America's favorite stores, Costco. Now,
there are a lot of shopping secrets to
reveal here. So, I'm going to show you
what a chef for and buys so your dinner
can be chefw worthy, too. Come on, let's
go.
[Music]
Let's head to the meat department.
Here's my chef's secret. I buy choice
beef, not prime. Now, Choice is just a
grade down, so it's less expensive, but
it's great quality. And if you ask me,
it's actually a beefier taste than Prime
cuts. And this right here is my pick,
the choice cut rib. It is perfect for
pan searing, and it has a wonderful fat
to meat ratio.
Next up is rotisserie chicken. Now, I'm
not talking about these famous birds.
Mm-
I'm talking about this. It's the same
delicious cooked rotisserie white meat
with all the bones removed. So that
saves you and me a lot of time and so I
can make my chicken salads, enchiladas,
tacos. You see where I'm going with
this. Right on to produce.
Now these are two of my favorites.
Papaya and pre-cut pineapple. Now not
having to cut pineapple saves me so much
time. And both of these are natural meat
tenderizers. They go perfect in so many
of my Caribbean dishes. The bottled
herbs and spices here are so much
cheaper than the supermarket. The pink
Himalayan salt. Okay, I know you're
thinking, "What am I going to do with
this much salt?" But it lasts forever.
And uh anything you have left over, put
a little scoop in your bathtub for a
soak, people.
Now, we're headed to the freezer
section. My chef's secret here.
It's wild caught Gulf shrimp. Now,
they're delicious and domestic. So, you
can really trust where they come from,
and that's important. And at this price,
uh, I am sold hook, line, and sinker. H,
I'm feeling it.
I have one final pit stop. Uh, can I see
these diamond earrings, please?
I mean, come on. A chef's got to look
her best, right? Okay, I definitely need
to check out now.
That That's a great garnish.
I hope you take those home. If you win
as your chef, you can buy that. No, I'm
going to take Dr. Oz's black card next
time. We're buying diamonds for
everybody. That's what we're going to
do. I know people want to know what's
the whole audience. Okay. So, tell us
what we're eating cuz we're having fun.
All right. So, what I bought at the
store, you saw I bought the shrimp and
this is a shrimp roll with pineapple
iioli. So, think like a lobster roll,
but we put shrimp with fresh pineapple
in there. It's got aoli with like a
sweet chili sauce. M I love it. Diamond
in Costco. I am going to run wild and
bring you something good. What? What?
Get my diamond. Get a diamond. I found
the diamond in my sound. Are you kidding
me? Give it to me. Yes. There's the
other one.
I buy it, too. That's like the sneaky
proposal. All of a sudden, it's in your
shrimp roll. Honey, I like your shrimp
roll. Oh, my diamonds. I'm like, I do
put them on. Tell you, I'm I'm happy
that you showed people how you shop
because every time I go to the grocery
store, people are always looking in my
basket to see what I'm buying. So, thank
you for giving the inside tip. I want to
know what you eat, too. Yes. Do you tell
you do the tuck underneath the top layer
for If there's something Yeah. If
there's something I want people to see,
like some cookies or something sweet,
you know. Oh my god. Stop. Oh, yeah. I'm
just glad I got a little extra minerals
in mind. There you go. Good for you.
Loved having you all here today. Thanks
for having me. Eat up. Thanks for the
tips. I'll see you next time. Always
good food here.
[Music]