[Music]
Are you ready for season 11?
[Applause]
[Music]
Good morning, America. As Robin Roberts
wakes us up every morning with the
latest headlines. Well, sometimes a
story stays with her long after the news
has been read. And today, Robin is
revealing one of those true crime ripped
from the headline stories about a baby
girl, Kamaya, who was abducted from her
mother's arms only hours after her
birth, only to find out 18 years later,
the woman who raised her isn't really
her mother at all. Robin exclusively
interviewed Kamaya and helped turn her
story into an emotional Lifetime movie.
Please welcome back my good friend Robin
Roberts.
So
I still say good morning. Good morning.
How are you? Oh, I love seeing you. Oh,
bless you. Thank you. Look better than
ever. Hello everyone.
Great to see you.
They adore you and so do I. Oh, right
back at them. There's so many things you
could talk about. There's so many things
you do talk about. Get the stories stuck
for you. What was it? You know, it was
one of those stories I remember when it
happened three years ago. And I knew
that I wanted to know more. So I'm like,
if I want to know more, do other people
want to know more? And I knew there was
more to the story. Let's get into it a
tiny bit because as I learned about it,
I was progressively stunned. This, by
the way, it's like unwrapping an onion.
I feel like I'm Shrek here talking about
this. First off, 18 years ago, how how
could someone walk into a hospital, take
a baby, and walk out? I don't How did
that happen? You tell me. You tell me,
doctor. It seems impossible to me. I
know. It does seem impossible. So, it
was it was 1998, and Gloria Williams was
a nurse in South Carolina. She drives to
Jacksonville. She's dressed as a nurse.
She knows what a nurse does. She goes
into the maternity ward, sees this young
teenage mother. M the baby was just
hours old. But this really made national
news because just as you said, how can
anybody walk into a hospital and walk
out with a baby? And that's why I was
hearing from mothers who say they put
like little stains on their baby and
things like that, little things, little
markers, so when the baby they know that
that is their baby. Now it's like Fort
Knox. Babies are locked up. Multiple arm
wrist. But that's because this was able
to occur. So in the film, here's how
you're able to depict how easily this
could happen. And I was stunned. No,
what's so different? It says, "You've
heard of babies getting mixed up, but a
baby being stolen is something
different." And when you steal a baby,
there's often evil intent, a desire to
harm the child for whatever crazy
reason. What was the excuse for Kamaya
being taken? Gloria Williams, her
abductor, was in a relationship with a
man named Charles Mano. It was a bad
relationship, and she thought having a
baby would save their relationship. She
was actually pregnant. She had a
miscarriage. And so she panicked because
she felt again that she needed a baby.
Now she claims that she just happened to
get in a car, just happened to drive
down to Jacksonville, happened to walk
into that she had no intent. That's that
what that's what she claimed. But then
she she did she did come clean and go
that was wrong. There's there's no sugar
coating it. Even though she did a
wonderful job in raising Kamaya, who she
called Alexis, that you you cannot do
something like this. How is it possible
that she would go back to her life in
South Carolina with Kamaya and nobody?
Yeah. And no one knew she was not the
biological child. Because there was
nothing that this woman had ever done
for people to think that she was capable
of something like this. And you know
what? She kept a baby bag packed. the
first few months because she just knew
I'm going to get found out. Someone's
going to come and and going to take the
baby. And then years go by and years go
by and then it was 16 years in. What
does What does What does the kid want to
do? Wants a job. Right. Yes. Someone the
kid wants a job. What do you need?
Social Security card. Thank goodness. I
know. Exactly. Right. And so when she
said she wanted a job, her mother
panicked and said and came clean. So
Kamaya actually knew for almost two
years before authorities were alerted.
Now Kamaya wanted to find out more about
herself. So she went online. She
actually called her birth mother, hung
up. Now her birthother, we should also
say every single year had a birthday
party. Every single year cut a piece of
birthday cake, put it in the freezer. Oh
my goodness. Believe that she was going
to see this child again. And that's
what's been so hard
is that Kamaya has this relationship
still with her abductor and it's very
hard for her mother Shinara. Very hard
uh for her. But can I just say that Ni
Nash uh Raven Fel um beautiful job
who play the three principal members
they really bring this story story to
life. C can you share what happens to
the mom the abductor 18 years in prison
she was sentenced 18 years one year for
every year she abducted Kamaya
one year for every year she abducted
her. So she is in jail in Florida and
Kamaya went to see her in December. This
past December for the first time in
three years she went there to the jail.
And so that is very difficult for the
biological mother. She can't wrap her
mind around why her daughter would still
want to have a relationship with this
woman. She's juggling two families, two
families who love her. It's the ultimate
dilemma in life. And the fact that she
has an abductor and a mother and she's
being torn to not ignore the abductor
who was there for her even though she
should never been in her life for many
years. And there's a part in the in it's
very emotional clip of the movie, maybe
the most. I mean, it's biblical almost.
You couldn't make up these kinds of
emotional tensions where good and evil
gets twisted and roped around each
other. You actually had an opportunity
to interview Kamaya. What was your
takeaway during that? What was very
important to me after the movie to have
the documentary and the way this
beautiful young woman is able to share
her story and I believe there's
something that will resonate with a lot
of people. I love how you elevate all
the stories you cover. So be sure to
tune in. Robin Roberts presents Stolen
by My Mother. The Kamaya Moy story
premieres on Lifetime January the 18th.
And stick around after the feature for
Robin's exclusive interview with Kamaya.
That's the part I really want to see as
she opens up about her life since her
true identity was exposed. Now, when we
come back, Robin Roberts can talk about
a lot of things, but she's going to
share how she's reclaiming her life
after battling health challenges. Stick
around.
Do you need a health reboot? something
you can stick with. We have an easy to
follow lifestyle system that can get you
back on track. 20 goals. Lose 20 lbs and
reduce your risk of disease by 20%. A
plan you can stick with because we made
it easy. From the way you eat to how
well you sleep and how you manage your
stress every day. System 20 for 2020.
Yes. Yes, honey. Oh, I feel I feel like
Oprah all of a sudden. Like a hug.
Thank you. Thank y'all.
All right. If you want to know who the
real Robin Roberts is, that's her
inspiring the audience during the break
when no one's watching. She didn't have
to do that. But that's what I love about
you. Now, they say sometimes superheroes
don't wear capes. And that phrase may
actually well may be true about Robin
Roberts. You've done so much with so
many ways. I think you deserve Cape
status. I nominate you for it.
And Robin is here to share her own keys
to resilience after experiencing two
life-threatening illnesses. We've had
many conversations or my wonderful life
with you. Uh but in 2007 when you're
diagnosed with cancer and subsequently
with my plastic syndrome, you went
through a couple combo punches that
would have leveled a lot of folks.
Update everyone. How are you feeling?
How you doing? Oh, uh, praise God. I'm
doing as as well as I am. I am so
incredibly grateful to the doctors, the
nurses, the technicians who still to
this day keep an eye on me. I do my due
diligence. I go for my regular checkups.
I have started meditating. Um, I watch
what I eat more so than I did before.
Um, all those things that I I I need to
do. But I I just I want to be a symbol
to people that this too shall pass. Uh,
everybody's got really
But but can I tell y'all something? When
I was first diagnosed in 2007 and I'm
seeing the doctors here in New York and
everything, my aunt Foya, may she rest
in peace. She said, "Have you talked to
Dr. Oz yet?" True story. True story. I
like
I'll get to him. All right. I know him.
But well, you got to talk to Dr. Oz.
Lived in Akran, Ohio. Yes. Well, as you
often say, everyone's got something and
we forget that we're all in this
together. That's the ultimate safety net
to humanity is being here for each
other. And there's something that you've
been saying that just really touched me.
You said being vulnerable is
therapeutic.
How has that philosophy helped you on
your health journey? Vulnerability. Why
do we shy away from that? Why do we uh
do that? I I know that when uh Hurricane
Katrina hit and devastated my hometown,
wiped out my hometown of Pastor Shan,
Mississippi, and I was live the next day
from the Gulf Coast, and I had just
joined GMA as a full-time uh host, and
I'm there on the Gulf Coast. Katrina has
blown through, and I cried. I actually
on live television, I couldn't I
couldn't hold it in. I had just found my
mother uh an hour before getting on the
air. I hadn't even known up until that
time. Oh my goodness. If she was alive
and I wasn't going to go on the air
until I did, but the fact that I cried
and I thought that I was going to lose
my job and just the opposite happened.
People were like, "Thank you. Thank you
for just being genuine." And it's not
weakness to be vulnerable. That is not a
weakness. Vulnerability. It's so funny
you had that experience. Not funny,
ironic because I was in in Miss in New
Orleans. Oprah had set me down and I got
Oh, look how he dropped that name. No,
you know, you you saw that. I know. and
I she wanted me to tape for her show and
she went, as you know, to a different
part of the in the uh the aftermath and
I I wasn't as doctory as I was supposed
to be because you couldn't look at at
what had happened to that beautiful city
that I had visited many times, dead
bodies in the street, floods, you know,
above the bars you'd had parties in
without really feeling it. and not
holding that in actually in many ways
opened my eyes to the reality that as
doctors we sometimes need to be
vulnerable because our patients are
comfortable telling the truth and it it
goes through and I'm glad you said that.
I mean it's it doesn't matter if you're
a journalist, if you're a doctor, what
walk of life that vulnerability is
something that we all should understand,
respect and embrace. We're hardwired for
it. Yes. Actually speaking of that to
quote
the wonderful philosopher your mom. Oh
who would say make your mess your
message. Make your mess your message.
What is the messenger? Tell us about the
message. Oh my gosh. I remember my mom
first told me that when I was uh
diagnosed with cancer and I was like I
don't what what is the message here? And
it was about early detection because I
found I was triple negative. Um but
because I had through self-detection
found the lump and I just told people
that that um that um early detection it
is not a guarantee um but it just it
increases your chances and so I I got
the message out there but my message has
been and what I've always made my me my
me my message is resiliency to be
resilient to to uh I have this wonderful
little placard in my dressing room I you
know I often say this too shall pass. It
says this too shall pass dot dot dot.
Now would be good, you know. I guess so.
What do you have in you talked to
everyone who's making news? What's big
for you and GMA over the next couple? Oh
my gosh. We've got the Super Bowl, baby.
So, we're Yes, we're very excited. Oh,
look at my boys. Oh, I love them. I love
them. We have a good You're going to
teach Trey Han a little bit about
formations.
Don't you start. But I really enjoy
being with them. I enjoy We enjoy saying
good morning to America to set that
tone. So, we have the Super Bowl. We're
going to send some super fans to uh the
Super Bowl in Miami. Also, the Oscars
coming up. We're going to be live the
morning after with the Oscars again from
LA. So, you're the best interviews on
those. God bless you. Thank you. Big
admirer. Thank you for being graceful.
Robert Roberts, you can catch a Good
Morning America Weekdays at 7 a.m. on
ABC. I joked about it at the beginning,
but I actually have to do this if you
don't mind. I actually custom made Oh,
no. a cape.
She has her own Robin Roberts case. out.
These are the LSU colors. Louisiana just
won the college championship.
Now, come back here.
There we are.
Where's Where's the wind blowing in
there? Yeah. Where's the wind? Go come
across here. The wind's Oh, she's
Thank you. Thank you. A welldeserved
tape. Robin Roberts. Stop.
[Applause]
Up next, 99 questions about CBD. Today,
we're investigating one of the biggest
and most controversial claims. Can CBD
help treat or prevent Alzheimer's? Are
there any real brain benefits?
Can CBD help my chronic CBD make me
skinny? Can CBD help my arthritis, my
indigestion, can my skin problems,
autism, epilepsy, boost my energy? and
CBD help me finally get a good night's
sleep.
All January long, we're investigating
one of the buzziest health topics of
2020, CBD. We've been tracking the trend
from the beginning and answering the 99
CBD questions you're just too afraid to
ask. Today, some of the most
controversial claims about CBD. For
example, can CBD boost your brain health
and improve your memory? and an even
bigger claim. Can it really help prevent
Alzheimer's and dementia? It caught my
attention when I saw the headlines and
the promises made me really skeptical.
So, I wanted to investigate further.
Could it really help someone like my
mom? Could it slow down her progression
of dementia? Or could it help me prevent
it? Here to help uncover the truth is
director of the Alzheimer's Prevention
Clinic in Wild Cornell Medicine, Dr.
Richard Isacson. Good friend.
CBD and Alzheimer's. Is it legit as a
world expert in the space or is it is it
hype? What does the research say? Well,
we're all here to find out. And I have
no idea. Um, we don't know. The science
doesn't know. I'm not pro CBD. I'm not
anti-CBD. I'm pro- evidence. And right
now, unfortunately, we just don't have
enough evidence to really understand
whether CBD can be helpful for the
treatment of Alzheimer's, for the
treatment of symptoms related to
Alzheimer's, like sleep disturbances and
behavioral complaints, or even in
prevention. We just don't know. The hype
has been so loud that the FDA has
already been warning about CBD products
claiming to treat Alzheimer's. So, I've
seen headlines about CBD oil and what it
can do for people who already have
dementia. What's been your experience?
What could it do for patients? Right.
So, I've had several patients that have
decided to try it on their own and they
come back after several months and
honestly, I guess I've seen mixed
results. Um, I don't think I've seen any
harmful um outcomes, but I've seen some
people that subjectively feel better.
Um, I had one patient several weeks ago
that said, you know, I I think he's
sleeping better and and he wakes up in
the morning and maybe he's more
refreshed. I've had other patients that
have taken, you know, different types of
CBD and, you know, they said, he's
sleeping all the time. So, what I would
say is, you know, from from my personal
experience, it's it's just mixed
results. So, Aby's like you a viewer who
says she's been using CBD oil to help
her mom. Take a look. I am especially
interested in the CBD oil for my
mother's severe anxiety. she is
experiencing due to her dementia. Mom
has been on CBD oil for about four
months and we have seen a slight change
in her anxiety and sleep patterns but we
have not seen an improvement in her
dementia. I hear stories like that all
the time. This there's some things that
got better but not the basic dementia
issues. So when it comes to CBD
products, things that we can actually
buy and give to our loved ones for
dementia or Alzheimer's, where are we
with the data? Right. So I I like that
story because it's a very realistic
story. We tried it. It's a relatively
safe intervention as long as they talked
to the doctor and the doctor approved.
You know, the side effects may be
limited, but is there going to be
benefit? In that case, maybe some of the
symptoms associated with Alzheimer's got
a little bit better. You know, there's
interesting data with with CBD for
sleep, and there's interesting data for
other aspects of brain health, anxiety,
um, even seizures. There's even an FDA
approved drug version of CBD for
seizures. But when it comes to treating
the dementia, the memory, I'm a little
more skeptical. When it comes to
treating the symptoms, I would say
maybe. All right. Another big claim
about CBD is that it can help improve
memory or mental performance. Let's
bring in investigative reporter Mars
Gavakmpo who's been investigating this.
What kind of products did you find?
Yeah, you know, I went online and in
stores and found a wide variety of
products from CBD capsules to powders
that have other herbs mixed in to oil
tinsters, even bottled drinks. And you
know, these products will make a variety
of claims. They have a lot of buzzwords.
They'll say things like stay sharp,
boost your brain function. They'll even
make really broad claims like optimize
brain health. Those are the things that
we're seeing. So, you made some calls uh
talked to people who were selling these
CBD products. You're the best at this
investigative game. So, what do they
yield to you? What do they reveal to
you? Yeah. Six out of the seven stores
that we called said that CBD can help
you with memory function. Some went as
far to recommend specific dosages to
take. And what's most alarming is that
some of them told us that CBD can help
with the early signs and symptoms of
dementia.
See that? This was happening. I think I
and I'm hearing it from my viewers over
and over again. And I don't want to even
call people liars because who the heck
knows? Maybe the right kind at the right
time might make a difference, but we
don't know enough to make those claims.
And that's alarming at six out of seven
shops, you know, bricks and mortar
facilities. Imagine what's going on
online. So, up next, can these products
help you really stay sharper? Or are
they just hype? Well, we tried them to
find out.
[Applause]
Jeffrey Epstein. Was it suicide or
murder? The medical examiner that was
inside his autopsy. Plus, the photos
that question how he died. All new OS.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Applause]
[Music]
We're back investigating 99 questions
about CBD. Can CBD help boost your brain
and improve your memory? One of the
biggest questions I get. Mars Gavakmpo
is here with her 3-day experiment trying
CBD brain products. Yeah, Dr. Oza, I
really wanted to know if these products,
which vary widely in dosages and
ingredients, would help me focus so I
could get through more of my to-do list
and my tasks, especially in the
afternoon when my concentration
generally starts to wne.
I'm going to test three CBD products to
see how they help with things like
memory, sharpness, and focus overall.
The first is a drink. So, you just drink
it up. These are capsules. I'll take
them throughout the day. And lastly,
sublingual drops.
The first product that I'm going to try
are these sublingual drops.
It reminds me of stuff my mom used to
give me as a kid to help me go to the
bathroom.
I've been working now for about 2 hours
straight. This is normally the time of
day where I would want some coffee. I'd
have a little bit of dip in energy. But
I have to say I do feel like I have been
very very focused and very calm. I just
feel at ease. I don't feel frantic, not
jittery.
So, I'm not sure if that is the reason,
but I've had a very productive
afternoon. It's day two, and today I'm
going to drink this before I start my
afternoon busy work.
Well, it definitely tastes a lot better
than that oil. It would be hard to taste
worse than the oil. Um, it really just
tastes like kind of a watered down apple
juice.
So, I've done nothing but procrastinate
all afternoon
and now I'm backed up because there are
certain things that I have to finish.
So, I'm going to have to kind of plow
through them. But, I will say I was not
focused at all this afternoon.
It's day three. Last up,
capsules. Uh, the instructions say take
one to three daily. I'm going to take
three. Again,
I'm taking it before doing the same
tasks, computer work, emails, the boring
stuff.
Those capsules absolutely have had a
calming effect on me and they I actually
realized that I'm rushing to do a lot of
things that don't need to be done today.
I'm not facing any hard deadlines today.
So, I just cut my to-do list in half.
Now, that may not be the most productive
thing, but it does feel really good for
me.
[Music]
Dr. Ro is joining us as well. Mara,
great three-day experiment. What
surprised you the most when you're
looking at CBD? Yeah, what surprises me
is that I really do feel an effect. I've
now tested several products over the
years and I really do believe that they
work, but for me the overwhelming effect
has been to be relaxed, but it doesn't
help me be more productive. I really
felt like I wasn't getting as much done.
Uh Dr. Isacson, you know, we you
discussed dementia, Alzheimer's,
not so sure about that in CBD, but what
about this issue of focus and
concentration, right? So, there's been a
variety of studies that have looked at
um CBD and and mental focus and and
mental clarity. And I think just like
your experiment, different types of CBD,
different ways to drink it, different
doses may really yield different
effects. It also may depend on whether
you take it during the morning or during
the evening. So, I think the data is a
little bit unclear, but I think there's
some promise for it. You've had personal
experience, Dr. Isacson. Yeah. So, I I
um not for prevention of Alzheimer's
disease. I do have family members that
have it. Um but I've actually used CBD
myself for headaches. Um, I have pretty
severe headaches and I actually am on
specific FDA approved drugs and other
treatments, but I talked to my doctor
and I said, "Hey, what do you think
about CBD?" And I decided to try it
myself. Um, just like you, I tried the
drink and I tried the pills and I tried
the gummies and I I literally tried one
of each. And honestly, it took about 10
or 12 different tries until I found one
type that I can take right before bed so
I don't have any of the woozy or or
seditive side effects. And I wake up in
the morning and the next day I'm a
little bit less likely to have a
headache. But if I do have a headache,
maybe the pain is a little bit lower.
But what you just articulated is so
critical for all of us to understand
that it might work for you if you find
the right one. You had a question, an
important question that links CBD and
marijuana maybe. Yeah. You know, Dr.
Isacson, some studies suggest that
marijuana could have a negative effect
on long and short-term memory. Should we
worry about this with CBD? This is a
great question and it's important that
when we ingest CBD oftentimes in the
products that you tested there may be
CBD but there may be other compounds. Um
for example there may be low levels of
THC or tetrahydroinabonol.
THC is the stuff that makes the
psychoactive effects and makes you feel
different in marijuana. In marijuana
exactly so depending on the product um I
think the devil is in the details like
Dr. Ros said some people may need a
little bit of this a little bit of that.
It's the combination, the dose, the
timing, and some people, it's probably
not going to work at all. Bottom line,
there's no good evidence right now for
CBD and brain health. But I do see
opportunities on the horizon, whether
it's for treating Alzheimer's, dementia,
improving memory. We're going to track
the latest research for you, and we'll
continue to bring you updates. Next week
in our CBD series, can CBD help melt
away stress and anxiety? That is
probably the single biggest question I'm
getting these days. We're revealing what
we've uncovered from a coast to coast
survey, and test results are going to be
there that, well, they might surprise
you. Tune in next Wednesday. If you have
a burning CBD question, go to my website
and submit it. We'll be right back.
[Applause]
Coming up on the Dish on us, I've got
these two chefs to confess to get this.
Use this microwave. Okay, wait a second.
Just because I'm a food expert does not
mean I'm always fancy. That's right.
We're going to reveal the secret way
chefs use microwaves to make our cooking
easier, but just as yummy.
If there's one thing that brings us all
together, it's food. So, we're calling
everyone to the table to dish on
everything from the latest food hacks
and trends to everyday recipes you can
make for dinner tonight. It's simple.
It's celebratory. And most of all, it's
about having a great time in the
kitchen. What is going on? I'm trying to
help. Let's dish.
Welcome back. The dish on Oscar is here
today and I asked Gail and Daphne a big
challenge. Here's the deal. Could they
tap their amazing culinary skills and
think inside the box? Like the microwave
box, right? So, what are you dishing up,
Daffhne?
Well, today you guys, we are making sure
that the microwave is not just for dorm
rooms or reheating leftovers anymore.
Gail and I have put our collective
culinary wisdom together, and today we
are sharing the chef's secrets to
microwave your way to quick and easy
meals. I'm going to hold on tight.
Cheers to that. Cheers to that. We are
making, get this, you guys, a lightened
up spaghetti carbonara with bacon. Not
skimping on the bacon. And to go with
that, we are going to make some yummy
roasted garlic bread. And by the way,
shaving literal hours off of your cook
time here. And then a chocolate brownie
mug cake. You are going to love.
Hallelujah. My favorite little magic
trick. I love this cake. It's a magic
trick in the kitchen. And it's really
fun for kids to watch. just if you want
to if you have a doctor in the house who
wants to then explain the science of how
it all works. It's really cool. But
anyway, my kids I think it's really fun,
too. Um, let's start with the main
course. I'm going to show you guys how
to make a spaghetti squash dinner with a
lightened up carbonara sauce. It's all
made in the microwave and um and it's
just something fun. I use a lot of
spaghetti squash in my cooking at home
because a you know, the sauce is what
counts and spaghetti squash is an
incredible standin if you're looking to
cut carbs or you want to swap out um
your pasta. So, spaghetti squash
obviously shows up at the grocery store
looking like this. You just slice it in
half. And then I'm going to scoop out
the seeds here. So, I'm just going to
add a little olive oil here. Gail, if
you'll grab this guy and just rub them
down with that olive oil and a little
salt. Thank you very much. And then I'm
just going to put it um cut side down
into a dish like so. We can do one at a
time or we can squeeze them into the hot
tub. Come on, guys. Share the hot tub.
Okay. And all you want to do is put
about an inch of water, tap water, up uh
on top of the uh squash so that you
actually are going to help steam it from
the microwave. Um, so I have about that
inch of water in there. It really is.
It's a squash spa. A squash spa. And by
the way, guys, 15 minutes in your
microwave and out it comes. Show me what
you're working with, Gail. Oh, yeah.
There you go. Check this out. And it
comes out. So, you can tell it's done.
Look, it's nice and it's nice and um,
you know, resist. It doesn't resist your
touch like that. Comes out looking like
so. And we each have one on our plates
that I'm going to show you how to come
how to uh, scrape and pull apart. But
obviously the carbonara sauce needs to
happen next. I've got four egg yolks
here. And this is, you know, you can see
it's sort of the traditional sauce here.
I've got a nice amount of pecorino or
parmesan, whichever you'd like. Then
I've got a little pinch of pepper. And
then because I promised you guys bacon
in this dish, I saved a little bacon fat
for you. Right there. You're good to us.
Just a little bit to give it some of
that fatty. I thought that was olive
oil. How mistaken I was. Smell it. No,
it's bacon. It's for sure bacon. Okay, I
gave you guys each some here. Now,
here's how fun this is to give everyone
their own portion. Okay, so grab some
Oh, we do it first. Yeah. Grab about
half of this sauce. And that's just what
I made right there. That egg yolk
mixture with the cheese. And then use
your fork and just pull up those strands
down from the skin. Okay. Give that a
little toss around right onto your
plate. And of course, grab some crispy
bacon. Give that a little topping here.
What are you doing? What are you? You
don't even need the bacon. You get the
bacon arguably. We always need the
bacon. You don't even need it. And give
that a quick taste. Let's see. Let's
season if we need to. Let's grab a
little bit. It actually the texture is
so reminiscent of real pasta, but of
course it's low carb, low glycemic. You
can do this on keto. You can have a
fantastic time. All right. So, it's time
to tally up how much we saved in time
with the microwave, right? Are you ready
for this recipe? The dish took 15
minutes to cook using the microwave. In
the oven, it would have taken 40
minutes. Time zap. 25 minutes.
Absolutely. Um, now here's the thing.
That's not the only time we're saving.
You're not going to believe this next
chef microwave secret. You can roast
garlic in the microwave. Gail, give us
the details on how to roast garlic. So,
everyone knows you can roast garlic in
the oven. You just roast it. You slice
it in half. Roast it in foil if you
want. I'm going to do the most amazing
microwave trick. So, you take a full
head of garlic and you just slice it in
half. Sort of 2/3 of the way up the
garlic head. So, it looks like this. Put
it in a bowl. I'm going to drizzle just
a little bit of olive oil on it. A
little bit of pepper
as well, some salt, and just a little
bit of water in the bottom. That little
bit of water is actually critical in
both of these recipes cuz that's part of
how the steam that's the cooking.
Exactly. I'm going to cover it. I'm
using another plate. I don't want to use
a plastic if I can help it. And then I'm
going to put it in the microwave right
here. And I'm going to take out the one
that I've cooked for eight or nine
minutes. Now, keep in mind, everybody's
microwave is a little bit different. So,
you have to watch it. I would look at it
halfway through. Make sure nothing's
exploding. Microwaves can be a bit
unruly. They get very hot. So,
everyone's going to be a little
different. This is about eight or nine
minutes in the microwave. And look how
brown and roasted and beautiful that is.
They keep you pinch them out. Yeah.
Well, here you go. Exactly.
Okay. So, to make perfect roasted garlic
bread, this is the greatest trick, too.
You have it and it you know that it has
pulled itself away from the skin. So all
you have to do is squeeze and all those
beautiful Does this actually work? It's
exactly the same as it was. It really
looked roasted, right? Make sure I don't
get that piece of ste, as you said, they
pulled away. Yep. Get all those pieces
out. And I'm just going to squeeze it
into a bowl with some parsley, some soft
like room temperature butter, and then
some chili flakes, a little salt and
pepper. Mash it all up, and you have
ready to go roasted garlic bread. So, as
you get ready to taste this, we're going
to talk about how much time we have
saved roasting garlic in the microwave
because it looks exactly the same as if
you had actually taken it to an oven.
Eight minutes, as you mentioned, Gail,
normally you have to to take it roughly
about an hour cooking an oven. That's 52
minutes. We have zapped off this recipe
with our microwave. How's it taste?
Great. Would you like to have a little
bite? And you can just serve this like
this kind of rustic and beautiful on the
table as a perfect side dish to your
carbonara spaghetti squash or you know
as an appetizer before the meal and
garlic fresh. Why waste 52 minutes when
it tastes exactly the same in the
microwave. I'll toast never going back.
You know what? I'll take this app.
Cheers. I'll raise you a main course
which you made also. But when we come
back we have a microwavable dessert you
can reach for whatever you want.
Something indulgent in just seconds.
Stay with us.
Jeffrey Epstein. Was it suicide or
murder? The medical examiner that was
inside his autopsy. Plus, the photos
that question how he died. All new Oz.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
We're back with a dish on Oz. And
microwaves have taken over that kitchen.
But here's the question. Can you really
microwave dessert and make it taste
great? Dish the details on this
concoction you come up with. Let me tell
you, the first time I saw this trick, I
thought it was magic. The fact that you
can make an ooey gooey delicious brownie
lava mug cake that is rich. It's poetry.
Delicious.
It takes 90 seconds. 90 seconds. On the
clock. So, here's what you do. The
simplest thing you'll ever make and your
friends and family will think you're a
genius. You can thank me later. Flour in
a bowl. I'm gonna mix in some sugar,
cocoa powder, a little bit of baking
powder, and just a pinch of salt. Okay.
All your dry ingredients into a bowl.
Give it a bit of a whisk. So, basically
homemade cake mix. Just really easy.
Exactly. Cake mix. Very simple. I mean,
no actual tricks here. It's just the
magic of the microwave. I'm going to
pour in some milk.
cup of milk. And you want to just pour
in that vanilla. Oh yeah, you gotoop.
There you go.
Look how clean we are. This is ready to
go. I love that part of this. Makes it
easy. This is the whole thing. Then I
literally just divide this cake mix into
four mugs. Microwavable mugs, microwave
safe mugs. Divide them in. And then the
most beautiful part, take a little
square of chocolate. I prefer dark
chocolate, of course. Stick it in the
center.
of each of the mugs in the cake mix.
This is the molten situation. Going to
be very satisfying later. Okay, so these
are going to go in the microwave. If you
want to grab me the finished one, 90
seconds. You want to cook for 30 second
intervals three times until it's done.
You'll know they're done when they have
a slight jiggle, but they look like
baked cake.
[Applause]
Oh, wow. Dad, look at that. They're
They're jiggling in the middle, but not
on the sides. This is it. They're done.
They're warm. Wow. I'm going to top them
with a little bit of vanilla ice cream,
right? Why stop with chocolate? Exactly.
It looks like um hot cocoa kind of but
better version.
Thank you very much. Have a bite, guys.
Cheers, guys. Cheers. Mhm. Cheers, Dad.
Okay, give us a little taste here. Oh,
it is. It's ooey gooey as described.
Full molten. Are you kidding? chocolatey
gooey cake and it's fully cooked. Oh my
goodness.
And I I actually one of my all-time
favorite desserts is brownies alam mode
because you get that warm brownie that
starts to melt the ice cream on top of
it and it just it the whole thing is
it's a race. You have to eat it fast.
This is what's happening. My favorite.
Okay, you guys. Speaking of microwaving
chocolate, everyone is freaking out over
Kim Kardashian's Snapchat video of she
and her sister Courtney. Of her and her
sister Courtney eating microwaved M&M's.
We didn't believe. We had to try for
ourselves. I put it in for 20 seconds.
We got ourselves a hefty portion of
M&M's, you guys. Wow. Okay, let's see if
this really works. Give it a try. I'm
going I mean, I will eat an I will eat
an M&M kind of anyway you give it to me.
But she did a good sell on it. I mean,
it is just that nice little warm soft
center. It takes advantage of that candy
coating so it doesn't melt everywhere.
Stays warm on the inside. Personally,
I'll go with a lava cake here. Uh-huh.
But when we come back, we have the food
that rivals my love of Greek yogurt.
He's still in my heart. Do I have a new
love? Stay tuned. It's all happening,
guys.
We're back with a dish. And I was
asking, could anything replace my
beloved my beloved Greek yogurt? Right.
Well, there's a delicious creamy
contender that has, get this, just as
much protein as Greek yogurt and even
more protein than two eggs. Daffy, it
is. Mhm. It is our food find of the day,
you guys. Daisy cottage cheese. Cottage
cheese is making a comeback as America's
go-to snack or meal because it's packed
with protein, like you just said, and
also because it's delicious. Can I stop
for a second? I got through college on
cottage cheese and I grew up as a little
boy. My mom would put cottage cheese and
and peaches together. I don't know what
happened to it. It disappeared for a
Didn't this seem to go away? So, today
we're going to make cottage cheese
breakfast bowls, giving you a kind of a
new spin on how to use that cottage
cheese. Dad, you're going to start
making one over there. Then, I'm going
to show you a couple others that would
work. And what I really love about Daisy
cottage cheese is made with simple
ingredients like cultured skim milk,
cream, and salt, plus no added sugar. I
love this. I love when you turn the
label around and you can see exactly you
recognize the ingredients and there's
only three of them here. It comes in two
varieties, 2% lowfat or 4% regular. So,
it can be a great way to get some
healthy fats into your day, too. And
what I really love about Daisy Cottage
cheese is how versatile it is. So, you
can add it to any recipe that needs some
creamy protein boost like some pancakes
or even pasta sauces in some cases. But
today, I want to show you two different
bowls that I'm making with 4% Daisy
cottage cheese because they're just so
pretty and they're also so delicious.
So, here I'm going to show you a savory
breakfast bowl. This one's kind of cool
because people think cottage cheese,
sometimes they think sweet. This one
actually uses roasted broccoli. I added
a layer of um smoked or or toasted
almonds there as well. I love that bit
of crunch. Then, I'm going to take a
wedge of lemon just to kick it up a
notch with that little bit of that tangy
kick. And I also added a little bit of
chili pepper flake because I do like
that bit of zing to it. This is a really
fun lunch or dinner or snack or a savory
breakfast if you like that. My dad is
making a sweet one. This one I think is
such a clever idea. Dad, tell us about
this dish. This is cottage cheese base.
Yeah. Some pears, some figs, toasted
walnuts. Omega threes in there. Guys,
look at how Instagrammable this is. Come
on. Give it a little drizzle. Little
drizzle. Like this. This could be you.
This could be you. Okay. Give it a
taste, too. Let's see. I I already know,
you know, I got to say I think this year
this year cottage cheese makes its big
comeback. It takes over where it should
be a top the line
fills your mouth diversity if you want
your your your protein from different
sources. I think it's a fantastic
solution. So, thanks to our sponsorship
partner, Daisy Cottage Cheese. My entire
studio audience is going home with a VIP
coupon for Daisy Cottage cheese. Enjoy
it. Oh, Gail, I love having you here.
Thank you. It's so my pleasure to be
here. You judge great, but your cook
even better. God bless you. It's been so
fun to hang out with. You can find every
recipe we dished up today on
dr.com/theish
and all of our sharable pictures on
Instagram at The Dishon. Send us some
notes. We'll see you next time. Bye,
guys.
[Applause]
[Music]