Hyaluronic acid, vitamin C, retinol. No,
you're not in chemistry lab, but most
likely in the skin care aisle reading
ingredient labels. So, what do these
ingredients do? And why do
dermatologists swear by them? And can
they help you with your aging skin,
giving exactly what it needs in those
skincare products? Dr. Rothia Rivera,
who's here on behalf of my trusted
sponsor partner, L'Oreal Parish, is here
to tell us more. Why do dermatologists
love these ingredients? Why do the
experts like you swear by them? Well,
hyaluronic acid, vitamin C, and retinol
are three of the top most effective and
derm proven ingredients, doctors. But
even me as a scientist, I get confused
in the skincare aisle. So, why don't we
do something? Why don't we rename them
for what dermatologist use them for? All
right. Hyaluronic acid to plump, vitamin
C to brighten, and retinol to reduce
wrinkles. That's all you need to know.
All right. Then you're going to drive it
home with a couple demonstrations. We're
going to walk you through all three of
these ingredients very specifically.
We'll start with hyaluronic acid, which
is incredibly powerful when you use it
correctly. Yes. So, I butcher a little
skin demo here. Think of your skin
cells, not the ones that make this
beautiful skin, but the ones that may
give rise to wrinkly skin. And they sort
of do this to you. You see, they they're
small, they dry, they flake, they don't
give you the the shine, the the beauty
that you want. That's correct. These are
the dry cells are under our skin, but
hyaluronic acid actually, Dr. Ross,
plumps the skin from within. And exactly
and uh what you can see here is you know
hyaluronic acid Dr. because it's a
naturally occurring molecule in our
bodies, right? But as we age, we lose it
and that's a very a has a a very aging
effect on our skin. So if this is
hyaluronic acid plumped cells compared
to what I just did, watch that happens
when you use products with hyaluronic
acid, the skin regains that, you know,
plump youthful look that we all want and
they bounce. I mean, take a look at
that. This is before and this is after
with hyaluronic acid. Quite a change,
huh? plumping, hydrating
just right from, you know, underneath.
And so what do you do? How do you apply
it? Well, you know, at L'Oreal Paris, we
developed the uh Revital Derm
Intensives. Just use my hand. I see you
when you're doing it. She wants to rub
my hand. I want the plump ones with
hyaluronic acid. We have the Revital
Derm Intensives ampules. Dr. Ross, these
have our highest concentration of pure
hyaluronic acid. They've been validated
by dermatologist to intensely plump the
skin in just seven days. May I just tell
you, don't be fooled by the size. Small
but powerful, huh? Is it? Yes. The
little ampiel. Show me how to use them.
I'm going to show you. Here's what we
do. You tap from the top. You crack from
the top like that. And here's a little
trick. You use the top and you close it
and use it at night. You can use it
twice a day. 7-day treatment. It's
clever. It's smart. Is that fantastic?
So twice a day, seven days. Twice a day,
seven days for that intense plumping.
And this is exactly what your cells I
like it. All right. Plant plumping is
the first thing you said for hyaluronic
acid. For vitamin C, you said it was
about brightness. Yes. Dealing with the
aging skin. Now you have two examples
here. Two, let's say two different
people. They both have equal aging skins
that have lost that brightness that we
crave when we want to look youthful.
That's right. So vitamin C brightens the
skin. Like you said, Dr. Ros, it is a
very powerful antioxidant. As you know,
it's a dorm must have. So, let's take a
look at this. Let's imagine this water
represents your uneven dull skin. Like
you said, two of them. So, what happens
when we uh add um vitamin C, a product
with vitamin C? Research shows that it
actually not only works on future signs
of aging because you know this skin, Dr.
For us, this is exactly what happens
when we are exposed every day to sun,
pollution, dirt. This is what happens.
It ages our skin. It becomes dull
uneven. So, you apply the cream like you
just did. Let's apply, you know, a
vitamin C skinare product. All right.
And and look what happens.
Look at the before and after. Isn't that
the best? It's the best demo you've ever
done on the show. I know. Well, we like
to bring you the best. Bring me the best
for you. But look at that brightness
back. Brightness. And again, this is
vitamin C taken primarily topically.
Topically. Research shows that when you
apply a product with vitamin C, Dr.
Ross, it is not only a very powerful
antioxidant, you know, it prevents
aging. Super important. Like with SPF,
but it also works on those signs of
aging that you already have. Yeah. You
you don't want to be this. You want to
be this. Yes. We want to work on that
uneven skin tone, the dullness that you
all we all have from the sun, the
pollution, the dirt. Retinol is the
third of the ingredients. The retinol I
keep hearing about from dermatologists
because it is powerful in so many ways.
But you going to demonstrate what it
does. Well, retinol, Dr. Os reduces
wrinkles. It is the most researched and
proven molecule that we have. Nothing
bits it. And let me just show you what
it does. This is our skin, right? It's
wrinkle. We have the fine lines, the
wrinkles. When you use products with
retinol, it smooths out the wrinkles.
Simply like that. No more complicated
than that. Smooths it out. Just be
consistent and this is what happens with
your wrinkles. So you got three powerful
products at once. How do you combine
them so people can actually make the
most out of it? You've formulated a new
product that you told me has all three
ingredients at once. Yes. So the L'Oreal
Revital Triple Power Moisturizer. It
doesn't have one but three of the top
dermatologist recommended ingredients
that we just saw. Hyaluronic acid,
vitamin C, and prinol. So plump,
brighten, and reduce wrinkles. Because
Dr. Rush, you should not settle for a
moisturizer that just hydrates. This is
why we call it triple power. Three
ingredients, three benefits, one week.
Yeah. And it's a moisturizer. It is a
fantastic moisturizer. It has terrific
texture. This is This one is actually on
fragrance. Um it's a beautiful,
beautiful texture. Very easy to use
morning and night. One of the beautiful
things about talking about skincare is
you actually have people who've tried
it. So, one of my viewers, Tracy, has
been using the Revital Lift Hyaluronic
Acid Ampules and the Revital Lift Triple
Power Moisturizer for five weeks. Is
that right? Yes. So, what was your skin
like before you started on this little
escapade?
To me, it looked very dull. It looked
lifeless. It was dry. I just was
embarrassed to even take pictures close
up. I saw a lot of lines in my lip and
on my smile. Even before you took this
product, I'm sure that you were worth
taking pictures of. I don't want you
ever thinking that no matter what.
Always. All right. So, you went on the
on the experiment for five weeks. How
did it turn out? I love the results. I
feel like my skin is smooth. I can feel
smoothness. I think it looks smooth. It
looks fresh. It looks plump. I noticed
that a lot of my lines have um
disappeared. I am just thrilled with the
results. Um, I went to the hairdresser
this week and she actually said
something to me without knowing I was
taking a pro or doing a product. That's
great. We love that. And she said, "Your
skin looks so much younger and
healthier." So, I was like, "Well,
actually," and I told her that I've been
using the products. Um, I have told some
of my friends, they're excited to start
beginning to use the products. I
absolutely love it. I traveled. It was
um very little to take along, right? Um,
it was wonderful. A little but powerful,
huh? Yep. As predicted. Barthia, you you
become an influencer. Yes. Yes. People
are going to be jealous of you soon.
Thank you. Her skin, how radiant, how
smooth, you know, it just it, you know,
I'm very excited. Beautiful before,
beautiful after. What's the best way to
apply the system? Well, you use it like
she said, you use it uh the ampule and
then you follow with the triple power
moisturizer and visible results in one
week. Morning, morning and evening.
Morning and evening. Yes. And you know,
use that trick. You use the top um if
you want to use Where do you find it?
What does it cost? You can find both of
these products at Walmart for just under
$20 each. Wow, that's wonderful. Isn't
that fantastic? Yes. You know what makes
it sustainable? God bless you for
coming, sharing your story. Thank you.
Thank you for having me. Thanks to my
partners. Thank you for sending me the
product. Of course. That feels good. It
does feel good. You know, the work that
goes into this, it just it's such a
humbling moment for us. Thank you so
much. Thank you for watching. Don't
forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good