[Applause]
To the former MissUSA, a successful
businesswoman and a controversial fan
favorite on the Real Housewives of
Atlanta. Today, in an Oz exclusive,
Kenya Moore is speaking out about her
recent health emergency. The frightening
pregnancy complications she never saw
coming to the post baby bounceback
photos that are causing a lot of uproar
and conspiracy theories online. Please
welcome Kenya Moore.
[Music]
Hey,
how are you? Oh my goodness, you look
well. Good to see you again. Good to see
you as well. Thank you for joining me
again. The last time you were
here, you weren't married, didn't have a
baby. I mean, life's changed for you.
Yes. It was so funny watching that clip,
I couldn't get those words out. I was so
excited but nervous because I was so
early on and I didn't want to say and it
was like I was put on the spot. I was
like, "Do I say? Do I say?" And it was I
had to put it out there. Are you
enjoying your new reality with a little
baby girl? Oh my god, I'm in heaven.
She's so precious. She's so precious and
has like this little angel face and
she's my whole world. You speak about
angels, but you came close to becoming
one. Uh, yes. So, let's talk a little
about that. So, your feet start getting
swollen. That's your image. Yes. Right.
You gained 17 pounds in one week. In one
week. And what was the diagnosis?
Preeacclampsia.
Have you all heard of that?
Preeacclampsia. Good. We We know the
name. We don't know the symptoms. That
rapid weight gain, uh, protein in urine.
Yep. And high blood pressure. Were you
scared? I was I was scared. It's a
leading cause probably of of moms dying
giving birth to babies. It is. And I
think that I was just not in my right
mind. And I just thought, you know, is
this really real? Do I really have this
condition? I don't understand what's
happening to me. Um I could could have
gone into seizures. Um so many things
can happen. Come on up. I want to show
everybody what actually happened. This
is why it's dangerous for mom and and
for the child. Sure. So this is a simple
way of looking at it. So for the mom,
the big issues are high blood pressure,
which you had stroke because of the high
blood pressure because you burst the
blood vessels in your brain. You can go
to kidney failure, which is what the
protein in the urine is all about. when
the kidneys can't hold on the protein,
they're failing. They're starting to pop
the little blood vessels in there and
leak out the protein and eventually
heart failure because your heart can't
keep up. Yeah. But the other part of the
equation is even if you can save mom for
babies, they're born prematurely often
times. Uh they can not grow normally
because they're were born early and they
may have been sick during the pregnancy.
And unfortunately, we lose a lot of
kids. And this is a big problem that I
want to touch on. It's one of the
reasons I'm so happy you came today.
Yeah. Because it's it's a reality of
moms in America. It's we're not where we
need to be. But let me finish your story
first. 12 hours after you're diagnosed
with preeacclampsia, 12 hours. Well,
yeah. They kept monitoring me and I
noticed, you know, I'm not a doctor, but
I noticed the numbers were going upward.
You know, it was 145 over 90. Then it
was 150 over 100, and it was and um my
doctor said, "Okay, get your bag. We're
going to deliver
today." And my husband wasn't in town. I
was home
alone. Uh, and I just started crying.
So, how'd you deal with that? I mean,
again, it's by yourself. Your life's at
risk. Your baby's life at risk. You
worked so hard to get here. I just
wanted her to be Well, at that point, I
didn't know it was if it was a boy or
girl, but I just wanted her to be
healthy and um I just wanted to deliver
a healthy baby. It was um Sorry. Sorry.
It was
just I didn't want to think about what
could have happened. I prayed and I
called my aunt and she came to get me
and we went to the hospital and he made
it in time and um then it was another
part of the drama in the hospital in the
delivery room. Um they gave me an
epidural. My husband was right by my
side. was holding my hand and you know
they put that sheet up where you can't
really see what's going on and I
remember the tugging the pulling I could
hear everything that was going on but at
some point I woke up
and I tried to talk to them but no one
could hear me no one was responding and
I was trying to force myself to yell
like hey can you hear me hello and no
one was responding and I thought you
know what I'm I died I didn't make it I
I felt like I was dead. Out of body
experience. It was because I knew I had
an epidural. In an epidural, you're
awake the entire time. So when I came to
eventually, I was able to speak and
people
responded and I was told that the
operation lasted for over three hours.
Oh my goodness. It was a 20 25 minute,
you know, operation, a C-section, a
cacaian, and they could not get the baby
out. They cut me. My doctor was cutting
through my uterus, and she said it was
so thick. She just kept cutting and
cutting and she could not reach the
baby. I had fibroids, which is why I'm
in this situation, you know, to begin
with. I had myomectomies and so I had
scar tissue. I still had fibroids and I
didn't want a blood transfusion and I
was bleeding out. So at some point um my
doctor Dr. um Melinda Millard Thrasher
decided that okay we're losing her too
much blood loss. We can't give her a
blood transfusion. We can't get to the
baby. So she not only cut me um
horizontally but then she had to cut me
vertically as well just to get the baby
up. And she said out of 20ome years of
her practicing, I was only the fifth
person that she ever had to cut twice.
It's a miracle you're alive. It's a
miracle I'm alive and my baby's
alive. Yeah. Oh, I have no idea. Yeah.
And my hemoglobins were so low and they
were so worried, but here I am. That's a
lot. It's a lot. A lot of risks all at
once. I know. All right. So you survive
something for all intents and purposes
you shouldn't have. Mhm. And if you're
going to be a miracle, you must be a
purpose to it. Yes. There are a lot of
women who are going to go through what
you went through. This country
unfortunately has a public health crisis
in preeacclampsia. Mhm. And despite
spending more money on healthcare than
any other country, our maternity care,
taking care of moms, is bad. It's worse
at preventing basic things, including
saving lives like yours were saved than
a lot of other developed nations. So I
can talk about this till the cows come
home. But when people like you tell
their personal story and folks at home
see themselves in you, that's what makes
a difference. Good. So God bless you for
sharing with us. I hope I can make a
difference. You are. Three weeks after
Kenya gave birth, she posted this photo.
Believe it or not, this photo which uh I
mean it's fantastic image, but it
unleashed an uproar about her quick
recovery on the internet. And there a
lot of concerns about what the heck was
going on. Find the truth behind these
photos. When we come back, we're back
with our Aussie exclusive with former
Atlanta housewife Kenya Moore, who is
speaking out about her frightening
pregnancy scare. I mean, as a doctor, I
know the real risks you survived. You
probably because you were there
understand them now. But between
bleeding out, three-hour plus operation,
waking up, maybe having crossed over in
the middle of the surgery. Yes. All that
happens and finally they put this little
beautiful baby in your arms. What did
that feel like? Oh, when we saw her,
they lifted her up and they said it was
a girl and she started whailing. She was
crying so hard and they they handed her
to us and skin-to-skin contact and she
was so tiny. She was only 5 lbs. And how
premature was she? Uh 5 and 1/2 weeks.
Yeah. And we they put her on my chest
and I just I just started crying so
hard. I saw the big spread in People
magazine. How's Little Brooklyn doing
now? She is fantastic. She's lifting her
head. She makes all these
faces. Um I think she's a little
advanced. Like she's doing things that a
little a little baby that's only uh five
weeks shouldn't be doing. Good for her.
Yeah. She's probably just should coming
out just about now probably. Exactly. So
you posted this picture. Mhm. And a lot
of folks looked at that and said it's
impossible. It raised doubts about what
had really gone on. You can't tell from
this picture that you had almost died.
Yeah. Yeah. Did you had a huge belly,
swollen feet? How much weight did you
gain during the pregnancy? I gained 75
lbs.
Yeah. And you that that's just a few
weeks later as your feet that were
swollen. Yeah. You know, a lot of it to
be honest because of the preeacclimsia
was water weight gain. So, a week after
I had given birth, I lost like 40 lbs.
But I had a um a C-section. So, I
couldn't really stand up. I obviously
couldn't work out or do anything like
that. But I was a workout person before.
I took care of my body and um I what we
call it just snapped back after like 2
weeks. I thought, "Wow, my my tummy is
flat again, you know, well, nearly
flat." And I didn't think that would
happen. I'm 47 years old, so I was
worried, too. Like, okay, the young
girls get the snapback, but what about
me?
And um so you take care of your body,
you eat well. But what are you eating?
Um I eat a lot of fruit. I drink a lot
of water. A lot of water. Um vegetables.
I'm really a pescatarian, so I I eat a
lot of fish. Um sushi, things like that.
Well, the fruit plate you posted was
beautiful. Oh, thank you. So, I gota ask
one question for all the Housewife fans
out there, and there quite a few of
them. Yes. You know, so you're not on
this coming season of Real Housewives of
Atlanta. I don't know how I could have
done it with a baby. There's no way. So,
are you back next year? I say never say
never. Never say never. That sounds like
a It sounds like you might be pregnant
again. I think she's pregnant and she's
coming back. Oh, that would be a
blessing. I love having you on. I love
being here. And thanks for telling the
story. I know that it's emotional, but
you're going to help a lot of people. I
hope so. God bless you. All right. Thank
you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good