[Applause]
My next guest is an undefeated boxing
world champion who learned the power of
giving back from the champ himself. Now,
Leila Ali is using what her dad taught
her to help improve the lives of
families in need of a fix with simple
home and food makeover hacks that you're
going to want to try.
>> We are going to the kid family. They've
got this living room that needs a little
help.
>> It's beige on top of beige on top of
beige.
>> Cue the transformation team.
>> Tell me what you don't like about it. We
picked up the furniture at a garage
sale.
>> It was a curb sale. It wasn't even in
the garage.
>> Now, this makeover.
>> How you feeling about this? It looks
dangerous.
>> Will take major skills.
>> It's time to get the last pieces in
place
>> to pull off the ultimate surprise.
[Music]
>> Please welcome back to the show, Leila
Ali.
[Applause]
Oh my goodness.
>> How you doing?
>> Nice to see you. Are we working out
today? Working out.
>> We are working out. I will do everything
with you.
>> You usually make me work out when I go.
>> I adore having you. The walk from the
from the workout. Exactly.
>> I'm so proud that you're here and I'm so
proud of your new project.
>> Thank you. And I love to understand how
it carries on the legacy of your dad
because he really instilled in you this
powerful love, this need to help people
who are in need.
>> Yes. This show, Homemade Simple, gives
me the perfect opportunity to do the
things that I love. We're working with
families that are so deserving. We might
have someone that is um you know,
battling terminal illness or someone who
has um their own kids as a single mom
and took in foster kids. So, you
definitely want to give back to them and
I get to, you know, give them spaces
that are just as beautiful and inspiring
as they are and get in the kitchen and
cook with them.
>> Well, you've helped a lot of folks. You
rearrange their homes if they work in
their kitchen, which is a in itself a
pretty brave thing to do. And you've
been able to make some big-time changes
with with with simple moves. That's the
part that's coolest about it.
>> You know, it's when people are going
through a lot and they're stressed, they
the last thing they think about is, you
know, a relaxing master bedroom or a spa
retreat for themsel in their homes. And
then we just expanded into a plantbased
line of cleaning products.
>> I'm proud of you for that.
>> Got lemon, lavender, rosemary, which is
good for memory retention. So I know you
love. So just those small changes,
incorporating them into people's lives
and making them better just makes me
feel good.
>> Of all the people that you've helped,
who what problems have you knocked out
that you're proud of stuff? A family
that's most rewarding.
>> You know, one that really stands out is
a family that had a dad that lost his
arm to cancer about eight years ago. Mom
suffered from heart problems. They have
two children. Mom homeschools and they
have a small home, one big space, but
they do so much in it. She wants a place
to homeschool, a place to read, do art,
you know, living area. I'm like, how are
we going to get all this in one space?
We have such amazing designers and
carpenters and a whole team that we work
with and we actually got it done and it
of course destressed their lives and
they're so much happier now.
>> Well, it's something to behold. In fact,
here's an example of the room. We just
saw a glimpse of it before. This is the
pre-La Ali version, right? And let me
just show the audience what the room
what the first part of the room anyway
looked like right after Leila and her
team were done. You see the after there.
Walk us through what's what's different
there.
>> So I noticed you you you painted the
back wall different.
>> Yeah. So there's different angles of
that room. You're not seeing the whole
room. That was their entryway. But we
definitely had to create defined spaces.
So they when we left they had a living
area. They had their music area, their
reading area. So they were defined
compartmentalized. So to have
organization in your home does wonders
for for families.
>> So there's a couple if you're up for it
that I would like you to help us with.
>> Of course.
>> Similar to what kinds of cases you've
had. Maybe a bit more severe. You'll see
why. Come on over here.
>> Oh, severe. That's a scary word.
>> We got Belinda and Eric here.
>> Okay.
>> They're wonderful people.
>> Hi.
>> You guys look good.
>> How you doing?
>> Thank you. Thank you. May I
>> want your problem?
>> Exactly. She asked for this.
>> Right. So, here's the thing. They come
here and they say when it comes to
making decisions about the home, they
just can't seem to meet me in the middle
and they're starting to cause problems
in the relationship. And if you know
them like I do, there's not a lot of
middle here. You got two very strong,
intelligent people with with we're
opinionated. All right. So, Eric, you
you've been trying to work on this for a
while, right?
>> I have. I have. Absolutely. I have. Um
I'm a stylist as as well. So, to me,
life is all things beautiful.
>> You got a white palette. You got to
splash in color and make it bold. You
know, we live in an amazing space. We're
going to be buying a new home very soon.
And um as far as I'm concerned, if you
move into it, I don't care if you're
there for six months or a year. You want
to know that when you walk in, it's
exactly what you want. It's worth your
work for everything. But my precious
angel here. So you actually
look at this room behind you. One
second. You see that? Now that's the
warm-up, right? Before they've actually
moved, you got a little trial running.
Is that right, Eric? I did.
>> All right. So Linda, your honest
opinion, and you always are honest. What
do you think about Eric's work here?
>> Okay. I like it, but I think it's a bit
much for where we are. Uh, and also
color then the little picture frames and
something inside of the picture frame.
It's a bit much for me.
>> She being polite. She you do you like
it? Yes or no?
>> I don't like it for where we are. No.
>> Okay. So, this is the way it currently
is.
>> Yes, that's the way it it currently is.
>> Right. So, how common is before we get
into the specifics for a couple to have
very strong opinions, both know they're
right, and there's no place for at least
it seems like there's no place where you
could actually design together.
>> Well, first of all, Eric, you did a
really nice job and I can see you know
that you have you both have style. Okay,
I see that you have both have style. I
want to say thank
>> Eric patronizing you. Yes. Yes. I
appreciate that.
>> As we know in design, there's so many
different styles, right? So, it doesn't
mean just because you don't it's not
your style per se. Exactly. Doesn't mean
it's not nice. But you both live there.
So you mentioned white with splash
splashes of color. Like we have a white
canvas. We need splashes of color. But
there is no white here. And I actually
think that the design aesthetic really
pops more when you have a neutral tone.
Cuz one thing I do see is like I'm like
where am I looking? Because you know the
the the artwork is blending with the
wall and the furniture and then the
carpet. Where does it start? Where does
it end? You would have more contrast and
then you would get what you want
>> and you would still have your design.
And I think it would actually pop more
and then it'll have like a fresh look.
And a coat of paint is one of the first
things we do on the show on Homemade
Simple because it's such an easy,
inexpensive transformation and it's
instant.
>> I'm buying Eric a paintbrush.
>> Happy life. Happy life.
>> I hope that's helpful for you.
>> You're trying to figure it out. You see
what I'm saying? Working with me here.
>> I hear you. I hear you.
>> All right. Right. When we come back,
switching from home makeovers to food
makeovers was something all of you are
going to want to try for breakfast.
Stick around. We're back with Ali. Now
it's time to make over breakfast. Now
cooking has always been a big part of
Leila's life. She's been making
delicious meals for her family since she
was a kid. You little You were not not
at that young age.
>> Not at that young age. About 910 I've
been cooking. My mom didn't cook, so I
got in the kitchen early and learned. I
like to eat. Hey,
>> you did it right.
>> Yeah.
>> And today she has a breakfast using
leftovers. That's all you need.
Leftovers. They will keep you full all
day long. It's a quick meal that will
change the way you look at breakfast for
good. Eric and Blinda are back. They
stopped fighting over that little room.
They're back to taste some breakfast.
When it when it comes to breakfast, you
guys get tired of the same old thing.
>> Yes, absolutely.
>> Yes, we do. Yeah, we eat the same thing
every morning.
>> Mix over the the meals, not the people.
That's what I say. So, all right. So,
what are you making today?
>> So, we are making breakfast pasta. Now,
my kids love pasta and they don't love
breakfast food. That's how I came up
with this idea. My daughter's like, I
want pasta. So, I was like, okay, how
can I make this healthy? Get some eggs
in it. You going to help me do this? I'm
going to show you. So, crack these eggs
for me.
>> Dr. O, my sue chef today. Okay,
>> so we're going to go ahead and just
>> How many do you need? just go ahead and
do like two or three. It doesn't matter.
Um it depends on what you like. So we're
going to go and put some oil in the pan.
We've got some precooked pasta here.
Now, everyone likes their pasta a
certain way, right? We've got whole
wheat. We got regular pasta, quinoa
pasta, all sorts of pasta. So if you're
gluten-free, you can still do pasta.
>> Yeah. You can pick your choice, right?
But you're making whole grain today.
>> We're using whole wheat. Yep.
>> Okay.
>> All right. So you can go ahead. Um let's
>> Oh my goodness. That's a lot of garlic.
>> It is. We're not going to put all that
in. We We like to season to taste.
Season to taste. Go ahead and mix those
up. So, you know, you can obviously can
boil this pasta, but I like to use I
always have pasta on hand. Like I said,
my kids love pasta. Okay, so we're just
going to go ahead and toss those in
>> without without spices.
>> I'm going to put the slices in next.
Yeah, there's no wrong way to do this.
It really ends up in the pan. So, I have
some turmeric here
cuz it's just good for you. I like to
just get good for your brain.
>> Yes. And then we have the pepper, right?
>> Yep.
>> And then I'm going to use depending on
how much do you like garlic?
>> I happen to love garlic. Got to go to
work usually after breakfast.
>> Oh, yeah. So, we'll just use a little
bit cuz I don't want anybody talking
about you. I don't want any
>> That's a little bit.
>> Yeah, that's a little bit.
>> Oh, jeez.
>> Don't worry. I got this. I got this. You
want to mix it? You like you're ready.
Go on and mix it up.
>> I tell I love breakfast foods that have
that have dinner components to them.
>> I like to eat what I love. So, whenever
it is, just eat the foods that you like
and make them as healthy as possible.
That's
>> I I used to pretty competitive
>> dairy. That's why I took this back over
cuz I saw you were taking over my dish
and I was like, "Hold on, Dr. Eyes. Hold
on. Come on over here, Eric. Come over.
Are you guys competitive?
>> Okay, we're going to play a little game
I play at my house. Grab one little
strand there.
>> And you grab one, Eric. Linda,
>> good. You guys ready?
>> Yes, we grab a really long one. All
right. Now, here's the deal. All you got
to do is slurp it up a You got You're
short. It's a lot shorter than mine. So,
I'm
>> All right. Let me see yours. You're the
one I carry. I'm going to beat you.
>> No, I'm going to beat you. Are you
ready? Put your mouth, guys. Share your
side. Three, two, one.
[Applause]
You lost.
>> I lost. How did you even the ladies out
of the way?
>> Yeah. How' you do that?
>> Doc, do you have that on slow-mo? Is it
Where is he hiding?
Slow. Come over here. Oh my goodness.
>> Seriously, I can't stir up that fast.
>> I know.
>> You practice at home?
>> No, I didn't.
>> I might have cheated a little bit. I
think I just kind of used my fingers,
but it's okay. I just couldn't let you
win. I couldn't let you win.
>> Well, you won. You won. All right. So,
this is basic. They make it scrambled
eggs with some pasta in it.
>> Yes. So, basically this is done. Okay.
And what I love about this is you could
add vegetables. You can add whatever you
want to it. You know, make it your way.
Do like a pasta bar. But I have some
turkey, some meatball um that I we
pre-made here. But I love to do meatball
turkeys.
>> I'm sorry, I said meatball turkey.
Turkey meatball.
>> They comes in both forms.
>> Yes, exactly.
>> And you put a couple in here.
>> And these again, these could be from
last night.
>> Yeah. And we already have um some for us
to taste. I'm just showing you how you
put taste that. Let's see what you guys
think.
>> Very good.
>> And here's one for you and one for me.
>> Are the kids usually happy eating this?
That's the question.
>> They are. I wouldn't put too too don't
want to put the herbs on for my kids or
they would eat it. Yeah.
>> You don't want them to see that?
>> No, definitely not.
>> Belinda slurper. Miss the slurper
champion of the world. What do you
think?
>> This is delicious. Very good.
>> Go like it. Eric, you happy?
>> I tell you what, in my home I, you know,
this is a design question. I think
everyone ought to focus their lives
around their kitchen, eating the right
foods, but it also is where communities
always happen.
>> Oh, yeah. that my my kitchen is my happy
place and my and my family room is right
off the kitchen because then my family
knows I'm going to be in the kitchen so
you better want to be you want to be
close to me.
>> Well, I'll make it the first room you
make over when you come to my house. God
bless you. You can check out by the way
dr.com or more importantly check out Lea
Ali's show homemade simple. It's on own
every Saturday.
>> Thanks, Angel.
>> Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
subscribe and turn on notifications so
you never miss out on new videos to live
the good