You're my best friend. My best friend.
Dr. Oz's best
[Music]
friend. My morning routine
is very quick. Water, lemon
juice, off to
work there.
Okay.
Water. You could act to kill the tub,
but it's a little early.
[Music]
When we posted this little video of my
morning routine, which was filmed by Dr.
Royen, so many of you had tons of
questions about lemon and water. It
happens to be one of my family's
favorite eating hacks. That was me
before work, so you can see it was still
dark outside. So, today, everything you
want to know about lemon water. And if
you've been bored by your diet or not
seeing the results that you want, we are
revealing the Oz family's hacks that
will get you out of a rut. Please
welcome my beautiful wife and editor at
large of the Good Life Bookazine, Lisa
[Applause]
Oz. So, this is the one like most moms
has got to get the kids out of a rut. We
all get into them once in a while. When
you see something happening, how do you
know it's a person in a rut? What are
the symptoms? Well, with food, the way
you know that you're in a rut, there are
a couple things. The first is pay
attention to your body. How do you feel?
Is the food you're eating making you
feel sluggish or moody or bloated? If
you're feeling bad, you're going to need
to change things up. Secondly, it's is
it boring? Cuz if you're not enjoying
what you're going to eat, what you're
eating and you're not having fun and
it's not delicious, then you're going to
cheat and eat something else. So, if
you're either of those are off, you know
it's time to change. And the great thing
about these hacks is they are super
simple and you get if you do them and
you stick with them and they're just
tiny little adjustments, it makes it
much easier easier to change other
stuff. All right, so we're going to
start off with the big eating hack to
get you out of a rut which is using
lemon in water, right? It's a great way
to boost your immunity. It takes her
seconds to do. Lisa posted this video of
my morning ritual, right? Thousands of
people responded with questions.
Everyone wanted to know why we start our
days drinking lemon water. And this is
one of those little rut changes Lisa
mentioned because most of us have coffee
first thing in the morning, right? I
want you just to try this. Just take a
couple days, put the coffee down. You
can have it an hour or two after you
wake. But the first thing you should do
in the morning is a little bit of water
with lemon. Why this timing? Well, first
thing in the morning, but lemon water is
great for you. If you you sleep all
night, eight hours, you probably get six
and a half to eight. You're dehydrated.
You haven't had anything to drink for
that amount of time. So, you need to
drink water when you first wake up. You
put lemon water in it and it boosts it.
So, as you said, it improves your
immunity. That's from the vitamin C, but
it also has a lot of minerals in it,
which makes it surprisingly alkal
alkalinizing um instead of acidifying
even though it is an acid and um it
tastes delicious. So, you'll be more
likely to drink it and it's um so good
for you. So, who here has tried lemon
juice in the morning with water? Couple
people, right? Spattering a polite a
polite spattering of applause. So here's
the deal, right? And because it most
people think I'm not going to like it,
I'm not going to like it. If you try it,
you'll find it's relatively mild, right?
Now, here's another question that comes
from Instagram all the time when is
which is will the acid in the lemon
bother my stomach? A very rational
question. Let me explain something
that's pretty profound. This lemon,
right, has an acidity that is no greater
than your stomach's. So, when you put a
little bit of lemon juice in water,
you're diluting it, which means your
stomach acidity is at least a hundred
times more than this lemon juice with a
little water that we're talking about.
Often a thousand or 10,000 times more
acidic than the lemon juice I'm
recommending. But it is more acidic than
your mouth. So, after you drink this,
you should probably rinse with plain
water. Yeah. You don't want it sitting
on your teeth. This is an excuse to
drink more water. Once you start with
this, it gets you going. And don't drink
the seeds. They're not good for you. I
didn't know that. Yeah, you're drinking
the seeds. Now you're telling me after
33 years of marriage now I learn
Instagram you didn't notice. So acidic
foods what do they do? First of all they
keep the blood sugar more stable. So if
you have some carbs around it doesn't
hurt you so much. Some say it helps with
constipation. Could it really? I want to
see how things move. It helps me. Does
it help you? I've never had that
problem. Oh. So no personal experience
but I wanted to see if it would work for
all of you. So we did an experiment. We
had three women and let's see. You guys
were all backed up, right? This is
Marlene, Sarah, and Rose. I don't want
to put words in your mouth, but let's
just assume I'm right and saying you
were backed up. I want to know the
verdict. Did the lemon juice in the
morning help you? Are you ready? Not
really. Sarah. Sarah's happy. Oh, look
at that smile. Look at that smile. I'll
take one out of three. I will take one
out of three. That's the thing. If you
don't like lemon, and some people don't
like the taste, there's a new twist
that's a little less tart. I just made
it for you. Take a look. I got to start
squeeze it. The nice thing about pomelo
is it's a little less sweet than a
grapefruit and in water.
Pretty good actually. This might be the
new deal. All right, we got lemon juice
down. Next eating hack to get you out of
a rut is whey protein because research
shows that whey protein can actually
suppress your appetite. Especially when
you compare it to other proteins, it's
more likely to improve your satiety. You
have a super easy hack, I'm told. Oh,
yes. adding whey protein to a whole slew
of things. You know, I'm a vegetarian,
so I'm always looking for ways to get
more protein into my diet. So, you can
add whey protein to your smoothie, which
is what I do every day, or you can put
it in oatmeal, you can put it in your
yogurt, but this is the hack. Put it in
your coffee. That much? Too much? No,
it's perfect. It's like a creamer. You
want actually you want to add it a
little at a time so it doesn't clump.
And or you can use a little mini whisk,
but you you try try this. It has a nice
creamy flavor and it gives you the
protein that'll keep you full. You can
go for, you know, hours without being
hungry after you drink this. Really,
it's brilliant. Yeah. Why would we ever
use creamers anymore? Seriously, there's
a whole spoonful of protein powder and
you get different flavors, right? This
actually I wouldn't do that. I would not
like do a ch Well, I guess you could do
a cocoa mocha. This is good. This is a
chocolate. You should name this. Yeah.
The Lisa Mocha. Okay. Lisa Mocha Cocoa.
Yeah, sure. All right. We'll figure
something out. Anyway, the next eating
hack is to create a carb calendar. This
is actually a big issue for a lot of
folks because you know you have to use
whole grains but to use them the right
way. So, how do you get us out of a rut?
Well, we talked I said before one of the
things you know that you need to switch
up is if you're bored and if you're
eating the same grain, say brown rice
every day, you're going to be bored. And
when I get bored, I go for pizza. I
don't know about you guys, pizza, French
fries, not healthy carbs. So, this is a
way to switch up your healthy carbs.
Choose a different carb every week. It
can be quinoa. It can be millet. It can
be bulgar wheat. It can be barley. Um,
so you pick that on Sunday or Saturday
in the beginning of the week. You make a
big batch of it and you put it in the
refrigerator if you want. You can even
put it in the freezer for later. And
then you can just add in whatever you
want. So how do you how do you actually
make it? Like this is a feroh. This is
ferro, right? Yeah. Pharaoh is actually
just like a wheat. It is a wheat
actually. It's a a type of wheat. So
just dump it into boiling water. Here
you go. Mis learning. Like you're making
pasta. Oh yes. Oh, I'm making farrow for
my wife. Oo. And I better put a little
salt in there. I know. That is salt,
right? Yeah, it was salt. And that's how
you do. And then you just add whatever
you want every night. Something
different. Like you could do a Thai
curry vegetable. This is one of the
things that I love. Again, faro is like
pasta. So anything you put on pasta, put
on the faro. Tomatoes, zucchini, a
little grated parmesan, some basil. Just
a little different. And you were saying
you could freeze it. It can last forever
then. Well, not forever. Not through the
zombie apocalypse, but for a long time.
Up next, if you've been watching what
you eat, I know you've probably been
eating a lot of these of late, right?
Here's the question. Who has the better
egg snack hack? The egg snack hack that
I'm going to offer you is fantastic.
Lisa's got Well, we'll see. Anyway, find
out whose recipe is going to break the
internet when we come back. We are back
with the family healthy eating hacks to
get you out of a rut. Now, the next hack
has to do with a food that is more Insta
famous than Kylie Jenner. It's got 48
million likes. Look at that. It's an
egg. It's an egg. When you're trying to
eat healthier, everyone says load up on
hard-boiled eggs for easy protein. But
listen, guys, that gets sort of boring,
right? I mean, hard-boiled eggs, that's
not so much to that. So, today, who has
the better egg snack hack? Me or
me? I've been campaigning with the
judges, who you'll meet in a few
seconds, whose recipe is going to break
the internet and give that Instagram egg
a run for its money. So, why do you
think you're an expert? Oh, you're such
a punster. Now, you I'm sure you're
alluding to my childhood on the farm
where we had chickens, but I'm not an
expert, but I do love eggs. I love that
they're a great source of protein. I
love that they're cheap, and I love that
they are so easy. I mean, insanely easy.
No one can. You can't even mess up an
egg. I've tried boiling water, egg, it
works. Bingo. Done. So, I have been
doing my homework, researching eggs up
and down. Have you had no 360 view of an
egg? There's actually a lot of science
to boiling an egg, right? And most of
you don't know this, but you're actually
supposed to begin the by putting the egg
in cold water and heating it up. When
you put the water and the eggs together
and they temp come up in temperature
together, it helps promote even cooking
and prevents cracking. They also want to
add a pinch of salt, right? That can
help solidify the egg white the little
faster. So, it's a perfect egg. So, heat
it up together with the water. Little
pinch of salt. That's a little easy
extra bonus hack. But the basic thing is
timing, right? And you all know this,
but let me put it down in real clear
numbers. If you only boil the egg for
four minutes, which is the right thing
to do, by the way. This is the way he
likes it all runny. You will get it
beautiful. Ooey gooey. Look at this.
It's coming in. Oh, it's fantastic.
Right. This is how I like to eat them.
And again, I like the taste of eggs.
However, if you want a firmer yet still
moderately runny egg, right? Then boil
it for 7
minutes. Is this what you like? No, I'm
down there. Why would anyone want a
10-minute boiled egg? It's a That's a
hardboiled egg. It's just hard. No. How
many hardboiled hard 10-minute people
are out there? Oh my goodness. See,
it tastes like cardboard. Okay, it's the
moment of truth, right? Whose egg snack
hack is better, Lisa's or mine? So, you
get to go. You want to go first? You go
first. Yes, of course. Thank you. No,
this is so simple. We'll take you just a
second. So, I start with avocados. So
creamy and delicious. You know what? I
actually think of this as like a Do you
guys like egg salad? You guys eat egg
salad? So, this is kind of like a a
healthy version deconstructed egg salad.
And and this instead of mayo, you use
the avocado, which are delicious. Then
you just take a hard-boiled egg. You
chop it up into quarters. Mix it in
there. A little olive oil. Again, some
healthy fats, a little pinch of salt. I
love some chives instead of onion.
They're a type of onion, but they're a
little milder. And then a little
parsley. And it's just like a
deconstructed egg salad. What do you
got? That's the best you got. All
right, here's my egg snack hack. I
present to you everybody the Bosphorus
egg, right? It's honor of the Bosphorus
Strait in Turkey where my parents are
from. This is what the final product
looks like. And I'm going to demonstrate
this. Again, ingredients, pretty simple.
You have an egg, right? You have hummus,
you have some goat cheese, and then you
have some whole grain crackers, right?
All you do, take the eggs. Don't
overcook them like I pointed out
earlier. Put the egg in the middle. Very
symmetrical. A little hummus on top.
See, you don't even know how to make it.
You start with the hummus and the cheese
and you put the egg on top. No, I This
is my variation. Oh, I'm sorry. The
finished one. This is the inside. It's
going to fall apart like that. This is
fantastic. Good lord. Any case, the goat
cheese gives you the extra little
creaminess of fewer calories per ounce
than other popular cheeses. Oh, she's
helping me a little bit now. She's
helping me. You need help. Okay, come on
over here. We're going to we're going to
do a little competition. We've got in
order to figure out whose snack is
better, three bike club members who are
harsh critics are tasting away. They
have been evaluating these. We have
spoken earlier. I think we have a
meeting of the minds here. So, bike
club, hold up the egg dish that you
prefer. Maybe one word of compliment
about how I prepared
[Laughter]
mine. What? What? What? I lost two to
one. I hate losing. Thank you. Thank
you. Thank you. Oh, you you can have a
little. I want to thank the bike club
for you for making Oh, please stop it.
God, I hate losing. I lost.
Excellent competition, Lisa. All right,
here's the deal. She works very hard on
the book cazine. It is fantastic. Of
course, called the book Good Luck.
That's what it looks like. It's on new
stands right now, and you guys
thankfully have been very interested in
it as well. Tell us what you like about
it. Give us your feedback. We adore
making it. But in addition, backed by
popular demand, you guys like all the
back issues. There was a your best body
issue which was incredibly popular. Now
we're putting them all up on Amazon so
you can order all the bag issues you
want, read them to your friends, a good
bedtime stories, all you want to do with
it, whatever you want to do, put them in
all your bathrooms, they're yours to
enjoy. Thank you for watching. Don't
forget to subscribe and turn on
notifications so you never miss out on
new videos to live the good