An Oz food investigation. Frozen fish.
One of our favorite heat and eat foods.
But what's really in those fish sticks?
The price is too cheap versus all the
others. There's probably some filler in
it. Are you being conned in your freezer
section? Plus, breaking news on a
dangerous outbreak. You're spreading
billions and billions of droplets and
many people can be exposed to that. How
to protect your family from the measles.
Coming up next.
[Music]
Y'all ready for season 10? Yeah.
I love you back.
[Music]
[Applause]
From this swimming around to this. And
then finally to this, right? Frozen fish
sticks and breaded fish fillets are
hugely popular heat and eat foods for
your families, right? We all eat them,
but they've also been called the hot dog
of the sea. Is there an undercurrent of
deception? Today, we're investigating to
find out if it's cod or a con in the
freezer section of your grocery store.
And to help me out, I invited the man
known as a supermarket guru who tracks
industry food and consumer changes, Phil
Lumper. Thank you very much. Thank you.
So, Phil says there's a lot of ways that
the history of frozen food, the industry
itself, tells us the story of the fish
stick. So, how do those histories match
up? It does. Uh, first of all, I love
frozen foods. When you really think
about it, they're convenient, they
reduce cost, and they give access to us.
So, think about the landlock um in the
middle of the country that didn't have
fish. So, by having frozen fish, what
we've basically been able to do is give
good nutrition throughout the entire
country. And that's so important. Now,
when we look at fish sticks, nobody woke
up in the morning and said, "Hey, I want
a fish stick." you know, whether it was
a kid or or a mom, what it really was is
the food companies going out there and
being able to get all this fish from the
ocean, bring it back, and make it into a
very convenient, very convenient product
because most people are really afraid of
fish. They don't know how to cook it.
Um, and if you look at consumption, fish
consumption is only about 14.7 pounds
per person per year versus poultry or
red meat, 222
pounds of meat. So that's why we need
frozen fish to be able to come into
every home. That's less than 10% of what
we eat in chicken and meat. Do you guys
have any idea about that? No. How many
people are afraid of fish here? Afraid
to cook it. Afraid to cook it. Yeah. Not
afraid of bent attack. Yeah. There are
some folks you would do. We do it the
right way. If we don't do it enough,
might get sick. If we do too much, it
tastes like wood. All right, let's take
a look at why fish stickicks became so
popular because I love when we get to
the roots of how this even happened.
Because you're right, no one came up
with the idea of a fish stickick. There
was a reason for it. So, Americans upped
their fish consumption during the war
when meat was scarce, right? You had
couponing, it was hard to get it, right?
But when sales dropped off, peace of
course broke out, the sales dropped off
and beef went back on the table. You
didn't have to do this. So the fish
industry had to up the ante and find
better ways to cut costs with freezing
and preserving the fish to sell to the
masses. So they got these trollers
ships, right? They became factories at
sea. They would catch and even processed
fish, right, before coming on shore. But
people still weren't convinced because
early frozen fish didn't do so well,
right? It had freezer burn, right? It
was sort of bland. It wasn't winning
over the customers. So, economists from
Harvard and scientists from MIT,
partially funded by our government, set
out to find a winning sales idea. And
Phil, that idea was,
you're going to laugh. It's breading it
and frying it. We love it. It's
delicious. All these big heads got
together with government funding and
figured that out. Exactly. Um, so it's
it's really important when we look at
fish sticks uh to really understand how
they're made, why they're made, and and
really the popularity of it. and all
these marketing dollars that have been
put against it to really convince people
that they should be eating fish. Let's
look at some of the the fish cons that
many of you out there have. Things that
people worry about. Fishcon number one
is that the fish sticks are not made of
real fish. Not true. Not true at all. In
fact, look at the ingredients. That's
always the key to this. So, it could be
made from tilapia, cod, or pollic or
some combination of it. What then
happens just as you described on the
boat, it is then put and frozen into
blocks. Usually the blocks are about
five times this size. This is fish. This
is fish. And the reason that they freeze
it into blocks and it's just solid fish.
There's no filler. Mash this up and put
like make into a box. Exactly. And then
it goes through basically saw blades to
make it into different shapes like
frozen fish sticks or it could be like a
little cookie cutters. So you have
frozen fish nuggets. It's like a lumber
yard. You're just cutting them. It's but
better. But again, it's all real fish,
so you don't have to worry about
anything like that. But again, always
read the ingredients. So, is there
filler in the fish? I mean, if I'm
literally just taking this and making
into a block and chopping it, is there
filler when I get the box in this box
today? No. Going back a few years, sure,
there were fillers in it. But frankly,
we as consumers are smarter. So, you see
right on the front of a lot of these
packages where it says no fillers
because that's the siren to a mom that
says, "This is what I want. We want
products that have less ingredients, not
more ingredients. If it doesn't say no
filler, that probably means there is
filler. Well, turn it around. There's
very few very few fish stickicks out
there now that have fillers, but it it's
possible. If the price is too cheap, you
know, versus all the others, uh, then
there's probably some filler in it. So,
once they have the right shape, right,
whatever shape you desire, then you take
it to the factory, you fry them, right?
Bride them, and they fry them, right?
Okay. So, what kind of oils they use in
order to accomplish that goal? And I ask
it because one of the main reasons I
talk about fish is because I want you to
get the healthy oils in there. Exactly.
And you're bringing up the biggest
problem because we want omega-3s. Um
that's the real benefit. So if they're
frying it in certain oils like
cottonseed oil or other vegetable oils
that are very high in saturated fats,
you're defeating the purpose. So again,
look at that nutritional information
panel. On it, it'll say how much
saturated fat is in that product. And if
it looks really high,
out the door. Out the door. Next frozen
fish con. Uh, and this is an important
one, was that these are just junk foods.
They're filled with preservatives
because they come in boxes. You know, it
doesn't come looking like a fish. So,
explain what what risks may really exist
here. Sure. Well, the first one is not a
risk. It's called STP. And basically
what this is is a polyphosphate. It's a
sodium bath. And the reason is if you
look at a piece of white fish like this,
it's made up of 80% water. If you look
at salmon, it's 70% water. So what
happens is in the freezing process, if
it's not done properly, and again,
properly meaning freeze it really quick,
really cold temperatures, what happens
is it gets a little little tough uh for
us. So that's why they're doing this. Um
very few companies are doing this
anymore because of the freezing process.
It is totally safe. Not a concern at
all. Just make the reason they did it
was it would hold on the water in the
fish the right way. Exactly. For the
protein. Not harmful, but we don't
really need it anymore. Correct. All
right. So, that's fine. How about this
stuff? The Well, TBHQ, that's a
different story. Now, this is used
basically to extend the shelf life of
products, not only fish, it could be
meats and so on. Now, the FDA says that
it can only be 0.02%
of the total amount of fat in a product.
There have been some animal studies out
there. We don't think it's dangerous.
We're not sure, but if my suggestion, if
you have an ingredient TBHQ on a
product, whether it's meat or fish,
avoid it. That's stated, it's very small
amount in each product. And I think the
bigger reason not to eat too many of
these is they're fried. So, as much as
you eat fried food, you could probably
get away with a little bit of this.
Exactly. All right. So, we reached out
to the American Frozen Food Institute
and they said that TBHQ isn't commonly
used anymore. Echoing what you said.
They also said read the label. Next fish
to con we investigated is the bread to
fish ratio. But who better to help with
these things, right, than Renatha?
You don't want a fried carb, you want a
healthy fish. So, I had Renatha cut open
some popular fish sticks and wanted to
see if these breaded products are just
bread or just a little crusting of bread
with real fish. What'd you find? So, I
mean, as you can see here, it's not all
that bad. We have some good news here,
right? So, the major brands, there's
pretty decent bread to fish ratio. And
it actually looks like fish up in there.
Okay. If you check it out on the on the
side right there. Right. Mostly fish.
Yeah, exactly. It's nice. Pretty decent
uh bread to fish ratio. But this one
over here. Okay. So, now this one is
called a fish patty. And when we cut
into it, um I don't know what's going on
in here. This fish look a little fishy.
Okay.
This fish look a little fishy. And it's
um circular like a bun. So Phil, I mean,
can you help me out? What's going on
with this one over here? Well, it's
chopped and formed. Um typically when
you see products like that, it could
have a list of 20, 30 ingredients, a lot
of chemicals, a lot of preservatives,
things that we've never heard of, lots
of spices. So, you know, you're the Dr.
Oz official taste tester. Take a bite. I
don't want to. Okay, fine. I don't blame
you.
But it's, you know, it looks more like a
hamburger patty. Same concept where
you're chopping up fish. It could be
varieties of fish. Oh, you're brave.
Okay. And then, and then it's tastes
pretty good, actually. Tastes good.
That's what all the spices and the
preservatives and the artificial
additives. That's what they all do.
I want fish. I know. But I wouldn't I
wouldn't pay for the good taste. I'm
paying for the fish. I want that to
taste good. Correct. All right. So, you
want you want to buy the fililelets, not
these pre-formed patties. Correct.
That's the big message.
Thank you as always. Want you want the
other half? No, you can have it.
Supermarket guru here says that the
frozen food aisle is changing when it
comes to fish. Come over here. Give
everyone a pep talk. This is a big deal.
These companies realize that you're
listening. They know that you want the
right food. So, they're making it for
you. What do we need to know? Well,
first of all, if we look in the past 3
years of all the innovation that's
happened in the frozen food case, it's
enormous. We're seeing products that
have three or four ingredients. They've
really shortened that list of chemicals
and preservatives as we talked about a
moment ago. We're seeing lots of
innovation. For example, baked fish that
comes with sauces to it. And also, what
I love is we're now starting to see
companies right on the back and the
front of the package list where the fish
comes from, what the species is.
Sometimes the name of the fisherman, the
plant manager, so we can get all the
information we want. What farmers,
ranchers, and fishermen all want is to
give us transparency. And now because of
technology called blockchain, we're able
we're actually able to trace a product,
a fish from the boat to the distributor
to the supermarket to the manager that
puts it out there and all that
information is wide open for everybody
to see. So great news in the
supermarket. Fish is a lot less fishy.
It is fantastic news. Oh yeah, you can
catch Phil and his new podcast, Farm
Food Facts. It's available on iTunes.
We're going to put a link to it on
dr.com. Check it out when we come back.
Salmon lies. There are salmon lies out
there in the grocery store. And the
grocery store doesn't want you even know
about it. Stay with us.
[Applause]
He could be the deadliest serial killer
in US history. Confessing to 90 unsolved
murders, sketching his victims. Every
single victim had the same deadlike
eyes. Could these drawings finally
identify who they are? This man said,
"That looks like my mother." Plus, how a
photographic memory solved this man's
murder. When I get into a crime scene, I
get into some sort of a zone. All new.
That's coming up tomorrow.
[Music]
Is there something fishy with your
supermarket salmon? Some experts are
saying that this healthy fish has turned
into one of the biggest grocery fraud.
So today, Carrie Hefernan from the
Mterrey Bay Aquarium Seafood Watch
Council of Chefs is here to investigate.
No one knows fish like this guy. So
listen, the first issue is is that the
salmon secret that supermarkets don't
want you to know has to do with
mislabeling. And studies are shown that
when we buy fresh salmon, we could be
getting duped almost half the time. Is
that real? Yeah, it's amazing. Uh
Oceanana, an ocean seafood conservancy
group, has found out that as much as 43%
of salmon is mislabeled. Oh, and this is
something fish fish loving people need
to know. Did you imagine that? I don't I
can say 5% mistake, but 43%. Let's look
at how this is happening because a lot
of it has to do with one problem, right?
And this is a big salmon secret. And
that problem is that 69% of mislabeled
fish is because they identify it as
being wild when it's actually farm
salmon. Now, how can this happen? Why
would people get this wrong? Well,
basically because they'll get more money
for wild salmon. So, one of the things
that you want to think about is actually
buying at some of the larger grocery
stores because they have better labeling
practices uh generally than some of the
smaller operations. Plus, they don't
want to have a big penalty if they're
caught doing it. Whereas the small guys
may not have the resources to figure it
out even. That's right. Much more at
risk. The other thing you need to think
about is that salmon has a season. Do we
have an opportunity? So, shop in the
season. Much like peaches and tomatoes,
it's late spring to early fall. So this
is when fish are at their physical peak.
They're in the ocean getting ready to go
back to their natal rivers and spawn.
And this is when less fraud tends to
occur because there's more wild salmon
naturally in the marketplace. All right.
So if I'm buying fish from now, I
basically go to salmon anyway. I want it
to be wild. I'll buy in the summer or
maybe give me a month or two around the
summer. True. Now the thing is it could
be frozen and then resold as and that's
not a bad thing necessarily. So you can
look for flash frozen salmon or
individually quick frozen salmon. Now
these animals are caught at sea, put
into a hole that's - 10° F in less than
15 minutes. So they actually go through
rigamortis in the defrosting process. So
well handled these fish can be amazing.
Well, why would I just buy my salmon
frozen then? In fact, it's a in the
winter months. Why don't just get it out
of the freezer, pay less, and have it go
through rigger mortise on my kitchen
table? Absolutely. No problem with that
at all. I like that. We'll save money,
too. Absolutely. All right. So, we
reached out to the National Fisheries
Institute for a statement. They agreed
completely that fish fraud is illegal
and ought to be stopped. And they
encourage cousin Ubers to ask
restaurants and retailers if they source
their fish from members of the Better
Seafood Board. The answer has to be yes,
guys. If we don't ask, it's going to
have get worse and worse. If half the
stuff's not what it's supposed to be, we
got to ask. Okay. Next salmon secret is
that your supermarket salmon maybe died
to be the pink color. Think about that
possibility. It's shocking to me they
would actually color your fish. Well,
it's not the worst thing in the world.
So, if you look at this is a wild
salmon. So, it gets that color naturally
from eating a bait that's high in
keratenoids, which could come from algae
or small crustaceans. So, what they do
is they actually introduce keratenoids
into the diet of the farm-raised fish.
And this is not this is farm raised,
right? Correct. Okay. And this is not a
terrible thing. This is FDA approved and
it's actually basically following a
natural pattern. However, just to show
you, if I gave you the fish without the
dye, it would look like this.
Exactly. Yeah. Exactly. Ow. So, how many
of you would buy this fish over this
fish over this fish? That's the real
question, right? Is that the point? That
that is exactly the point. This this
this fish is devoid of carnoids. It has
none of it in it. It hasn't been
introduced to the diet. So, it looks
white and it's a little less appealing
and it's going to get less money. All
right. So just looking at it in a bigger
the the color and the price is more of a
scale here. So the the pinker I make it,
the more money I'll get paid. Exactly.
This So how do they I'm sorry I missed
this. In in the wild they algae to make
this happen. They give it pieces of
shrimp. Is that what they That's right.
They give it algae and ground up
crustaceian shells which is totally what
it would be found in the wild diet. Oh.
So they're not giving it paint or dyes
to eat. No, they're reintroducing many
of the things that the fish naturally
would get. Perfect. I feel much better
about this stuff. And by the way, if
you're in New York City, his restaurant
is called Grand Banks. is actually on a
boat. We tackled the pink, but how about
the white? What is that white stuff that
oozes out of your salmon as you cook?
You ever wonder that? I actually like
the taste of it. The answer as we go to
break.
[Music]
[Applause]
Up next, a breaking news alert about the
measles outbreak. What top health
officials are saying about why this
contagious disease is making an ugly
comeback.
[Music]
[Applause]
A breaking news alert. An infectious
disease that has been declared
eliminated almost 20 years ago is making
an ugly comeback and threatening health
emergencies all over the country. Today,
what you need to know about one of the
most contagious infectious disease known
to man. More contagious than smallox,
influenza, even ebola. We investigate
the measles outbreak. What's really
behind the resurgence of this deadly
disease?
It has plagued humanity for centuries. A
dreaded and highly contagious virus few
could escape, the measles. It starts
with a fever, cough, and runny nose.
Then comes a rash consisting of small
red spots as the body's temperature
climbs dangerously higher and higher.
Complications can be devastating with
ear infections, pneumonia and
encphilitis and inflammation of the
brain. Historically millions of children
were infected every year and hundreds
died from this highly contagious
disease. But in 1963 all that changed
with the advent of the measles vaccine.
By 1980, it was required for all
children attending public schools
nationwide, although some states do
allow for exemptions. Infection rates
plummeted. And finally, in 2000, measles
was considered to be eliminated. That
was 18 years ago. Today, shockingly, the
measles is back. Outbreaks springing up
across the country. Health officials
have likened the resurgence to throwing
a match into a can of gasoline. At
highest risk, infants younger than 12
months, pregnant women with no evidence
of measles immunity, and those with
severely compromised immune systems.
Outrage at the new measles threat is
building. How could this happen? And how
can you protect yourself and your
family?
Let me show you why measles is a
national concern. The outbreak across
the country started last year with more
than 360 cases in 28 states. I mean,
find your state. It's all over the
country. In just in the first two months
of 2019, more than a 100 cases have been
reported. Dr. Nancy Messier, the CDC's
director of the National Center for
Immunization and Respiratory Diseases,
joins us now. Dr. Messier, why has there
been such a huge resurgence of measles
after being eliminated in the US nearly
two decades ago?
Measles has been eliminated in the
United States, but it's continued to
circulate globally, which means we have
continued to have outbreaks in the US.
So, unvaccinated Americans traveling
abroad get exposed to measles and they
bring it back home with them,
contaminating their families and their
communities. You expect this measles
outbreak to spread to more states at
least this year?
Measles is really difficult to predict,
but it's early in the year and I would
expect to see more cases and more states
impacted. Most Americans are vaccinated
against measles, which limits the spread
of the outbreak, but unvaccinated
Americans put themselves and everyone
around them at risk. This includes
people who can't be vaccinated, for
example, young infants who really count
on the cushion of protection provided by
their communities. So, if there's no
treatment or cure for measles once
you've gotten it, what can people do
right now? What should they know about
preventing measles? There is no
treatment or cure for measles. We also
can't predict how serious each case of
measles is going to be. Eating well,
getting enough exercise, getting good
sleep. Those are all parts of a healthy
lifestyle. But the only way to prevent
measles is to get vaccinated. Before you
travel abroad, you should make sure that
you're protected against measles. And
parents should talk to their doctors to
make sure they're protected against
measles and other vaccinereventable
diseases. Dr. Matson, thank you for what
you're doing at the CDC. So, so many of
us, including doctors, have never seen
or remember what measles looks like. So,
let me show you exactly what goes down,
right? So, measles viruses are spread by
little droplets from an infected person.
you sneeze it out or you touch something
and the symptoms start about 10 days
after the infection. You get coldlike
symptoms, runny nose, you get watery red
eyes, high fever. The classic symptoms
that only measles can give you are these
little white spots inside of your mouth.
They're on the cheeks, right? They're
like little grains of white sand. About
2 to four days later, a rash will start
behind the ears before spreading
outwards to the head, the neck, the rest
of the body over the next few days. And
these will coales the spots will
initially be small but they'll get
they'll join together get bigger as and
then as that happens you'll get this
very typical sign of measles. Let's
explain just how contagious the disease
is. Virus hunter Dr. Ian Lipkin is
joining us now. He's an infectious
disease expert from Maya University
Colombia.
I've always respected your expertise on
these issues. You break it down but you
you know you are the person our nation
turns to when we've got viruses we got
to figure out. How contagious is measles
and compare it to Ebola which we all
fear? Compare it to SARS which we hear
about all the time. So this is one of
the most contagious diseases that we
know. When you talk about Ebola which is
something that everyone is concerned
about one person may infect two people.
SARS one person may infect four. So so
even SARS which we talk about being
pretty infectious is one person gets it
four others are at risk on average. Yes
that's an average. Right. So if one
person has measles, how many people on
average will they pass it on to? 12 to
18. 18. As many as 18 people. It's a lot
of folks. Assuming those people are not,
of course, vaccinated. And the reason
for that is because it lies dormant in
your body for a couple days or just the
virus itself tends to infect more
people. It just infects more people.
When you have this this uh period even
before you get the rash, when you're
coughing and so forth, you're spreading
billions and billions of droplets. And
many people can be exposed to that.
Billions and billions of droplets. You
sound like Carl Sean.
So, how quickly can an infection occur?
And I know the unvaccinated are at
greatest risk. They should be paying
attention that yes, the unvaccinated are
the ones who at risk. If you're
vaccinated, um, you know, you have
excellent protection. But how fast do
you get infected if you haven't been
vaccinated? If you get infected, you
have this period of sort of an eclipse
phase when the virus is dormant and you
don't really see anything very much. But
within 4 days to two weeks, you begin to
see the signs that you showed. The spots
inside the mouth, the swelling of the
glands behind the ears, the rash which
covers your body, and that many people
have pneumonia. So, odds are you may not
even know who infected you. That's
correct. Which makes it even scarier for
me. So, up next, we investigate just how
effective and safe is the vaccine? Could
you get the measles even if you've been
vaccinated? Lots of questions like that,
so stick around.
[Music]
Press a few buttons and pop an instant
healthy snack. Or is it more additives,
more chemicals, more stuff? Is there a
microwave popcorn cover up? And the
extremely candid Phillips gets her very
own house call. I'm going to have my Dr.
Oz and I'm going to ask you questions
all the time. Plus, it's the dish on Oz.
This week, the best leftover makeovers.
All new Oz.
That's coming up on Wednesday.
So, when I came in contact with the
measles, I started having runny nose, a
fever, um a very severe cough that would
not go away. Um I woke up at night and
um I was struggling to breathe. So, I
went into a coma for 9 months, came out
of the coma. They told my parents,
"Look,
she is probably not going to be able to
move. able. He's not going to be a be
able to speak. I lost hearing. I lost my
vision. My speech I had to go through
many many years through uh to to take
speech therapy. But here I am 30 years
later. I am here to tell my story. You
know that the measles is deadly.
We're back investigating the recent
resurgence of one of the most contagious
diseases out there, measles. Now, that
woman we're just hearing from, we don't
we don't know this for sure, but you're
saying that that loss of hearing is a
pretty common complication. It's a very
common complication of measles. So,
obviously, if you can't hear, you can't
speak. And so, it you know, it takes a
while to do them both together. So, it's
back from the brink of extinction and
causing outbreaks all around the
country. Dr. Lipkin is here to answer
your urgent questions about measles
vaccinations. I'm going to start with a
question I've been getting asked a lot.
If you have been vaccinated already as a
child, you have to get vaccinated again.
Can you still get the measles despite
the fact that you were vaccinated all
those years ago? If you receive both
vaccines, the starter and the booster,
you're not you have 97% protection. So
that's still possible that you could get
measles, but it's very very unlikely
throughout your whole life, even when
you're older. It's lifelong immunity.
All right. So since the outbreak of
these of the measles and the vaccines of
course have been increasing
dramatically, 500% in some affected
areas, but there are still some people
who have not gotten it. So let's talk to
our audience. Krista has been vaccinated
by the with the measles vaccine, but you
still got a question for us. Yes. So, do
I need to get the booster dose again as
an adult since I've already had it as a
child? Well, if you've had both doses of
the vaccine, then you're as protected as
you're going to be. If you only had one
dose, then it's advisable to have a
second dose. But I can see that you're
expecting. Yes, I am. So, I'm concerned.
And if you're pregnant, you should not
have this vaccine. Okay. What? You
should wait until after you have the
child and then you should have the
vaccine. Well, what what if you're not
sure if you've been vaccinated, then you
get it. That's correct. If you if you
can't find any record to indicate that
you've been vaccinated twice, you've
received the first dose and the booster,
then you should take the vaccine. Okay.
Okay. Maria's got a question for us. If
my kid is too young for the second dose,
should I be worried? So they got the
first dose already when they were at 15
months old or so, right? Then now you're
in between that and school age, which is
when you get second dose normally. What
do you do? You can have the second dose
of the vaccine as soon as four weeks
after the first dose. So this is if this
really is a major concern for you,
you're going abroad. You're concerned
that the child may be exposed, you can
get that second dose of vaccine. Okay.
Some worry about the safety of vaccines.
What are the risks?
There's risk with anything we do,
whether you take aspirin or an
antibiotic. But the risk, as you've
seen, with measles, is so extreme that
the risk benefit ratio makes sense. We
have saved 20 million lives since we've
started using the measles vaccine. Some
people are concerned that this vaccine,
the MMR vaccine, may cause autism. We
and others have looked into this in
detail and we found no evidence that
that's the case.
Thank you for answering our questions
and for all of you for being earnest
about this. If if the measles could come
back from the brink of extinction, what
other diseases do we need to watch out
for? The virus hunter's health threat
forecast is next. What you need to do to
protect yourself. Stay with us.
[Music]
Press a few buttons and pop an instant
healthy snack. Or is it more additives,
more chemicals, more stuff? Is there a
microwave popcorn cover up? All new Oz.
That's coming up on Wednesday.
[Music]
[Applause]
We are back investigating highly
contagious infectious diseases that are
making a troubling comeback. If cases of
measles are spreading, well, then what's
next? the virus hunter, Dr. Ian Lipkin
is back with the health threat forecast
that you need to know about right now.
How can you protect yourself against
some of the most highly contagious
diseases, right, that have caused
sickness and they have caused death each
year. The first health threat to watch
out for is shingles. Now, this is an
infection that's caused by the same
pathogen, same virus that causes
chickenpox. What do we need to know
about it? Uh, so if you're infected with
chickenpox
uh as a child, the virus lies dormant.
It goes into the nervous system. It
lives there. It waits. And at various
points, it can resurface and cause
disease. A third of people who've had
chickenpox will have an episode of
what's called shingles at some point
during their lifetime. It's most common.
A third a third. It's most common at the
age of 60. And it's a it can be a severe
problem. So many people with shingles,
up to a third, will have this syndrome
called post-erpetic neuralgia, which
means that they have an enormous amount
of pain. It's typically in a band around
their chest or around their abdomen in
the same place where they had the
original rash. And this can be prevented
largely by taking a vaccine. And so
there's a very good, very effective
vaccine now that will give you 90%
protection against having shingles. So
we strongly recommend this for everybody
over the age of 60. Now why is it
concerning now?
It's just becoming we're becoming more
aware of it. We also for the very first
time have a way in which we can actually
prevent people from having this disease.
Now there are some people who are more
at risk for shingles than others. people
who are imunosuppressed because they
have cancer or they have an autoimmune
disease. But in our view, everybody over
the age of 60 should have this vaccine.
Yeah, that ugly rash we showed you
earlier is not the real issue. It's the
pain. It's the pain that follows the
rash because what it does is it causes
damage to the nerves. It actually tracks
along the path of the nerves and makes
them hyper sensitive and the pain is
really excruciating for many people. The
next health threat that's been popping
up all over the and it's in the
headlines right now is whooping cough.
There are health officials saying that
this infectious disease is reemerging
right this second. Why do they believe
that? Well, one of the things about
hooping cough is that we know that we
had a we have a very good vaccine to
prevent this disorder. But unlike the
measles vaccine that we were talking
about earlier, you don't get lifelong
immunity. So, you really should have
boosters for hooping cough every 10
years. And if you do that, then you have
good protection against whooping cough.
So adults can get whooping cough as Dr.
Lipin was saying. So listen careful.
This is what it sounds like
a whooping crane, right? You cough so
much you're having trouble getting air
back into your lungs which could cause
other flu-l like symptoms. Pneumonia is
an example of a complication that comes
from it as well. So who's most at risk
and what can you do to protect yourself?
People again who are imunosuppressed
as I said because of cancer, autoimmune
disease, HIV, AIDS, there are whole
series of things that can make you more
vulnerable to hooping cough. Again, the
best way to protect yourself is to have
this vaccine and you should do that on a
regular basis because again, you do not
get lifelong protection. Dr. Liman,
thank you for all you do. We'll be right
back.
You plan all year for that time away,
but what if your next trip turned
deadly? Tourists are extremely
vulnerable. She was found with rope
slashed. Vacation nightmares. Plus, the
dark underground world of child labor.
All new Oz. That's coming up on
Thursday.
Today I want to focus on one of the most
neglected areas of your skin. I'm
talking about your scalp. Now while you
may not notice right some of the
symptoms of dandruff like the itchiness,
the flakes, the dryness and redness of
the moment, could your future proofing
of your scalp actually help you prevent
problems before they return? My next
guest scientist Dr. Rolanda Wilkerson
says yes. She's here on behalf of my
trusted sponsorship partner, Head and
Shoulders. So why do people forget to
treat their scalp? Well, Dr. Guys, as
you know, our scalp is a part of our
skin. However, most people don't even
think about it unless a problem arises.
For many of us, it's an area covered
with a lot of hair. So, we have this out
of sight, out of mind mentality when it
comes to dealing with it. But taking
care of your scalp is so very important
because you want to have that right
environment, a healthy environment in
order for the healthiest hair to emerge.
Now, just doing damage control on your
scalp and your hair is not the best
approach, but future proofing it,
preventing issues from happening down
the road actually is. look very
trustworthy. Be honest now. Any problems
here? It looks amazing. Because my kids
criticize me all the time. That looks
okay. They're telling the truth. Okay,
you're telling the truth. Thank you.
Backhanded praise. Let me show you why
scientists believe it is so important to
futureproof your hair. So, if you
haven't paid attention to your scalp,
come on over here. Let's get this
together. That is what it may look like.
You see a little the flakiness over
here. They get a little crunchy almost,
right? Flaky and dry. Yeah. It may not
look as healthy as it needs to be, which
means everything else is going to be a
little bit awkward as well, including
the itchiness that you may sense.
Exactly. Dr. Wilkers, show us what
happens if you use a scalp moisturizing
shampoo. Something that actually treats
the layers of the scalp correctly. Sure.
You're able to effectively moisturize
the scalp and this eliminates the
dryness and itchiness and oiliness
essentially enabling you to grow healthy
hair. Now, look at this. This is the
kind of hair you want. That's what you
want. Mhm. And you want them coming out
of a nice bed, right? Of skin that's
healthy and plump and looks like it's
happy. It's happy. It's happy and it's
healthy. This is not itchy and there's
not going to be any flaking landing on
your on your shoulders. Exactly. All
right. So, what do you recommend to help
future proof your hair? Simple, easy
plan that everyone can do. Simple, easy
plan. I'd recommend the Head and
Shoulders deep moisture collection. Now,
many people think Head and Shoulders is
only for dandruff, but that is not the
case. Head and Shoulders enables you to
have a healthy scalp. It gives you that
healthy environment in order for your
hair hair to grow healthy and emerge
from the scalp healthy. Now, our deep
moisture conditioner actually
moisturizes the scalp and cares for the
scalp 10 layers deep. And that's what
regular use. And you have 10 layers of
scalp. Yes. Did you guys know that? 10
surface layers. We focus on the out the
outer one that sheds on us. Exactly. But
we should have a regular scalp care so
that we're moisturizing it and care for
it just like we would our skinincare.
Now, our shampoo cares for the scalp and
moisturizes the scalp 75% better than a
leading moisturizing shampoo, and that's
after 16 weeks of regular use in the
study that we conducted. So, a nurse
scalp plus gorgeous hair. I mean, who
doesn't want that? Everyone wants that,
including my next guest is Jesse James
Decker's here on behalf of Head and
Shoulders, and she's joining us via Zoom
from her living room where she has
already started to futureproof her hair.
Jesse, you look wonderful.
Thank you. How are you all doing? Doing
well. Listen, I'm always curious if you
can do it. I'm sure everyone will be
impressed cuz you've got three kids
running around. I know they're quiet at
the moment, but what was your hair like?
Quiet. What was your hair like before
this all started? You know, I have
naturally dry skin. I always have. Um,
everyone knows it. And I too never knew
that I needed to take care of my scalp
the way that I should have. But as soon
as I started using Head and Shoulders,
my scalp feels so much more moisturized.
And I do feel like I don't know, I just
took care of business.
How long did it take for you to notice a
difference? You know, once I started
using Head and Shoulder shampoo and
conditioner, I saw immediately a
difference. And I did realize how
important like my scalp health was to
have beautiful hair. And you know, I'm a
performer so I want to showcase pretty
hair. But, you know, now that my scalp
is healthy and moisturized, I just keep
using Head and Shoulders a few times a
week just to futureproof my scalp
against any damage. Well, I look at that
their beautiful home behind you and I
know that you don't have a lot of time
to yourself. So, I'm assuming this is a
plan that every woman could use because
you can squeeze it into your busy day.
Oh, yeah. You can you can give yourself
a little massage and take care of your
scalp in 15 seconds. Trust me. All
right. Well, God bless you. Look forward
to seeing you here in the set soon. Take
care. Yes. Good to see y'all.
So, Dr. Wilkerson,
how typical are the results that Jesse
James Decker is reporting to us? Her
results are very typical. Head and
Shoulders protects both the scalp and
the hair even before it emerges from the
scalp. That's why we are the only hair
care brand to win a skin award. In fact,
we've won four. The most recent one is
an anti-aging award. And that is because
of the futurep proofing that our
products do for the scalp. So, where do
you find the Head and Shoulders deep
moisture line? You can find it at
Walmart and Walmart.com. Now, here's the
thing. You don't have to look for it if
you're in our audience because thanks to
our partner, Head and Shoulders, my
entire studio audience is going home
with Head and Shoulders deep moisture
shampoo and a conditioner.
But there's more. There's more. You also
get a gift card to Walmart. So, enjoy
it. We'll be right back.
I love getting to talk with you on my
show every single day. But when the
cameras stop rolling, the conversation
is not over. I still have a lot that I
want to talk about. So download the Dr.
Oz podcast on Apple Podcast or wherever
you get your podcast.
[Applause]
Today, an easy hack that you can do to
improve your memory. New research says
your nose your nose can help you
remember. In fact, breathing through
your nose, it won't do it together.
Breath through your nose rather than
through your mouth may help you recall
things easier. Scent can actually help
trigger the brain into remembering. For
example, remember the smell of fresh
baked cookies takes you back to your
childhood, right? Or smell of a flower
or your grandparents house, right? It
seems to stimulate this deep
understanding, this memory. And here's
why researchers say the nose knows. The
nose knows because the part of your
brain that's involved in smell, right,
the olfactory cortex, olactory gland,
it's directly next to the area of the
brain, this area right here, that's
responsible for memory. It's known as
the hippocampus, right? And this is
really critical because when the brain
has two parts that are next to each
other that are doing things, they sort
of reinforce each other. So, we like to
test things out on the show. I conducted
a social experiment to determine if
using your sense of smell can actually
help your memory. We asked five staff
members to try and memorize two
different grocery shop store lists.
Right? These are shopping lists. One
before smelling peppermint essential oil
and a different list afterwards. And we
found 60% scored better on the test
after spelling the essential oil. We
also tried this with a member of our
audience today. Avery is joining us.
Thanks for being here. So baseline
before you got the lavender spell, we
gave you a shopping list with eight
items. And how'd you do? Uh, I didn't do
so hot. Um, I think initially I was
like, "Okay, I got it." And then I think
I only got like maybe four or five of
the items. Well, these are the act the
checks are the four you actually got.
Okay. Four. Okay. This list is not
important because we're going to test
you again. We just gave you some
peppermint oil backstage. Yes. Right.
You remember what to do now. I'm going
to give you another list. Going to show
it to you. You got to remember, right?
You saw the second list. Yeah. Okay.
Audience, here's the second list. You
can see it, but she can't. Go ahead. See
how you can do. Okay.
Um, okay. So, is it lavender on your Is
it on your fingers? We put uh peppermint
on my wrist. Peppermint? Oh, good. Cuz
lavender will put you to sleep. Okay.
Peppermint on your wrist. So, smell. All
right. I think it um Okay. Eggs, kale,
um walnuts,
yogurt. You tied yourself. Okay. Uh
blueberries. Ooh.
Oh, avocados
and uh olive oil. Oh, that's seven out
of eight.
Let me see. That's okay. Let's put it up
here. How close are those? Put the
shopping list up here. It's You see it
all? You got seven out of eight. That's
really good. I think that helped. You
think the peppermint helped you? I think
it's actually It's so weird cuz I think
it's actually kind of really soothing.
So it makes me like not so anxious about
trying to remember something. Maybe
whether the scent helps your mood or
your comfort level or actually your
memory if it's working. It's working. It
is weird. Think things you actually have
at your fingertips. We don't use all the
time. I'm very proud of you for doing
it. And if you got a great memory now
keep me close to you. Remember the nose
those and try to use your sense of smell
next time you need to remember
something. The other change is
happening. Our journey is just
beginning. See you next time.
[Music]